<bill session="110" type="h" number="1012" updated="2009-01-08T18:56:58-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"/></status>

	<introduced date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Growth Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To reform laws and procedures affecting small business.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412196"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400149" joined="2007-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412230" joined="2007-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412235" joined="2007-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400051" joined="2007-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2007-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400651" joined="2007-03-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"><text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committees on Small Business, the Judiciary, Oversight and Government Reform, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"><text>Referred to House Small Business</text></action>
		<action date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1174276800" datetime="2007-03-19"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, the Internet, and Intellectual Property.</text></action>
		<action date="1181016000" datetime="2007-06-05"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/13/2007--Introduced.<br/>Small Business Growth Act of 2007 - Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to provide for establishment and governance of association health plans (AHPs), which are group health plans that meet certain ERISA certification requirements and whose sponsors are trade, industry, professional, chamber of commerce, or similar business associations. Requires the Secretary to establish a Solvency Standards Working Group.<br/>Preempts any state law that may preclude a health insurance issuer from: (1) offering health insurance coverage in connection with a certified AHP; or (2) offering health insurance coverage of the same policy type to other employers operating in the state that are eligible for coverage under such AHPs, whether or not such other employers are participating employers in such plan.<br/>Amends the Internal Revenue Code to extend through 2011 the increased expensing allowance for small business assets.<br/>Amends the Paperwork Reduction Act to prohibit agency heads from imposing civil fines for first-time paperwork violations by small business concerns unless certain requirements are met.<br/>Amends Rule 11 of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure to require courts to impose sanctions on attorneys, law firms, or parties who file frivolous lawsuits. Sets forth provisions concerning: (1) additional sanctions for willful and intentional destruction of certain documents; and (2) public disclosure of Rule 11 proceedings.<br/>Amends the Small Business Act to increase the government-wide goal for procurement contracts awarded to small businesses concerns to 25% (currently, 23%) of federal procurement contracts awarded in a fiscal year.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
