<bill session="110" type="h" number="1036" updated="2009-01-08T18:59:58-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1179247380" datetime="2007-05-15T13:43:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Administrator of General Services to convey a parcel of real property to the Alaska Railroad Corporation.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400440"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text></action>
		<action date="1171429200" datetime="2007-02-14"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text></action>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01" ><text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1178826360" datetime="2007-05-10T16:46:00-04:00"><text>Reported by the Committee on Transportation. H. Rept. 110-145.</text></action>
		<calendar number="85" date="1178826360" datetime="2007-05-10T16:46:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 85.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1179246900" datetime="2007-05-15T13:35:00-04:00"><text>Ms. Johnson, E. B. moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1179246960" datetime="2007-05-15T13:36:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H5003-5004"/></action>
		<action date="1179246960" datetime="2007-05-15T13:36:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1036.</text></action>
		<vote date="1179247380" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-05-15T13:43:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H5003-5004"/></vote>
		<action date="1179288000" datetime="2007-05-16"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
		<action date="1212724800" datetime="2008-06-06"><text>Provisions of Measure Incorporated into Title IV, Section 401 of P.L. 110-244, (H.R. 1195)..</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/15/2007--Passed House amended. Requires the Administrator of the General Services Administration (GSA) to convey all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the GSA Fleet Management Center (located in Anchorage, Alaska) to the Alaska Railroad Corporation in exchange for: (1) suitable replacement property and such other consideration as agreed to; or (2) payment of fair market value. Requires any proceeds received to be deposited into the Federal Buildings Fund.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
