<bill session="110" type="h" number="1050" updated="2009-01-08T19:01:41-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1171429200" datetime="2007-02-14"/></status>

	<introduced date="1171429200" datetime="2007-02-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">A Living Wage, Jobs For All Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a living wage, jobs for all policy for all peoples in the United States and its territories, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400237"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2008-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2008-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400227" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400080" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2008-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400198" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400130" joined="2008-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400402" joined="2008-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400350" joined="2008-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400074" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400638" joined="2008-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2008-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2008-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2008-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400204" joined="2008-06-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400310" joined="2008-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400240" joined="2008-04-02"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1171429200" datetime="2007-02-14"><text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committees on the Budget, Armed Services, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1171429200" datetime="2007-02-14"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1171429200" datetime="2007-02-14"><text>Referred to House Budget</text></action>
		<action date="1171429200" datetime="2007-02-14"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1171429200" datetime="2007-02-14"><text>Referred to House Rules</text></action>
		<action date="1173844800" datetime="2007-03-14"><committee name="House Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text></action>
		<action date="1181016000" datetime="2007-06-05"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/14/2007--Introduced.<br/>A Living Wage, Jobs for All Act - Declares that Congress affirms the basic economic rights and responsibilities under the 1944 &quot;Economic Bill of Rights,&quot; while updating and extending it to include: (1) certain rights to decent jobs, income security for individuals unable to work for pay, a decent living for farm families, freedom from monopolies, decent housing, adequate health services, Social Security in old age, sickness, accidental injury, and unemployment, and education and work training; and (2) certain other rights relating to collective bargaining, a safe working environment, information on trends in pollution sources and products and processes that affect the well-being of workers throughout the world, voting and campaigning, and personal security. Requires corporations registered with the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to disclose fully in annual reports the impact of their activities on environmental quality and on the rights of other stakeholders, including employees, consumers, and communities. Requires each state to require all state-chartered corporations to submit such annual reports. Directs the Attorney General to establish a computerized registration program of all corporations found guilty of violating a federal or state law. Authorizes the President to deny federal contracts, loans, or loan guarantees to non-compliant corporations. Requires federal agencies and commissions, including the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, to help establish and maintain conditions under which all adult Americans may freely exercise the economic rights specified in 1944 and in this Act. Prohibits federal agencies or commissions from promoting recession, stagnation, or unemployment to reduce wages or inflation. Directs the President to establish a full employment framework for the annual budget submitted to Congress that meets specified goals for: (1) quality of life and environment; (2) responsible, sustainable growth; (3) unemployment reduction; and (4) human rights. Requires the Joint Economic Committee to oversee actions under this Act and submit an annual Concurrent Resolution on Economic Policy setting forth its proposed employment goals.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
