<bill session="110" type="h" number="1067" updated="2009-01-08T19:03:49-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a Federal coordination and planning process for advanced research instrumentation and facilities.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400011"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"><text>Referred to the Committee on Science and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"><text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text></action>
		<action date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1172034000" datetime="2007-02-21"><committee name="House Science and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Research and Science Education.</text></action>
		<action date="1181016000" datetime="2007-06-05"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/15/2007--Introduced.<br/>Requires the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy to: (1) use the National Science and Technology Council as a forum for coordination and collaboration among federal agencies in developing best practices for the support of advanced research instrumentation and facilities at academic institutions; (2) encourage the development of centralized programs for the support of advanced research instrumentation and facilities at all federal research agencies that sponsor research at academic institutions; and (3) develop and implement policies for federal support for advanced research instrumentation and facilities as described in this Act. Requires such forum to also provide advice to the Director in developing those policies.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
