<bill session="110" type="h" number="1074" updated="2009-01-08T19:04:40-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Reducing the Need for Abortion and Supporting Parents Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Title X Family Planning Services Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for programs that reduce the number of unplanned pregnancies, reduce the need for abortion, help women bear healthy children, and support new parents.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400352"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400227" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400177" joined="2007-03-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400092" joined="2008-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400623" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400129" joined="2007-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400443" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400379" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400124" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400229" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400300" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400412" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400355" joined="2007-03-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400216" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400007" joined="2007-10-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400230" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412193" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400103" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400087" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400270" joined="2008-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400259" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400195" joined="2008-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400251" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400211" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400120" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2007-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400326" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412228" joined="2008-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400391" joined="2007-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400215" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400114" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400062" joined="2008-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400233" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400100" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400309" joined="2007-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412233" joined="2007-02-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Education and Labor, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1181016000" datetime="2007-06-05"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Healthy Families and Communities.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/15/2007--Introduced.<br/>Reducing the Need for Abortion and Supporting Parents Act - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to provide education on preventing teen pregnancies.<br/>Provides for: (1) grants to prevent teen pregnancy; and (2) a national center for parents of adolescents to support parents in preventing teen pregnancy.<br/>Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of Social Security Act to expand coverage of family planning services. Sets forth requirements for primary care clinics that receive federal financial assistance and provide abortion services.<br/>Expands state options to provide health care coverage to low-income pregnant women.<br/>Title X Family Planning Services Act of 2007 - Authorizes appropriations for voluntary family planning projects.<br/>Amends the Public Health Service Act to prohibit individual health insurance coverage from excluding pregnancy as a preexisting condition. Provides for: (1) grants for ultrasound equipment and prenatal testing for pregnant women; and (2) programs to better identify and treat pregnant women and mothers who are victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking. Allows the Secretary to make grants to public institutions of higher education to assist students who have decided to carry their pregnancies to term and parenting students in continuing their studies and graduating. Requires the Secretary to require that federally funded group homes for pregnant and parenting women provide, upon request, adoption counseling and counseling on parenting skills.<br/>Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) increase the tax credit for adoption expenses; (2) make such tax credit refundable; and (3) increase the exclusion from gross income for employer-paid adoption expenses.<br/>Provides for: (1) education of teen and first-time mothers through home visits by registered nurses; and (2) the collection and reporting of abortion surveillance data.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
