<bill session="110" type="h" number="1075" updated="2009-01-08T19:04:48-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">United States Territories Infrastructure Bond Bank Authorization Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the United States Territories Infrastructure Bond Bank, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400041"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400073" joined="2007-02-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"><text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1172811600" datetime="2007-03-02"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insular Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/15/2007--Introduced.<br/>United States Territories Infrastructure Bond Bank Authorization Act - Directs the Secretary to establish a United States Territories Infrastructure Bond Bank to provide low-cost financing for the governments of American Samoa, Guam, the U.S. Virgin Islands, and the Northern Mariana Islands to construct infrastructure or to refinance debt acquired to construct infrastructure. Directs the Secretary to incorporate the Bank in a U.S. jurisdiction and organize the initial meeting of its Board of Directors, which shall consist of five members, with one appointed by the Secretary and each of the governors of American Samoa, Guam, the U.S. Virgin Islands, and the Northern Mariana Islands. Allows the Secretary, after the initial five years of the Bank's existence, to invite the governor of another U.S. territory to appoint a Board member, at which time eligibility for Bank services shall be extended to that territory. Authorizes the interception of federal aid intended for a U.S. territory that has defaulted on an obligation to the Bank. Exempts Bank activities and income from taxation. 
	</summary>
</bill>
