<bill session="110" type="h" number="1088" updated="2009-01-08T19:06:25-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Elizabeth Cady Stanton Pregnant and Parenting Student Services Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a pilot program to provide grants to encourage eligible institutions of higher education to establish and operate pregnant and parenting student services offices for pregnant students, parenting students, prospective parenting students who are anticipating a birth or adoption, and students who are placing or have placed a child for adoption.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400211"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400380" joined="2007-09-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400096" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400095" joined="2007-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400132" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400288" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400285" joined="2007-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400055" joined="2007-09-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400352" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400640" joined="2007-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400299" joined="2007-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400617" joined="2007-10-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="2007-05-16"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1181016000" datetime="2007-06-05"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/15/2007--Introduced.<br/>Elizabeth Cady Stanton Pregnant and Parenting Student Services Act of 2007 - Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) pregnant college students should not have to make a choice between keeping their baby and staying in school; (2) the pilot program under this Act will help institutions of higher education to establish offices that will operate independent of federal funding within five years after enactment of this Act; and (3) amounts appropriated to carry out other federal programs should be reduced to offset the costs of this Act. Directs the Secretary of Education to establish a pilot program to provide grants to encourage eligible institutions of higher education to establish and operate pregnant and parenting student services offices for pregnant students, parenting students, prospective parenting students anticipating a birth or adoption, and students who are placing or have placed a child for adoption.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
