<bill session="110" type="h" number="11" updated="2009-01-08T16:41:53-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/></status>

	<introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">NSA Oversight Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To reiterate that chapters 119 and 121 of title 18, United States Code, and the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 are the exclusive means by which domestic electronic surveillance may be conducted, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400361"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400413" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2007-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400134" joined="2007-01-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400102" joined="2007-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400246" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400430" joined="2007-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400129" joined="2007-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400003" joined="2007-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400184" joined="2007-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400355" joined="2007-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="412188" joined="2007-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400245" joined="2007-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400402" joined="2007-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400663" joined="2007-01-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="2007-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400166" joined="2007-01-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400426" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2007-03-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="412200" joined="2007-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400193" joined="2007-01-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400415" joined="2007-01-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400649" joined="2007-01-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400043" joined="2007-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400097" joined="2007-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400025" joined="2007-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400622" joined="2007-01-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Referred to House Intelligence (Permanent Select)</text></action>
		<action date="1170392400" datetime="2007-02-02"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/4/2007--Introduced.<br/>NSA Oversight Act - States that provisions of the federal criminal code concerning wire and electronic communications and their interception and the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (FISA) are the exclusive means by which domestic electronic surveillance may be conducted until specific statutory authorization for any other such surveillance is enacted. Requires the President to report to the congressional intelligence committees on the Terrorist Surveillance Program of the National Security Agency (NSA) as well as any other program which involves electronic surveillance of U.S. persons in the United States conducted by a federal department or agency without fully complying with FISA procedures. Authorizes additional judges for the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court (Court). Extends from 72 to 168 hours the period after initiating an emergency electronic surveillance to apply for a court order authorizing such surveillance. States that a court order is not required for the acquisition of communications between persons not located within the United States for the purpose of collecting foreign intelligence information, whether the communication passes through, or the surveillance device is located within, the United States. Authorizes the hiring of additional personnel within the Department of Justice (DOJ), Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI), NSA, and the Court.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
