<bill session="110" type="h" number="1118" updated="2009-01-08T19:10:46-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"/></status>

	<introduced date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Drug Trafficking Elimination Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Controlled Substances Act to enhance criminal penalties for drug trafficking offenses relating to distribution of heroin, marijuana, and methamphetamine and distribution to and use of children, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400212"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400381" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400137" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400071" joined="2007-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400365" joined="2007-02-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="412196" joined="2007-10-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400654" joined="2007-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400321" joined="2007-02-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"><text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1172552400" datetime="2007-02-27"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1174276800" datetime="2007-03-19"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/16/2007--Introduced.<br/>Drug Trafficking Elimination Act of 2007 - Amends the Controlled Substances Act and the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act to increase prison terms or impose mandatory minimum prison terms for: (1) manufacturing, distributing, dispensing, or possessing certain large amounts of heroin, marihuana, or methamphetamine; (2) importing or exporting such drugs; (3) manufacturing or cultivating a controlled substance on federal property; (4) using hazardous substances on federal land in connection with illegal drug activities; (5) possessing a listed chemical with intent to manufacture a controlled substance; (6) committing a crime of violence during and in relation to a drug trafficking crime; (7) engaging in a dangerous drug trafficking organization; (8) distributing controlled substances to persons under age 21 or to a pregnant person; (9) distributing controlled substances in or near schools; and (10) employing or involving persons under age 18 in illegal drug activities.<br/>Directs the Attorney General to develop a National Drug Trafficking Enforcement Strategy. 
	</summary>
</bill>
