<bill session="110" type="h" number="1136" updated="2009-01-08T19:13:04-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"/></status>

	<introduced date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Ethics Reform Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To abolish the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct in the House of Representatives, establish an Independent Ethics Commission, and provide for the transfer of the duties and functions of the committee to the Commission.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400033"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400419" joined="2007-02-16"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"><text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on Rules, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"><text>Referred to House House Administration</text></action>
		<action date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"><text>Referred to House Rules</text></action>
		<action date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1171688400" datetime="2007-02-17"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E394-395)</text></action>
		<action date="1174276800" datetime="2007-03-19"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text></action>
		<action date="1179374400" datetime="2007-05-17"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H5335-5336)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/16/2007--Introduced.<br/>Ethics Reform Act of 2007 - Amends Rule X (Organization of Committees) of the Rules of the House to abolish the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct. Establishes within the legislative branch an Independent Ethics Commission to perform the duties of the Committee. Amends the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 to transfer functions of the Secretary of the Senate and the Clerk of the House to the Commission with respect to: (1) registration of lobbyists; (2) disclosure and enforcement; (3) penalties; and (4) rules of construction. Requires quarterly instead of semiannual filing of lobbying disclosure reports with the Commission in an electronic form to made available to the public free of charge over the Internet. Requires the Commission to continue any investigations pending before the Committee six months after the enactment of this Act. Sets forth House procedures for consideration of Commission recommendations.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
