<bill session="110" type="h" number="1148" updated="2009-01-08T19:14:35-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"/></status>

	<introduced date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Safe Food Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Food Safety Administration to protect the public health by preventing food-borne illness, ensuring the safety of food, improving research on contaminants leading to food-borne illness, and improving security of food from intentional contamination, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400103"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400160" joined="2007-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2007-03-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400198" joined="2007-05-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400063" joined="2007-03-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400274" joined="2007-10-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400101" joined="2008-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400245" joined="2007-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400663" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400259" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400346" joined="2008-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2007-04-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400211" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400074" joined="2007-03-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2008-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2008-06-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400024" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="2007-02-16"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action date="1172552400" datetime="2007-02-27"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/16/2007--Introduced.<br/>Safe Food Act of 2007 - Establishes the Food Safety Administration to administer and enforce food safety laws. Directs the Administrator of the Food Safety Administration to: (1) promulgate regulations to ensure the security of the food supply from all forms of contamination; (2) implement federal food safety inspection, enforcement, and research efforts to protect the public health; (3) develop consistent and science-based standards for safe food; and (4) prioritize federal food safety efforts and deployment of resources to achieve the greatest possible benefit in reducing food-borne illness. Transfers to the Administration all functions of specified federal agencies that relate to the administration or enforcement of food safety laws. Requires the Administrator to: (1) administer a national food safety program based on an analysis of the hazards associated with different food and the processing of different food; (2) establish standards for processors of food and food establishments; (3) establish a certification system for foreign governments or food establishments seeking to import food to the United States; (4) establish requirements for tracing food and food producing animals from point of origin to retail sale; (5) maintain an active surveillance system of food, food products, and epidemiological evidence; (6) establish a sampling system to monitor contaminants in food; (7) rank and analyze hazards in the food supply; (8) establish a national public education campaign on food safety; and (9) conduct research relating to food safety. Sets forth provisions regarding prohibited acts, administrative detention, condemnation, temporary holds, recall, penalties for violations of food safety laws, whistle blower protection, and civil actions.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
