<bill session="110" type="h" number="1149" updated="2009-01-08T19:14:42-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"/></status>

	<introduced date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Justice for Public Safety Officers Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, to protect federally funded public safety officers.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400115"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400267" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400361" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400196" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400176" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400433" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400144" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400006" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400277" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400057" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400343" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400039" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400400" joined="2007-03-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1171688400" datetime="2007-02-17"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E390)</text></action>
		<action date="1174276800" datetime="2007-03-19"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/16/2007--Introduced.<br/>Justice for Public Safety Officers Act - Amends the federal criminal code to prohibit and impose enhanced criminal penalties for: (1) killing (or attempting or conspiring to kill) a federally protected safety officer (or former officer) while such officer is engaged in official duties or on the account of the performance of such duties; and (2) interstate or foreign flight to avoid prosecution, custody, or confinement for killing a federally protected safety officer. Defines &quot;federally protected safety officer&quot; as a public safety officer for a public agency that receives annual federal assistance of more than $10,000. Includes within the definition of &quot;federally protected safety officer&quot; judicial officers, law enforcement officers, firefighters, chaplains, and members of a rescue squad or ambulance crew.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
