<bill session="110" type="h" number="1169" updated="2009-01-08T19:17:11-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"/></status>

	<introduced date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Student Achievement and Successful Schools Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to clarify Federal requirements under such Act.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400259"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400073" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400160" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400155" joined="2007-11-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400080" joined="2007-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="412195" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400198" joined="2007-10-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400132" joined="2007-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400285" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412198" joined="2007-11-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400001" joined="2007-11-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400346" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400299" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="412186" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400440" joined="2007-11-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400043" joined="2007-11-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400345" joined="2007-12-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1181016000" datetime="2007-06-05"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/16/2007--Introduced.<br/>Student Achievement and Successful Schools Act of 2007 - Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) full funding should be provided to schools to allow them to satisfy federal mandates required under the No Child Left Behind Act of 2001 (NCLBA), which amended the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA); and (2) states and school districts should have the necessary flexibility in implementing NCLBA to ensure that all students are successful and achieve all of the goals of the law. Amends ESEA to revise requirements relating to: (1) adequate yearly progress (AYP); (2) measurements of student achievement, allowing such measurements to be made on a longitudinal basis; (3) supplemental educational services; (4) deadlines for evaluating teachers and paraprofessionals as highly qualified; and (5) the process by which teachers of multiple subjects may demonstrate such competence. Directs the Secretary of Education to: (1) allocate federal funds to pay for administrative costs of demonstrating AYP and for paraprofessional training; and (2) make performance bonus grants to eligible states for non-administrative functions by schools that have closed achievement gaps to a certain degree between specified subgroups. Authorizes state and local educational agencies and schools to defer implementation of certain ESEA requirements in any fiscal year when the amount appropriated under ESEA and the Individuals with Disabilities Act does not equal or exceed a specified authorized amount. Directs the Comptroller General to study and report on certain topics concerning how costs of NCLBA mandates may affect adequate funding for ESEA.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
