<bill session="110" type="h" number="1179" updated="2009-01-08T19:18:24-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"/></status>

	<introduced date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To clarify the authority of the Secretary of the Interior with regard to management of elk in Rocky Mountain National Park.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400412"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400155" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400274" joined="2007-06-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E376-377)</text></action>
		<action date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1172466000" datetime="2007-02-26"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/16/2007--Introduced.<br/>Declares that nothing in the Act of March 2, 1929, (relating to prohibited acts of killing, wounding, or capturing wild birds and animals and fish in Rocky Mountain National Park, Colorado) or other applicable law shall be construed as prohibiting the Secretary of the Interior from using the services of qualified individuals, as volunteers or under contract with the Secretary, to assist in the implementation of the Elk and Vegetation Management Plan for the Park by using lethal means to reduce the population of elk within the Park. Instructs the Secretary to consult with the Colorado Division of Wildlife regarding possible participation by it in the implementation of such Plan. Prohibits anything in this Act from being construed as applicable to the taking of wildlife within Rocky Mountain National Park for any purpose other than the implementation of the Elk and Vegetation Management Plan. 
	</summary>
</bill>
