<bill session="110" type="h" number="1186" updated="2009-01-08T19:19:12-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"/></status>

	<introduced date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">United States-India Energy Security Cooperation Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To promote global energy security through increased cooperation between the United States and India in diversifying sources of energy, stimulating development of alternative fuels, developing and deploying technologies that promote the clean and efficient use of coal, and improving energy efficiency.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400433"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2007-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400400" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400195" joined="2007-02-16"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/16/2007--Introduced.<br/>United States-India Energy Security Cooperation Act of 2007 - Declares it is the policy of the United States to: (1) cooperate with India to address common energy challenges, to ensure future global energy security, and to increase the world-wide availability of clean energy; (2) promote dialogue and increased understanding between the United States and India on our respective national energy policies and strategies as an integral part of the expanding strategic partnership between the two countries; and (3) collaborate with India in energy research that fosters market-based approaches to energy security and offers the promise of technological breakthroughs that reduce oil dependency globally. Authorizes the President to establish programs in support of greater energy cooperation between the United States and India. Authorizes assistance for cooperation related to: (1) clean coal and emission reduction technologies and carbon sequestration projects; (2) alternative fuel sources, such as ethanol, bio-mass, coal-based fuels, and hydrogen; (3) energy efficiency projects; (4) commercially available technologies that promote clean and efficient energy use in India; and (5) technical assistance in support of India's development of a strategic oil reserve.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
