<bill session="110" type="h" number="1184" updated="2009-01-08T19:18:58-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"/></status>

	<introduced date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">At-Risk Youth Protection Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To increase community service by students at risk of education failure and thereby reduce youth and gang violence.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400423"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"><text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1181016000" datetime="2007-06-05"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Healthy Families and Communities.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/16/2007--Introduced.<br/>At-Risk Youth Protection Act of 2007 - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to make grants to states for subgrants to alternative public schools or programs that serve the needs of students at risk of educational failure. Requires subgrantees to require their secondary school students to perform at least 100 hours of community service each school year and receive training or counseling on conflict resolution as a prerequisite to performing such service. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide a tax deduction to a business of: (1) $750 per 100 hours of community service provided by such a student through such business during the taxable year; and (2) $2,000 for each graduate of such alternative school or program who completes one year of employment with such business.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
