<bill session="110" type="h" number="1196" updated="2009-01-08T19:20:26-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1172552400" datetime="2007-02-27"/></status>

	<introduced date="1172552400" datetime="2007-02-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="popular" as="">Authorization bill FY2007 Intelligence Agencies</title>
		<title type="popular" as="">Intelligence Agencies FY2007 Authorization bill</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2007 for intelligence and intelligence-related activities of the United States Government, the Community Management Account, and the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability System, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400337"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1172552400" datetime="2007-02-27"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select).</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/27/2007--Introduced.<br/>Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2007 - Authorizes appropriations for FY2007 for the conduct of intelligence and intelligence-related activities of the: (1) Office of the Director of National Intelligence; (2) Central Intelligence Agency (CIA); (3) Department of Defense (DOD); (4) Defense Intelligence Agency (DIA); (5) National Security Agency (NSA); (6) Departments of the Army, Navy, and Air Force; (7) Departments of State, the Treasury, Energy, and Justice; (8) Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI); (9) National Reconnaissance Office; (10) National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency; (11) Coast Guard; (12) Department of Homeland Security; and (13) Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA). Specifies that the amounts authorized and the authorized personnel ceilings as of September 30, 2007, for such activities are those specified in the classified Schedule of Authorizations, which shall be made available to the Senate and House Appropriations Committees and the President. Allows the Director of Central Intelligence, with the approval of the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, to authorize employment of civilian personnel in excess of the number authorized for FY2007 when necessary for the performance of important intelligence functions. Requires notification of the congressional intelligence committees on the use of such authority. Authorizes appropriations for the Intelligence Community Management Account for FY2007, as well as for full-time personnel for elements within such Account. Authorizes appropriations for FY2007 for the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability Fund. Specifies that the authorization of appropriations by this Act shall not be deemed to constitute authority for the conduct of any intelligence activity which is not otherwise authorized by the Constitution of laws of the United States.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
