<bill session="110" type="h" number="1219" updated="2009-01-08T19:23:08-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1172552400" datetime="2007-02-27"/></status>

	<introduced date="1172552400" datetime="2007-02-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Equity and Fairness in Fee-for-Service Reimbursement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide geographic equity in fee-for-service reimbursement for providers under the Medicare Program.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400437"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1172552400" datetime="2007-02-27"><text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1172552400" datetime="2007-02-27"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1172552400" datetime="2007-02-27"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1172638800" datetime="2007-02-28"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1173243600" datetime="2007-03-07"><committee name="House Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/27/2007--Introduced.<br/>Medicare Equity and Fairness in Fee-for-Service Reimbursement Act of 2007 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a system for making adjustments to the amount of payment made to providers of services and health care professionals for services provided under the original Medicare fee-for-service program, with specified formulae for states whose average per beneficiary amount is: (1) greater than 100% of the national average; or (2) less than 100% of the national average. Provides for a three year phase-in of such rates.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
