<bill session="110" type="h" number="121" updated="2009-01-08T16:57:45-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/></status>

	<introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">High-Performance Green Buildings Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To improve efficiency in the Federal Government through the use of high-performance green buildings, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400114"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400420" joined="2007-10-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400039" joined="2007-01-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, Science and Technology, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text></action>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text></action>
		<action date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"><committee name="House Science and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text></action>
		<action date="1170392400" datetime="2007-02-02"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text></action>
		<action date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"><committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Organization, and Procurement.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/4/2007--Introduced.<br/>High-Performance Green Buildings Act of 2007 - Directs the Administrator of General Services to establish an Office of High-Performance Green Buildings. Requires the Office Director to: (1) establish a Green Building Advisory Committee; (2) carry out public outreach; (3) develop and recommend a high-performance green building research plan; (4) analyze current budget and contracting practices that affect achievement of high-performance green buildings; and (5) develop and implement a comprehensive indoor air quality program for federal facilities. Requires the Director to identify incentives to encourage the use of green buildings and related technology in federal government operations. Requires the Director of the Office of Federal Procurement Policy to: (1) revise applicable acquisition regulations; and (2) issue guidance to federal procurement executives on renegotiating proposed facilities design, existing facilities renovations, and leased facilities improvements. Requires the Director to consult with the Committee to assist in the implementation of the Environmental Stewardship Scorecard announced at the White House Summit on federal sustainable buildings in 2006. Requires the Office to carry out specified demonstration projects at federal buildings and universities to contribute to its research goals. 
	</summary>
</bill>
