<bill session="110" type="h" number="1244" updated="2009-01-08T19:26:23-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1172638800" datetime="2007-02-28"/></status>

	<introduced date="1172638800" datetime="2007-02-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Student Medical Access Raising Test Scores Health Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to establish the School-Based Health Clinic program, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400204"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400290" joined="2007-09-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400102" joined="2007-12-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400216" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="412204" joined="2007-05-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2007-10-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400201" joined="2007-05-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400090" joined="2007-10-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1172638800" datetime="2007-02-28"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/28/2007--Introduced.<br/>Student Medical Access Raising Test Scores Health Act of 2007 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to award grants for the cost of operating school-based health clinics (SBHCs) to provide comprehensive primary health services during school hours to children and adolescents by health professionals. Requires SBHCs to: (1) provide services to children and adolescents for whom parental or guardian consent has been obtained; (2) provide on-site access during the academic day when school is in session and 24-hour coverage through an on-call system and backup health providers to ensure access to services on a year-round basis when the school or SBHC is closed. Allows the Secretary to: (1) give preference to applicants who demonstrate an ability to serve populations of children and adolescents that have historically demonstrated difficulty in accessing health and mental health services; and (2) waive certain requirements under this Act for a designated period.<br/>Requires the Secretary to establish a program to provide technical and other assistance to SBHCs.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
