<bill session="110" type="h" number="124" updated="2009-01-08T16:58:06-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/></status>

	<introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Farm Programs Payment Limitation Integrity Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require the prompt issuance by the Secretary of Agriculture of regulations to restore integrity to the payment limitation requirements applicable to commodity payments and benefits, to reduce waste, fraud, and abuse related to the receipt of commodity payments and benefits, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400640"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400443" joined="2007-01-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text></action>
		<action date="1172811600" datetime="2007-03-02"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on General Farm Commodities and Risk Management.</text></action>
		<action date="1172811600" datetime="2007-03-02"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Specialty Crops, Rural Development, and Foreign Agriculture.</text></action>
		<action date="1172811600" datetime="2007-03-02"><text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/4/2007--Introduced.<br/>Farm Programs Payment Limitation Integrity Act - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to promulgate regulations to establish measurable standards to prevent the use of separate entities to exceed commodity payment limitations and to provide payments only to active farmers. Amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to provide that if the Secretary determines that a person has committed fraud in connection with the adoption of a scheme or device to evade payment limitations such person shall be ineligible for farm program payments in the crop year for which the scheme or device was adopted and the succeeding five crop years. 
	</summary>
</bill>
