<bill session="110" type="h" number="1243" updated="2009-01-08T19:26:16-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1172638800" datetime="2007-02-28"/></status>

	<introduced date="1172638800" datetime="2007-02-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Gulf Coast Back to Business Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To address ongoing small business and homeowner needs in the Gulf Coast States impacted by Hurricane Katrina and Hurricane Rita.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400201"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400635" joined="2007-02-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400399" joined="2007-02-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1172638800" datetime="2007-02-28"><text>Referred to the Committee on Small Business, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1172638800" datetime="2007-02-28"><text>Referred to House Small Business</text></action>
		<action date="1172638800" datetime="2007-02-28"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1172638800" datetime="2007-02-28"><text>Referred to House Financial Services</text></action>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/28/2007--Introduced.<br/>Gulf Coast Back to Business Act of 2007 - Authorizes appropriations for the Economic Development Administration of the Department of Commerce for grants to appropriate state government agencies in Louisiana and Mississippi for small businesses located in disaster areas caused by Hurricanes Katrina or Rita. Amends the Small Business Act to authorize the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to defer for a conditional period the payment of principal and interest on disaster loans made to small businesses affected by such hurricanes in the case of loans made before December 31, 2006. Prohibits an increased collateral requirement with respect to the deferred loans. Includes as a HUBZone (historically underutilized business zone) any area in which the President has declared a major disaster as a result of such hurricanes. Amends the Small Business Competitive Demonstration Program Act of 1988 to make the small business competitive demonstration program (to test innovative small business procurement methods and procedures) inapplicable, for a conditional period, to any contract related to relief or reconstruction from such hurricanes.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
