<bill session="110" type="h" number="1254" updated="2009-01-08T19:27:36-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1173929040" datetime="2007-03-14T12:24:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="142"/></status>

	<introduced date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Presidential Library Donation Reform Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Presidential Library Donation Reform Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Presidential Library Donation Reform Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Presidential Library Donation Reform Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 44, United States Code, to require information on contributors to Presidential library fundraising organizations.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400425"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2007-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400116" joined="2007-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400003" joined="2007-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400423" joined="2007-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="2007-03-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400055" joined="2007-03-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400001" joined="2007-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="412211" joined="2007-03-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400251" joined="2007-03-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400120" joined="2007-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400074" joined="2007-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400415" joined="2007-03-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400090" joined="2007-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400321" joined="2007-03-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text></action>
		<action date="1173330000" datetime="2007-03-08"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1173330000" datetime="2007-03-08" ><text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1173476340" datetime="2007-03-09T17:39:00-05:00"><text>Reported by the Committee on Oversight and Government. H. Rept. 110-43.</text></action>
		<calendar number="19" date="1173476340" datetime="2007-03-09T17:39:00-05:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 19.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1173879480" datetime="2007-03-14T10:38:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Murphy (CT) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text></action>
		<action date="1173879540" datetime="2007-03-14T10:39:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2493-2496"/></action>
		<action date="1173879540" datetime="2007-03-14T10:39:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1254.</text></action>
		<action date="1173880860" datetime="2007-03-14T11:01:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1173884160" datetime="2007-03-14T11:56:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2507-2508"/></action>
		<vote date="1173929040" how="roll" roll="142" datetime="2007-03-14T12:24:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" suspension="1" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 390 - 34 (Roll no. 142).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H2493-2494"/></vote>
		<action date="1173931200" datetime="2007-03-15"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1185940800" datetime="2007-08-01" ><text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1193025600" datetime="2007-10-22"><text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman with amendments. With written report No. 110-202.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="435" date="1193025600" datetime="2007-10-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 435.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/22/2007--Reported to Senate amended. Presidential Library Donation Reform Act of 2007 - Amends federal law regarding presidential archival depositories to require any presidential library fundraising organization to submit quarterly reports to the National Archives and Records Administration and specified congressional committees on every contributor who: (1) respecting a Presidential archival depository (including a depository of a President who currently holds the Office of President) for which the Archivist of the United States has not accepted, taken title to, or entered into an agreement to use any land or facility for the archival depository, gave a contribution or contributions (whether monetary or in-kind) totaling $200 or more for a quarterly period; or (2) respecting such a depository for which the Archivist has accepted, taken title to, or entered into an agreement to use any land or facility for the archival depository, gave the organization a contribution or contributions (whether monetary or in-kind) totaling $1, 250 or more for a quarterly period. Requires the submission of such information to continue to apply to a Presidential library fundraising organization during the lifetime of the President whose archives benefit from such fundraising. Requires the Archivist to make such information available to the public through the Internet (or a successor technology readily available to the public) as soon as is practicable after each quarterly filing. Requires that such information be made available without a fee or other access charge, in a searchable, sortable, and downloadable database. Prohibits knowing and willful submissions of false information or omissions of material information by contributors or the fundraising organization. Prescribes criminal penalties for violation of such prohibitions. Prohibits any person from knowingly and willfully: (1) making a contribution described above in the name of another person; (2) permitting his or her name to be used to effect such a contribution; and (3) accepting such a contribution that is made by one person in the name of another person. Prescribes penalties for violation of such prohibition. Requires the Archivist to promulgate regulations to carry out this Act. Makes this Act: (1) applicable to an organization established to raise funds for creating, maintaining, expanding, or conducting activities at a Presidential archival depository or any facilities related to such a depository; and (2) only applicable with respect to contributions (whether monetary or in-kind) made after enactment of this Act. 
	</summary>
</bill>
