<bill session="110" type="h" number="1269" updated="2009-01-08T19:29:27-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"/></status>

	<introduced date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Rail and Public Transportation Security Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the security of railroad, public transportation, and over-the-road bus systems in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400299"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400048" joined="2007-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400100" joined="2007-03-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E451)</text></action>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text></action>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1172811600" datetime="2007-03-02"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text></action>
		<action date="1172811600" datetime="2007-03-02"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
		<action date="1173070800" datetime="2007-03-05"><committee name="House Homeland Security"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation Security and Infrastructure Protection.</text></action>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>For Further Action See P.L. 110-53, Titles XIV and XV.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/1/2007--Introduced.<br/>Rail and Public Transportation Security Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (Secretary) for the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to develop and implement a plan entitled the National Strategy for Rail and Public Transportation Security. Requires the Secretary to promulgate regulations that require each high- or medium- risk tier railroad carrier, public transportation operator, or over-the-road bus private operator to submit for approval by the Secretary: (1) an assessment of the vulnerability of the rail or public transportation system or over-the-road bus to terrorism; and (2) a security plan that addresses the vulnerabilities identified in the assessment. Requires the Secretary to implement a security program for covered transportation not assigned to a high- or medium-risk tier. Requires the Secretary to establish a program for the Secretary of Transportation to make grants to railroad carriers, designated public transportation recipients, and over-the-road bus private operators for certain security improvements. Makes grants to Amtrak for certain fire and life-safety improvements to tunnels on the Northeast Corridor. Requires the Secretary to: (1) develop a training program to prepare railroad, public transportation, and over-the-road bus workers for potential threat conditions; and (2) establish a security exercises program for such workers and other named entities to respond to acts of terrorism. Sets forth certain whistleblower protections for DHS, Department of Transportation (DOT), rail and public transportation, and over-the-road bus employees (including contractors and subcontractors) who have provided information or otherwise assisted in any investigation regarding conduct related to, or who have refused to violate or assist in, the violation of any regulation related to national or homeland security. Requires an increase in the number of DHS surface transportation security inspectors. Sets forth civil penalties for violations of regulations and orders of the Secretary.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
