<bill session="110" type="h" number="1270" updated="2009-01-08T19:29:35-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"/></status>

	<introduced date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Journey Through Hallowed Ground National Heritage Area Education and Tourism Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Journey Through Hallowed Ground National Heritage Area Education and Tourism Act, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400017"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="409888" joined="2007-03-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400153" joined="2007-03-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400141" joined="2007-05-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1173416400" datetime="2007-03-09"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/1/2007--Introduced.<br/>Journey Through Hallowed Ground National Heritage Area Education and Tourism Act of 2007 - Establishes the Journey Through Hallowed Ground National Heritage Area which may consist of the 175-mile region following the Route 15 corridor and surrounding areas through Pennsylvania, Maryland, West Virginia, and Virginia. Designates the Journey Through Hallowed Ground Partnership as the management entity for the Area. Requires the membership on the Board of Trustees of the Partnership to be open to the public and to include representatives from a broad cross-section of individuals, agencies, organizations, states, and governments participating in the Area that will oversee the development of the management plan. Requires the Partnership to develop a management plan for the Area that presents strategies and recommendations for promoting tourism within the Area and for educating the public about the historic significance of the Area. Makes the Federal Advisory Committee Act inapplicable to the Board of Trustees.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
