<bill session="110" type="h" number="1296" updated="2009-01-08T19:33:19-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"/></status>

	<introduced date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">District of Columbia District Attorney Establishment Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the District of Columbia Home Rule Act to establish the Office of the District Attorney for the District of Columbia, headed by a locally elected and independent District Attorney, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400295"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E439)</text></action>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text></action>
		<action date="1174968000" datetime="2007-03-27"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia.</text></action>
		<action date="1209009600" datetime="2008-04-24"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/1/2007--Introduced.<br/>District of Columbia District Attorney Establishment Act of 2007 - Amends the District of Columbia Home Rule Act to establish the Office of the District Attorney for the District of Columbia (DA). Specifies the qualifications for the DA, including residence and domicile in the District. Prohibits the DA from engaging directly or indirectly in private practice. Requires the DA to be elected to a four-year term on a partisan basis. Requires the Mayor to appoint the first DA, to serve until succeeded by an elected one. States that nothing in this Act shall affect the authority of the Attorney General or the U.S. Attorney for the District to exercise jurisdiction concerning violations of federal laws.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
