<bill session="110" type="h" number="1292" updated="2009-01-08T19:32:18-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"/></status>

	<introduced date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To repeal the Authorization for Use of Military Force Against Iraq Resolution of 2002 (Public Law 107-243), and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400233"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400062" joined="2008-06-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"><committee name="House Foreign Affairs"/><text>Committee Hearings Held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/1/2007--Introduced.<br/>Repeals P.L. 107-243 (Authorization for Use of Military Force Against Iraq Resolution of 2002). Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) Congress should vote on a new authorization for use of force resolution that reflects the current Iraq situation, abandons the Bush Doctrine of preemption and unilateralism, and realigns U.S. policy with its long-held priorities of diplomacy, deterrence, and containment; (2) the United States should establish a quick-reaction U.S. military force with an over-the-horizon presence in the region; (3) the United States should intensify diplomatic relations to support the difficult internal steps that the government of Iraq should take to promote national reconciliation; (4) the United States should increase efforts to engage all neighboring countries and the League of Arab States in promoting Iraq's stability; (5) the United States should continue to provide humanitarian and reconstruction assistance in Iraq; (6) the United States should redirect diplomatic, economic, and military support to Afghanistan; and (7) the United States should aggressively pursue Osama Bin Laden, Ayman al-Zawahiri, al Qaeda and other terrorist organizations that continue to pose an imminent threat to the United States. 
	</summary>
</bill>
