<bill session="110" type="h" number="1290" updated="2009-01-08T19:32:04-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"/></status>

	<introduced date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Biosurveillance Enhancement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish a National Biosurveillance Integration Center.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400230"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400073" joined="2007-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400219" joined="2007-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400245" joined="2007-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400402" joined="2007-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400648" joined="2007-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412235" joined="2007-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400654" joined="2007-03-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E431)</text></action>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text></action>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1173070800" datetime="2007-03-05"><committee name="House Homeland Security"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emerging Threats, Cybersecurity, and Science and Technology.</text></action>
		<action date="1173070800" datetime="2007-03-05"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/1/2007--Introduced.<br/>Biosurveillance Enhancement Act of 2007 - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish a National Biosurveillance Integration Center (NBIC) to enhance the government's capability to rapidly identify, characterize, and localize a biological event (a terrorist act involving biological agents or toxins or a naturally occurring outbreak of infectious disease of potential national significance) by integrating and analyzing data related to human health, animals, plants, food, and the environment.<br/>Requires the Director of NBIC to develop, operate, and maintain an integrated network to detect a biological event that presents a risk to the United States or its infrastructure or key assets. Includes among the Director's responsibilities establishment of a procedure to enable government and private sector entities to report suspicious events. Requires the Director to continuously evaluate data, integrate homeland security information with NBIC data, and establish a mechanism for real-time communication with the National Operations Center.<br/>Directs the Secretary to: (1) seek agreements for appropriate federal agency heads to integrate biosurveillance information capabilities through NBIC and to provide timely, evaluated information; (2) ensure that the Director is notified of homeland security information regarding significant biological threats and receives timely reports; (3) designate NBIC as a public health authority; and (4) ensure that NBIC complies with the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 and applicable privacy regulations.<br/>Requires: (1) the Director to establish an interagency working group; and (2) the Secretary to report annually to Congress.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
