<bill session="110" type="h" number="1294" updated="2009-01-08T19:32:50-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1178649420" datetime="2007-05-08T15:37:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Thomasina E. Jordan Indian Tribes of Virginia Federal Recognition Act of 2006</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Thomasina E. Jordan Indian Tribes of Virginia Federal Recognition Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Thomasina E. Jordan Indian Tribes of Virginia Federal Recognition Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To extend Federal recognition to the Chickahominy Indian Tribe, the Chickahominy Indian Tribe-Eastern Division, the Upper Mattaponi Tribe, the Rappahannock Tribe, Inc., the Monacan Indian Nation, and the Nansemond Indian Tribe.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400283"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400364" joined="2007-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400336" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400095" joined="2007-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400216" joined="2007-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400331" joined="2007-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400098" joined="2007-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400308" joined="2007-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400001" joined="2007-03-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E450-451)</text></action>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1176868800" datetime="2007-04-18"><text>Committee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1177473600" datetime="2007-04-25"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1177473600" datetime="2007-04-25" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1178559720" datetime="2007-05-07T14:42:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-124.</text></action>
		<calendar number="73" date="1178559780" datetime="2007-05-07T14:43:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 73.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1178574060" datetime="2007-05-07T18:41:00-04:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 377 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1294 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Natural Resources now printed in the bill, modified by the amendments printed in the report of the Committee on Rules to accompany this resolution, shall be considered as adopted.</text></action>
		<action date="1178642280" datetime="2007-05-08T13:38:00-04:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 377 passed House.</text></action>
		<action date="1178648280" datetime="2007-05-08T15:18:00-04:00"><text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 377.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H4592-4607"/><reference label="text of measure as reported in House" ref="CR H4592-4598"/></action>
		<action date="1178648280" datetime="2007-05-08T15:18:00-04:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1294 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Natural Resources now printed in the bill, modified by the amendments printed in the report of the Committee on Rules to accompany this resolution, shall be considered as adopted.</text></action>
		<action date="1178648340" datetime="2007-05-08T15:19:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 1294, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1178649420" datetime="2007-05-08T15:37:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H4607"/></action>
		<vote date="1178649420" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-05-08T15:37:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On passage Passed by voice vote.</text></vote>
		<action date="1178651820" datetime="2007-05-08T16:17:00-04:00"><text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 1294.</text></action>
		<action date="1178683200" datetime="2007-05-09"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1222315200" datetime="2008-09-25"><text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/8/2007--Passed House amended. Thomasina E. Jordan Indian Tribes of Virginia Federal Recognition Act of 2007 - Extends federal recognition to the following Indian tribes of Virginia and states their relationship with the federal government as described below: (1) the Chickahominy Tribe; (2) the Chickahominy Indian Tribe--Eastern Division; (3) the Upper Mattaponi Tribe; (4) the Rappahannock Tribe, Inc.; (5) the Monacan Indian Nation; and (6) the Nansemond Indian Tribe. Makes each Tribe and tribal members eligible for all services and benefits provided by the federal government to federally recognized Indian tribes. Sets forth the service area of the Tribe and requirements for the Tribe with respect to submission of a membership roll and governing documents and the governing body of the Tribe. Requires the Secretary of the Interior, upon a certain land transfer, to take specified lands into trust for the benefit of the Tribe, which shall be considered part of the Tribe's reservation. Prohibits the Tribe from conducting gaming activities.<br/>Specifies this Act's effect with regard to the hunting, fishing, trapping, gathering, and water rights of the Tribe and its members. Grants the state of Virginia jurisdiction over criminal offenses and civil actions on lands within Virginia that are owned by or held in trust for the Tribe. Authorizes the Secretary to accept all or a portion of the state's jurisdiction over such offenses and actions upon verification by the Secretary of a certification by a tribe that it possesses the capacity to reassume such jurisdiction.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
