<bill session="110" type="h" number="1311" updated="2009-01-08T19:35:07-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1204671960" datetime="2008-03-04T19:06:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="89"/></status>

	<introduced date="1173070800" datetime="2007-03-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Nevada Cancer Institute Expansion Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Nevada Cancer Institute Expansion Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Nevada Cancer Institute Expansion Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Nevada Cancer Institute Expansion Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to convey the Alta-Hualapai Site to the city of Las Vegas, Nevada, for the development of a cancer treatment facility.</title>
		<title type="official" as="amended by house">To provide for the conveyance of the Alta-Hualapai Site to the Nevada Cancer Institute, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400024"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412218" joined="2007-03-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400324" joined="2007-03-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1173070800" datetime="2007-03-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1173243600" datetime="2007-03-07"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action date="1193112000" datetime="2007-10-23"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1202878800" datetime="2008-02-13"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1202878800" datetime="2008-02-13"><text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands Discharged.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1202878800" datetime="2008-02-13" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1204259940" datetime="2008-02-28T12:39:00-05:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-533.</text></action>
		<calendar number="324" date="1204260000" datetime="2008-02-28T12:40:00-05:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 324.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1204654620" datetime="2008-03-04T14:17:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Rahall moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1204654620" datetime="2008-03-04T14:17:00-05:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H1193"/></action>
		<action date="1204654620" datetime="2008-03-04T14:17:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1311.</text></action>
		<action date="1204654740" datetime="2008-03-04T14:19:00-05:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1204671420" datetime="2008-03-04T18:57:00-05:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H1205-1206"/></action>
		<vote date="1204671960" how="roll" roll="89" datetime="2008-03-04T19:06:00-05:00" where="h" type="vote" suspension="1" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 377 - 0 (Roll no. 89).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H1193"/></vote>
		<action date="1204671960" datetime="2008-03-04T19:06:00-05:00"><text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action date="1204693200" datetime="2008-03-05"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1208232000" datetime="2008-04-15"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1210132800" datetime="2008-05-07" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1213588800" datetime="2008-06-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. With written report No. 110-380.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="812" date="1213588800" datetime="2008-06-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 812.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/16/2008--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the House on March 4, 2008. The summary of that version is repeated here.)<br/>Nevada Cancer Institute Expansion Act - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Land Management (BLM), to accept the relinquishment of all or part of the Alta-Hualapai Site by the city of Las Vegas, Nevada. Directs the Secretary, after relinquishment of all or part of the Alta-Hualapai Site, to convey to the Nevada Cancer Institute (the Institute) in Las Vegas, the part of the Site that is necessary for the development of a nonprofit cancer institute. Requires the Secretary, after a request from the city, to convey to the city any remaining part of the Alta-Hualapai Site necessary for ancillary medical or nonprofit use compatible with the Institute's mission. Requires any conveyance by the city of any part of the land received to be for no less than fair market value and the proceeds from any such conveyance to be distributed in accordance with Public Law 105-263 (the Southern Nevada Public Land Management Act of 1998).<br/>Provides that the conveyance by the Secretary under this Act shall be at no cost, except that the Secretary may require the recipient to bear any costs associated with the transfer of title or any necessary land surveys. Requires the Secretary to submit a report on all transactions conducted under Public Law 105-263. Authorizes the Secretary to grant rights-of-way to the Las Vegas Valley Water District on a portion of the Alta-Hualapai Site for a flood control project and a water pumping facility. 
	</summary>
</bill>
