<bill session="110" type="h" number="1345" updated="2009-01-08T19:39:38-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1173157200" datetime="2007-03-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1173157200" datetime="2007-03-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Energy Employees Occupational Illness Compensation Program Act of 2000 to include certain former nuclear weapons program workers in the Special Exposure Cohort under the energy employees occupational illness compensation program.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400641"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400378" joined="2007-03-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400338" joined="2007-03-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1173157200" datetime="2007-03-06"><text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1173157200" datetime="2007-03-06"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1173157200" datetime="2007-03-06"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1181016000" datetime="2007-06-05"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/6/2007--Introduced.<br/>Amends the Energy Employees Occupational Illness Compensation Program Act of 2000 to include certain former nuclear weapons program workers in the Special Exposure Cohort under the energy employees occupational illness compensation program. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) modify regulations and procedures to conform to amendments under this Act; and (2) initiate a petition to include workers employed at the Bethlehem Steel site in Lackawanna, New York, as a class to be included in the Special Exposure Cohort. 
	</summary>
</bill>
