<bill session="110" type="h" number="1369" updated="2009-01-08T19:42:38-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1173243600" datetime="2007-03-07"/></status>

	<introduced date="1173243600" datetime="2007-03-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Family and Medical Leave Expansion Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 to expand the scope of the Act, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400251"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400295" joined="2008-03-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1173243600" datetime="2007-03-07"><text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, and House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1173243600" datetime="2007-03-07"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1173243600" datetime="2007-03-07"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1173243600" datetime="2007-03-07"><text>Referred to House House Administration</text></action>
		<action date="1182312000" datetime="2007-06-20"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1365)</text></action>
		<action date="1182916800" datetime="2007-06-27"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/7/2007--Introduced.<br/>Family and Medical Leave Expansion Act - Family Income to Respond to Significant Transitions Insurance Act - Directs the Secretary of Labor to make five-year grants to a state or local government to pay for the federal share of the cost of carrying out projects that assist families by providing wage replacement for eligible individuals responding to caregiving needs resulting from the birth or adoption of a son or daughter or other family caregiving needs. Family and Medical Leave Fairness Act of 2005 [sic]- Amends the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 (FMLA) to extend coverage to employees at worksites where the employer employs at least 25 (currently, 50) employees at the worksite and within 75 miles of that worksite. Amends FMLA and federal civil service law to entitle to leave those employees who must address the effects of domestic violence. Federal Employees Paid Parental Leave Act of 2005 [sic]- Permits the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to contract with one or more employing agencies to conduct a grant project that provides paid leave for eligible individuals who are responding to caregiving needs resulting from the birth or adoption of a son or daughter or other family caregiving needs. Requires the leave to last for at least six weeks during a 12-month period. Time for Schools Act of 2005 [sic] - Amends FMLA to allow employees covered by such Act to take up to 24 hours, during any 12-month period, of school involvement leave to participate in: (1) an academic activity of their child's school, such as a parent-teacher conference or an interview for a school; or (2) literacy training under a family literacy program. Amends federal civil service law to provide the same school involvement leave allowance for federal employees.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
