<bill session="110" type="h" number="1405" updated="2009-01-08T19:47:10-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1174968000" datetime="2007-03-27" /></status>

	<introduced date="1173330000" datetime="2007-03-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Wildlife GAINS Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Wildlife Global Animal Information Network for Surveillance Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a wildlife global animal information network for surveillance internationally to combat the growing threat of emerging diseases that involve wild animals, such as bird flu, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400103"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400219" joined="2007-11-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400289" joined="2007-11-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2007-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412221" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400122" joined="2007-11-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400246" joined="2007-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400271" joined="2007-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400430" joined="2007-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="2007-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400264" joined="2007-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400231" joined="2007-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400087" joined="2008-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400259" joined="2007-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400346" joined="2008-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400366" joined="2007-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400125" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2007-03-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1173330000" datetime="2007-03-08"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, Natural Resources, and Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1173330000" datetime="2007-03-08"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1173330000" datetime="2007-03-08"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1173330000" datetime="2007-03-08"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1173330000" datetime="2007-03-08"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action date="1173416400" datetime="2007-03-09"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1174017600" datetime="2007-03-16"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, and Oceans.</text></action>
		<action date="1174968000" datetime="2007-03-27"><committee name="House Foreign Affairs"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1174968000" datetime="2007-03-27" ><committee name="House Foreign Affairs"/><text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1175227200" datetime="2007-03-30"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Credit, Energy, and Research.</text></action>
		<action date="1175227200" datetime="2007-03-30"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry.</text></action>
		<action date="1175227200" datetime="2007-03-30"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Horticulture and Organic Agriculture.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/8/2007--Introduced.<br/>Wildlife Global Animal Information Network for Surveillance Act or Wildlife GAINS Act - Requires the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) to offer to enter into a contract with a nongovernmental wildlife conservation organization to establish a Wildlife Global Animal Information Network for Surveillance. Requires the eligible organization, in coordination with USAID, to manage an international surveillance program under which federal and non-federal partners: (1) monitor and test for the presence or arrival of avian pathogens and other significant pathogens in free-ranging wildlife; (2) use trained professionals to collect samples and data; (3) conduct disease surveillance, field investigations, training and capacity-building activities, and research; (4) send samples for pathogen identification and testing to certified laboratories; and (5) transmit information related to global distribution and characteristics of significant pathogens to the Administrator.<br/>Requires the Administrator, acting through the organization, to: (1) use surveillance reports and other sources to identify and investigate local outbreaks of infectious diseases involving wildlife; (2) develop a long-term baseline of regional data related to pathogens in migratory birds and other wildlife for analysis between and across sites to create a system to identify when and where outbreaks might occur and paths of dispersal; (3) provide technical assistance for disease prevention and control programs; (4) provide analytical disease findings to USAID and other federal partners; and ( 5) manage, map, and make available on an Internet database all results and information gathered under this Act. Directs the Administrator to request accredited colleges of veterinary medicine and other partners to train members of the Network to: (1) monitor important wildlife areas around the world; and (2) test for the presence or arrival of avian influenza and other significant pathogens of zoonotic concern or of concern to domestic or wild animals.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
