<bill session="110" type="h" number="1410" updated="2009-01-08T19:47:45-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1173330000" datetime="2007-03-08"/></status>

	<introduced date="1173330000" datetime="2007-03-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Emergency Child Care for the Gulf Coast Region Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide emergency child care in the Gulf Coast Region, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400201"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412221" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400295" joined="2007-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2007-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400402" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400048" joined="2007-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400399" joined="2007-03-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1173330000" datetime="2007-03-08"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1182916800" datetime="2007-06-27"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/8/2007--Introduced.<br/>Emergency Child Care for the Gulf Coast Region Act of 2007 - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish grant programs for: (1) businesses and consortia in the Gulf Coast Region to pay start-up costs and to provide additional child care services for employees; (2) nonprofit business organizations in the Region to provide technical assistance to such businesses for child care services; (3) entities to develop distance learning child care training technology infrastructures and model technology-based training courses for child care providers and workers in the Region; and (4) child care providers in the Region to improve the qualifications and promote the retention of such providers. Defines &quot;Gulf Coast Region&quot; to mean the area declared by the President to be a major disaster as a consequence of Hurricanes Katrina and Rita. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make scholarship grants to child care providers to improve their educational qualifications to provide services.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
