<bill session="110" type="h" number="1413" updated="2009-01-08T19:48:05-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1197406260" datetime="2007-12-11T16:51:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1173330000" datetime="2007-03-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Assistant Secretary of Homeland Security (Transportation Security Administration) to address vulnerabilities in aviation security by carrying out a pilot program to screen airport workers with access to secure and sterile areas of airports.</title>
		<title type="official" as="amended by house">To direct the Assistant Secretary of Homeland Security (Transportation Security Administration) to address vulnerabilities in aviation security by carrying out a pilot program to screen airport workers with access to secure and sterile areas of airports, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400246"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400253" joined="2007-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400257" joined="2007-03-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="412221" joined="2007-03-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400430" joined="2007-03-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400361" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400184" joined="2007-11-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400288" joined="2007-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400152" joined="2007-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400427" joined="2007-04-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400245" joined="2007-03-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400402" joined="2007-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400230" joined="2007-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400048" joined="2007-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400051" joined="2007-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400328" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400654" joined="2007-03-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1173330000" datetime="2007-03-08"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text></action>
		<action date="1174276800" datetime="2007-03-19"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation Security and Infrastructure Protection.</text></action>
		<action date="1177387200" datetime="2007-04-24"><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1177387200" datetime="2007-04-24"><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Unanimous Consent .</text></action>
		<action date="1177387200" datetime="2007-04-24"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1177387200" datetime="2007-04-24" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1182744000" datetime="2007-06-25"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H7052)</text></action>
		<action date="1185940800" datetime="2007-08-01"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1185940800" datetime="2007-08-01" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1197433080" datetime="2007-12-11T12:18:00-05:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 110-482.</text></action>
		<calendar number="297" date="1197433080" datetime="2007-12-11T12:18:00-05:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 297.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1197405480" datetime="2007-12-11T16:38:00-05:00"><text>Mrs. Lowey moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1197405540" datetime="2007-12-11T16:39:00-05:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H15270-152773"/></action>
		<action date="1197405540" datetime="2007-12-11T16:39:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1413.</text></action>
		<vote date="1197406260" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-12-11T16:51:00-05:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H15270-15271"/></vote>
		<action date="1197406260" datetime="2007-12-11T16:51:00-05:00"><text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action date="1197435600" datetime="2007-12-12"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	12/11/2007--Passed House amended. Directs the Assistant Secretary of Homeland Security (Transportation Security Administration) to: (1) implement a pilot program at seven commercial service airports to screen all individuals with unescorted access to secure and sterile areas of the airport; and (2) conduct a vulnerability assessment of, and an operational assessment at, each airport participating in such program. Requires: (1) at least two of the participating airports to be large hub airports and at least one of the airports to be a category III airport, with each of the remaining airports representing a different airport security risk category; (2) screening to be conducted under the same standards as apply to passengers at airport security screening checkpoints, to be carried out by private screeners, and, in addition, the designation of at least one lane to be used to screen individuals with unescorted access on a priority basis; (3) deployment of alternative means of screening of all individuals at one of the participating airports; (4) each participating airport operator to conduct an assessment of the screening technology used at the airport and to submit the results to the Assistant Secretary; and (5) the program to be carried out for not less than 180 days. Authorizes appropriations. Requires the Assistant Secretary to report to Congress on the results of the program.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
