<bill session="110" type="h" number="1411" updated="2009-01-08T19:47:51-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1173330000" datetime="2007-03-08"/></status>

	<introduced date="1173330000" datetime="2007-03-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Emergency Gulf Coast Child Care Construction and Rebuilding Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the construction and rehabilitation of child care facilities in areas of the Gulf Coast affected by Hurricanes Katrina and Rita.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400201"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412221" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400295" joined="2007-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2007-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400402" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400048" joined="2007-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400399" joined="2007-03-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1173330000" datetime="2007-03-08"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/8/2007--Introduced.<br/>Emergency Gulf Coast Child Care Construction and Rebuilding Act - Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 to authorize the use of community development block grants to construct and renovate child care facilities located in any major disaster area resulting from Hurricane Katrina or Rita of 2005. Amends the National Housing Act to authorize the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to insure: (1) mortgages for new or substantially rehabilitated child care and development facilities; (2) loans to such facilities for fire safety equipment; and (2) mortgages executed in connection with the purchase or refinancing of existing child care facilities. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to study and report to Congress on the availability of secondary markets for such mortgages. Authorizes HUD grants to eligible nonprofit organizations for technical and financial assistance to assist eligible child care providers in acquiring or improving facilities or equipment. 
	</summary>
</bill>
