<bill session="110" type="h" number="1432" updated="2009-01-08T19:50:34-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1173416400" datetime="2007-03-09"/></status>

	<introduced date="1173416400" datetime="2007-03-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Preserve Access to Affordable Generics Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit brand name drug companies from compensating generic drug companies to delay the entry of a generic drug into the market.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400425"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400415" joined="2007-09-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1173416400" datetime="2007-03-09"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1173416400" datetime="2007-03-09"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1173416400" datetime="2007-03-09"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1173672000" datetime="2007-03-12"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/9/2007--Introduced.<br/>Preserve Access to Affordable Generics Act - Amends the Clayton Act to make it unlawful for a person, in connection with the sale of a drug product, to be a party to any agreement resolving or settling a patent infringement claim in which: (1) an abbreviated new drug (generic) application filer receives anything of value; and (2) such filer agrees not to research, develop, manufacture, market, or sell the generic product for any period. Excludes a resolution or settlement that includes no more than the right to market the generic product prior to the expiration of the patent. Amends the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003 to set forth additional filing requirements related to agreements between a brand name drug company and a generic drug applicant. Requires the Chief Executive Officer or the company official responsible for negotiating any agreement to file a certification that materials filed with respect to such agreements are complete, final, and exclusive. Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to provide that forfeiture of the 180-day exclusivity period for the marketing of a generic drug occurs if there is a final decision of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) or the court that an agreement has violated this Act.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
