<bill session="110" type="h" number="1436" updated="2009-01-08T19:51:04-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1173416400" datetime="2007-03-09"/></status>

	<introduced date="1173416400" datetime="2007-03-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Retired Pay Restoration Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 10, United States Code, to permit certain retired members of the uniformed services who have a service-connected disability to receive both disability compensation from the Department of Veterans Affairs for their disability and either retired pay by reason of their years of military service or Combat-Related Special Compensation.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412250"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400123" joined="2008-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2007-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400367" joined="2007-09-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400419" joined="2007-10-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400095" joined="2007-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400443" joined="2008-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400662" joined="2008-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400359" joined="2008-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400640" joined="2007-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400006" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-06-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400147" joined="2008-07-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400172" joined="2008-02-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="412205" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400346" joined="2008-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="412240" joined="2008-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400153" joined="2007-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400651" joined="2008-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400654" joined="2008-04-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1173416400" datetime="2007-03-09"><text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1173416400" datetime="2007-03-09"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1173416400" datetime="2007-03-09"><text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1175572800" datetime="2007-04-03"><committee name="House Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/9/2007--Introduced.<br/>Retired Pay Restoration Act - Allows the receipt of both military retired pay and veterans' disability compensation with respect to any service-connected disability (currently, only a disability rated at 50 percent or more). Makes the 2004 through 2013 phase-in limitations for the concurrent receipt of such pay for qualified retirees with service-connected disabilities rated as total applicable: (1) only during 2004 for retirees with a 100 percent disability; and (2) only during 2004 through 2007 for retirees with a total disability by reason of unemployability. Makes eligible for the full concurrent receipt of both veterans' disability compensation and either military retired pay or combat-related special pay those individuals who were retired or separated from military service due to a service-connected disability.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
