<bill session="110" type="h" number="1457" updated="2009-01-08T19:53:28-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1173416400" datetime="2007-03-09"/></status>

	<introduced date="1173416400" datetime="2007-03-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Post-Abortion Depression Research and Care Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for research on, and services for individuals with, post-abortion depression and psychosis.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400320"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400137" joined="2007-03-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400151" joined="2007-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400385" joined="2007-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400095" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2007-03-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400040" joined="2007-06-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400285" joined="2007-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400055" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400427" joined="2007-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400640" joined="2007-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400017" joined="2007-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400287" joined="2007-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400153" joined="2007-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="412201" joined="2007-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400005" joined="2007-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400649" joined="2007-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400145" joined="2007-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400141" joined="2007-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400157" joined="2007-11-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="412191" joined="2007-03-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1173416400" datetime="2007-03-09"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1173672000" datetime="2007-03-12"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/9/2007--Introduced.<br/>Post-Abortion Depression Research and Care Act of 2007 - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) and the Director of the National Institute of Mental Health (NIMH), to expand and intensify NIMH research and related activities with respect to post-abortion depression and psychosis. Requires the Director of NIMH to: (1) conduct or support research to expand the understanding of the causes of, and to find a cure for, such post-abortion conditions; and (2) conduct a study to determine the incidence and prevalence of cases of post-abortion conditions and the symptoms, severity, and duration of such cases, toward the goal of more fully identifying the characteristics of such cases and developing diagnostic techniques. Requires the Secretary to make grants to establish, operate, and coordinate effective and cost-efficient systems for the delivery of essential services to individuals with such post-abortion conditions.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
