<bill session="110" type="h" number="1460" updated="2009-01-08T19:53:53-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1173416400" datetime="2007-03-09"/></status>

	<introduced date="1173416400" datetime="2007-03-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Change the Course in Iraq Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To commend the members of the United States Armed Forces on their performance and bravery in Iraq, to repeal the Authorization for Use of Military Force Against Iraq Resolution (Public Law 107-243), to require the Secretary of Defense to submit to Congress a plan for the phased redeployment of United States Armed Forces from Iraq, to establish a Coordinator for Iraq Stabilization, and to place conditions on the obligation of funds to the Government of Iraq based on the achievement of benchmarks established by Iraq and the United States.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400396"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400092" joined="2007-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400379" joined="2007-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400101" joined="2007-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="412223" joined="2007-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412209" joined="2007-11-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400087" joined="2007-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400270" joined="2007-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400166" joined="2007-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="412200" joined="2007-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2007-06-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1173416400" datetime="2007-03-09"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1173416400" datetime="2007-03-09"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1173416400" datetime="2007-03-09"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"><committee name="House Foreign Affairs"/><text>Committee Hearings Held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/9/2007--Introduced.<br/>Change the Course in Iraq Act - Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) members of the U.S. Armed Forces have shown great valor and courage in Iraq in the performance of their duties; and (2) the sacrifices of such members and their families are recognized and appreciated. Repeals the Authorization for Use of Military Force Against Iraq Resolution of 2002. Requires the Secretary of Defense to submit to the congressional defense committees a plan for the phased redeployment of U.S. Armed Forces from Iraq. Expresses the sense of Congress that the United States should increase its diplomatic efforts within the government of Iraq to help stabilize Iraq and the region. Directs the President to appoint a Coordinator for Iraq Stabilization. Conditions U.S. assistance for Iraqi security forces or Iraq relief and reconstruction, beginning on December 31, 2007, upon the President certifying to the defense committees that the Iraqi government has taken certain actions with respect to stabilizing the Iraqi government, guaranteeing rights of Iraqi citizens, and controlling its security forces.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
