<bill session="110" type="h" number="1463" updated="2009-01-08T19:54:15-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1173416400" datetime="2007-03-09"/></status>

	<introduced date="1173416400" datetime="2007-03-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Lands REPAIR Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Lands Restoration, Enhancement, Public Education, and Information Resurces Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide a source of funds to carry out restoration activities on Federal lands under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400412"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400394" joined="2007-03-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1173416400" datetime="2007-03-09"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E503-504)</text></action>
		<action date="1173416400" datetime="2007-03-09"><text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1173416400" datetime="2007-03-09"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1173416400" datetime="2007-03-09"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action date="1173758400" datetime="2007-03-13"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/9/2007--Introduced.<br/>Federal Lands Restoration, Enhancement, Public Education, and Information Resources Act or Federal Lands REPAIR Act - Amends the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976, the National Park Service Organic Act, the National Wildlife Refuge System Administration Act of 1966, and federal law relating to National Forest System lands, to make available any moneys received from fines or any moneys received from collateral payments in lieu of appearance for violations of rules and regulations applicable to federal lands under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture for certain restoration and public informational activities on such lands. Transfers any such excess funds to the Crime Victims Fund established under the Victims of Crime Act of 1984. 
	</summary>
</bill>
