<bill session="110" type="h" number="1471" updated="2009-01-08T19:55:12-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1173672000" datetime="2007-03-12"/></status>

	<introduced date="1173672000" datetime="2007-03-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Better Access to Chiropractors to Keep our Veterans Healthy Act (BACK Veterans Health Act)</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to permit eligible veterans to receive direct access to chiropractic care.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400133"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400658" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400311" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400153" joined="2007-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400024" joined="2008-04-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1173672000" datetime="2007-03-12"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E524)</text></action>
		<action date="1173672000" datetime="2007-03-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1174017600" datetime="2007-03-16"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1177560000" datetime="2007-04-26"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/12/2007--Introduced.<br/>Better Access to Chiropractors to Keep our Veterans Healthy ( BACK Veterans Health) Act - Includes chiropractic services and counseling, as well as periodic and preventative chiropractic examinations and services, among the medical, rehabilitative, and preventive health services available to veterans. Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to permit eligible veterans to receive medical, rehabilitative, and preventative health services from a licensed doctor of chiropractic on a direct access basis at the election of the veteran, if such services are within the State scope of practice of such doctor. Prohibits the Secretary from discriminating among licensed health-care providers in the determination of needed services.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
