<bill session="110" type="h" number="1476" updated="2009-01-08T19:55:51-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1173672000" datetime="2007-03-12"/></status>

	<introduced date="1173672000" datetime="2007-03-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Senior Safety and Dignity Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend titles XVIII and XIX of the Social Security Act to expand the nursing home patients' bill of rights to include the right to receive care from a credible caregiver by requiring background checks on direct access employees and the right to a safe environment during an emergency or natural disaster by requiring nursing long-term care facilities to establish disaster emergency and evacuation plans.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400051"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400222" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412218" joined="2008-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400367" joined="2007-03-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400414" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400027" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400149" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400626" joined="2007-03-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400660" joined="2007-03-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400151" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400276" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400071" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400324" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400017" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400131" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400636" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400321" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412202" joined="2007-03-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1173672000" datetime="2007-03-12"><text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1173672000" datetime="2007-03-12"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1173672000" datetime="2007-03-12"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1173758400" datetime="2007-03-13"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1174622400" datetime="2007-03-23"><committee name="House Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/12/2007--Introduced.<br/>Senior Safety and Dignity Act of 2007 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) and title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to include in the nursing home patient's bill of rights the right to receive care from a creditable caregiver. Requires a skilled nursing facility (SNF), before hiring a worker, to conduct a background check on the applicant. Prohibits the hiring of abusive workers or workers convicted of a relevant crime. Establishes civil penalties for violations of this Act, including knowing retention of SNF workers who fail background checks. Applies such requirements and prohibitions to a long-term care facility or provider.<br/>Directs the Secretary to establish a national criminal background check program, after evaluation of the pilot program under the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003, in order to prevent abuse of nursing facility and SNF residents and individuals receiving home health care services and other long-term care services under the Medicare or Medicaid programs. Requires the Federal Bureau of Investigation to conduct such criminal background checks.<br/>Requires the national criminal background check program to be made available to a long-term care facility or provider.<br/>Adds to the nursing home patient's bill of rights the right to a safe environment during an emergency or natural disaster. Requires a SNF under Medicare and Medicaid to: (1) have a clear and preestablished disaster plan; and (2) inform residents and next-of-kin about it and the location of possible evacuation in case of an emergency disaster. Applies the same requirement to other long-term care facilities.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
