<bill session="110" type="h" number="1483" updated="2009-01-08T19:56:40-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1193281680" datetime="2007-10-24T12:08:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="996"/></status>

	<introduced date="1173672000" datetime="2007-03-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Celebrating America's Heritage Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Abraham Lincoln National Heritage Area Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Freedom's Way National Heritage Area Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Journey Through Hallowed Ground National Heritage Area Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Muscle Shoals National Heritage Area Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Niagara Falls National Heritage Area Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Santa Cruz Valley National Heritage Area Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Celebrating America's Heritage Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Abraham Lincoln National Heritage Area Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Freedom's Way National Heritage Area Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Journey Through Hallowed Ground National Heritage Area Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Muscle Shoals National Heritage Area Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Niagara Falls National Heritage Area Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Santa Cruz Valley National Heritage Area Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Celebrating America's Heritage Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Omnibus Parks and Public Lands Management Act of 1996 to extend the authorization for certain national heritage areas, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400334"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412229" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400227" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400155" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400407" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400268" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400049" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400433" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412208" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400235" joined="2007-05-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400352" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412222" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400234" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400211" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400269" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400421" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412228" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400016" joined="2007-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400042" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400208" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400114" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400075" joined="2007-04-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1173672000" datetime="2007-03-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1173931200" datetime="2007-03-15"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action date="1179201600" datetime="2007-05-15"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1190779200" datetime="2007-09-26"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1190779200" datetime="2007-09-26"><text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands Discharged.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1190779200" datetime="2007-09-26" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 23 - 12.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1192733340" datetime="2007-10-18T15:49:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-388.</text></action>
		<calendar number="242" date="1192733340" datetime="2007-10-18T15:49:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 242.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1193090580" datetime="2007-10-22T19:03:00-04:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 765 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1483 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text></action>
		<action date="1193169360" datetime="2007-10-23T16:56:00-04:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 765 passed House.</text></action>
		<action date="1193232300" datetime="2007-10-24T10:25:00-04:00"><text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 765.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H11940-11965"/><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR H11940"/><reference label="text of measure as reported in House" ref="CR H11940-11963"/></action>
		<action date="1193232300" datetime="2007-10-24T10:25:00-04:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1483 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text></action>
		<action date="1193232360" datetime="2007-10-24T10:26:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 1483.</text></action>
		<action date="1193236200" datetime="2007-10-24T11:30:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H11963"/></action>
		<action date="1193236200" datetime="2007-10-24T11:30:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Bishop (UT) moved to recommit with instructions to Natural Resources.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H11963-11964"/><reference label="text" ref="CR H11963"/></action>
		<action date="1193236260" datetime="2007-10-24T11:31:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Bishop (UT) motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to report the same to the House forthwith with the following amendment which adds a new Title VI- Application of Certain Laws pertaining to Application of Certain State and Local Laws.</text></action>
		<action date="1193236440" datetime="2007-10-24T11:34:00-04:00"><text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H11964"/></action>
		<action date="1193237940" datetime="2007-10-24T11:59:00-04:00"><text>On motion to recommit with instructions Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 344 - 71 (Roll no. 995).</text></action>
		<vote date="1193281680" how="roll" roll="996" datetime="2007-10-24T12:08:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 291 - 122 (Roll no. 996).</text></vote>
		<action date="1193281680" datetime="2007-10-24T12:08:00-04:00"><text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 1483.</text></action>
		<action date="1193284800" datetime="2007-10-25"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1208923200" datetime="2008-04-23"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1210132800" datetime="2008-05-07" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1213588800" datetime="2008-06-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 110-381.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="813" date="1213588800" datetime="2008-06-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 813.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/16/2008--Reported to Senate amended. Celebrating America's Heritage Act - Title I: Designations: Subtitle A: Muscle Shoals National Heritage Area - (Sec. 1103) Establishes the Muscle Shoals National Heritage Area in Alabama. (Sec. 1104) Designates the Muscle Shoals Regional Center as the local coordinating entity for the Area. Requires the Muscle Shoals Regional Center to prepare and submit a management plan for the Area. Authorizes the Muscle Shoals Regional Center, subject to the prior approval of the Secretary of the Interior, to use federal funds made available under this subtitle to: (1) make grants to the state, political subdivisions of the state, nonprofits, and other persons; and (2) enter into cooperative agreements with or provide technical assistance to the state, political subdivisions of the state, nonprofits, federal agencies, and other interested parties. Prohibits the Muscle Shoals Regional Center from using federal funds received under this subtitle to acquire any interest in real property. (Sec. 1105) Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) provide technical assistance under the authority of this subtitle for the development and implementation of the management plan; and (2) enter into cooperative agreements with interested parties to carry out this subtitle. (Sec. 1106) Authorizes the Secretary: (1) upon request of the Muscle Shoals Regional Center, to provide technical and financial assistance to it, on a reimbursable or non-reimbursable basis (as determined by the Secretary), to develop and implement the management plan; and (2) enter into cooperative agreements with the Muscle Shoals Regional Center and other public or private entities to provide such technical or financial assistance. Requires the Secretary to evaluate and report on the accomplishments of the Area. (Sec. 1107) Specifies this subtitle's effect with regard to: (1) other federal agencies; and (2) property owners and certain related regulatory protections. (Sec. 1109) Authorizes appropriations. Limits: (1) the amount to be appropriated to carry out this subtitle to $10 million of which not more than $1 million may be made available for any fiscal year; and (2) the federal cost share of any activity carried out using any assistance made available under this subtitle to 50%. Prohibits anything in this subtitle from precluding the Muscle Shoals Regional Center from using federal funds made available under other laws for the purposes for which those funds were authorized. (Sec. 1110) Terminates the authority of the Secretary to provide financial assistance under this subtitle 15 years after enactment of this Act. Subtitle B: Santa Cruz Valley National Heritage Area (Sec. 1203) Establishes the Santa Cruz Valley National Heritage Area in Arizona. Designates the Santa Cruz Valley Heritage Alliance, Inc. as the local coordinating entity for the Area. (Sec. 1204) Requires the Alliance to prepare and submit a management plan for the Area. Authorizes the Alliance to use federal funds made available under this subtitle to: (1) make grants to the state, political subdivisions of the state, nonprofits, and other persons; and (2) enter into cooperative agreements with or provide technical assistance to political subdivisions of the state, nonprofits, federal agencies, and other interested parties. Prohibits the Alliance from using federal funds received under this subtitle to acquire any interest in real property. Prohibits anything in this subtitle from precluding the Alliance from using federal funds from other sources for authorized purposes. (Sec. 1206) Authorizes the Secretary: (1) upon request of the Alliance, to provide technical and financial assistance to it, on a reimbursable or non-reimbursable basis (as determined by the Secretary), to develop and implement the management plan; and (2) enter into cooperative agreements with the Alliance and other public or private entities to provide such technical or financial assistance. Requires the Secretary to evaluate and report on the accomplishments of the Area. (Sec. 1207) Specifies this subtitle's effect with regard to: (1) other federal agencies; and (2) property owners and certain related regulatory protections. (Sec. 1209) Authorizes appropriations. Limits: (1) the amount to be appropriated to carry out this subtitle to $10 million of which not more than $1 million may be made available for any fiscal year; and (2) the federal cost share of any activity carried out using any assistance made available under this subtitle to 50%. (Sec. 1210) Terminates the authority of the Secretary to provide financial assistance under this subtitle 15 years after enactment of this Act. Title II: Study - (Sec. 2001) Requires the Secretary to study and report on the suitability and feasibility of establishing the Northern Neck National Heritage Area to be comprised of: (1) the area of land between the Potomac and Rappahannock Rivers of the eastern coastal region of Virginia; (2) Westmoreland, Northumberland, Richmond, King George, and Lancaster Counties of Virginia; and (3) any other area adjacent to or in the vicinity of those areas that have similar heritage aspects. Title III: Technical Amendments - (Sec. 3001) Amends the Erie Canalway National Heritage Corridor Act to modify requirements concerning the Canalway National Heritage Corridor Commission. Requires the Commission to be composed of at least 21 members (under current law, 27 members), but not more than 27 members at any given time. Extends the duration of the Commission for an additional 5 years. Provides for Department of Interior employees detailed to the Commission to assist the Commission in carrying out its duties (under current law, duties with regard to the preparation and approval of the Canalway Plan for the Corridor). Authorizes the Superintendent of Saratoga National Historical Park in New York, upon request, to provide any operational assistance that is appropriate to assist with the implementation of the Canalway Plan. Makes the amount authorized to be appropriated for the Corridor in any fiscal year available until expended. (Sec. 3002) Amends federal law relating to the establishment of the Blackstone River Valley National Heritage Corridor (re-named the John H. Chafee Blackstone River Valley National Heritage Corridor) in Massachusetts and Rhode Island to modify the composition of the membership of the John H. Chafee Blackstone River Valley National Heritage Corridor Commission. 
	</summary>
</bill>
