<bill session="110" type="h" number="1496" updated="2009-01-08T19:58:13-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1173758400" datetime="2007-03-13"/></status>

	<introduced date="1173758400" datetime="2007-03-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Beating Infections through Research and Development Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide incentives for pharmaceutical companies, biotechnology companies, and medical device companies to invest in research and development with respect to antibiotic drugs, antivirals, diagnostic tests, and vaccines that may be used to identify, treat, or prevent serious and life-threatening infectious diseases.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400011"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400132" joined="2007-09-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400068" joined="2007-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400255" joined="2007-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400088" joined="2007-03-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1173758400" datetime="2007-03-13"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1173758400" datetime="2007-03-13"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1173758400" datetime="2007-03-13"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1173758400" datetime="2007-03-13"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1173844800" datetime="2007-03-14"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1177041600" datetime="2007-04-20"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, the Internet, and Intellectual Property.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/13/2007--Introduced.<br/>Beating Infections through Research and Development Act of 2007 - Sets forth circumstances under which the term of a patent may be extended for qualified infectious disease products.<br/>Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to designate qualified infectious disease products as fast-track products for approval.<br/>Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Director of the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases to expand and intensify efforts to assist small manufacturers to conduct end-stage clinical trials on qualified infectious disease products.<br/>Amends the Internal Revenue Code to establish an infectious disease research credit and a qualified infectious disease products manufacturing facilities investment credit.<br/>Establishes the Commission on Infectious Diseases Product Development to identify drug-resistant infectious pathogens that are a significant threat to public health and make recommendations to the Secretary on how best to address such pathogens.<br/>Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require the Secretary, acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, to issue guidelines for the conduct of clinical trials with respect to antibiotic drugs.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
