<bill session="110" type="h" number="1503" updated="2009-01-08T19:59:03-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1185247740" datetime="2007-07-23T12:29:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1173758400" datetime="2007-03-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Avra/Black Wash Reclamation and Riparian Restoration Project</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Avra/Black Wash Reclamation and Riparian Restoration Project</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to participate in the Avra/Black Wash Reclamation and Riparian Restoration Project.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400162"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1173758400" datetime="2007-03-13"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1174276800" datetime="2007-03-19"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text></action>
		<action date="1179374400" datetime="2007-05-17"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1181620800" datetime="2007-06-12"><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1181620800" datetime="2007-06-12"><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Unanimous Consent .</text></action>
		<calendar date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1185246000" datetime="2007-07-23T12:00:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-251.</text></action>
		<calendar number="160" date="1185246060" datetime="2007-07-23T12:01:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 160.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1185247560" datetime="2007-07-23T12:26:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Grijalva moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1185247620" datetime="2007-07-23T12:27:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8195-8196"/></action>
		<action date="1185247620" datetime="2007-07-23T12:27:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1503.</text></action>
		<vote date="1185247740" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-07-23T12:29:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text as passed in House" ref="CR S8195-8196"/></vote>
		<action date="1185249600" datetime="2007-07-24"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1207627200" datetime="2008-04-08"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/23/2007--Passed House amended. Avra/Black Wash Reclamation and Riparian Restoration Project - Amends the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior, in cooperation with Pima County, Arizona, to participate in the planning, design, and construction of water recycling facilities and to enhance and restore riparian habitat in the Black Wash Sonoran Desert ecosystem in Avra Valley west of the metropolitan Pima County area. Limits the federal share of the project's cost to 25%. Authorizes appropriations. Permits federal funds provided by this Act to be used only for the design, planning, and construction of water-related infrastructure.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
