<bill session="110" type="h" number="1510" updated="2009-01-08T19:59:54-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1173758400" datetime="2007-03-13"/></status>

	<introduced date="1173758400" datetime="2007-03-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Credit Card Repayment Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require enhanced disclosure to consumers regarding the consequences of making only minimum required payments in the repayment of credit card debt, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400326"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400080" joined="2007-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400647" joined="2007-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400412" joined="2007-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400130" joined="2007-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400352" joined="2007-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2007-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2007-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400125" joined="2007-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2007-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="2007-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400425" joined="2007-05-21"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1173758400" datetime="2007-03-13"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/13/2007--Introduced.<br/>Credit Card Repayment Act of 2007 - Amends the Truth in Lending Act to include among the mandatory disclosures at each billing cycle of open end consumer credit plans: (1) the words &quot;Minimum Payment Warning: making only the minimum payment will increase the amount of interest that you pay and the time it will take to repay your outstanding balance;&quot; (2) the number of years and months it would take the consumer to pay the entire amount of the balance if the consumer pays only the required minimum monthly payments; (3) the total cost to the consumer, as well as a breakdown in principal and interest payments, of paying that balance in full if the consumer pays only the required minimum monthly payments, and if no further advances are made; (4) the monthly payment amount that would be required to eliminate the outstanding balance in 36 months if no further advances are made; and (5) a toll-free telephone number for information about accessing credit counseling and debt management services. Directs the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and the Federal Trade Commission to issue jointly guidelines for creditors to establish and maintain a toll-free telephone number for such disclosures.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
