<bill session="110" type="h" number="151" updated="2009-01-08T17:01:27-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/></status>

	<introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to ensure that projects funded through the National Institutes of Health comply with wage rate requirements commonly referred to as the &quot;Davis-Bacon Act&quot;, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400160"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1170392400" datetime="2007-02-02"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1178683200" datetime="2007-05-09"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/4/2007--Introduced.<br/>Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to require that applications for a National Institutes of Health (NIH) loan, grant, contract, or cooperative agreement for any project include reasonable assurance that all laborers and mechanics employed by contractors or subcontractors in the performance of construction or modernization on the project will be paid wages at rates not less than those prevailing on similar work in the locality as determined by the Secretary of Labor.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
