<bill session="110" type="h" number="1520" updated="2009-01-08T20:01:03-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1190657460" datetime="2007-09-24T15:11:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1173844800" datetime="2007-03-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Hudson-Fulton-Champlain Quadricentennial Commemoration Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Hudson-Fulton-Champlain Quadricentennial Commemoration Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Champlain Quadricentennial Commemoration Commission, the Hudson-Fulton 400th Commemoration Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400178"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400420" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400031" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400219" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400257" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400289" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412221" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412224" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400122" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400246" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400333" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400271" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400268" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400003" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400264" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400642" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400416" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412223" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400087" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412222" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400426" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400195" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400251" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400378" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400366" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412239" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400338" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2007-07-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400641" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400139" joined="2007-03-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1173844800" datetime="2007-03-14"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text></action>
		<action date="1174968000" datetime="2007-03-27"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia.</text></action>
		<action date="1184817600" datetime="2007-07-19"><text>Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia Discharged.</text></action>
		<action date="1184817600" datetime="2007-07-19"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1184817600" datetime="2007-07-19" ><text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1190657040" datetime="2007-09-24T15:04:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Davis (IL) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text></action>
		<action date="1190657040" datetime="2007-09-24T15:04:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H10709-10713"/></action>
		<action date="1190657100" datetime="2007-09-24T15:05:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1520.</text></action>
		<vote date="1190657460" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-09-24T15:11:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H10709-10712"/></vote>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="385" date="1190692800" datetime="2007-09-25" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 385.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1213156800" datetime="2008-06-11"><text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S5530"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/24/2007--Passed House without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)<br/>Hudson-Fulton-Champlain Quadricentennial Commemoration Act of 2007 - Title I: Findings and Purposes - (Sec. 101) Sets forth findings and purposes concerning the establishment of a Champlain Quadricentennial Commemoration Commission and a Hudson-Fulton 400th Commemoration Commission. Title II: Champlain Quadricentennial Commemoration Commission - (Sec. 202) Directs the Secretary of the Interior to establish the Champlain Quadricentennial Commemoration Commission to plan and execute programs and activities to commemorate the 400th anniversary of the voyage of Samuel de Champlain (the first European to discover and explore Lake Champlain). Sets forth requirements regarding the Champlain Commission's meetings, including a requirement for such meetings at least twice annually or at the call of the Chairperson or majority of Commission members. Requires the Champlain Commission to prepare a strategic plan for its activities the carried out under this Act. Sets forth Commission powers. Authorizes the Champlain Commission to make grants not to exceed $20,000 to: (1) communities, nonprofit organizations, and commemorative commissions formed by New York and Vermont to develop programs to assist in the commemoration research; and (2) scholarly organizations to research, publish, or distribute information relating to the early history of the voyages of Samuel de Champlain. Directs the Champlain Commission to coordinate and consult with the Lake Champlain Basin Program in providing grants and technical assistance for the conduct of activities relating to the commemoration of the voyage of Samuel de Champlain. Authorizes the Champlain Commission to accept the services of, and provide reimbursement for, personnel detailed from New York and Vermont and the Lake Champlain Basin Program. Requires the Champlain Commission to submit: (1) annual reports to Congress on each gift, bequest, or devise valuing more than $250, together with the identity of the donor; and (2) a final report to the Secretary by September 30, 2010, regarding its activities, funds received and expended, and its findings and recommendations. Terminates the the Champlain Commission on December 31, 2010. (Sec. 203) Requires annual audits of such Commission.<br/>(Sec. 204) Authorizes appropriations. Title III: Hudson-Fulton 400th Commemoration Commission - (Sec. 302) Directs the Secretary to establish the Hudson-Fulton 400th Commemoration Commission to plan and execute programs and activities to commemorate the 400th anniversary of the voyage of Henry Hudson (the first European to sail up the Hudson River) and the 200th anniversary of the voyage of Robert Fulton (the first person to use steam navigation on a commercial basis). Sets forth requirements regarding the Hudson-Fulton Commission's meetings, including a requirement for such meetings at least twice annually or at the call of the Chairperson or a majority of Commission members. Requires the Hudson-Fulton Commission to prepare a strategic plan for its activities carried out under this Act. Sets forth Commission powers. Authorizes the Hudson-Fulton Commission to make grants of not to exceed $20,000 to: (1) communities, nonprofit organizations, and commemorative commissions formed by New York to develop programs to assist in the commemoration; and (2) research and scholarly organizations to research, publish, or distribute information relating to the early history of the voyages of Henry Hudson and Robert Fulton. Authorizes the Hudson-Fulton Commission to accept the services of, and provide reimbursement for, personnel detailed from New York. Requires the Hudson-Fulton Commission to submit: (1) annual reports to Congress on each gift, bequest, or devise valuing more than $250, together with the identity of the donor; and (2) a final report to the Secretary by September 30, 2010, regarding its activities, funds received and expended, and its findings and recommendations. Terminates the Hudson-Fulton Commission on December 31, 2010. (Sec. 303) Requires annual audits of such Commission.<br/>(Sec. 304) Authorizes appropriations. 
	</summary>
</bill>
