<bill session="110" type="h" number="1548" updated="2009-01-08T20:04:42-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1173931200" datetime="2007-03-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1173931200" datetime="2007-03-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Northern Border Economic Development Commission Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Northern Border Economic Development Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412220"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412224" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400274" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400264" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400007" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412239" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412219" joined="2007-03-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1173931200" datetime="2007-03-15"><text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1173931200" datetime="2007-03-15"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1173931200" datetime="2007-03-15"><text>Referred to House Financial Services</text></action>
		<action date="1174017600" datetime="2007-03-16"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/15/2007--Introduced.<br/>Northern Border Economic Development Commission Act of 2007 - Establishes the Northern Border Economic Development Commission, having a region of specified counties in Maine, New Hampshire, New York, and Vermont, to develop plans and programs and to approve grants for the economic development of the region. Requires each such state to submit a development plan for the area of the region represented by such state. Outlines program development criteria, and provides for the approval of development plans and projects. Requires as a Commission goal to address economic distress along the northern border of the United States east of, and including, Cayuga County, New York, especially in rural areas.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
