<bill session="110" type="h" number="1546" updated="2009-01-08T20:04:28-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1173931200" datetime="2007-03-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1173931200" datetime="2007-03-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize members of the Armed Forces receiving outpatient care at Walter Reed Army Medical Center to receive such care through the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412222"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="412229" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400295" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400184" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400331" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400048" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400087" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412204" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400251" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412239" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400043" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400641" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400186" joined="2007-03-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1173243600" datetime="2007-03-07"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H2250)</text></action>
		<action date="1173931200" datetime="2007-03-15"><text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1173931200" datetime="2007-03-15"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1173931200" datetime="2007-03-15"><text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1174017600" datetime="2007-03-16"><committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1175572800" datetime="2007-04-03"><committee name="House Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/15/2007--Introduced.<br/>Requires the Secretary of Defense, upon request of a member of the Armed Forces receiving outpatient care at or through Walter Reed Army Medical Center, Maryland, to transfer such member to the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for the receipt of such care. Requires such Secretaries to jointly provide such members information on the nature and quality of outpatient care services available through the Department of Veterans Afffairs (VA). Directs that the VA-chosen care be provided at the VA facility closest to the permanent duty station or residence of such member. Terminates the transfer requirement after certification from the Secretary of Defense to the congressional defense committees with respect to DOD processing of status claims and facility quality and the staffing of case management and psychological counselor positions at Walter Reed.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
