<bill session="110" type="h" number="1580" updated="2009-01-08T20:08:35-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"/></status>

	<introduced date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Wounded Warriors Joint Health Care Ombudsman Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To create a Department of Defense-wide Ombudsman Office.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412250"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="2007-03-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="412196" joined="2007-03-20"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
		<action date="1175572800" datetime="2007-04-03"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/20/2007--Introduced.<br/>Wounded Warriors Joint Health Care Ombudsman Act - Directs the Secretary of Defense to establish a Department of Defense (DOD)-wide Ombudsman Office and to assign Office oversight responsibility to the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Health Affairs. Requires the Ombudsman to provide assistance to and answer questions from medical holdover patients and their families regarding: (1) administrative processes, financial matters, and non-military related services available to such patients and families; (2) transfer to the care of the Veterans Administration (VA); and (3) support services available upon the patient's return home. Directs the Ombudsman to establish toll-free telephone numbers for such patients and family members. Makes the Ombudsman responsible for handling congressional inquiries regarding medical holdover patients and other medical questions related to the Armed Forces. Defines a medical holdover patient as one held over for medical treatment by DOD for an injury, illness, or disease incurred or aggravated while on active duty.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
