<bill session="110" type="h" number="1581" updated="2009-01-08T20:08:42-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"/></status>

	<introduced date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Iraq Reconstruction Improvement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To improve coordination, implementation, and oversight of United States economic reconstruction assistance for Iraq, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400231"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2007-10-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400003" joined="2007-03-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="2007-06-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1177041600" datetime="2007-04-20"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/20/2007--Introduced.<br/>Iraq Reconstruction Improvement Act of 2007 - Directs the the President to: (1) appoint a Coordinator of United States Economic Reconstruction Assistance for Iraq; (2) provide assistance to increase the capacity and improve the sustainability of Iraq's national, provincial, and local governmental institutions; (3) provide assistance for anti-corruption activities in Iraq; (4) provide assistance to support provincial and local reconstruction programs in Iraq; (5) support private sector development and employment programs, including short-term job creation programs, in Iraq; (6) provide assistance to improve the auditing, investigation, and oversight capacity of the Offices of the Inspector General of the Department of State and the United States Agency for International Development (USAID); and (7) provide assistance to improve Department of State and USAID reconstruction contracting capacity in Iraq. Directs the Secretary of State to provide assistance to: (1) refugees from Iraq who have been outside Iraq in a Middle East country since no earlier than March 19, 2003; and (2) internally displaced persons in Iraq who have been outside their original residence since no earlier than March 19, 2003. Increases FY2007-FY2008 refugees admissions in order to admit Iraqi refugees. Amends the Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act for Defense and for the Reconstruction of Iraq and Afghanistan, 2004 to extend authority for the Office of Special Inspector General for Iraq Reconstruction. Prohibits Iraq-related contracts from being given to contractors who have overcharged the federal government, committed fraudulent acts, or been suspended under federal regulations. Authorizes waivers in the interest of national security on a case-by-case basis. Directs the Secretary: (1) in consultation with the Administrator of USAID, to establish a Civilian Active Response Corps to provide stabilization and reconstruction activities in foreign countries or regions that are in, are in transition from, or likely to enter into conflict or civil strife; (2) in consultation with relevant executive agencies, to establish a Civilian Reserve Readiness Corps to augment the Active Corps; and (3) to develop an inter-agency stabilization and reconstruction strategy. 
	</summary>
</bill>
