<bill session="110" type="h" number="1587" updated="2009-01-08T20:09:52-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"/></status>

	<introduced date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Levee Safety Program Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Army to carry out programs and activities to enhance the safety of levees in the United States.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412010"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E591)</text></action>
		<action date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text></action>
		<action date="1174449600" datetime="2007-03-21"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/20/2007--Introduced.<br/>National Levee Safety Program Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, to: (1) inspect each levee in the United States constructed or maintained by the Secretary or identified by a state governor, excluding levees the failure of which would not pose a significant threat to human life or property; (2) notify the governor of the state in which a levee is located of inspection results, hazardous conditions found, and necessary remedial measures; (3) submit, annually, a priority list of flood damage reduction studies and projects; and (4) periodically publish an inventory of U.S. levees, including inspection results. Establishes the Interagency Committee on Levee Safety to support federal levee safety programs through coordination and information exchange among federal agencies concerning the implementation of levee safety guidelines. Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish the National Levee Safety Review Board to monitor levee safety and state implementation of this Act and to advise the Secretary on national levee safety policy; (2) establish a national levee safety program, including federal levee safety guidelines; (3) provide assistance for and periodically review state levee safety programs; (4) carry out a program of technical and archival research regarding levee construction, rehabilitation, inspection, safety, security, and management; and (5) establish a program to train state safety agency staff and inspectors.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
