<bill session="110" type="h" number="1582" updated="2009-01-08T20:08:49-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"/></status>

	<introduced date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Gang Abatement and Prevention Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To increase and enhance law enforcement resources committed to investigation and prosecution of violent gangs, to deter and punish violent gang crime, to protect law-abiding citizens and communities from violent criminals, to revise and enhance criminal penalties for violent crimes, to expand and improve gang prevention programs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400361"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400123" joined="2007-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400290" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400659" joined="2007-06-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400618" joined="2007-11-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400065" joined="2007-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400344" joined="2007-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400405" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400412" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="412187" joined="2007-11-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412199" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400039" joined="2007-03-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400570" joined="2007-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="412196" joined="2007-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2007-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="412233" joined="2007-06-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1177041600" datetime="2007-04-20"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/20/2007--Introduced.<br/>Gang Abatement and Prevention Act of 2007 - Amends the federal criminal code to define &quot;criminal street gang&quot; and &quot;gang crime&quot; and to prohibit: (1) the commission of a gang crime or crime of violence to further the activities of a criminal street gang ; and (2) the recruitment of another person to join a criminal street gang.<br/>Increases criminal penalties for: (1) certain violent crimes in aid of racketeering activity; (2) possession of firearms by repeat offenders; and (3) crimes of violence and drug trafficking crimes committed by illegal aliens. Provides for criminal forfeiture of any property used to commit a gang crime Amends the Controlled Substances Act to impose criminal penalties for murder and other violent crimes committed in the course of a drug trafficking crime.<br/>Authorizes the Attorney General to: (1) designate certain areas in states as high intensity interstate gang activity areas and to provide assistance to such areas; (2) expand the Project Safe Neighborhoods program to require U.S. attorneys to prosecute criminal street gangs operating in their districts; (3) require the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) to increase funding for the Safe Streets Programs and support criminal street gang enforcement teams; (4) conduct media campaigns in high intensity interstate gang activity areas to educate the public about efforts to combat criminal gang activities; and (5) make grants to states to prevent abductions of children by family members.<br/>Amends the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994 to authorize grants for technology and training to increase accurate identification of gang members and violent offenders.<br/>Establishes in the U.S. Marshals Service a Short-Term Witness Protection Section to provide protection for witnesses in state and local trials involving homicide or other violent crimes. Expands the federal witness relocation and protection program to include protection against criminal street gangs.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
