<bill session="110" type="h" number="1603" updated="2009-01-08T20:12:00-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"/></status>

	<introduced date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Emergency Coverage During an Incident of National Significance Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 5, United States Code, to establish a national health program administered by the Office of Personnel Management to offer Federal employee health benefits plans to certain individuals affected by an incident of national significance, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400201"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"><text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1174968000" datetime="2007-03-27"><committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia.</text></action>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><committee name="House Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/20/2007--Introduced.<br/>Emergency Coverage During an Incident of National Significance Act of 2007 - Directs the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to administer a health insurance program for certain individuals affected by an incident of national significance. Requires OPM to contract with three or more carriers to make available five or more federal health benefits plans (subject to the provisions of this Act) to eligible individuals. Allows an income-related tax credit for amounts paid by eligible individuals for coverage under the health insurance plan established by this Act. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to establish a program for making payments on behalf of certain individuals to such plan. Requires the Secretary of Homeland Security, other federal officers, and the Director of OPM to submit a plan that: (1) provides for the orderly implementation of the amendments made by this Act; and (2) includes a schedule of actions to be taken to provide for that implementation. 
	</summary>
</bill>
