<bill session="110" type="h" number="1613" updated="2009-01-08T20:13:18-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"/></status>

	<introduced date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Sons and Daughters of America Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Revised Statutes of the United States to provide for legal protection against frivolous lawsuits directed at statutes prohibiting picketing at military and other funerals, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400405"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400123" joined="2007-03-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400279" joined="2007-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400242" joined="2007-03-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="412230" joined="2007-03-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400191" joined="2007-03-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400652" joined="2007-03-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400433" joined="2007-03-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400400" joined="2007-03-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400320" joined="2007-03-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400643" joined="2007-03-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="412213" joined="2007-06-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400145" joined="2007-03-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400351" joined="2007-03-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400654" joined="2007-03-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/20/2007--Introduced.<br/>Sons and Daughters of America Act - Amends the Revised Statutes of the United States to provide that the remedies for a civil action for deprivation of rights are limited to injunctive and declaratory relief where the deprivation: (1) consists of a violation of the right to freedom of speech secured by the Constitution; and (2) is the result of a statute, ordinance, regulation, custom, or usage which prohibits or restricts picketing, protesting, or demonstrating at a funeral or any other ceremony, procession, or memorial service held in connection with the burial or cremation of the dead.<br/>Prohibits the award of attorney's fees with respect to the prevailing party in such a claim, including one in any action brought against the United States or any federal agency or official acting in his or her official capacity in any court.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
