<bill session="110" type="h" number="1624" updated="2009-01-08T20:14:41-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1174449600" datetime="2007-03-21"/></status>

	<introduced date="1174449600" datetime="2007-03-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Colorectal Cancer Mortality Prevention Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to establish a program of grants for the detection and control of colorectal cancer.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400215"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-03-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400268" joined="2007-03-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2007-03-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400645" joined="2007-03-21"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1174449600" datetime="2007-03-21"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1174536000" datetime="2007-03-22"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/21/2007--Introduced.<br/>Colorectal Cancer Mortality Prevention Act of 2007 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to allow the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to make matching grants to states to carry out programs to: (1) screen for colorectal cancer as a preventive health measure; (2) provide referrals for medical treatment to individuals screened and ensure appropriate follow-up services; (3) develop and disseminate information and education programs for the detection and control of colorectal cancer; (4) improve the education, training, and skills of health professions in the detection and control of colorectal cancer; (5) establish mechanisms to monitor the quality of screening procedures for colorectal cancer; and (6) evaluate such activities through surveillance or program-monitoring. Requires states to meet specified matching fund requirements and other criteria to receive a grant, including ensuring that 60% of grant money is spent on screening and medical treatment, assuring the quality of screening procedures, giving priority to low-income individuals, and limiting the fees charged. Allows the Secretary to provide training, technical assistance, supplies, equipment, and services to aid the state in carrying out such a program. Requires the Secretary to: (1) issue guidelines for assuring the quality of any colorectal screening procedures carried out under this Act; and (2) evaluate the programs annually.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
