<bill session="110" type="h" number="1638" updated="2009-01-08T20:16:20-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1174536000" datetime="2007-03-22"/></status>

	<introduced date="1174536000" datetime="2007-03-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">James Zadroga 9/11 Health and Compensation Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To extend and improve protections and services to individuals directly impacted by the terrorist attack in New York City on September 11, 2001, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400251"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400031" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400219" joined="2007-04-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400257" joined="2007-04-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412224" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400380" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400122" joined="2007-03-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400268" joined="2007-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2007-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400132" joined="2007-04-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="2007-03-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400264" joined="2007-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="2007-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400087" joined="2007-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412222" joined="2007-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400426" joined="2007-03-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400195" joined="2007-03-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2007-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400366" joined="2007-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412186" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400139" joined="2007-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400309" joined="2007-04-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1174536000" datetime="2007-03-22"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1174536000" datetime="2007-03-22"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1174536000" datetime="2007-03-22"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1174622400" datetime="2007-03-23"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1177041600" datetime="2007-04-20"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/22/2007--Introduced.<br/>James Zadroga 9/11 Health and Compensation Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to extend and expand arrangements with certain medical providers and the New York City Fire Department for monitoring and other services for those exposed to airborne toxins from the terrorist attacks of September 11, 2001 in New York City (9/11 attacks). Expands the categories of individuals to be covered by such arrangements and provides for a nationwide network of health care providers for treating victims residing outside the New York City area.<br/>Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to conduct or support research on the diagnosis and treatment of physical and mental health conditions related to the 9/11 attacks. Authorizes the Secretary to establish similar research programs for victims of the attack at the Pentagon on September 11, 2001.<br/>Directs the Secretary to convene a 9/11 Health Emergency Coordinating Council to discuss, examine, and formulate recommendations with respect to the adequacy and coordination of: (1) care and compensation for victims of the 9/11attacks; and (2) federal tracking of the monitoring of, and treatment for, individuals affected by such attacks.<br/>Amends the Air Transportation Safety and System Stabilization Act to provide, under certain circumstances, for an extension for filing claims under the September 11th Victim Compensation Fund of 2001.<br/>Directs the Secretary to extend and expand arrangements with New York City that provide for the World Trade Center Health Registry.<br/>Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to the New York City Department of Health and Mental Hygiene for the mental health needs of individuals affected by the 9/11 attacks.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
