<bill session="110" type="h" number="1642" updated="2009-01-08T20:16:48-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1178569140" datetime="2007-05-07T17:19:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1174536000" datetime="2007-03-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Homeless Veterans Housing at Sepulveda Ambulatory Care Center Promotion Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Homeless Veterans Housing at Sepulveda Ambulatory Care Center Promotion Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to ensure that, to the extent possible, an enhanced-use lease for a homeless housing project at the Department of Veterans Affairs facility known as the Sepulveda Ambulatory Care Center, located in North Hills, California, shall provide that such housing project shall be maintained as a sober living facility for veterans only, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400371"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2007-03-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1174536000" datetime="2007-03-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1174622400" datetime="2007-03-23"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations.</text></action>
		<action date="1176264000" datetime="2007-04-11"><text>Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations Discharged.</text></action>
		<action date="1176868800" datetime="2007-04-18"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1176868800" datetime="2007-04-18" ><text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1178567700" datetime="2007-05-07T16:55:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Filner moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text></action>
		<action date="1178567700" datetime="2007-05-07T16:55:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H4516-4519"/></action>
		<action date="1178567700" datetime="2007-05-07T16:55:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1642.</text></action>
		<vote date="1178569140" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-05-07T17:19:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H4516"/></vote>
		<action date="1178596800" datetime="2007-05-08"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/7/2007--Passed House without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Homeless Veterans Housing at Sepulveda Ambulatory Care Center Promotion Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to enter into an enhanced-use lease for a homeless housing project at the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) facility known as the Sepulveda Ambulatory Care Center. Requires the lease to contain specified terms and conditions, including that the project: (1) provides housing exclusively for veterans; (2) is maintained as a sober living facility; and (3) is adequately staffed with health care, counseling, and security personnel.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
