<bill session="110" type="h" number="1669" updated="2009-01-08T20:20:15-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1174622400" datetime="2007-03-23"/></status>

	<introduced date="1174622400" datetime="2007-03-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Positive Aging Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for integration of mental health services and mental health treatment outreach teams, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400215"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400344" joined="2007-03-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1174622400" datetime="2007-03-23"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1174881600" datetime="2007-03-26"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/23/2007--Introduced.<br/>Positive Aging Act of 2007 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to : (1) require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to public and private nonprofit entities for projects to demonstrate ways of integrating mental health services for older adults into primary care settings and for multidisciplinary geriatric mental health outreach teams in community settings where older adults reside or receive social services; (2) require the Director of the Center for Mental Health Services to designate a Deputy Director for Older Adult Mental Health Services to address the mental health needs of older adults; (3) require the inclusion of representatives of older adults and their families and geriatric mental health professionals on the Advisory Council for the Center; (4) designate as a project of national significance the treatment of older adults with substance-related disorders; and (5) require state plans under the Community Mental Health Services Block Grant program to describe outreach to, and services for, older individuals and individuals who are homeless and living in rural areas.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
