<bill session="110" type="h" number="1690" updated="2009-01-08T20:22:44-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1174881600" datetime="2007-03-26"/></status>

	<introduced date="1174881600" datetime="2007-03-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Guaranteeing Airport Physical Screening Standards Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To improve airport screening and security.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400246"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1174881600" datetime="2007-03-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text></action>
		<action date="1176177600" datetime="2007-04-10"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation Security and Infrastructure Protection.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/26/2007--Introduced.<br/>Guaranteeing Airport Physical Screening Standards Act - Directs the Assistant Secretary of Homeland Security (Transportation Security Administration) to: (1) implement a pilot program at five commercial service airports to physically screen all airport workers with access to sterile areas of the airport; (2) issue regulations, directives, or other appropriate measures to implement requirements directing airport perimeter screening of all individuals, goods, property, vehicles, and other equipment before entry into a secured airport area; and (3) set a schedule for requiring airports to update their airport security plans to comply with such perimeter screening requirements. Requires, with respect to the pilot program: (1) at least two of the participating airports to be large hub airports, with each of the remaining airports representing a different airport security risk category; (2) screening to be conducted under the same standards as apply to individuals at airport security screening checkpoints and to be carried out by contract screeners at a minimum of two airports; and (3) that it shall be carried out for not less than 180 days. Authorizes the Secretary of Homeland Security to hire the necessary number of passenger and baggage screeners to ensure aviation security.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
