<bill session="110" type="h" number="1706" updated="2009-01-08T20:24:39-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1174968000" datetime="2007-03-27"/></status>

	<introduced date="1174968000" datetime="2007-03-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">United States Specialty Crop Export Opportunities Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for assistance to United States exporters of certain fruits and vegetables in order to ensure better access to foreign markets.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400297"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400403" joined="2007-03-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1174968000" datetime="2007-03-27"><text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1174968000" datetime="2007-03-27"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action date="1174968000" datetime="2007-03-27"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1174968000" datetime="2007-03-27"><text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text></action>
		<action date="1175054400" datetime="2007-03-28"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E654-655)</text></action>
		<action date="1176177600" datetime="2007-04-10"><committee name="House Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text></action>
		<action date="1176436800" datetime="2007-04-13"><committee name="House Homeland Security"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border, Maritime, and Global Counterterrorism.</text></action>
		<action date="1178251200" datetime="2007-05-04"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Horticulture and Organic Agriculture.</text></action>
		<action date="1178251200" datetime="2007-05-04"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text></action>
		<action date="1178251200" datetime="2007-05-04"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Specialty Crops, Rural Development, and Foreign Agriculture.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/27/2007--Introduced.<br/>United States Specialty Crop Export Opportunities Act of 2007 - Amends the Agricultural Risk Protection Act of 2000 to authorize the Secretary of Agriculture to regulate plants, plant products, biological control organisms, and noxious weeds for export purposes. Directs the Secretary to: (1) coordinate fruit and vegetable market analyses with the private sector and the Administrator of the Foreign Agricultural Service; and (2) make publicly available on an Internet website the status of all export petitions and an explanation of the sanitary or phytosanitary issues associated with each pending export petition, and information on the import requirements of foreign countries for fruits and vegetables. Amends the Homeland Security Act to repeal the transfer of agricultural import and entry inspection functions from the Department of Agriculture to the Department of Homeland Security (DHS). Directs the Secretary to establish: (1) within the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service the international agricultural inspection program to carry out import and entry agricultural inspections; (2) a federal-state agricultural inspection communications system; (3) the International Trade Inspection Advisory Committee; and (4) a special export credit guarantee program. Amends the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 to extend: (1) the promotion of agricultural exports to emerging markets program; and (2) the E. (Kika) de la Garza Agricultural Fellowship program.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
