<bill session="110" type="h" number="1711" updated="2009-01-08T20:25:15-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1174968000" datetime="2007-03-27"/></status>

	<introduced date="1174968000" datetime="2007-03-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Flexibility in Assessments for Individuals Reform Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to improve certain accountability and assessment provisions.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400186"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400073" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400080" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="2007-11-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="412195" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400198" joined="2007-10-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400132" joined="2007-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400285" joined="2007-11-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400346" joined="2007-12-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2007-12-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="412186" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400043" joined="2007-11-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="2007-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400345" joined="2007-12-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1174968000" datetime="2007-03-27"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1182916800" datetime="2007-06-27"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/27/2007--Introduced.<br/>Flexibility in Assessments for Individuals Reform Act of 2007 - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to alter requirements regarding state assessments of whether students are making adequate yearly progress (AYP) toward academic achievement standards by allowing states to: (1) track AYP on a longitudinal basis; (2) permit disabled students and students for religious reasons to opt out of the assessments; (3) reschedule assessments for students who for specified reasons cannot attend scheduled assessments; and (4) count disabled students who graduate from secondary school within reasonable periods of time in favorable AYP graduation rates. Includes students in the limited-English proficient subgroup for three school years after they attain English proficiency, when determining whether the subgroup has made AYP. Requires limited-English proficient students to be included in English proficiency assessments if they have attended U.S. schools for more than five consecutive years. (Currently, they are subject to such assessments after attending U.S. schools for three or more consecutive years.) 
	</summary>
</bill>
