<bill session="110" type="h" number="1725" updated="2009-01-08T20:27:01-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1184089920" datetime="2007-07-10T14:52:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1175054400" datetime="2007-03-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Rancho California Water District Recycled Water Reclamation Facility Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Rancho California Water District Recycled Water Reclamation Facility Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Rancho California Water District Recycled Water Reclamation Facility Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to participate in the Rancho California Water District Southern Riverside County Recycled/Non-Potable Distribution Facilities and Demineralization/Desalination Recycled Water Treatment and Reclamation Facility Project.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400039"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400196" joined="2007-03-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400239" joined="2007-03-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400057" joined="2007-03-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1175054400" datetime="2007-03-28"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1175659200" datetime="2007-04-04"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text></action>
		<action date="1179374400" datetime="2007-05-17"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1181620800" datetime="2007-06-12"><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1181620800" datetime="2007-06-12"><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Unanimous Consent .</text></action>
		<action date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28" ><text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1184087160" datetime="2007-07-10T14:06:00-04:00"><text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-222.</text></action>
		<calendar number="138" date="1184087160" datetime="2007-07-10T14:06:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 138.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1184089560" datetime="2007-07-10T14:46:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Sarbanes moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text></action>
		<action date="1184089560" datetime="2007-07-10T14:46:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H7444-7445"/></action>
		<action date="1184089560" datetime="2007-07-10T14:46:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1725.</text></action>
		<vote date="1184089920" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-07-10T14:52:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H7444"/></vote>
		<action date="1184126400" datetime="2007-07-11"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1207627200" datetime="2008-04-08"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1210132800" datetime="2008-05-07" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1213588800" datetime="2008-06-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment. With written report No. 110-383.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="815" date="1213588800" datetime="2008-06-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 815.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/16/2008--Reported to Senate amended. Rancho California Water District Recycled Water Reclamation Facility Act of 2008 - Amends the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior, in cooperation with the Rancho California Water District, to participate in the design, planning, and construction of permanent facilities for water recycling, demineralization, and desalination and distribution of non-potable water supplies in Southern Riverside County, California. Limits the federal share to the lesser of 25% of the total project cost or $20 million. Prohibits funds provided by the Secretary from being used for project operation or maintenance.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
