<bill session="110" type="h" number="1766" updated="2009-01-08T20:32:13-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/></status>

	<introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Chesapeake's Healthy and Environmentally Sound Stewardship of Energy and Agriculture Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">CHESSEA Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend conservation and biofuels programs of the Department of Agriculture to promote the compatible goals of economically viable agricultural production and reducing nutrient loads in the Chesapeake Bay and its tributaries by assisting agricultural producers to make beneficial, cost-effective changes to cropping systems, grazing management, and nutrient management associated with livestock and poultry production, crop production, bioenergy production, and other agricultural practices on agricultural land within the Chesapeake Bay watershed, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400415"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400060" joined="2007-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400364" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400149" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400137" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="412234" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400295" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400095" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400658" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400017" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400098" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400147" joined="2007-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400070" joined="2007-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412222" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400189" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412212" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400090" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400321" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400435" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400349" joined="2007-03-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E691)</text></action>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text></action>
		<action date="1178251200" datetime="2007-05-04"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Credit, Energy, and Research.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/29/2007--Introduced.<br/>Chesapeake's Healthy and Environmentally Sound Stewardship of Energy and Agriculture Act of 2007 or CHESSEA Act of 2007 - Amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to extend funding for the the environmental quality incentives program. Gives program allocation priority to interstate watersheds. Provides a cost-share payment exception for limited resource and beginning farmers. Provides: (1) cost-share and incentive payments for private forest owners to carry out specified conservation activities; and (2) state performance incentives. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to enter into agreements with states containing all or a portion of a large waterbody or its tributaries for water quality initiatives. (States that the Chesapeake Bay and its tributaries shall be one of such waterbodies.) Authorizes appropriations. Directs (currently, authorizes) the Secretary to pay the cost of conservation innovation grants. Makes such grants available for projects that include a technology transfer plan. Extends: (1) the conservation reserve program; (2) the conservation security program; and (3) the wetlands reserve program. Directs the Secretary to establish a conservation planning pilot program in the Chesapeake Bay watershed. Authorizes appropriations. Amends the Federal Crop Insurance Act to: (1) extend the agricultural management assistance program; and (2) make Virginia eligible for such assistance. Amends the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 with respect to the biorefinery and biofuel grant program to: (1) extend such program; and (2) provide grants for Chesapeake Bay Watershed states (Delaware, Maryland, New York, Pennsylvania, Virginia, and West Virginia and the District of Columbia) to develop the commercial viability of no-till soybean biodiesel production, cellulosic ethanol production, manure to energy processes, and other technologies that promote the conversion of biomass to fuels and chemicals and the reduction of nutrient impacts to water. Extends the renewable energy systems and energy efficiency improvements program. Obligates amounts for Chesapeake Bay Watershed states. 
	</summary>
</bill>
