<bill session="110" type="h" number="1769" updated="2009-01-08T20:32:38-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/></status>

	<introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Endangered Salmon Predation Prevention Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 to reduce predation on endangered Columbia River salmon, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400011"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400659" joined="2007-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400419" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412201" joined="2007-07-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400171" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400109" joined="2007-03-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1176177600" datetime="2007-04-10"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, and Oceans.</text></action>
		<action date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/29/2007--Introduced.<br/>Endangered Salmon Predation Prevention Act - Amends the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 to authorize the Secretary of Commerce to issue one-year permits for the lethal taking of California sea lions if the Secretary determines that alternative measures to reduce sea lion predation on threatened or endangered salmonid stocks in the Columbia River do not adequately protect the salmonid stocks from such predation. Limits the cumulative annual taking of California sea lions to one percent of the annual potential biological removal level of such sea lions. Requires the Secretary to determine whether alternative measures to reduce sea lion predation on salmonid stocks will adequately protect such stocks. Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) nonlethal means of preventing sea lion predation of salmonid stocks in the Columbia River is preferable to lethal means; (2) permit holders exercising lethal removal authority should be trained in wildlife management; and (3) the federal government should continue to fund, research, and support effective nonlethal alternative measures for preventing such predation.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
