<bill session="110" type="h" number="1792" updated="2009-01-08T20:35:30-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/></status>

	<introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Temporary Agricultural Labor Reform Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To simplify the process for admitting temporary alien agricultural workers under section 101(a)(15)(H)(ii)(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, to increase access to such workers, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400154"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400313" joined="2007-11-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400095" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412217" joined="2007-06-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400241" joined="2007-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400030" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400287" joined="2007-10-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400643" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400221" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400431" joined="2008-05-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action date="1177041600" datetime="2007-04-20"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text></action>
		<action date="1178251200" datetime="2007-05-04"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from Dept of Homeland Security.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/29/2007--Introduced.<br/>Temporary Agricultural Labor Reform Act of 2007 - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to revise employer and employee association application requirements for admission of H-2A temporary agricultural workers, including assurances: (1) that the job opportunity is temporary, and is not the result of a labor dispute; (2) that attempts have been made to hire U.S. workers; (3) respecting wages and benefits, and labor law compliance; (4) respecting nondisplacement of U.S. workers; and (5) respecting placement with other employers. Requires the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish a mandatory employment verification program. Revises related provisions respecting: (1) penalties; and (2) admissions and extensions of stay. Provides special provisions for alien sheepherders, goatherders, and dairy workers. Amends the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to: (1) authorize the Secretary of Agriculture to make grants to H-2A employers for the transportation costs of workers whose employment is cut short by natural disaster; and (2) direct the Secretary to establish an H-2A Worker Program Ombudsman within the Office of the Chief Economist of the Department of Agriculture. Amends the Immigrant Reform and Control Act of 1986 to limit the conditions under which the Legal Services Corporation may: (1) provide legal assistance for, or on behalf of, any alien; (2) bring a civil action for damages on behalf of an H-2A nonimmigrant (requires prior mediation); and (3) enter onto an employer's property.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
