<bill session="110" type="h" number="1791" updated="2009-01-08T20:35:23-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/></status>

	<introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Fairness in Firearm Testing Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives to make video recordings of the examination and testing of firearms and ammunition, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400151"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400627" joined="2007-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400367" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400209" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412234" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412210" joined="2008-01-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400040" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412231" joined="2008-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400285" joined="2008-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400412" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400030" joined="2008-01-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400316" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400006" joined="2007-12-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400068" joined="2007-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400311" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400335" joined="2008-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400287" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400153" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412201" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400421" joined="2007-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400440" joined="2007-10-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400141" joined="2007-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400345" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400341" joined="2007-03-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1177041600" datetime="2007-04-20"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/29/2007--Introduced.<br/>Fairness in Firearm Testing Act - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives to make a video recording of the entire process of its examination and testing of an item for the purpose of determining whether the item is a firearm (and if so, the type of firearm) or ammunition. Bars the Bureau from editing or erasing any such recording.<br/>Directs the Bureau to make available a digital video disc that contains a copy of the recording: (1) at the request of a person who claims an ownership interest in such item; and (2) to a defendant in a criminal proceeding involving such item. Provides that an item which the Bureau has determined is a firearm or ammunition shall not be admissible as evidence unless: (1) the Bureau has complied with the requirements of this Act to make its digital video disc available; or (2) such compliance has been waived in writing by the person against whom the item is offered as evidence.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
