<bill session="110" type="h" number="1805" updated="2009-01-08T20:37:02-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/></status>

	<introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening Public Health Protections in Major Disasters and Emergencies Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to provide for the health and safety of certain volunteers and workers in disaster areas, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400201"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1175227200" datetime="2007-03-30"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text></action>
		<action date="1175227200" datetime="2007-03-30"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/29/2007--Introduced.<br/>Strengthening Public Health Protections in Major Disasters and Emergencies Act of 2007 - Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to authorize the President to carry out a program for the protection, assessment, monitoring, and study of the health and safety of individuals who responded to Hurricane Katrina or Hurricane Rita or who respond to a major disaster or emergency, if chemicals or substances associated with potential acute or chronic human health effects were or are released in a major disaster area.<br/>Makes participation voluntary. Requires the President to take appropriate measures to protect the privacy of registry or study participants. Authorizes the President to carry out such a program through a cooperative agreement with a medical institution (including a local health department) or a consortium of medical institutions. Requires the President to carry out such a program in accordance with certain privacy regulations.<br/>Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to enter jointly into a contract with the National Academy of Sciences to study and report on disaster area health and environmental protection and monitoring.<br/>Extends through September 30, 2010, the President's authority to establish a program to provide technical and financial assistance to state and local governments for the implementation of cost-effective predisaster hazard mitigation measures.<br/>Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize payments from allotments made to a state for community outreach and education programs and other activities designed to prevent health and health care disparities.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
