<bill session="110" type="h" number="1806" updated="2009-01-08T20:37:09-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/></status>

	<introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Youth Crime Deterrence Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 to provide quality prevention programs and accountability programs relating to juvenile delinquency, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400204"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400073" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400227" joined="2007-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400344" joined="2007-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400339" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="2007-05-21"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1183953600" datetime="2007-07-09"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Healthy Families and Communities.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/29/2007--Introduced.<br/>Youth Crime Deterrence Act of 2007 - Amends the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 to set forth additional requirements for state plans under the juvenile justice and delinquency prevention program (program) relating to juvenile truancy from detention or placement settings and housing, reentry and aftercare services for juveniles released from the juvenile justice system. Authorizes the Administrator of the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention to make grants to or contracts with public and nonprofit private agencies for: (1) family and community programs to prevent and reduce the participation of juveniles in criminal gangs; (2) treatment programs for juvenile offenders who are victims of child abuse or neglect and their families; and (3) mentoring programs for at-risk juveniles.<br/>Authorizes the Administrator to make grants to states for certain challenge activities under the program. Defines &quot;challenge activity&quot; as a state program maintained to: (1) provide juveniles in the juvenile justice system with basic health, mental health, and education services; (2) increase community-based alternatives to incarceration of juveniles; (3) provide secure settings for the placement of violent juvenile offenders; (4) establish and operate a state ombudsmen office for monitoring out-of-home care for juveniles; or (5) adopt policies for alternatives to suspension and expulsion from school and for prohibiting discrimination against juveniles in program placement or treatment based on perceived or actual sexual orientation or gender identity.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
