<bill session="110" type="h" number="1828" updated="2009-01-08T20:40:01-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/></status>

	<introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Teaching Fellows Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a national teaching fellowship program to encourage individuals to enter and remain in the field of teaching at public schools.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400326"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400280" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400289" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400616" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400155" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400282" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="412225" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400271" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400424" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412214" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412198" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400048" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412204" joined="2007-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="412232" joined="2008-09-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400266" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400125" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="2007-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400363" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400163" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400179" joined="2007-03-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1183953600" datetime="2007-07-09"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/29/2007--Introduced.<br/>Teaching Fellows Act of 2007 - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of Education to make competitive matching grants to states for Teaching and Partnership Fellows programs of scholarships for prospective public school teachers. Provides for scholarships: (1) under the Teaching program for high school seniors and second-year college students to encourage them to enter the teaching field and become career educators; and (2) under the Partnership program for individuals, such as paraprofessional educational personnel and others currently in the education field, to complete a bachelor's degree with a state license or certification to teach through partnerships among associate- and bachelor-degree-granting institutions. Requires scholarship recipients to repay specified amounts if they do not fulfill certain obligations to teach in their state's public elementary or secondary schools, under such Teaching and Partnership Fellows program.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
