<bill session="110" type="h" number="1826" updated="2009-01-08T20:39:47-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/></status>

	<introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Nuclear Disarmament and Economic Conversion Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for nuclear disarmament and economic conversion in accordance with District of Columbia Initiative Measure Number 37 of 1992.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400295"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1175227200" datetime="2007-03-30"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E707)</text></action>
		<action date="1177560000" datetime="2007-04-26"><committee name="House Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Strategic Forces.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/29/2007--Introduced.<br/>Nuclear Disarmament and Economic Conversion Act of 2007 - Requires the U.S. Government to: (1) disable and dismantle all its nuclear weapons and refrain from replacing them at any time with weapons of mass destruction; (2) undertake vigorous good faith efforts to eliminate war, armed conflict, and all military operations; (3) actively promote policies to induce all other countries to join in these commitments for world peace and security; and (4) redirect resources that are currently being used for nuclear weapons programs to constructive, ecologically beneficial peacetime activities and to address human and infrastructure needs such as housing, health care, education, agriculture, and environmental restoration. Makes this Act effective when the President certifies to Congress that all foreign countries possessing nuclear weapons have established legal requirements comparable to those set forth in this Act.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
