<bill session="110" type="h" number="1849" updated="2009-01-08T20:42:45-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/></status>

	<introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Credit Union Small Business Lending Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Credit Union Act and the Small Business Act to improve small business lending, improve cooperation between the National Credit Union Administration and the Small Business Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400416"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="412189" joined="2007-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400311" joined="2007-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400363" joined="2007-06-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Referred to House Financial Services</text></action>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Referred to House Small Business</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/29/2007--Introduced.<br/>Credit Union Small Business Lending Act - Amends the Federal Credit Union Act to exclude from the meaning of &quot;member business loan,&quot; and thereby from specified limitations on member business loans made by a credit union, certain small business loans made in cooperation with the Small Business Administration (SBA), without regard to whether any portion of such a loan is or is not SBA-guaranteed. Amends the Small Business Act to direct the SBA Administrator to implement a program to: (1) provide outreach and assistance to credit unions to increase their participation in the SBA small business loan program; (2) simplify the application process for such participation; and (3) provide a guaranty of up to 85% for loans made by credit unions to their members in underserved areas. 
	</summary>
</bill>
