<bill session="110" type="h" number="1847" updated="2009-01-08T20:42:31-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1216785600" datetime="2008-07-23" /></status>

	<introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Trails System Willing Seller Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">National Trails System Willing Seller Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Trails System Act to clarify Federal authority relating to land acquisition from willing sellers for the majority of the trails in the System, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400412"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412224" joined="2007-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400216" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400013" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400318" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400119" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="2008-01-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400218" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400238" joined="2007-03-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1175227200" datetime="2007-03-30"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E721)</text></action>
		<action date="1176177600" datetime="2007-04-10"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action date="1215662400" datetime="2008-07-10"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1216785600" datetime="2008-07-23"><text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands Discharged.</text></action>
		<action date="1216785600" datetime="2008-07-23"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1216785600" datetime="2008-07-23" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1221191940" datetime="2008-09-11T12:59:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-841.</text></action>
		<calendar number="541" date="1221191940" datetime="2008-09-11T12:59:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 541.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/11/2008--Reported to House amended. National Trails System Willing Seller Act - Amends the National Trails System Act to: (1) prohibit the federal acquisition of land and interest in land outside the exterior boundaries of any federally administered area, except with the owner's consent, for the Oregon, Mormon Pioneer, Lewis and Clark, and Nez Perce National Historic Trails and the Continental Divide, North Country, Ice Age, and Potomac Heritage National Scenic Trails; and (2) provide that federal authority to acquire fee title shall be limited to an average of not more than one-quarter mile on either side of the Oregon, Mormon Pioneer, Continental Divide, Lewis and Clark, and Nez Perce trails. Authorizes appropriations to implement the provisions of the Act relating to trails designated by the Act as national scenic or historic trails. Limits funding for the acquisition of land or interests for, or for the development of, the Natchez Trace National Scenic Trail. Instructs the administering agency for the Natchez Trace National Scenic Trail to encourage volunteer participation in the development of such Trail. 
	</summary>
</bill>
