<bill session="110" type="h" number="1848" updated="2009-01-08T20:42:38-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/></status>

	<introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">CSRS Retirement Repayment Technical Correction Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 5, United States Code, to exempt certain individuals under the Civil Service Retirement System from the requirement to pay interest on the repayment of amounts received as refunds of retirement contributions as a condition of receiving credit under such System for the service covered by the refund.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400415"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E695)</text></action>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Referred to House House Administration</text></action>
		<action date="1176696000" datetime="2007-04-16"><committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/29/2007--Introduced.<br/>CSRS Retirement Repayment Technical Correction Act of 2007 - Exempts federal employees and Members of Congress from the Civil Service Retirement System (CSRS) interest repayment requirement with respect to retirement contribution amounts withdrawn between October 1, 1990-February 28, 1991. Makes such exemption effective as if included in the enactment of the Omnibus Budget and Reconciliation Act of 1990.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
