<bill session="110" type="h" number="1857" updated="2009-01-08T20:43:42-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1176696000" datetime="2007-04-16"/></status>

	<introduced date="1176696000" datetime="2007-04-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Local Control of Education Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To restore State sovereignty over public elementary and secondary education.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400089"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400029" joined="2007-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400017" joined="2007-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400311" joined="2007-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400131" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400145" joined="2007-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400182" joined="2007-04-16"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1176696000" datetime="2007-04-16"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1183953600" datetime="2007-07-09"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/16/2007--Introduced.<br/>Local Control of Education Act of 2007 - Prohibits the Secretary of Education from providing any funds to a state for any program under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA), and prohibits such program from operating in that state, unless the state legislature has by law expressly and specifically authorized operation of its program and, in doing so, has waived the state's rights and authorities to act inconsistently with any requirement that might be imposed as a condition of receiving federal funds. Requires state authorization of the program's operation before any federal officer, employee, or authority may enforce any program requirement against a state authority, and before any state authority may be obliged to obey any such requirement. Prohibits the Secretary from providing any funds under an ESEA program to a local governmental entity unless the state's chief law enforcement officer certifies that the entity's participation in the program is consistent with any applicable state law requirements.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
