<bill session="110" type="h" number="1869" updated="2009-01-08T20:45:08-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1176782400" datetime="2007-04-17"/></status>

	<introduced date="1176782400" datetime="2007-04-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Communities First Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Community Banks Serving Their Communities First Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Seasoned Customer CTR Exemption Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance the ability of community banks to foster economic growth and serve their communities, boost small businesses, increase individual savings, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400416"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400059" joined="2007-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400659" joined="2008-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400228" joined="2007-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="412221" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400385" joined="2007-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400313" joined="2008-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412231" joined="2007-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412189" joined="2007-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400084" joined="2007-10-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400652" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400412" joined="2007-10-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400055" joined="2007-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="412208" joined="2008-01-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400038" joined="2007-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400311" joined="2007-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400051" joined="2007-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400340" joined="2007-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="412204" joined="2007-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400653" joined="2007-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400645" joined="2007-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400118" joined="2007-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400284" joined="2007-10-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412186" joined="2007-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412213" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400043" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400182" joined="2007-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400654" joined="2007-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400363" joined="2007-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400656" joined="2007-06-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1176782400" datetime="2007-04-17"><text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1176782400" datetime="2007-04-17"><text>Referred to House Financial Services</text></action>
		<action date="1176782400" datetime="2007-04-17"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1176782400" datetime="2007-04-17"><text>Referred to House Small Business</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/17/2007--Introduced.<br/>Community Banks Serving Their Communities First Act, or the Communities First Act - Revises regulatory requirements for community banks, including amendments to: (1) the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to permit certain insured depository institutions to submit a short form report of condition; (2) the Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002 to exempt certain small-sized depository institutions from annual management assessment of internal controls requirements; (3) the Securities Investor Protection Act of 1970 to exempt certain small-size community banks from its prohibition against advances for customers' net equity claims; (4) the Federal Reserve Act to increase the asset size of banks exempt from the limitation on extensions of credit to executive officers, directors, and principal shareholders; and (5) the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to increase the shareholder registration threshold. Amends the Truth in Lending Act to direct the Federal Reserve Board to prescribe regulations authorizing a consumer to waive the right of rescission as to certain transactions when the creditor is an insured depository institution. Seasoned Customer CTR Exemption Act of 2007 - Instructs the Secretary of the Treasury to prescribe regulations to exempt a depository institution from filing a currency transaction report (CTR) in the case of certain qualified customers. Amends additional Acts, including: (1) the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act to exempt specified community banks from furnishing a mandatory privacy notice; (2) the Fair Credit Reporting Act to require a consumer's written consent before a consumer reporting agency may furnish a consumer report upon request from another creditor; and (3) the Federal Reserve Act to limit loans to executive officers. Amends the Internal Revenue Code with respect to specified tax provisions for long-term certificates of deposit, loans secured by agricultural real property, qualified small issue bonds, Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation-insured limited liability companies, and young savers accounts. Repeals the individual alternative minimum tax for individuals and community banks. Reduces the tax rates for community banks. Revises certain Subchapter S requirements for tax treatment of small businesses. Amends the Small Business Act with respect to: (1) reduced fees for specified loans; and (2) a low documentation loan program.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
