<bill session="110" type="h" number="1861" updated="2009-01-08T20:44:10-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1176696000" datetime="2007-04-16"/></status>

	<introduced date="1176696000" datetime="2007-04-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Joshua Haglund Justice and Peace Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To urge the Government of the Republic of Armenia to resolve the murder case of Joshua Haglund, a United States citizen, in Yerevan, Armenia, and to fund scholarships at the University of Minnesota in the memory of Joshua Haglund for study abroad and diversity training.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400259"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1176696000" datetime="2007-04-16"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1176696000" datetime="2007-04-16"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1176696000" datetime="2007-04-16"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1183953600" datetime="2007-07-09"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/16/2007--Introduced.<br/>Joshua Haglund Justice and Peace Act of 2007 - Urges the Secretary of State to express to Armenian officials the serious concern and strong desire of Congress to achieve justice in the unresolved murder of Joshua Haglund, a Minnesota resident who was teaching English in Armenia. Calls on Armenia to continue pursuing, in cooperation with U.S. officials, the investigation into his death, and to use all appropriate means to achieve justice in the case. Authorizes appropriations to the Secretary of Education to fund the Joshua Haglund Memorial Peace Scholarship Fund at the University of Minnesota, which will finance study abroad scholarships and diversity training to further Joshua Haglund's vision of compassion, peace, and community service.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
