<bill session="110" type="h" number="1890" updated="2009-01-08T20:48:15-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1176782400" datetime="2007-04-17"/></status>

	<introduced date="1176782400" datetime="2007-04-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Public Safety Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure that the incarceration of inmates is not provided by private contractors or vendors and that persons charged with or convicted of an offense against the United States shall be housed in facilities managed and maintained by Federal, State, or local governments.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400183"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400279" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400257" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400228" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400160" joined="2008-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412234" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2007-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400316" joined="2007-04-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="412222" joined="2008-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400653" joined="2008-03-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2007-07-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400026" joined="2007-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400217" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400645" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400244" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2007-12-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400286" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400024" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412206" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400345" joined="2008-02-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1176782400" datetime="2007-04-17"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1178251200" datetime="2007-05-04"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/17/2007--Introduced.<br/>Public Safety Act - Prohibits funds provided by the federal government to a state or local government for the purpose of providing core correctional services from being used to contract with private contractors or vendors to provide such services. Defines &quot;core correctional services&quot; as the housing, safeguarding, protecting, and disciplining of persons charged with or convicted of an offense.<br/>Amends the federal criminal code to require the Bureau of Prisons to provide that: (1) any penal or correctional facility or institution, except a facility for nonprofit community correctional confinement (such as halfway houses), confining any person convicted of any offense against the United States shall be under the direction of the Director of the Bureau and shall be managed and maintained by federal, state, or local government employees; and (2) the housing, safeguarding, protection, and disciplining of any person charged with or convicted of any offense against the United States (with that exception) shall be conducted and carried out by federal, state, or local government employees.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
