<bill session="110" type="h" number="1895" updated="2009-01-08T20:49:03-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1176782400" datetime="2007-04-17"/></status>

	<introduced date="1176782400" datetime="2007-04-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Anti-Gun Trafficking Penalties Enhancement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the tracking of stolen firearms and firearms used in a crime, to allow more frequent inspections of gun dealers to ensure compliance with Federal gun law, to enhance the penalties for gun trafficking, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400257"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412221" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="2007-06-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1176782400" datetime="2007-04-17"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1178251200" datetime="2007-05-04"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/17/2007--Introduced.<br/>Anti-Gun Trafficking Penalties Enhancement Act of 2007 - Amends the Science, State, Justice, Commerce, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2006 to repeal restrictions on disclosure of the content of the Firearms Trace System database (database). Directs the Attorney General to provide state and local governments or law enforcement agencies with information from such database upon receipt of a written request.<br/>Requires federal law enforcement agencies investigating a crime to provide information about firearms stolen or used in such crime to the Bureau of Alcohol, Firearms, Tobacco, and Explosives (BAFTE) for inclusion in the database. Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to require state and local law enforcement agencies investigating a crime to provide information about firearms stolen or used in such crime to BAFTE for inclusion in the database. Amends the federal criminal code to include illegal firearms sales and trafficking in the definition of racketeering activity.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
