<bill session="110" type="h" number="1891" updated="2009-01-08T20:48:23-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1176782400" datetime="2007-04-17"/></status>

	<introduced date="1176782400" datetime="2007-04-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Ready, Willing, and Able Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To promote the development of disaster plans that will protect the maximum number of citizens; to foster public trust, confidence, and cooperation with these plans; and to encourage greater public participation in homeland security by allowing the American people to have a direct and influential role in developing and modifying community disaster preparedness, response, recovery, and mitigation plans in collaboration with government officials, emergency managers, health authorities, and professional responders, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400215"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400152" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400245" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400402" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400230" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2007-04-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1176782400" datetime="2007-04-17"><text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1176782400" datetime="2007-04-17"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1176782400" datetime="2007-04-17"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1176782400" datetime="2007-04-17"><text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text></action>
		<action date="1176868800" datetime="2007-04-18"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text></action>
		<action date="1176868800" datetime="2007-04-18"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1177819200" datetime="2007-04-29"><committee name="House Homeland Security"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emergency Communications, Preparedness, and Response.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/17/2007--Introduced.<br/>Ready, Willing, and Able Act - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting jointly, to establish a working group to assist their respective departments to: (1) promote the development of disaster plans that will protect the maximum number of citizens; (2) help state and local officials provide the necessary means and infrastructure for the American public to volunteer to assume a direct and influential role in community-based disaster preparedness, response, recovery, and mitigation planning efforts; and (3) develop standards to measure the success of a community's level of direct, participatory disaster planning efforts. Amends the Public Health Service Act to revise the requirements for a state application for a grant to improve state, local, and hospital preparedness for and response to bioterrorism and other public health emergencies. Requires the application to include an assurance that the state will take specific steps to comply with any recommendations of the working group.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
