<bill session="110" type="h" number="1915" updated="2009-01-08T20:51:36-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1176868800" datetime="2007-04-18"/></status>

	<introduced date="1176868800" datetime="2007-04-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">American Automobile Industry Promotion Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To promote the future of the American automobile industry, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400070"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400225" joined="2007-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400119" joined="2007-06-21"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1176868800" datetime="2007-04-18"><text>Referred to the Committee on Science and Technology, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1176868800" datetime="2007-04-18"><text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text></action>
		<action date="1176868800" datetime="2007-04-18"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1176868800" datetime="2007-04-18"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1176955200" datetime="2007-04-19"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text></action>
		<action date="1178596800" datetime="2007-05-08"><committee name="House Science and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/18/2007--Introduced.<br/>American Automobile Industry Promotion Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of Energy to: (1) offer to enter into an arrangement with the National Academy of Sciences to assess state-of-the-art battery technologies with potential application for electric drive transportation; (2) conduct a program of research, development, demonstration, and commercial application for electric drive transportation technology (i.e., vehicles that use electric motors for all or part of the motive power); and (3) establish and carry out an Advanced Battery Initiative to support research, development, demonstration, and commercial application of battery technologies in on-road or nonroad vehicles. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to redefine the new advanced lean burn technology motor vehicle credit to suspend, until 2012 and later model vehicles, requirements that vehicles, to qualify for the credit, receive a certificate stating they meet or exceed certain weight and emission standards. Amends the Clean Air Act to: (1) define &quot;biodiesel&quot; and &quot;biodiesel blend&quot;; and (2) require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to promulgate regulations to establish standards for each biodiesel blend.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
