<bill session="110" type="h" number="1922" updated="2009-01-08T20:52:28-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1204656360" datetime="2008-03-04T14:46:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1176868800" datetime="2007-04-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Jupiter Inlet Lighthouse Outstanding Natural Area Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Jupiter Inlet Lighthouse Outstanding Natural Area Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Jupiter Inlet Lighthouse Outstanding Natural Area Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To designate the Jupiter Inlet Lighthouse and the surrounding Federal land in the State of Florida as an Outstanding Natural Area and as a unit of the National Landscape System, and for other purposes.</title>
		<title type="official" as="amended by house">To designate the Jupiter Inlet Lighthouse and the surrounding Federal land in the State of Florida as an Outstanding Natural Area and as a unit of the National Landscape Conservation System, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412197"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="2007-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412198" joined="2007-06-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1176868800" datetime="2007-04-18"><text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1176868800" datetime="2007-04-18"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1176868800" datetime="2007-04-18"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1176955200" datetime="2007-04-19"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text></action>
		<action date="1177387200" datetime="2007-04-24"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action date="1193112000" datetime="2007-10-23"><committee name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1202878800" datetime="2008-02-13"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1202878800" datetime="2008-02-13"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands Discharged.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1202878800" datetime="2008-02-13" ><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1204569480" datetime="2008-03-03T14:38:00-05:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-536, Part I.</text></action>
		<action date="1204569540" datetime="2008-03-03T14:39:00-05:00"><text>Committee on Transportation discharged.</text></action>
		<calendar number="327" date="1204569540" datetime="2008-03-03T14:39:00-05:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 327.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1204656180" datetime="2008-03-04T14:43:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Rahall moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1204656240" datetime="2008-03-04T14:44:00-05:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H1201-1203"/></action>
		<action date="1204656240" datetime="2008-03-04T14:44:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1922.</text></action>
		<vote date="1204656360" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-03-04T14:46:00-05:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H1201-1202"/></vote>
		<action date="1204656360" datetime="2008-03-04T14:46:00-05:00"><text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action date="1204693200" datetime="2008-03-05"><text>Received in the Senate.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="724" date="1209441600" datetime="2008-04-29" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 724.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>For Further Action See P.L. 110-229, Title II, Section 202 (S. 2739).</text></action>
		<action date="1213156800" datetime="2008-06-11"><text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S5530"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/4/2008--Passed House amended. Jupiter Inlet Lighthouse Outstanding Natural Area Act of 2008 - Establishes the Jupiter Inlet Lighthouse Outstanding Natural Area in Palm Beach County, Florida. Withdraws the federal lands and interests in such land included within the Outstanding Natural Area from: (1) all forms of entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws, and (3) operation of the mineral leasing and geothermal leasing laws and the mineral materials laws. Revokes certain Executive Orders and a certain public land order. Directs the Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with the Commandant of the Coast Guard, to: (1) develop a comprehensive management plan to provide long-term management guidance for the public land in the Outstanding Natural Area; and (2) ensure that the Outstanding Natural Area fulfills the purposes for which it is established. Requires the Secretary to: (1) manage the Outstanding Natural Area as part of the National Landscape Conservation System; and (2) in a manner that conserves, protects, and enhances the unique and nationally important historical, natural, cultural, scientific, educational, scenic, and recreational values of the Outstanding Natural Area, including an emphasis on the restoration of native ecological systems. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) enter into cooperative agreements with federal, state, county, other local government agencies, and other partners (including the Loxahatchee River Historical Society) for the long-term management of the Outstanding Natural Area; and (2) acquire for inclusion in the Outstanding Natural Area any state or private land or any interest in state or private land that is adjacent to the Outstanding Natural Area and identified in the management plan as appropriate for acquisition. Prohibits restrictions on specified law enforcement activities and ongoing and future Coast Guard operations in the Outstanding Natural Area. Authorizes appropriations. 
	</summary>
</bill>
