<bill session="110" type="h" number="1930" updated="2009-01-08T20:53:29-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1176868800" datetime="2007-04-18"/></status>

	<introduced date="1176868800" datetime="2007-04-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Securing Knowledge, Innovation, and Leadership Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">SKIL Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to increase competitiveness in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400368"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400367" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400060" joined="2007-05-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400660" joined="2007-04-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400113" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400658" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400206" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400068" joined="2007-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400131" joined="2008-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412216" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400655" joined="2007-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400315" joined="2007-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400654" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400141" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412011" joined="2007-05-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1176868800" datetime="2007-04-18"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1180929600" datetime="2007-06-04"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/18/2007--Introduced.<br/>Securing Knowledge, Innovation, and Leadership Act of 2007 or the SKIL Act of 2007 - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to exempt from the annual H-1B (specialty occupation) visa cap an alien who has: (1) earned a master's or higher degree from an accredited U.S. university; or (2) been awarded a medical specialty certification based on post-doctoral training and experience in the United States. Increases the annual H-1B cap, with a 20% increase for the following year if the previous year's quota is reached. Exempts from worldwide immigration caps an alien who: (1) has earned a master's or higher degree from an accredited U.S. university; (2) has been awarded medical specialty certification based on postdoctoral training and experience in the United States; (3) will work in shortage occupations; (4) has earned a master's degree or higher in science, technology, engineering, or math and has been working in a related field in the United States during the three-year period preceding his or her immigrant visa application; (5) has extraordinary ability or received a national interest waiver; or (6) is the spouse or minor child of an employment-based immigrant. Increases the annual immigrant visa cap. Revises student visa provisions. Authorizes an L-1 (intracompany transfer) visa extension beyond the fifth or seventh year if the individual has a immigrant application pending. Permits an alien with an approved labor certification to apply for permanent resident status adjustment if there is no visa immediately available by paying a $500 supplemental fee. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish a pre-certification procedure for employers who file multiple employment petitions. Revises certain labor certification provisions. Prohibits immigration application approval until background and security checks have been completed and any fraud allegations have been resolved. Authorizes temporary workers (E, H, I, L O, or P visas) who have not violated their status to renew their same category visa from within the United States.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
