<bill session="110" type="h" number="1939" updated="2009-01-08T20:54:37-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1176955200" datetime="2007-04-19"/></status>

	<introduced date="1176955200" datetime="2007-04-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Reading First Improvement Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to improve the Reading First program.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400267"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400070" joined="2007-04-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1176955200" datetime="2007-04-19"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1183953600" datetime="2007-07-09"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/19/2007--Introduced.<br/>Reading First Improvement Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to provide for the creation of a Reading First Advisory Committee, governed by the Federal Advisory Committee Act, to replace the peer review panel that reviews state grant applications under the Reading First program, designed to improve the reading skills of children in kindergarten through grade three. Prohibits the Committee from being composed of a majority of members selected by one individual or entity. Allows the Committee to form one or more subcommittees. Directs the Secretary of Education to: (1) establish a process to screen Committee or subcommittee members for potential conflicts of interest; and (2) develop guidance for how the Committee and any subcommittees will review applications, and provide feedback to states and the Secretary. Directs the Secretary to ensure that the independent organization tasked with evaluating the Reading First program does not hold a contract or subcontract to implement any aspect of the program and does not subcontract with an entity that has such a conflict. Authorizes the Secretary to contract with independent entities for the provision of Reading First technical assistance to states, local educational agencies, and schools; but requires such entities and their subcontractors to screen potential employees for conflicts of interest and clearly separate their provision of such technical assistance from their other activities. Directs the Secretary to provide guidance to Department of Education employees implementing the program on compliance with the prohibition against federal government usurpation of state or local control over school administration.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
