<bill session="110" type="h" number="1952" updated="2009-01-08T20:56:12-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1176955200" datetime="2007-04-19"/></status>

	<introduced date="1176955200" datetime="2007-04-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Health Information Incentive Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XI of the Social Security Act to achieve a national health information infrastructure, and to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to increase the deduction under section 179 for the purchase of qualified health care information technology by medical care providers.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400152"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400160" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400657" joined="2007-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400151" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400229" joined="2008-06-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400254" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400055" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2007-05-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400634" joined="2007-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400642" joined="2008-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400006" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400147" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400416" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="412199" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400234" joined="2007-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400645" joined="2007-05-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400628" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="412200" joined="2007-05-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1176955200" datetime="2007-04-19"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1176955200" datetime="2007-04-19"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1176955200" datetime="2007-04-19"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1177041600" datetime="2007-04-20"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1177473600" datetime="2007-04-25"><committee name="House Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/19/2007--Introduced.<br/>National Health Information Incentive Act of 2007 - Establishes within the Office of the Secretary of Health and Human Services an Office of the National Coordinator for Health Information Technology. Amends title XI of the Social Security Act to add a new part D (Building the National Health Information Infrastructure). Directs the Secretary to make additional Medicare payment incentives to assure that small medical care providers have the capability to move toward a national health care information infrastructure by acquiring electronic health record systems and other health information technologies. Provides for optional financial incentives to small health care providers and entities to implement such an infrastructure. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) make grants to small medical care providers for the purpose of assisting them to acquire and adopt patient registries, evidence-based clinical decision support tools at the point of care, electronic health records, secure e-mail, and other health information technologies defined by the Secretary as a key component of a national health care information infrastructure; and (2) make and guarantee loans to assist small medical care providers to acquire and adopt such things. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to treat qualified health care information technology as a depreciable asset for which a deduction from taxable income is allowable for the taxable year in which it is placed in service.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
