<bill session="110" type="h" number="1951" updated="2009-01-08T20:56:04-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1176955200" datetime="2007-04-19"/></status>

	<introduced date="1176955200" datetime="2007-04-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Legal Employee Verification Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a mandatory system for employers to verify the employment eligibility of potential employees, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412206"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400177" joined="2007-10-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="412225" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="412223" joined="2007-11-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1176955200" datetime="2007-04-19"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E803)</text></action>
		<action date="1176955200" datetime="2007-04-19"><text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Education and Labor, and Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1176955200" datetime="2007-04-19"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1176955200" datetime="2007-04-19"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1176955200" datetime="2007-04-19"><text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text></action>
		<action date="1177819200" datetime="2007-04-29"><committee name="House Homeland Security"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border, Maritime, and Global Counterterrorism.</text></action>
		<action date="1178251200" datetime="2007-05-04"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text></action>
		<action date="1183953600" datetime="2007-07-09"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/19/2007--Introduced.<br/>Legal Employee Verification Act - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to require visas issued by the Secretary of State and immigration related documents issued by the Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security to comply with authentication and biometric standards recognized by domestic and international standards organizations. Requires the Commissioner of Social Security to: (1) establish an Employment Eligibility Confirmation System to respond to inquiries made by employers regarding the identities and employment authorizations of their employees; (2) design, implement, and maintain an Employment Eligibility Database, including annual reverification; and (3) develop a plan to phase all workers into the Database and phase out the employer verification system established in specified existing provisions. Requires the Secretary of Homeland Security (currently, the Attorney General) to implement an integrated entry and exit data system. Requires a process under which an H-2B alien (temporary nonagricultural worker) who files a nonfrivolous complaint regarding a violation of this Act and is otherwise eligible to remain and work in the United States may be allowed to seek other employment in the United States for a period not to exceed the maximum period of stay for that nonimmigrant.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
