<bill session="110" type="h" number="1955" updated="2009-01-08T20:56:33-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1193169960" datetime="2007-10-23T17:06:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="993"/></status>

	<introduced date="1176955200" datetime="2007-04-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Homegrown Terrorism Prevention Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Violent Radicalization and Homegrown Terrorism Prevention Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Violent Radicalization and Homegrown Terrorism Prevention Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To prevent homegrown terrorism, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400166"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400073" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="412221" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400660" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="412234" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400246" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="412192" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400652" joined="2007-10-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400245" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400402" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400648" joined="2007-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400230" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400653" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400617" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400109" joined="2007-09-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1176955200" datetime="2007-04-19"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E803)</text></action>
		<action date="1176955200" datetime="2007-04-19"><text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1176955200" datetime="2007-04-19"><text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text></action>
		<action date="1176955200" datetime="2007-04-19"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1178510400" datetime="2007-05-07"><committee name="House Homeland Security"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Intelligence, Information Sharing, and Terrorism Risk Assessment.</text></action>
		<action date="1182744000" datetime="2007-06-25"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, the Internet, and Intellectual Property.</text></action>
		<action date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"><committee name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Intelligence, Information Sharing, and Terrorism Risk Assessment"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"><committee name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Intelligence, Information Sharing, and Terrorism Risk Assessment"/><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"><committee name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Intelligence, Information Sharing, and Terrorism Risk Assessment"/><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text></action>
		<action date="1185940800" datetime="2007-08-01"><committee name="House Homeland Security"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1185940800" datetime="2007-08-01" ><committee name="House Homeland Security"/><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1192568880" datetime="2007-10-16T18:08:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 110-384, Part I.</text></action>
		<action date="1192568940" datetime="2007-10-16T18:09:00-04:00"><text>Committee on Judiciary discharged.</text></action>
		<calendar number="239" date="1192568940" datetime="2007-10-16T18:09:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 239.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1193148300" datetime="2007-10-23T11:05:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Thompson (MS) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1193148300" datetime="2007-10-23T11:05:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H11854-11862"/></action>
		<action date="1193148300" datetime="2007-10-23T11:05:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1955.</text></action>
		<action date="1193150940" datetime="2007-10-23T11:49:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1193169420" datetime="2007-10-23T16:57:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H11899-11900"/></action>
		<vote date="1193169960" how="roll" roll="993" datetime="2007-10-23T17:06:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" suspension="1" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 404 - 6 (Roll no. 993).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H11854-11857"/></vote>
		<action date="1193198400" datetime="2007-10-24"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/23/2007--Passed House amended. Violent Radicalization and Homegrown Terrorism Prevention Act of 2007 - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to add a new section concerning the prevention of violent radicalization (an extremist belief system for facilitating ideologically based violence to advance political, religious, or social change) and homegrown terrorism (violence by a group or individual within the United States to coerce the U.S. government, the civilian population, or a segment thereof in furtherance of political or social objectives). Establishes within the legislative branch the National Commission on the Prevention of Violent Radicalization and Homegrown Terrorism to: (1) examine and report on facts and causes of violent radicalization, homegrown terrorism, and ideologically based violence in the United States; and (2) build upon, bring together, and avoid unnecessary duplication of related work done by other entities toward such goal. Requires: (1) interim reports and a final report from the Commission to the President and Congress on its findings and recommendations; (2) the public availability of such reports; and (3) Commission termination 30 days after its final report. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish or designate a university-based Center of Excellence for the Study of Violent Radicalization and Homegrown Terrorism in the United States to assist federal, state, local, and tribal homeland security officials, through training, education, and research, in preventing violent radicalization and homegrown terrorism in the United States. Requires the Secretary to: (1) conduct a survey of methodologies implemented by foreign nations to prevent violent radicalization and homegrown terrorism; and (2) report to Congress on lessons learned from survey results. Prohibits Department of Homeland Security (DHS) efforts to prevent ideologically based violence and homegrown terrorism from violating the constitutional and civil rights or civil liberties of U.S. citizens or lawful permanent residents. Directs the: (1) Secretary to ensure that activities and operations are in compliance with DHS's commitment to racial neutrality; and (2) DHS Civil Rights and Civil Liberties Officer to develop and implement an auditing system to ensure that compliance does not violate the constitutional and civil rights or civil liberties of any racial, ethnic, or religious group, and to include audit results in its annual report to Congress.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
