<bill session="110" type="h" number="1981" updated="2009-01-08T20:59:44-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1177041600" datetime="2007-04-20"/></status>

	<introduced date="1177041600" datetime="2007-04-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, to direct the Assistant Secretary of Homeland Security (Transportation Security Administration) to issue regulations establishing security standards for foreign repair stations performing maintenance for aircraft used to provide air transportation.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400230"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400198" joined="2007-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400392" joined="2007-12-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400402" joined="2007-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400653" joined="2007-07-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400645" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="412228" joined="2007-07-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1177041600" datetime="2007-04-20"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text></action>
		<action date="1177300800" datetime="2007-04-23"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation Security and Infrastructure Protection.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/20/2007--Introduced.<br/>Requires the Assistant Secretary of Homeland Security (Transportation Safety Administration) to issue regulations ensuring that federal aircraft security standards apply to all foreign aircraft maintenance employees (including requiring a criminal history record check and a review of law enforcement databases), as well as all foreign aircraft repair stations. Requires the Assistant Secretary, if the regulations are not issued by 60 days after enactment of this Act, to prohibit the use of foreign repair stations, except in an emergency. Reduces from 18 months to 9 months after enactment of this Act the deadline for a security review and audit of foreign repair stations.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
