<bill session="110" type="h" number="1993" updated="2009-01-08T21:01:13-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1177300800" datetime="2007-04-23"/></status>

	<introduced date="1177300800" datetime="2007-04-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Counterterrorism Financing Coordination Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the delivery of counterterrorism financing training and technical assistance by providing for greater interagency coordination and cooperation, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400661"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="2007-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400363" joined="2007-04-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1177300800" datetime="2007-04-23"><text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1177300800" datetime="2007-04-23"><text>Referred to House Financial Services</text></action>
		<action date="1177300800" datetime="2007-04-23"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/23/2007--Introduced.<br/>Counter Terrorism Financing Coordination Act - Directs The Secretary of State and the Secretary of the Treasury to negotiate and enter into a Memorandum of Agreement specifying each Department's role in providing foreign counterterrorism financing training and technical assistance. Requires such Agreement to include provisions respecting: (1) leadership and role designations; (2) dispute resolution methodology; (3) funding and resource coordination; (4) private contractor determinations; and (5) performance evaluation criteria. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to include in the annual congressional report on terrorist assets information on the nature and extent of activities to block the financial asset access of owners or account holders with terrorism connections. 
	</summary>
</bill>
