<bill session="110" type="h" number="2012" updated="2009-01-08T21:03:28-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1177387200" datetime="2007-04-24"/></status>

	<introduced date="1177387200" datetime="2007-04-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Contact Lens Consumer Health Protection Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Fairness to Contact Lens Consumers Act to require contact lens sellers to provide a toll-free telephone number and a dedicated email address for the purpose of receiving communications from prescribers.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400345"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400627" joined="2007-09-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400222" joined="2007-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="412234" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400129" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400344" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400165" joined="2007-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400040" joined="2007-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400241" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400254" joined="2007-12-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400658" joined="2007-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400010" joined="2007-11-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400007" joined="2007-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400645" joined="2008-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400281" joined="2008-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="412201" joined="2008-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2007-10-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400431" joined="2007-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400321" joined="2007-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="412202" joined="2008-04-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1177387200" datetime="2007-04-24"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1177473600" datetime="2007-04-25"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/24/2007--Introduced.<br/>Contact Lens Consumer Health Protection Act - Amends the Fairness to Contact Lens Consumers Act to require the seller to provide the prescriber with a toll-free telephone number and email address for questions relating to a contact lens prescription verification request. Revises the verification event in which a prescription is verified if the prescriber fails to communicate with the seller within eight business hours, or a similar time as defined by the Federal Trade Commission (FTC), after receiving required patient and prescription information from the seller to provide that, if a prescriber communicates a question or concern to a seller through such toll-free telephone service or dedicated email address before such eight-hour period has ended, the seller must obtain affirmative confirmation of the accuracy of the prescription from the prescriber before the prescription is considered verified. Authorizes a prescriber to make a written request to a seller that all contact lens prescription verification requests be communicated by a preferred method of communication, including telephone, facsimile, or email. Prohibits any seller of contact lenses from overfilling a prescription. Authorizes fines for violations of this Act in amount up to $100,000 per violation.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
