<bill session="110" type="h" number="2048" updated="2009-01-08T21:08:25-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1177560000" datetime="2007-04-26"/></status>

	<introduced date="1177560000" datetime="2007-04-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Traumatic Brain Injury Access to Options Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To facilitate the provision of care and services for members of the Armed Forces for traumatic brain injury, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412205"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400414" joined="2007-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400177" joined="2007-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="412225" joined="2007-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400333" joined="2008-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="412208" joined="2007-09-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400631" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="412206" joined="2007-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400321" joined="2007-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400309" joined="2007-04-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1177560000" datetime="2007-04-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
		<action date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/26/2007--Introduced.<br/>Traumatic Brain Injury Access to Options Act - Directs the Secretary of Defense to ensure that each member of the Armed Forces who incurs a traumatic brain injury (where the member is unable to perform activities of daily living for at least five consecutive days from the date of a medical assessment) while on active duty shall be retained on active duty for one year after the date of the assessment. Prohibits such member from being evaluated during the one-year period by a physical evaluation board for determining eligibility for retirement or separation due to such disability. Allows a member (or his or her guardian or legal advocate) to choose to make such requirements inapplicable to the member. Authorizes the Secretary of the military department concerned to extend the one-year period as appropriate in light of medical progress. Requires annual Comptroller General assessments of traumatic brain injury care and services provided by the Departments of Defense and Veterans Affairs.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
