<bill session="110" type="h" number="2058" updated="2009-01-08T21:09:39-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1177560000" datetime="2007-04-26"/></status>

	<introduced date="1177560000" datetime="2007-04-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To include costs incurred by the Indian Health Service, a federally qualified health center, an AIDS drug assistance program, certain hospitals, or a pharmaceutical manufacturer patient assistance program in providing prescription drugs toward the annual out of pocket threshold under part D of title XVIII of the Social Security Act and to provide a safe harbor for assistance provided under a pharmaceutical manufacturer patient assistance program.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400184"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400142" joined="2007-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400080" joined="2007-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400295" joined="2007-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2007-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400268" joined="2007-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400132" joined="2007-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400402" joined="2008-06-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400048" joined="2007-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="412199" joined="2007-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2007-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="412200" joined="2007-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2007-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="2007-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400090" joined="2007-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400042" joined="2007-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="2007-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400024" joined="2008-07-30"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1177560000" datetime="2007-04-26"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1177560000" datetime="2007-04-26"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1177560000" datetime="2007-04-26"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1177905600" datetime="2007-04-30"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1178078400" datetime="2007-05-02"><committee name="House Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/26/2007--Introduced.<br/>Helping Fill the Medicare Rx Gap Act of 2007 - Amends part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA), with respect to the annual out of pocket threshold, to count costs incurred in providing prescription drugs by the Indian Health Service, a federally-qualified health center, an AIDS drug assistance program, certain hospitals, or a pharmaceutical manufacturer patient assistance program.<br/>Amends SSA title XI, with respect to criminal penalties for certain illegal remunerations, to exclude from prohibited remunerations (provide safe harbor for) any remuneration paid by a pharmaceutical manufacturer patient assistance program, either in cash or through the distribution or donation of covered Part D drugs, to an individual enrolled in a Part D plan or a Medicare Advantage Prescription Drug (MA-PD) plan under SSA title XVIII part C.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
