<bill session="110" type="h" number="206" updated="2009-01-08T17:09:20-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/></status>

	<introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Anti-hunger Empowerment Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Beyond the Soup Kitchen Grants Program Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Food Stamp Act of 1977 to provide greater access to the food stamp program by reducing duplicative and burdensome administrative requirements, authorize the Secretary of Agriculture to award grants to certain community-based nonprofit feeding and anti-hunger groups for the purpose of establishing and implementing a Beyond the Soup Kitchen Pilot Program for certain socially and economically disadvantaged populations, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400366"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400087" joined="2007-01-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400426" joined="2007-01-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400251" joined="2007-01-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text></action>
		<action date="1170738000" datetime="2007-02-06"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/4/2007--Introduced.<br/>Anti-hunger Empowerment Act of 2007 - Amends the Food Stamp Act of 1977 to replace current food stamp program (program) administrative cost provisions with provisions authorizing 75% reimbursement for specified state activities to increase program access. States that fingerprinting shall not be required for program participation. Beyond the Soup Kitchen Grants Program Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to establish a Beyond the Soup Kitchen pilot program to provide grants: (1) to a primary community-based nonprofit feeding and anti-hunger group in each designated pilot community which shall allocate subgrants to other nonprofit feeding and anti-hunger groups in such community; and (2) for technical assistance grants. Sets forth program provisions.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
