<bill session="110" type="h" number="2093" updated="2009-01-08T21:14:10-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1177992000" datetime="2007-05-01"/></status>

	<introduced date="1177992000" datetime="2007-05-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 to provide for additional reporting by lobbying firms.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400269"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="2007-05-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1177992000" datetime="2007-05-01"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/1/2007--Introduced.<br/>Amends the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (LDA) to revise the definition of &quot;lobbying activities&quot; (for purposes of a lobbying firm only) to include paid communications campaigns to influence the general public to lobby Congress. Redefines &quot;lobbying firm&quot; to include a person or entity retained by one or more clients (other than that person or entity) to engage in paid communications campaigns to influence the general public to lobby Congress, and receives income of, or spends or agrees to spend, an aggregate of $100,000 or more for such efforts in any quarterly period. Defines &quot;paid communications campaigns to influence the general public to lobby Congress&quot; as efforts by a lobbying firm, on behalf of a client, to influence the general public or its segments to contact one or more covered legislative or executive branch officials (or Congress generally) to urge them to take specific action regarding a specific matter. Excludes from the meaning of such communications: (1) any made to the members of the client; or (2) direct mail communications to the general public or its segments made primarily to recruit members to join an organization. Sets forth LDA registration and reporting requirements of such lobbying firms. 
	</summary>
</bill>
