<bill session="110" type="h" number="2097" updated="2009-01-08T21:14:42-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1177992000" datetime="2007-05-01"/></status>

	<introduced date="1177992000" datetime="2007-05-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Teen Pregnancy Prevention, Responsibility, and Opportunity Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize grants to carry out projects to provide education on preventing teen pregnancies, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400346"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2007-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400001" joined="2007-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="2007-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="412186" joined="2007-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="2007-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="2007-09-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1177992000" datetime="2007-05-01"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1177992000" datetime="2007-05-01"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1177992000" datetime="2007-05-01"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1177992000" datetime="2007-05-01"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1183953600" datetime="2007-07-09"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Healthy Families and Communities.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/1/2007--Introduced.<br/>Teen Pregnancy Prevention, Responsibility, and Opportunity Act of 2007 - Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to local educational agencies, state and local public health agencies, and nonprofit private entities for projects to provide education on preventing teen pregnancies. Gives priority to communities with significantly above averages rates of teen pregnancy. Requires the Secretary to establish criteria to evaluate such projects. Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to increase authorized appropriations for community learning centers. Authorizes appropriations for physical education programs. Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to reauthorize appropriations for TRIO and GEARUP programs. Authorizes the Secretary to make matching grants to public or nonprofit private entities for demonstrating innovative approaches to prevent teen pregnancies.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
