<bill session="110" type="h" number="2100" updated="2009-01-08T21:15:03-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1177992000" datetime="2007-05-01"/></status>

	<introduced date="1177992000" datetime="2007-05-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Equal Opportunity Protection and Civil Rights Restoration Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for equal protection of the law and to prohibit discrimination and preferential treatment on the basis of race, color, national origin, or sex in Federal actions, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400394"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1177992000" datetime="2007-05-01"><text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, Education and Labor, and House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1177992000" datetime="2007-05-01"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1177992000" datetime="2007-05-01"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1177992000" datetime="2007-05-01"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1177992000" datetime="2007-05-01"><text>Referred to House House Administration</text></action>
		<action date="1180929600" datetime="2007-06-04"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text></action>
		<action date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/1/2007--Introduced.<br/>Equal Opportunity Protection and Civil Rights Restoration Act of 2007 - Prohibits discrimination or preferences in federal employment and contracting and other federal programs and activities on the basis of race, color, national origin, or sex. Prohibits requiring or encouraging any federal contractor or subcontractor to so discriminate or grant a preference. Prohibits states and private entities that receive federal financial assistance from so discriminating or granting a preference in connection with any contract or subcontract, employment, or admission to any educational institution. Prohibits construing this Act to prohibit or limit: (1) any act designed to benefit historically Black colleges or universities; or (2) any action under a federal law or treaty relating to the Indian tribes. Declares that this Act does not prohibit or limit employment classifications based on sex if sex is a bona fide occupational qualification reasonably necessary to normal operation or the classification is applied regarding an armed forces member. Allows any aggrieved person to obtain, in a civil action, appropriate relief (including back pay) from the violator, including from a government entity. Requires awarding a prevailing plaintiff attorney's fees as part of the costs.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
