<bill session="110" type="h" number="2109" updated="2009-01-08T21:16:13-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1178078400" datetime="2007-05-02"/></status>

	<introduced date="1178078400" datetime="2007-05-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Empowering Our Local Communities Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, to provide Federal penalties for certain killings by illegal aliens, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400658"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400060" joined="2007-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400099" joined="2007-09-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2007-06-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="409888" joined="2007-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400652" joined="2007-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412250" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400288" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400277" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412235" joined="2007-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400570" joined="2007-10-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400153" joined="2007-09-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400644" joined="2007-09-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1178078400" datetime="2007-05-02"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1180929600" datetime="2007-06-04"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text></action>
		<action date="1180929600" datetime="2007-06-04"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/2/2007--Introduced.<br/>Empowering Our Local Communities Act of 2007 - Amends the federal criminal code to impose a minimum mandatory prison term of five years and a maximum term of 40 years on any illegal alien who commits manslaughter while operating a motor vehicle under the influence of alcohol. Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to impose criminal penalties on individuals present in the United States in violation of immigration laws. Requires the Department of Homeland Security to continue to operate and implement the Institutional Removal Program for the identification and removal from the United States of criminal aliens. Requires such program to be extended to all states. Authorizes states to detain criminal aliens after the completion of their prison sentences to effectuate their transfer to federal custody.<br/>Authorizes appropriations for the training of state and local government officers or employees to perform certain functions of a federal immigration officer.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
