<bill session="110" type="h" number="2111" updated="2009-01-08T21:16:27-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1178078400" datetime="2007-05-02"/></status>

	<introduced date="1178078400" datetime="2007-05-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Foreign Language Education Partnership Program Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to establish a partnership program in foreign languages.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400184"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400123" joined="2007-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400337" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400257" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400080" joined="2007-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412221" joined="2007-06-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400282" joined="2007-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="412224" joined="2007-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400430" joined="2007-07-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400129" joined="2007-05-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="2007-05-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400124" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400003" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400423" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400437" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2007-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412198" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400235" joined="2007-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400663" joined="2007-05-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400048" joined="2007-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400442" joined="2007-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400346" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412204" joined="2007-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400125" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="412186" joined="2007-05-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2007-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2007-05-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="2007-05-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400011" joined="2007-05-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400179" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400067" joined="2007-06-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1178078400" datetime="2007-05-02"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/2/2007--Introduced.<br/>Foreign Language Education Partnership Program Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to replace the program providing incentive payments to public elementary schools for foreign language instruction with a partnership program in foreign languages that provides matching incentive payments to partnerships composed of state or local educational agencies and institutions of higher education. Requires such partnerships to establish, improve, or expand model programs of foreign language learning from kindergarten through grade 12 that increase the number of high school graduates who attain advanced proficiency in at least one foreign language. Requires each model program to have a dimension allowing the student to gain an understanding of the historic, geographic, cultural, economic, and other contextual factors of countries whose people speak the language studied. Conditions a partnership's continued funding, for an initial four-year period and two additional five-year periods, on its demonstrating its program effectiveness based on nationally recognized standardized foreign language assessments. Directs the Secretary to collect annually and analyze data on such programs and disseminate aggregated program data nationally, as well as information on successful programs and practices.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
