<bill session="110" type="h" number="2132" updated="2009-01-08T21:18:57-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"/></status>

	<introduced date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Health Plans Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to establish a small business health benefits program.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400007"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400160" joined="2007-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412208" joined="2008-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400103" joined="2007-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400259" joined="2007-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400013" joined="2007-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400111" joined="2007-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2007-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400120" joined="2007-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400638" joined="2007-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400326" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412220" joined="2008-09-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400024" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400345" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400062" joined="2007-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400425" joined="2007-05-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/3/2007--Introduced.<br/>Small Business Health Plans Act of 2007 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a small business health benefits program (SBHBP) under which small employers may offer health insurance coverage to employees and their dependents. Outlines program elements and coverage requirements, including that small employers are provided access to qualified health pooling arrangements under which their employees may elect coverage substantially similar to the federal employees benefit program (FEHB) coverage. Requires the Secretary to: (1) establish a program of premium assistance for small employers under SBHBP that provides a sliding scale of assistance based on the number of employees, the average wage level of such employees, and the employer profit margin; (2) provide for reinsurance coverage for an individual's claims that exceed a specified amount for a year; and (3) provide grants to states for the establishment, initial administration, and operations of qualified health pooling arrangements. Directs the Secretary and the Secretary of Labor to provide for a national health pooling arrangement for eligible small employers modeled after FEHB.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
