<bill session="110" type="h" number="2139" updated="2009-01-08T21:19:49-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1182796260" datetime="2007-06-25T15:31:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">FHA Manufactured Housing Loan Modernization Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">FHA Manufactured Housing Loan Modernization Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">FHA Manufactured Housing Loan Modernization Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To modernize the manufactured housing loan insurance program under title I of the National Housing Act.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412205"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400661" joined="2007-06-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400222" joined="2007-06-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400209" joined="2007-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400282" joined="2007-06-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400385" joined="2007-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400096" joined="2007-06-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400313" joined="2007-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400633" joined="2007-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2007-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400406" joined="2007-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400225" joined="2007-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400331" joined="2007-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412227" joined="2007-06-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400442" joined="2007-06-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400044" joined="2007-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400057" joined="2007-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400131" joined="2007-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="2007-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400644" joined="2007-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400125" joined="2007-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="412186" joined="2007-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400371" joined="2007-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400042" joined="2007-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400150" joined="2007-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400363" joined="2007-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412206" joined="2007-06-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400639" joined="2007-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400067" joined="2007-05-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text></action>
		<action date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1182470820" datetime="2007-06-21T21:07:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 110-206.</text></action>
		<calendar number="125" date="1182470820" datetime="2007-06-21T21:07:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 125.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1182795660" datetime="2007-06-25T15:21:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Donnelly moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1182795660" datetime="2007-06-25T15:21:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H7025-7027"/></action>
		<action date="1182795660" datetime="2007-06-25T15:21:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2139.</text></action>
		<vote date="1182796260" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-06-25T15:31:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H7025-7026"/></vote>
		<action date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/25/2007--Passed House amended. (This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on June 21, 2007. The summary of that version is repeated here.) FHA Manufactured Housing Loan Modernization Act of 2007 - Amends the National Housing Act with respect to Federal Housing Administration (FHA) housing loan insurance for manufactured homes (or lots for such homes). (Sec. 3) Exempts such loans from certain financial institution portfolio limits, increasing an allowable claim for loss from 10% to 90% of an institution's total amount of such loans, credit advances, and purchases. (Sec. 4) Makes any new contract of insurance for such loans, credit advances, or purchases conclusive evidence of an institution's insurance eligibility. (Thus requires each loan to be insured individually instead of as part of a bundle of such loans.) (Sec. 5) Increases loan limits, requiring annual indexing. (Sec. 6) Prescribes requirements for payment by a borrower of premium charges for credit insurance, including an up-front premium of up to 2.25% and an annual premium of up to 1%. (Sec. 7) Revises requirements for the handling and disposal of any real or personal conveyed to or acquired by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD), and the pursuit of all claims against mortgagors assigned to the Secretary by mortgagees. (Sec. 8) Directs the Secretary of HUD to: (1) establish underwriting criteria for loans and credit in connection with a manufactured home, or a lot for one, that will ensure the manufactured housing program's financial soundness; and (2) revise within six months existing criteria to accord with those established under this Act. (Sec. 9) Prohibits any grant of credit insurance to a financial institution unless the borrower to which a housing renovation or modernization loan or advance of credit was made, and each member of the borrower's family age 18 years or older, including the borrower's spouse, has a valid Social Security number. (Sec. 10) Directs the Comptroller General to assess, and report to Congress on, how the Secretary of HUD utilizes the FHA manufactured housing loan insurance program, the community development block grant program, and other programs and resources to mitigate the risks to manufactured housing residents and communities resulting from tornados.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
