<bill session="110" type="h" number="2149" updated="2009-01-08T21:20:59-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"/></status>

	<introduced date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Healthcare Eligibility for Late Participants (HELP) in Medicare Part D Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to waive the late enrollment penalty under the Medicare part D benefit for certain months for individuals who are first eligible to enroll for such benefit for 2006 or 2007 and who enroll by the end of the first annual, coordinated election period following their initial enrollment period, to limit the amount of such penalty, and to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to conduct a study on such penalty.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400123"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400662" joined="2007-06-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2007-05-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400006" joined="2007-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2007-05-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1179201600" datetime="2007-05-15"><committee name="House Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/3/2007--Introduced.<br/>Healthcare Eligibility for Late Participants (HELP) in Medicare Part D Act of 2007 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to waive the late enrollment penalty under Medicare part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program) for certain months for individuals who: (1) are first eligible to enroll for such benefit for 2006 or 2007; and (2) enroll by the end of the first annual, coordinated election period following their initial enrollment period. Limits the amount of such penalty for any eligible individual for a continuous period of eligibility to 25% of the base beneficiary premium. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to report to Congress on the Medicare prescription drug late enrollment penalty.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
