<bill session="110" type="h" number="2141" updated="2009-01-08T21:20:03-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"/></status>

	<introduced date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Small Community Options for Regulatory Equity Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To allow small public water systems to request an exemption from the requirements of any national primary drinking water regulation for a naturally occurring contaminant, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400655"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400134" joined="2007-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400376" joined="2007-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412217" joined="2008-01-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400247" joined="2007-05-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/3/2007--Introduced.<br/>Small Community Options for Regulatory Equity Act of 2007 - Amends the Safe Drinking Water Act to require states exercising primary enforcement responsibility for public water systems to exempt any nonprofit small public water system (serving 10,000 or fewer persons) that so requests in accordance with this Act from the requirements of any national primary drinking water regulation for naturally occurring contaminants, including arsenic, radon, radium, uranium, and specified disinfection byproducts. Requires exemption requests to include a finding that the system's compliance with applicable national primary drinking water regulations is not economically feasible. Precludes judicial or administrative review of such findings.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
