<bill session="110" type="h" number="2156" updated="2009-01-08T21:21:47-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"/></status>

	<introduced date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require a clear accounting of the combat proficiency of the security forces of Iraq.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400195"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400031" joined="2007-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400282" joined="2007-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412234" joined="2007-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412192" joined="2007-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400352" joined="2007-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412239" joined="2007-10-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412220" joined="2007-05-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/3/2007--Introduced.<br/>Declares that it shall be U.S. policy to ensure that: (1) the security forces of Iraq are trained to achieve the highest level of combat efficiency in order to provide for the security and stability of the Iraqi people; (2) as each battalion of the Iraqi security forces achieves a level of combat proficiency such that it can conduct independent combat operations without Coalition support a comparable U.S. Armed Forces unit will be redeployed from Iraq; and (3) regular, accurate accounts of the combat proficiency of battalions of the Iraqi security forces are necessary for the American public to gauge Iraqi security force development. Directs the President to transmit to the appropriate congressional committees a monthly report respecting the number of Iraqi security force battalions at specified combat proficiency levels.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
