<bill session="110" type="h" number="2175" updated="2009-01-08T21:24:02-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"/></status>

	<introduced date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Interstate Horseracing Act of 1978 to require, as a condition to the consent for off-track wagering, that horsemen's groups and host racing commissions offer insurance coverage for professional jockeys and other horseracing personnel, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400391"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400431" joined="2007-05-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/3/2007--Introduced.<br/>Jockeys' Insurance Fairness Act - Amends the Interstate Horseracing Act of 1978 to add as conditions for the acceptance of interstate off-track wagers by an off-track betting system that: (1) a consenting host racing associations’s agreement with the horseman’s group must provide that such group shall pay not less than 50% of the amount it receives to the host racing commission for the purpose of offering insurance coverage for professional jockeys, exercise riders, and backside personnel and trainers (except where such persons are included in a state worker’s compensation program); and (2) the consenting host racing commission must agree to offer such insurance. Defines &quot;insurance coverage&quot; to mean health and injury insurance for jockeys, exercise riders, and backside personnel and trainers who are employed or under contract for training or horse racing in the state of the host racing association and who may be injured in the performance of their official duties. Allows a jockey, exercise rider, or trainer or other backside personnel to bring a civil action for a violation of this Act.<br/>Prohibits a person from entering a horse in any race that is the subject of an interstate off-track wager if such horse has been given anabolic steroids. Requires the appropriate host racing commission to develop procedures for and administer testing for anabolic steroids.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
