<bill session="110" type="h" number="2176" updated="2009-01-08T21:24:09-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1214421240" datetime="2008-06-25T16:14:00-04:00" where="h" result="fail" how="roll" roll="458"/></status>

	<introduced date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for and approve the settlement of certain land claims of the Bay Mills Indian Community.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400391"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400276" joined="2007-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400215" joined="2007-10-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1202274000" datetime="2008-02-06"><text>Committee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1202878800" datetime="2008-02-13"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1202878800" datetime="2008-02-13" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 21 - 5.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1204825800" datetime="2008-03-06T13:50:00-05:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-541, Part I.</text></action>
		<action date="1204779600" datetime="2008-03-06"><text>Referred sequentially to the House Committee on the Judiciary for a period ending not later than April 4, 2008 for consideration of such provisions of the bill and amendment as fall within the jurisdiction of that committee pursuant to clause 1(k) of rule X.</text></action>
		<action date="1205467200" datetime="2008-03-14"><text>Committee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1207108800" datetime="2008-04-02"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1207108800" datetime="2008-04-02" ><text>Ordered to be Reported Unfavorably by the Yeas and Nays: 29 - 0.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1207364940" datetime="2008-04-04T12:09:00-04:00"><text>Reported adversely by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 110-541, Part II.</text></action>
		<calendar number="345" date="1207365000" datetime="2008-04-04T12:10:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 345.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1214340180" datetime="2008-06-24T17:43:00-04:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1298 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2176. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. In lieu of the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Natural Resources now printed in the bill, the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in this report shall be considered as adopted.</text></action>
		<action date="1214452320" datetime="2008-06-25T12:52:00-04:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 1298 passed House.</text></action>
		<action date="1214414280" datetime="2008-06-25T14:18:00-04:00"><text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 1298.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H6045-6058"/><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR H6045"/></action>
		<action date="1214414280" datetime="2008-06-25T14:18:00-04:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2176. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. In lieu of the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Natural Resources now printed in the bill, the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in this report shall be considered as adopted.</text></action>
		<action date="1214414400" datetime="2008-06-25T14:20:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 2176.</text></action>
		<action date="1214418660" datetime="2008-06-25T15:31:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H6055"/></action>
		<action date="1214418720" datetime="2008-06-25T15:32:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Hensarling moved to recommit with instructions to Natural Resources.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H6055-6056"/><reference label="text" ref="CR H6056"/></action>
		<action date="1214418780" datetime="2008-06-25T15:33:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hensarling motion to recommit with instructions, pending reservation of a point of order. The instruction contained in the motion seek to report the same back to the House with an amendment to repeal alternative fuel procurement requirement for federal agencies.</text></action>
		<action date="1214419140" datetime="2008-06-25T15:39:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Rahall raised a point of order against the motion to recommit with instructions. Mr. Rahall stated that the provisions contained in the motion to recommit were not germane to the bill. Sustained by the Chair.</text></action>
		<action date="1214419140" datetime="2008-06-25T15:39:00-04:00"><text>Point of order sustained against the motion to recommit with instructions.</text></action>
		<action date="1214419260" datetime="2008-06-25T15:41:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Hensarling appealed the ruling of the chair. The question was then put on sustaining the ruling of the chair.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H6056"/></action>
		<action date="1214419260" datetime="2008-06-25T15:41:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Rahall moved to table the motion to appeal the ruling of the chair</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H6056-6057"/></action>
		<action date="1214420700" datetime="2008-06-25T16:05:00-04:00"><text>On motion to table the motion to appeal the ruling of the chair Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 226 - 189 (Roll no. 457).</text></action>
		<vote date="1214421240" how="roll" roll="458" datetime="2008-06-25T16:14:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="fail" ><text>On passage Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 121 - 298 (Roll no. 458).</text></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/4/2008--Reported to House without amendment, Part II. (This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on March 6, 2008. The summary of that version is repeated here.)<br/>Requires the Secretary of the Interior to take lands identified as alternative lands in the Settlement of Land Claim (the agreement between the Bay Mills Indian Community and the Governor of Michigan executed on August 23, 2002, including the document titled Addendum to Settlement of Land Claim, executed on November 13, 2007) into trust for the benefit of the Community within 30 days after the Secretary has: (1) received a title insurance policy for the alternative lands that shows that such lands are not subject to mortgages, liens, deeds of trust, options to purchase, or other security interests; and (2) confirmed that the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 has been complied with regarding the trust acquisition of the property.<br/>Provides for the alternative lands to become part of the Community's reservation immediately upon attaining trust status. Requires the alternative lands to be taken into trust as part of the settlement and extinguishment of the Community's Charlotte Beach land claims and to be deemed lands obtained in settlement of a land claim within the meaning of the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act.<br/>Extinguishes, concurrent with the Secretary taking the alternative lands into trust, all claims by the Community: (1) to the Charlotte Beach lands; or (2) against the United States, the State of Michigan, or any other person or entity based on or relating to claims to such lands, whether based on aboriginal or recognized title. Approves and ratifies the Settlement of Land Claim, which shall be enforceable by the Community or the Governorn according to its terms. Vests exclusive jurisdiction over any enforcement action in the U.S. District Court for the Western District of Michigan.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
