<bill session="110" type="h" number="2182" updated="2009-01-08T21:24:50-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"/></status>

	<introduced date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">For the relief of Elvira Arellano, Juan Carlos Arreguin, Martin Guerrero Barrios, Maria I. Benitez, Francisco J. Castro, Jaime Cruz,Martha Davalos, Herminion Davalos, Disifredo Adan Delvalle, Angel Espinoza, Veronica Lopez, Francisca Lino, Maria A. Martin, Juan Jose Mesa, Maria Natividad Loza,Blanca E. Nolte,Domenico Papaianni, Romina Perea, Juan Jose Rangel Sr., Dayron S. Rios Arenas, Araceli Contreras-Del Toro, Doris Oneida Ulloa, Bladimir I. Caballero, Arnulfo Alfaro, Consuelo and Juan Manuel Castellanos, Eliseo Pulido, Gilberto Romero, Maria Liliana Rua-Saenz, Aurelia and Tomas F. Martinez-Garcia, Flor Crisostomo; Fatuma Karuma, Stanislaw Rychtarczyk, Slobodan Radanovich, and Agustin Sanchez-Dominguez.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400350"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1178251200" datetime="2007-05-04"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E953)</text></action>
		<action date="1181534400" datetime="2007-06-11"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/3/2007--Introduced.<br/>Provides for the relief of Elvira Arellano, Juan Carlos Arreguin, Martin Guerrero Barrios, Maria I. Benitez, Francisco J. Castro, Jaime Cruz,Martha Davalos, Herminion Davalos, Disifredo Adan Delvalle, Angel Espinoza, Veronica Lopez, Francisca Lino, Maria A. Martin, Juan Jose Mesa, Maria Natividad Loza,Blanca E. Nolte,Domenico Papaianni, Romina Perea, Juan Jose Rangel Sr., Dayron S. Rios Arenas, Araceli Contreras-Del Toro, Doris Oneida Ulloa, Bladimir I. Caballero, Arnulfo Alfaro, Consuelo and Juan Manuel Castellanos, Eliseo Pulido, Gilberto Romero, Maria Liliana Rua-Saenz, Aurelia and Tomas F. Martinez-Garcia, Flor Crisostomo; Fatuma Karuma, Stanislaw Rychtarczyk, Slobodan Radanovich, and Agustin Sanchez-Dominguez.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
