<bill session="110" type="h" number="2184" updated="2009-01-08T21:25:06-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1178510400" datetime="2007-05-07"/></status>

	<introduced date="1178510400" datetime="2007-05-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003 to expand comparative effectiveness research and to increase funding for such research to improve the value of health care.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400007"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400386" joined="2008-09-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400121" joined="2007-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400026" joined="2007-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400215" joined="2007-09-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400425" joined="2007-07-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1178510400" datetime="2007-05-07"><text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1178510400" datetime="2007-05-07"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1178510400" datetime="2007-05-07"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1178510400" datetime="2007-05-07"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1179201600" datetime="2007-05-15"><committee name="House Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/7/2007--Introduced.<br/>Enhanced Health Care Value for All Act of 2007 - Amends the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003 to expand the scope of research on the comparative effectiveness of health care items and services. Renames as the Comparative Effectiveness Advisory Board the stakeholders group the Secretary of Health and Human Services is required to consult in developing research priorities. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to establish in the Treasury the Health Care Comparative Effectiveness Research Trust Fund. Makes appropriations. Imposes on health insurance policy issuers (including self-insured health plans) a fee for each specified policy for each policy year, whose equivalent amounts shall be transferred into the Fund. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a permanent council to assist the offices and agencies of the Departments of Health and Human Services, of Veterans Affairs, and of Defense, and any other department or agency, to coordinate the conduct or support of health services research.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
