<bill session="110" type="h" number="2193" updated="2009-01-08T21:26:15-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1178510400" datetime="2007-05-07"/></status>

	<introduced date="1178510400" datetime="2007-05-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Animal Protection Accountability Improvement Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Animal Welfare Act to increase the penalties for violations of such Act, to prohibit the use of animals for marketing medical devices, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400195"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400222" joined="2007-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400227" joined="2007-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400430" joined="2007-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400003" joined="2007-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="2007-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412232" joined="2008-06-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2008-02-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1178510400" datetime="2007-05-07"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text></action>
		<action date="1180584000" datetime="2007-05-31"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/7/2007--Introduced.<br/>Animal Protection Accountability Improvement Act - Amends the Animal Welfare Act to prohibit a person from using a live animal to: (1) demonstrate a medical device or product to a sales representative, or in a workshop or training session, for marketing purposes; (2) train a sales representative to use a medical device or product; or (3) create a multimedia recording for the purpose of marketing a medical device or product. Exempts from this requirement the training of medical personnel for a purpose other than marketing a medical device or product.<br/>Increases the cap on the fine for violations of humane standards and record keeping requirements at auction sales from $2,500 to $10,000 for each violation. Provides that each animal that is the subject of a violation shall be a separate offense.<br/>Requires the Secretary of Agriculture to include in a report to Congress an identification of all research facilities, intermediate handlers, carriers, and exhibitors registered under such Act.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
