<bill session="110" type="h" number="2199" updated="2009-01-08T21:26:58-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1179956640" datetime="2007-05-23T18:44:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="413"/></status>

	<introduced date="1178596800" datetime="2007-05-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Traumatic Brain Injury Health Enhancement and Long-Term Support Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Traumatic Brain Injury Health Enhancement and Long-Term Support Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide certain improvements in the treatment of individuals with traumatic brain injuries, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400274"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400279" joined="2007-05-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400420" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400122" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400635" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400385" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="412192" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="412210" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400323" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="412231" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412214" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="412250" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400184" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400285" joined="2007-05-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="412208" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400007" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400386" joined="2007-05-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400048" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412205" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400399" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="412204" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400255" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400645" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="412239" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400299" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412220" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400204" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400090" joined="2007-05-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400042" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="412219" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400024" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412233" joined="2007-05-21"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1178596800" datetime="2007-05-08"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1178683200" datetime="2007-05-09"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1178769600" datetime="2007-05-10"><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1178769600" datetime="2007-05-10"><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Unanimous Consent .</text></action>
		<action date="1179201600" datetime="2007-05-15"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1179201600" datetime="2007-05-15" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1179928380" datetime="2007-05-23T10:53:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 110-166.</text></action>
		<calendar number="100" date="1179928500" datetime="2007-05-23T10:55:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 100.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1179951000" datetime="2007-05-23T17:10:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Filner moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1179951060" datetime="2007-05-23T17:11:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H5671-5678"/></action>
		<action date="1179951060" datetime="2007-05-23T17:11:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2199.</text></action>
		<action date="1179953220" datetime="2007-05-23T17:47:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1179956220" datetime="2007-05-23T18:37:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H5682-5683"/></action>
		<vote date="1179956640" how="roll" roll="413" datetime="2007-05-23T18:44:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" suspension="1" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 421 - 0 (Roll no. 413).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H5671-5674"/></vote>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/23/2007--Passed House amended. Traumatic Brain Injury Health Enhancement and Long-Term Support Act of 2007 - (Sec. 2) Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish a program to screen veterans eligible for Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) hospital, medical, and nursing home care for symptoms of traumatic brain injury (TBI). Requires the Secretary to develop and carry out a program of long-term care for post-acute TBI rehabilitation in four geographically dispersed polytrauma network sites designated by the Secretary. Makes eligible for such program veterans who: (1) served on active duty in a theater of combat operations during a period of war after the Persian Gulf War or during a period of hostilities after November 11, 1998; (2) are diagnosed with moderate to severe TBI; and (3) are unable to manage routine daily living activities without supervision or assistance. Requires a program report from the Secretary to the congressional veterans' committees. Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish a TBI transition office at each polytrauma network site to coordinate the provision of health care and services to veterans who suffer from moderate to severe TBI and are in need of health care and services not immediately offered by the VA; and (2) establish and maintain the Traumatic Brain Injury Veterans' Health Registry. Requires: (1) the Secretary to establish and operate up to five centers for TBI research, education, and clinical activities; (2) the establishment of a peer review panel to assess the scientific and clinical merit of proposals submitted for the designation of such centers; (3) the VA Under Secretary of Health to ensure that information produced at such centers is disseminated throughout the Veterans Health Administration (VHA); and (4) annual reports from the Secretary to the veterans' committees on the status and activities of the centers. Authorizes appropriations. Directs the Secretary to establish within the VHA the Committee on Care of Veterans with Traumatic Brain Injury. Requires annual reports from the Secretary to the veterans' committees on Committee activities. (Sec. 3) Directs the Secretary to carry out a pilot program to provide veterans' readjustment counseling, related mental health services, benefits outreach, and claims assistance through the use of mobile Vet Centers. Requires: (1) the establishment of two mobile Vet Centers in each of five specified Veterans Integrated Service Network areas; and (2) a pilot program report from the Secretary to the veterans' committees. (Sec. 4) Directs the Secretary to establish the Advisory Committee on Rural Veterans to advise the Secretary with respect to the administration of VA benefits for rural veterans. Requires: (1) the Committee to report to the Secretary on each odd-numbered year through 2013 on VA programs and activities that pertain to rural veterans; and (2) the Secretary to forward each report to Congress.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
