<bill session="110" type="h" number="2212" updated="2009-01-08T21:28:36-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1178596800" datetime="2007-05-08"/></status>

	<introduced date="1178596800" datetime="2007-05-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require the President to close the Department of Defense detention facility at Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400166"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400227" joined="2007-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400289" joined="2007-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="2007-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400001" joined="2007-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="412222" joined="2007-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400251" joined="2007-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400366" joined="2008-01-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="412239" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400042" joined="2007-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400301" joined="2007-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400062" joined="2007-12-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1178596800" datetime="2007-05-08"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E979-980)</text></action>
		<action date="1178596800" datetime="2007-05-08"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/8/2007--Introduced.<br/>Requires the President to close the Department of Defense (DOD) detention facility at Guantanamo Bay, Cuba. Requires all current detainees there to be: (1) transferred to a military or civilian detention facility in the United States (U.S. facility) and charged with a violation of U.S. or international law and tried before a regularly-constituted court; (2) transferred to a U.S. facility without being charged if the detainee may be held as an enemy combatant or pursuant to other legal authority; (3) transferred to an international tribunal operating under authority of the United Nations (UN) with jurisdiction to hold trials; (4) transferred to their country of citizenship or a different country for further legal process, provided that such country provides adequate assurances that the individual will not be subject to torture or cruel, inhuman, or degrading treatment; or (5) released from any further detention. 
	</summary>
</bill>
