<bill session="110" type="h" number="222" updated="2009-01-08T17:11:38-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/></status>

	<introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Central Idaho Economic Development and Recreation Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To promote the economic development and recreational use of National Forest System lands and other public lands in central Idaho, to designate the Boulder-White Cloud Management Area to ensure the continued management of certain National Forest System lands and Bureau of Land Management lands for recreational and grazing use and conservation and resource protection, to add certain National Forest System lands and Bureau of Land Management lands in central Idaho to the National Wilderness Preservation System, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400376"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/4/2007--Introduced.<br/>Central Idaho Economic Development and Recreation Act - Requires the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service, and the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Land Management (BLM), to convey specified parcels of federal land to certain counties and cities in central Idaho. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to convey, to the state of Idaho a specified parcel or parcels of BLM land, including roads thereon, for a motorized recreation park. Designates specified parcels of federal land in central Idaho as wilderness areas to be managed as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System (NWPS). Repeals existing law requiring review of portions of the Sawtooth National Recreation Area (SNRA) for possible inclusion in the NWPS. Establishes the Boulder-White Cloud Management Area on federal lands in the Challis National Forest, the Sawtooth National Forest, SNRA, and Challis District of the BLM that are not designated as wilderness areas under this Act. 
	</summary>
</bill>
