<bill session="110" type="h" number="2246" updated="2009-01-08T21:32:51-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1196793660" datetime="2007-12-04T14:41:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1178683200" datetime="2007-05-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To validate certain conveyances made by the Union Pacific Railroad Company of lands located in Reno, Nevada, that were originally conveyed by the United States to facilitate construction of transcontinental railroads, and for other purposes.</title>
		<title type="official" as="amended by house">A bill to provide for the release of any reversionary interest of the United States in and to certain lands in Reno, Nevada.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412218"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400324" joined="2007-10-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400024" joined="2007-10-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1178683200" datetime="2007-05-09"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1179115200" datetime="2007-05-14"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action date="1193112000" datetime="2007-10-23"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1194411600" datetime="2007-11-07"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1194411600" datetime="2007-11-07"><text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands Discharged.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1194411600" datetime="2007-11-07" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1196793180" datetime="2007-12-04T14:33:00-05:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-461.</text></action>
		<calendar number="285" date="1196793180" datetime="2007-12-04T14:33:00-05:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 285.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1196793360" datetime="2007-12-04T14:36:00-05:00"><text>Ms. Bordallo moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1196793360" datetime="2007-12-04T14:36:00-05:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H14095"/></action>
		<action date="1196793360" datetime="2007-12-04T14:36:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2246.</text></action>
		<vote date="1196793660" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-12-04T14:41:00-05:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H14095"/></vote>
		<action date="1196793660" datetime="2007-12-04T14:41:00-05:00"><text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action date="1196830800" datetime="2007-12-05"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1215576000" datetime="2008-07-09"><text>Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="1018" date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1018.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/16/2008--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the House on December 4, 2007). The summary of that version is repeated here.) Releases any reversionary interests of the United States (including interests under the Union Pacific Railroad Act) in and to specified railroad lands in the City of Reno, Nevada, that were originally granted to the Union Pacific Railroad under the provisions of such Act.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
