<bill session="110" type="h" number="2248" updated="2009-01-08T21:33:05-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1178683200" datetime="2007-05-09"/></status>

	<introduced date="1178683200" datetime="2007-05-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Redistricting Reform Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit States from carrying out more than one Congressional redistricting after a decennial census and apportionment, to require States to conduct such redistricting through independent commissions, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400245"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400618" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400129" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400065" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400361" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400124" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="412189" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400396" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400384" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400355" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400231" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400663" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400347" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400356" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400259" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400166" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2007-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400371" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400062" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400425" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="2007-05-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1178683200" datetime="2007-05-09"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1182744000" datetime="2007-06-25"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/9/2007--Introduced.<br/>Redistricting Reform Act of 2007 - Prohibits a state that has been redistricted after an apportionment from being redistricted again until after the next apportionment of Representatives, unless the state is ordered by a court to conduct such a subsequent redistricting in order to: (1) comply with the U.S. Constitution; or (2) enforce the Voting Rights Act of 1965.<br/>Requires such redistricting to be conducted according to: (1) a plan developed by the independent redistricting commission established in the state; or (2) if such plan is not enacted into law, the redistricting plan selected by the state's highest court or developed by a U.S. district court.<br/>Provides for: (1) establishment by each state of an independent bi-partisan redistricting commission; (2) development by such commission of a redistricting plan; (3) submission of the plan to, and consideration and enactment of a plan by, the state legislature; (4) selection of a plan by the state's highest court or development of a plan by the U.S. district court, under specified conditions; (5) special rules for redistricting conducted under a federal court order; (6) Election Assistance Commission payments to states for carrying out redistricting; (7) civil enforcement to carry out this Act; and (8) the right of action for a person who is aggrieved by a violation of this Act.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
