<bill session="110" type="h" number="225" updated="2009-01-08T17:12:02-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/></status>

	<introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To withhold United States funding from the United Nations Human Rights Council.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400388"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400279" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400627" joined="2007-01-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400385" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400441" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400254" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400652" joined="2007-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400288" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400658" joined="2007-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400206" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400296" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400220" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400131" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400145" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400032" joined="2007-01-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400651" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400088" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412011" joined="2008-07-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E22-23)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/4/2007--Introduced.<br/>Expresses the sense of Congress that the United Nations Human Rights Council should: (1) be a body that upholds the ideals enumerated in the United Nations Charter and the Universal Declaration on Human Rights; (2) allow full participation by Israel in Council operations; and (3) be made up of countries that hold regular democratic elections, permit freedom of expression, and have a credible civil society. Expresses the sense of Congress that the United States should not support the Council, and should withhold financial support for the Council until meaningful human rights reforms are carried out. Directs the Secretary of State to withhold from a U.S. contribution to a regularly assessed biennial U.N. budget an amount equal to the percentage of such contribution that the Secretary determines would be allocated by the United Nations to the Council. 
	</summary>
</bill>
