<bill session="110" type="h" number="2292" updated="2009-01-08T21:38:21-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179115200" datetime="2007-05-14"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179115200" datetime="2007-05-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Pay Veterans First Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the payment of bonuses to certain officers of the Department of Veterans Affairs unless fewer than 100,000 disability compensation claims are pending before the Department.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412222"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412229" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400227" joined="2007-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400177" joined="2007-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400257" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412231" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412189" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412214" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412197" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400339" joined="2007-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="412193" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412205" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400631" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412240" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412204" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="412219" joined="2007-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400024" joined="2007-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412194" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400100" joined="2007-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400186" joined="2007-05-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179115200" datetime="2007-05-14"><text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1179115200" datetime="2007-05-14"><text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1179115200" datetime="2007-05-14"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1179806400" datetime="2007-05-22"><committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/14/2007--Introduced.<br/>Pay Veterans First Act - Prohibits for FY2007 the payment of a performance-based bonus to any officer of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) who is appointed by the President, by and with the consent of the Senate, or who is a senior politically appointed officer unless, at the time of the payment, fewer than 100,000 claims for veterans' disability compensation are pending before the VA. Requires the Comptroller General to conduct an audit of VA claims processing, and report audit results to Congress, for any quarter of FY2007 during which the percentage of disallowed claims exceeds by more than 10% the percentage that were disallowed during FY2006.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
