<bill session="110" type="h" number="2296" updated="2009-01-08T21:38:52-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179115200" datetime="2007-05-14"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179115200" datetime="2007-05-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Future Fuels Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To reduce the Nation's oil dependence and enhance the Nation's ability to produce alternative fuels.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400147"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179115200" datetime="2007-05-14"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1179115200" datetime="2007-05-14"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1179115200" datetime="2007-05-14"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text></action>
		<action date="1179115200" datetime="2007-05-14"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1179115200" datetime="2007-05-14"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1179201600" datetime="2007-05-15"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/14/2007--Introduced.<br/>Future Fuels Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow an investment credit to eligible manufacturers for an advanced technology motor vehicle. Amends federal transportation law to revise the fuel economy calculations for manufacturing incentives for dual fueled and gaseous fuel dedicated automobiles.<br/>Sets forth a calendar schedule for an increased percentage of alternative fueled automobiles or flexible fuel vehicles. Directs the Secretary of Transportation to carry out: (1) evaluation projects to determine how technology can best be applied to assess mileage-based road user charges on major highways at peak-commuting times; and (2) a national evaluation pilot project to assess how offering commuters the option to receive the cash value of their workplace parking place, if any, instead of free parking can reduce oil usage, lessen highway congestion, and expand travel alternatives. Instructs the Secretary of Transportation (Secretary) to: (1) establish an incentives program for insurance providers to sell automobile insurance policies on a per-mile basis; (2) designate at least 20 transit-oriented development corridors in urbanized areas by 2015, and 50 by 2025; (3) award transit grants to construct or improve transit facilities, bicycle transportation facilities, and pedestrian walkways in such corridors, including capital projects; and (4) establish a transit-oriented development corridors research and development program for best practices and performance criteria. Directs the Secretary to develop a national tire fuel efficiency program for tires designed for use on passenger cars and light trucks.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
