<bill session="110" type="h" number="2293" updated="2009-01-08T21:38:28-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1184609700" datetime="2007-07-16T15:15:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1179115200" datetime="2007-05-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of State to submit to Congress a report on efforts to bring to justice the Palestinian terrorists who killed John Branchizio, Mark Parson, and John Marin Linde.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400003"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400344" joined="2007-06-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400231" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400371" joined="2007-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400315" joined="2007-05-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179115200" datetime="2007-05-14"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26" ><text>Committee Agreed to Seek Consideration Under Suspension of the Rules, by Unanimous Consent.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1184608920" datetime="2007-07-16T15:02:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Ackerman moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text></action>
		<action date="1184608980" datetime="2007-07-16T15:03:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H7798-7800"/></action>
		<action date="1184608980" datetime="2007-07-16T15:03:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2293.</text></action>
		<vote date="1184609700" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-07-16T15:15:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H7798"/></vote>
		<action date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/16/2007--Passed House without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the Palestinian Authority's (PA) continued inability or unwillingness to pursue and bring to justice the Palestinian terrorists who killed John Branchizio, Mark Parson, and John Marin Linde calls into question the PA's suitability as a U.S. partner in diplomatic efforts to resolve the Palestinian-Israeli conflict; (2) future U.S. assistance to the PA may be suspended or conditioned, and the continued operation of the PLO Representative Office in Washington may be jeopardized, if the PA does not cooperate in bringing these individuals to justice; and (3) it is in the U.S. national interest to safeguard diplomats and all embassy and consulate personnel, and to use the full power of the United States to bring to justice any individual or entity that threatens or harms them. Directs the Secretary of State, within 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and every 120 days thereafter, to report to the appropriate congressional committees describing U.S. and PA efforts to bring to justice the Palestinian terrorists who killed John Branchizio, Mark Parson, and John Marin Linde.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
