<bill session="110" type="h" number="2304" updated="2009-01-08T21:39:48-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1181707200" datetime="2007-06-13" /></status>

	<introduced date="1179115200" datetime="2007-05-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Advanced Geothermal Energy Research and Development Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Advanced Geothermal Energy Research and Development Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Energy to conduct a program of research, development, demonstration, and commercial application for geothermal energy, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412189"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400280" joined="2007-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400155" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400419" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400361" joined="2007-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400229" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400254" joined="2007-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400663" joined="2007-06-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2007-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412222" joined="2007-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400255" joined="2007-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400193" joined="2007-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2007-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400024" joined="2007-06-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179115200" datetime="2007-05-14"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Science and Technology.</text></action>
		<action date="1180584000" datetime="2007-05-31"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text></action>
		<action date="1181102400" datetime="2007-06-06"><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1181102400" datetime="2007-06-06"><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text></action>
		<action date="1181707200" datetime="2007-06-13"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1181707200" datetime="2007-06-13" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text></calendar>
		<action date="1182462180" datetime="2007-06-21T18:43:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science and Technology. H. Rept. 110-203.</text></action>
		<calendar number="122" date="1182462240" datetime="2007-06-21T18:44:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 122.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1210046400" datetime="2008-05-06"><text>Hearing Held by Subcommittee on Energy and Environment Prior to Introduction and Referral (May 17, 2007).</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/21/2007--Reported to House amended. Advanced Geothermal Energy Research and Development Act of 2007 - (Sec. 4) Instructs the Secretary of Energy to support research, development, demonstration, and commercial application programs to expand geothermal energy production from hydrothermal systems. Specifies programs to: (1) develop advanced geophysical, geochemical, and geologic tools to assist in locating hidden hydrothermal resources and increase the reliability of site characterization; and (2) demonstrate technologies and techniques of exploratory drilling for undiscovered resources in a variety of geologic settings. (Sec. 5) Directs the Secretary to support research, development, demonstration, and commercial application of subsurface components and systems capable of withstanding extreme geothermal environments and necessary to develop, produce, and monitor geothermal reservoirs and produce geothermal energy. Directs the Secretary also to support such programs to: (1) create models of geothermal reservoir performance; and (2) mitigate or preclude potential adverse environmental impacts of geothermal energy development, production, or use. (Sec. 6) Directs the Secretary to support research, development, demonstration, and commercial application programs for: (1) enhanced geothermal systems; (2) enhanced geothermal systems reservoir stimulation technologies and techniques; and (3) geothermal energy production from oil and gas fields and production and recovery of energy from geopressured resources. (Sec. 8) Sets forth federal cost share, organization, and administration requirements for projects under this Act. Requires the Secretary to allow a competitive bidding process to play a role in determining the final cost-share ratio. (Sec. 9) Instructs the Secretary to award grants for five-year periods to institutions of higher education (or consortia of them) for establishment of two Centers for Geothermal Technology Transfer, including a Hydrothermal Center and an Enhanced Geothermal Systems Center, to serve as information clearinghouses. (Sec. 10) Requires the Secretary to expand the Department of Energy's GeoPowering the West program, renamed &quot;GeoPowering America,&quot; to extend its geothermal technology transfer activities throughout the entire United States. Continues to base the program in the Department of Energy office in Golden, Colorado. (Sec. 11) Directs the Secretary to study and report to specified congressional committees on: (1) advanced technologies to maximize geothermal resources; (2) progress of projects under this Act; and (3) legal and regulatory barriers to such projects. (Sec. 13) Authorizes appropriations for FY2008-FY2012. 
	</summary>
</bill>
