<bill session="110" type="h" number="2339" updated="2009-01-08T21:43:59-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1217461800" datetime="2008-07-30T20:50:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1179288000" datetime="2007-05-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Produced Water Utilization Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Produced Water Utilization Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Produced Water Utilization Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To encourage research, development, and demonstration of technologies to facilitate the utilization of water produced in connection with the development of domestic energy resources, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400165"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179288000" datetime="2007-05-16"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Science and Technology.</text></action>
		<action date="1180584000" datetime="2007-05-31"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text></action>
		<action date="1210046400" datetime="2008-05-06"><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1210046400" datetime="2008-05-06"><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text></action>
		<action date="1216180800" datetime="2008-07-16"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1216180800" datetime="2008-07-16" ><text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1217427540" datetime="2008-07-30T11:19:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science and Technology. H. Rept. 110-801.</text></action>
		<calendar number="518" date="1217427540" datetime="2008-07-30T11:19:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 518.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1217461500" datetime="2008-07-30T20:45:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Matheson moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1217461500" datetime="2008-07-30T20:45:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H7606-7608"/></action>
		<action date="1217461500" datetime="2008-07-30T20:45:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2339.</text></action>
		<vote date="1217461800" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-07-30T20:50:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H7607"/></vote>
		<action date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/30/2008--Passed House amended. Produced Water Utilization Act of 2008 - Defines &quot;produced water&quot; to mean water from an underground source that is brought to the surface as part of the process of exploration for or development of coalbed methane, oil, natural gas, or any other substance to be used as an energy source.<br/>Requires the Secretary of Energy, in conjunction with an existing domestic petroleum production program of the Department of Energy, to conduct a program of research, development, and demonstration of technologies for environmentally sustainable utilization of produced water for agriculture, irrigation, municipal, or industrial uses or other environmentally sustainable purposes. Requires the program to be designed to maximize the utilization of produced water in the United States by increasing its quality and reducing its environmental impacts.<br/>Requires that the program address: (1) produced water recovery, including research for desalination and demineralization to reduce total dissolved solids in the produced water; (2) re-injection of produced water into subsurface geological formations to increase energy production; and (3) improving safety and minimizing environmental impacts of such activities.<br/>Requires the Secretary, through the appropriate National Laboratory, to carry out research, development, and demonstration activities that are complementary to and supportive of such program.<br/>Authorizes appropriations.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
