<bill session="110" type="h" number="2331" updated="2009-01-08T21:43:01-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179201600" datetime="2007-05-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179201600" datetime="2007-05-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">First Response Broadcasters Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to support efforts by local or regional television or radio broadcasters to provide essential public information programming in the event of a major disaster, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400635"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412260" joined="2008-09-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412229" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400657" joined="2008-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400096" joined="2007-10-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400443" joined="2008-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400437" joined="2008-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-06-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400426" joined="2008-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400645" joined="2007-05-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400319" joined="2007-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400440" joined="2008-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400309" joined="2008-02-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179201600" datetime="2007-05-15"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text></action>
		<action date="1179288000" datetime="2007-05-16"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/15/2007--Introduced.<br/>First Response Broadcasters Act of 2007 - Authorizes appropriations to the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) for facility and equipment expenses to construct an additional 25 Primary Entry Point stations (radio broadcast stations designated to provide public information following emergencies where there is no commercial power) in the continental United States and territories.<br/>Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish a pilot program, the Broadcast Disaster Preparedness Grant Program, under which the Administrator may make grants to first response broadcasters. Sets forth provisions regarding priorities in making grants, use of funds, the federal share, and termination of grant authority.<br/>Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to: (1) include specified assistance to first response broadcasters among the essential assistance that federal agencies may provide to meet immediate threats to life and property resulting from a major disaster; (2) prohibit a federal officer or employee from confiscating fuel, water, or food from such a broadcaster during a disaster if that broadcaster documents that such supplies will be used to enable the broadcast of essential disaster-related public information in the affected area; and (3) direct the head of a federal agency to allow access to the area affected by a major disaster for technical personnel, broadcast engineers, and equipment needed to restore, repair, or resupply any facility or equipment critical to such a broadcaster's ability to continue to acquire, produce, and transmit essential disaster-related public information, subject to specified limitations. Establishes guidelines for press access to a disaster area.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
