<bill session="110" type="h" number="2342" updated="2009-01-08T21:44:20-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1206984540" datetime="2008-03-31T14:29:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1179288000" datetime="2007-05-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Integrated Coastal and Ocean Observation Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">National Integrated Coastal and Ocean Observation Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">National Integrated Coastal and Ocean Observation Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the President to establish a National Integrated Coastal and Ocean Observation System, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400007"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400041" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400149" joined="2007-05-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400403" joined="2007-05-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400129" joined="2007-05-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="412189" joined="2007-07-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400384" joined="2007-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400184" joined="2007-09-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="2007-05-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400359" joined="2007-05-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400663" joined="2007-06-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400166" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2007-06-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400439" joined="2007-05-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400266" joined="2007-05-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400193" joined="2007-05-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2007-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="2007-05-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400097" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400062" joined="2007-05-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400425" joined="2007-05-16"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179288000" datetime="2007-05-16"><text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Science and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1179288000" datetime="2007-05-16"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1179288000" datetime="2007-05-16"><text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text></action>
		<action date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, and Oceans.</text></action>
		<action date="1180584000" datetime="2007-05-31"><committee name="House Science and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text></action>
		<action date="1202878800" datetime="2008-02-13"><committee name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, and Oceans"/><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee Without Recommendation (Amended) by Unanimous Consent .</text></action>
		<action date="1202878800" datetime="2008-02-13"><committee name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, and Oceans"/><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1205294400" datetime="2008-03-12" ><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1205294400" datetime="2008-03-12"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1207020000" datetime="2008-03-31T12:20:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-558, Part I.</text></action>
		<action date="1207020060" datetime="2008-03-31T12:21:00-04:00"><text>Committee on Science and Technology discharged.</text></action>
		<calendar number="341" date="1207020120" datetime="2008-03-31T12:22:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 341.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1206983940" datetime="2008-03-31T14:19:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Kennedy moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1206983940" datetime="2008-03-31T14:19:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H1778-1781"/></action>
		<action date="1206983940" datetime="2008-03-31T14:19:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2342.</text></action>
		<vote date="1206984540" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-03-31T14:29:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H1778-1780"/></vote>
		<action date="1207022400" datetime="2008-04-01"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/31/2008--Passed House amended. National Integrated Coastal and Ocean Observation Act of 2008 - Directs the President to establish a National Integrated Coastal and Ocean Observation System to: (1) support national defense, marine commerce, energy production, basic and applied research, ecosystem-based marine and coastal resource management, public safety and public outreach training and education; (2) promote awareness of ocean, coastal, and Great Lakes resources; (3) improve the ability to measure, track, explain, and predict weather and climate change and natural climate variability; (4) fulfill the plan contained in the document entitled &quot;Ocean.US Publication No. 9, The First Integrated Ocean Observing System (IOOS) Development Plan&quot;; and (5) fulfill the nation's international obligations to contribute to the global earth and ocean observation systems. Makes the National Ocean Research Leadership Council responsible for coordination and long-term operations plans, policies, protocols, and standards for the System and for coordination with other earth observing activities. Makes the existing Interagency Working Group responsible for, among other things, implementation of operations plans and policies, budget development, identification of observation coverage gaps or capital improvements needs, data management and communication protocols and standards, observation data variables, and establishment of a competitive matching grant or other program to promote research and development of innovative observation technologies. Makes the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) the lead federal agency for the System. Requires the Administrator to certify or establish Regional Information Coordination Entities to coordinate state, federal, local, and private interests at a regional level. Requires the Administrator to establish a System Advisory Committee. Authorizes member departments and agencies of the Council, subject to appropriations, to participate in interagency financing and share funds appropriated to any member agency to carry out this Act. Requires a biennial report to Congress on the status of the System. Requires the Council to develop a policy that defines processes for making decisions about the roles of the federal government, states, Regional Information Coordination Entities, the academic community, and the private sector in providing to end-user communities environmental information, products, technologies, and services related to the System. Requires the Interagency Working Group, through the Administrator and the Director of the National Science Foundation, to submit to Congress an independent cost estimate for certain aspects of the System.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
