<bill session="110" type="h" number="2347" updated="2009-01-08T21:44:57-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1185937920" datetime="2007-07-31T12:12:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="765"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179288000" datetime="2007-05-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Iran Sanctions Enabling Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Iran Sanctions Enabling Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Iran Sanctions Enabling Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize State and local governments to direct divestiture from, and prevent investment in, companies with investments of $20,000,000 or more in Iran's energy sector, and for other purposes.</title>
		<title type="official" as="amended by house">A bill to authorize State and local governments to direct divestiture from, and prevent investment in, companies with investments of $20,000,000 or more in Iran's energy sector, companies that sell arms to the Government of Iran, and financial institutions that extend $20,000,000 or more in credit to the Government of Iran for 45 days or more, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400140"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400060" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400089" joined="2007-06-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400336" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400122" joined="2007-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400333" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400623" joined="2007-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400430" joined="2007-05-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="2007-06-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400332" joined="2007-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400344" joined="2007-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400063" joined="2007-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412192" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400003" joined="2007-05-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400274" joined="2007-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412189" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400254" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="2007-05-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400285" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400055" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400249" joined="2007-05-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="412198" joined="2007-05-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400658" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400225" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400231" joined="2007-05-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400017" joined="2007-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400147" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400308" joined="2007-06-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400166" joined="2007-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400628" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400644" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400415" joined="2007-06-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400009" joined="2007-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400371" joined="2007-05-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400145" joined="2007-07-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2007-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400139" joined="2007-06-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="412220" joined="2007-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400024" joined="2007-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400025" joined="2007-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400141" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400163" joined="2007-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400321" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="412233" joined="2007-07-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179288000" datetime="2007-05-16"><text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Education and Labor, and Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1179288000" datetime="2007-05-16"><text>Referred to House Financial Services</text></action>
		<action date="1179288000" datetime="2007-05-16"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1179288000" datetime="2007-05-16"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23"><committee name="House Financial Services"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23" ><committee name="House Financial Services"/><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1185852600" datetime="2007-07-30T12:30:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 110-277, Part I.</text></action>
		<action date="1185852600" datetime="2007-07-30T12:30:00-04:00"><text>Committee on Education and Labor discharged.</text></action>
		<action date="1185852600" datetime="2007-07-30T12:30:00-04:00"><text>Committee on Oversight and Government discharged.</text></action>
		<calendar number="179" date="1185852600" datetime="2007-07-30T12:30:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 179.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1185812580" datetime="2007-07-30T13:23:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Sherman moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1185812640" datetime="2007-07-30T13:24:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules. (consideration: CR 7/31/2007 H8855-8861)</text></action>
		<action date="1185812640" datetime="2007-07-30T13:24:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2347.</text></action>
		<action date="1185814380" datetime="2007-07-30T13:53:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1185937440" datetime="2007-07-31T12:04:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H9211-9212"/></action>
		<vote date="1185937920" how="roll" roll="765" datetime="2007-07-31T12:12:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" suspension="1" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 408 - 6 (Roll no. 765).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H8855-8856"/></vote>
		<action date="1185937920" datetime="2007-07-31T12:12:00-04:00"><text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action date="1185940800" datetime="2007-08-01"><text>Received in the Senate.</text></action>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/31/2007--Passed House amended. Iran Sanctions Enabling Act of 2007 - (Sec. 3) Directs the President to ensure biannual publication in the Federal Register of a list of each person that: (1) has an investment of more than $20 million in the energy sector in Iran; (2) sells arms to the government of Iran; or (3) is a financial institution that extends $20 million or more in credit for 45 days or more to the government of Iran.<br/>Instructs the President to use only publicly available (including proprietary) information when compiling such list.<br/>Requires the list to: (1) describe to the extent practicable the investment made by each listed person, including dollar value, intended purpose, and status as of the date of publication; and (2) be updated and published on a government website.<br/>Declares it is the policy of the United States to support the decision of state and local governments and educational institutions to divest from, and to prohibit the investment of assets they control in: (1) persons that have investments of more than $20 million in Iran's energy sector; (2) persons that sell arms to the government of Iran; and (3) financial institutions that extend $20 million or more in credit for 45 days or more to the government of Iran.<br/>Authorizes a governmental entity to adopt and enforce measures to divest its assets from, or prohibit investment of assets in a person that: (1) is included on the most recent list; (2) sells arms to the government of Iran; (3) is a financial institution that extends $20 million or more in credit for 45 days or more to the government of Iran; or (4) is included on a state or local government-authorized list of entities invested in or doing business in or with Iran.<br/>(Sec. 5) Amends the Investment Company Act of 1940 to shield any registered investment company from civil, criminal, or administrative action based solely upon its divesting from, or avoiding investing in, securities issued by companies included on such most recent list.<br/>(Sec. 6) Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to shield from treatment as breaching a fiduciary duty any person divesting plan assets from, or avoiding investing plan assets in, persons included on such most recent list.<br/>(Sec. 9) Terminates this Act 30 days after the President certifies to Congress that the government of Iran has ceased: (1) providing support for acts of international terrorism and no longer satisfies the requirements for designation as a state-sponsor of terrorism; and (2) the pursuit, acquisition, and development of nuclear, biological, and chemical weapons and ballistic missiles and ballistic missile launch technology.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
