<bill session="110" type="h" number="2341" updated="2009-01-08T21:44:13-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179288000" datetime="2007-05-16"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179288000" datetime="2007-05-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Trading on Congressional Knowledge Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit securities and commodities trading based on nonpublic information relating to Congress, and to require additional reporting by Members and employees of Congress of securities transaction, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400011"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400227" joined="2008-09-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412214" joined="2008-09-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="2007-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412197" joined="2008-09-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-06-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400378" joined="2007-05-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400645" joined="2007-07-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="412186" joined="2007-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2007-06-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179288000" datetime="2007-05-16"><text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on House Administration, the Judiciary, Agriculture, and Standards of Official Conduct, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1179288000" datetime="2007-05-16"><text>Referred to House Financial Services</text></action>
		<action date="1179288000" datetime="2007-05-16"><text>Referred to House House Administration</text></action>
		<action date="1179288000" datetime="2007-05-16"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1179288000" datetime="2007-05-16"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action date="1179288000" datetime="2007-05-16"><text>Referred to House Standards of Official Conduct</text></action>
		<action date="1182744000" datetime="2007-06-25"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text></action>
		<action date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on General Farm Commodities and Risk Management.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/16/2007--Introduced.<br/>Stop Trading on Congressional Knowledge Act - Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 and the Commodities Exchange Act to direct both the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) and the Commodities Futures Trading Commission (CFTC) to prohibit purchase or sale of either securities or commodities for future delivery by a person in possession of material nonpublic information regarding pending or prospective legislative action if the information was obtained: (1) knowingly from a Member or employee of Congress; (2) by reason of being a Member or employee of Congress; and (3) other federal employees. Amends the Code of Official Conduct of the Rules of the House of Representatives to prohibit designated House personnel from disclosing material nonpublic information relating to any pending or prospective legislative action relating to either securities of a publicly-traded company or a commodity if such personnel has reason to believe that the information will be used to buy or sell the securities or commodity based on such information. Amends the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 to require formal disclosure of certain securities and commodities futures transactions to either the Clerk of the House of Representatives or the Secretary of the Senate. Amends the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 to subject to its registration, reporting, and disclosure requirements political intelligence activities, contacts, firms, and consultants.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
