<bill session="110" type="h" number="2364" updated="2009-01-08T21:47:02-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179374400" datetime="2007-05-17"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179374400" datetime="2007-05-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Local Food and Farm Support Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To promote expanded economic opportunities for farmers and ranchers through local and regional markets, expand access to healthy food in underserved communities, provide access to locally and regionally grown food for schools, institutions, and consumers, and strengthen rural-urban linkages, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400033"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400227" joined="2007-07-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400092" joined="2007-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400080" joined="2007-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2007-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400268" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="412210" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400124" joined="2007-07-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400184" joined="2007-05-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="2007-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400007" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="412223" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2007-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="412240" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="412204" joined="2007-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400350" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="412239" joined="2007-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400211" joined="2007-07-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400100" joined="2007-05-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179374400" datetime="2007-05-17"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1078)</text></action>
		<action date="1179374400" datetime="2007-05-17"><text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1179374400" datetime="2007-05-17"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action date="1179374400" datetime="2007-05-17"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1179806400" datetime="2007-05-22"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H5535)</text></action>
		<action date="1181102400" datetime="2007-06-06"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H6012)</text></action>
		<action date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text></action>
		<action date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on General Farm Commodities and Risk Management.</text></action>
		<action date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Credit, Energy, and Research.</text></action>
		<action date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Horticulture and Organic Agriculture.</text></action>
		<action date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Specialty Crops, Rural Development, and Foreign Agriculture.</text></action>
		<action date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Healthy Families and Communities.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/17/2007--Introduced.<br/>Local Food and Farm Support Act - Amends the Agricultural Risk Protection Act of 2000 to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to establish a grant program to support value-added agricultural products which shall include a socially disadvantaged farmer and rancher component and may include a small and individual producer grant component. Directs the Secretary to establish a Family Rancher and Rancher Viability and Innovation Fund. Amends the Specialty Crops Competitiveness Act of 2004 to direct the Secretary, through the Agricultural Marketing Service, to: (1) establish a grant program for eligible entities to conduct enterprise feasibility studies, including studies of consumer preference; and (2) provide loans and loan guarantees to eligible entities and individual producers to develop processing, distribution, and information infrastructure for locally or regionally produced food. Amends the Farmers-to-Consumers Direct Marketing Act of 1976 to direct the Secretary to carry out a direct to consumer marketing assistance program to make grants to eligible entities for projects to establish, expand, and promote farmers' markets and other farmer to consumer direct marketing opportunities. Extends: (1) the Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children (WIC) farmers' market nutrition program; (2) the senior farmers' market nutrition program; (3) the food stamp community food project program; and (4) the farm-to cafeteria program. Establishes: (1) the food stamp fruit and vegetable incentive program; and (2) the urban agriculture production program.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
