<bill session="110" type="h" number="2398" updated="2009-01-08T21:51:12-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">CREATE-21 Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Creating Research Extension and Teaching Excellence for the 21st Century Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To reauthorize and provide additional funding for essential agricultural research, extension, education, and related programs, to establish the National Institutes for Food and Agriculture as an independent agency reporting to and coordinating with the Secretary of Agriculture, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400628"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400327" joined="2007-07-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412229" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400618" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="412210" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400030" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="412240" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400431" joined="2007-06-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400363" joined="2007-05-21"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1106-1107)</text></action>
		<action date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/21/2007--Introduced.<br/>Creating Research Extension and Teaching Excellence for the 21st Century Act of 2007 or CREATE-21 Act of 2007 - Establishes the National Institutes for Food and Agriculture, which shall be located in Washington, DC. Transfers specified authorities of the Department of Agriculture and other authorities to the Institutes. Sets forth organizational and funding provisions. Amends the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 to repeal authority for the National Agricultural Research, Extension, Education, and Economics Advisory Board. Eliminates specified funding provisions respecting agricultural research at 1890 land-grant colleges. Extends and revises specified agricultural programs, including research, extension, and education programs. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to establish the Borlaug International Agricultural Science and Technology Fellowship Program to provide fellowships for scientific training in the United States to individuals from eligible countries who specialize in agricultural education and research and extension. 
	</summary>
</bill>
