<bill session="110" type="h" number="2395" updated="2009-01-08T21:50:51-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Security and Financial Empowerment (SAFE) Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Victims' Employment Sustainability Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Victims of Abuse Insurance Protection Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To promote the economic security and safety of victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400347"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2007-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400282" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400246" joined="2007-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400652" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400384" joined="2007-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400007" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400245" joined="2007-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400201" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400024" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400011" joined="2007-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="2007-05-21"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H5475)</text></action>
		<action date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"><text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"><text>Referred to House Financial Services</text></action>
		<action date="1180065600" datetime="2007-05-25"><committee name="House Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Income Security and Family Support.</text></action>
		<action date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Healthy Families and Communities.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/21/2007--Introduced.<br/>Security and Financial Empowerment (SAFE) Act - Sets forth entitlement standards and implementation guidelines for employee use of emergency leave to address domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, or stalking (domestic or sexual violence). Permits victims of domestic or sexual violence to substitute existing leave in lieu of emergency leave. Authorizes state use of funds under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act (Temporary Assistance for Needy Families) (TANF) to provide nonrecurrent short-term emergency benefits for victims of domestic or sexual violence on emergency leave. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to prohibit denial of unemployment compensation to individuals separated from employment due to their experience of domestic or sexual violence. Amends the Social Security Act to require training of unemployment compensation and TANF personnel to provide necessary services to victims of domestic or sexual violence.<br/>Victims' Employment Sustainability Act - Prohibits certain discriminatory employer practices against victims of domestic or sexual violence. Victims of Abuse Insurance Protection Act - Prohibits denial or restriction of insurance coverage (including termination of health insurance coverage) based on the status of the applicant or insured as a victim of domestic or sexual violence. 
	</summary>
</bill>
