<bill session="110" type="h" number="2403" updated="2009-01-08T21:51:48-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Southern Empowerment and Economic Development Act to authorize the Delta Black Belt Regional Authority</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to provide for comprehensive community and economic development in the distressed Southern Black Belt and Mississippi Delta region while leveraging existing efforts, entities, and resources.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400092"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"><text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"><text>Referred to House Financial Services</text></action>
		<action date="1179806400" datetime="2007-05-22"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text></action>
		<action date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Specialty Crops, Rural Development, and Foreign Agriculture.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/21/2007--Introduced.<br/>Southern Empowerment and Economic Development Act to authorize the Delta Black Belt Regional Authority - Amends the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to rename the Delta Regional Authority as the Delta/Black Belt Regional Authority. Extends the Authority's termination date. Directs the Authority to establish a Constituency Representation Board which shall: (1) ascertain state and congressional district community strategic planning efforts; and (2) evaluate and fund programs. Amends the Delta Development Act to revise the definition of the &quot;Lower Mississippi&quot; region.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
