<bill session="110" type="h" number="2413" updated="2009-01-08T21:52:58-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Border Security and Immigration Reform Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide for an increase in border patrol agents and other immigration enforcement activities, for a temporary agricultural worker program, and for a program to adjust the status of certain qualified long-term residents.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400617"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"><text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Homeland Security, and Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"><text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text></action>
		<action date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1180411200" datetime="2007-05-29"><committee name="House Homeland Security"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border, Maritime, and Global Counterterrorism.</text></action>
		<action date="1182744000" datetime="2007-06-25"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text></action>
		<action date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/21/2007--Introduced.<br/>Border Security and Immigration Reform Act of 2007 - Increases the number of: (1) full-time Border Patrol agents; and (2) immigration-related workplace enforcement personnel.<br/>Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish an employment eligibility verification system. Sets forth program provisions. Authorizes, and subsequently requires, the use of such system for previously hired individuals and for recruiting and referrals.<br/>Provides expedited removal for certain illegal aliens from a country that is not contiguous to the United States who are apprehended within 100 miles of a U.S. port or land border.<br/>Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to establish: (1) a nonimmigrant seasonal agricultural worker program (W-visa), which shall include annual numerical limitations and monthly limitations based on agricultural employment region; and (2) a trust fund to administer and enforce the program and provide a monetary incentive for such workers to return to their countries upon visa expiration. Prohibits status adjustment for such workers.<br/>Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to provide lawful status (which shall not be considered as permanent resident status) for qualifying aliens who have been in continuous unlawful residence in the United States since before January 1, 2002. Sets forth program provisions, including: (1) imposition of a $1,000 fine; and (2) prohibition of derivative lawful status for family members.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
