<bill session="110" type="h" number="2412" updated="2009-01-08T21:52:51-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Equity in Prescription Insurance and Contraceptive Coverage Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require equitable coverage of prescription contraceptive drugs and devices and contraceptive services under health plans.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400246"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400282" joined="2007-10-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400001" joined="2007-09-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2007-10-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/21/2007--Introduced.<br/>Equity in Prescription Insurance and Contraceptive Coverage Act of 2007 - Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) and the Public Health Service Act to prohibit a group health plan, and a health insurance issuer providing group coverage, from: (1) excluding or restricting benefits for prescription contraceptive drugs, devices, and outpatient services if the plan provides benefits for other outpatient prescription drugs, devices, or outpatient services; (2) denying eligibility based on use or potential use of such items or services; (3) providing monetary payments or rebates to a covered individual to encourage acceptance of less than the minimum protections available; (4) penalizing, reducing, or limiting a professional's reimbursement because the professional prescribed such drugs or devices or provided such services; or (5) providing incentives to a professional to induce the professional to withhold such drugs, devices, or services. Applies such prohibitions to coverage offered in the individual market. 
	</summary>
</bill>
