<bill session="110" type="h" number="2416" updated="2009-01-08T21:53:18-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Commission on the Accountability and Review of Federal Agencies Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a commission to conduct a comprehensive review of Federal agencies and programs and to recommend the elimination or realignment of duplicative, wasteful, or outdated functions, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400405"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400279" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="412218" joined="2007-06-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400137" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400113" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400441" joined="2007-10-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400095" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2007-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400433" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400288" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400055" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400427" joined="2007-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400017" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400172" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400655" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="412010" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="412213" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400145" joined="2007-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400315" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400141" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400252" joined="2007-05-21"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"><text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"><text>Referred to House Rules</text></action>
		<action date="1181620800" datetime="2007-06-12"><committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Organization, and Procurement.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/21/2007--Introduced.<br/>Commission on the Accountability and Review of Federal Agencies Act - Establishes the Commission on the Accountability and Review of Federal Agencies to: (1) evaluate executive agencies and their programs; and (2) submit to Congress a plan recommending agencies and programs that should be realigned or eliminated and proposing implementing legislation. Requires the Commission to recommend: (1) realignment where a function performed by two or more agencies or programs can be consolidated; (2) realignment or elimination of any agency or program that has wasted federal funds; and (3) elimination of any agency or program that has completed its purpose, become irrelevant, or failed to meet objectives.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
