<bill session="110" type="h" number="2427" updated="2009-01-08T21:54:40-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179806400" datetime="2007-05-22"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179806400" datetime="2007-05-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require that an independent review of the efficiency and effectiveness of all headquarters offices of USDA Rural Development and the Natural Resource Conservation Service be carried out before any county Rural Development office may be merged with a county office of the Natural Resource Conservation Service or any county office of the Natural Resource Conservation Service may be merged with a county Rural Development office.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400628"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179806400" datetime="2007-05-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text></action>
		<action date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text></action>
		<action date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"><text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/22/2007--Introduced.<br/>Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to contract with an independent reviewing authority to review the efficiency and effectiveness of operations at all headquarters offices of the Department of Agriculture's Rural Development office and its Natural Resources Conservation Service, including: (1) the headquarters offices in Washington, DC; and (2) all state offices. Prohibits the Secretary from merging any county Rural Development office with a county office of the Natural Resources Conservation Service, or any county office of the Natural Resources Conservation Service with a county Rural Development office before the later of: (1) the date on which the Secretary determines that each headquarters office has implemented the recommendations contained in the report required under this Act; or (2) October 1, 2008. 
	</summary>
</bill>
