<bill session="110" type="h" number="2420" updated="2009-01-08T21:53:49-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23" /></status>

	<introduced date="1179806400" datetime="2007-05-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">International Climate Cooperation Re-engagement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">International Climate Cooperation Re-engagement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To declare United States policy on international climate cooperation, to authorize assistance to promote clean and efficient energy technologies in foreign countries, and to establish the International Clean Energy Foundation.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400231"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400253" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400128" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400280" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400102" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400380" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400122" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400271" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400430" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400379" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400003" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400423" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400355" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400437" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412198" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412188" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400087" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400638" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400193" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412186" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400371" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400025" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400179" joined="2007-05-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179806400" datetime="2007-05-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 29 - 16.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1183047600" datetime="2007-06-28T13:20:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Foreign Affairs. H. Rept. 110-215.</text></action>
		<calendar number="131" date="1183047660" datetime="2007-06-28T13:21:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 131.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/28/2007--Reported to House amended. International Climate Cooperation Re-engagement Act of 2007 - Title I: United States Policy on Global Climate Change - (Sec. 103) Establishes within the Department of State an Office on Global Climate Change, which shall be headed by the Ambassador-at-Large for Global Climate Change. States that the primary responsibility of the Ambassador-at-Large shall be to advance U.S. goals with respect to reducing global greenhouse gas emissions and addressing global climate change. Authorizes the Ambassador-at-Large to represent the United States in diplomatic contacts relating to global climate change. Title II: Assistance to Promote Clean and Efficient Energy Technologies in Foreign Countries - (Sec. 202) Directs the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) to support policies and programs in developing countries that promote clean and efficient energy technologies to: (1) produce the necessary market conditions for private sector delivery of energy and environmental management services; and (2) promote the use of American-made clean and efficient energy technologies, products, and energy and environmental management services. Directs the Administrator to report to the appropriate committees annually respecting implementation of such policies and programs through FY2012. Authorizes FY2008-FY2012 appropriations. (Sec. 203) States that the Secretary of Commerce shall direct the United States and Foreign Commercial Service to expand or create a Foreign Commercial Service corps to promote U.S. exports in clean and efficient energy technologies and build the capacity of government officials in India, China, and other countries to become more familiar with clean energy technologies. Directs the Secretary to report to the appropriate committees respecting such activities for each of FY2008-FY2012. Authorizes FY2008-FY2012 appropriations. (Sec. 204) States that the Secretary of Commerce shall direct the International Trade Administration to expand or create trade missions to and from the United States to encourage private sector trade and investment in clean and efficient energy technologies by: (1) organizing trade missions to foreign countries and by matching U.S. private sector companies with foreign market opportunities; and (2) creating reverse trade missions in which the Department of Commerce facilitates the meeting of foreign private and public sector organizations with U.S. private sector companies. Directs the Secretary to report to the appropriate committees respecting such activities for each of FY2008-FY2012. Authorizes FY2008-FY2012 appropriations. (Sec. 205) Expresses the sense of Congress that the Overseas Private Investment Corporation (OPIC) should promote greater investment in clean and efficient energy technologies by: (1) reaching out to U.S. companies that are interested in investing in clean and efficient energy technologies in countries that are significant contributors to global greenhouse gas emissions; (2) giving preferential treatment to projects that involve the investment or utilization of clean and efficient energy technologies; and (3) providing greater flexibility in supporting projects that involve the investment or utilization of clean and efficient energy technologies. Requires that OPIC include such activities (or an explanation for the lack of such activities) in its annual report. (Sec. 206) Requires the Director of the Trade and Development Agency to establish policies that fund, and give priority to, projects that involve clean and efficient energy technologies, particularly to countries that have the potential for significant reduction in greenhouse gas emissions. Directs the President to include such activities in the annual Trade and Development Agency report. (Sec. 207) Authorizes the Secretary of State to establish a global climate change exchange program to strengthen research, educational exchange, and international cooperation with the aim of reducing global greenhouse gas emissions and addressing global climate change. Directs the Secretary to report to the appropriate committees respecting such activities for each of FY2008-FY2012. Authorizes FY2008-FY2012 appropriations. (Sec. 208) Directs the President to provide assistance to the Interagency Working Group to support a Clean Energy Technology Exports Initiative to: (1) leverage federal resources to enhance the export of U.S. clean energy technologies; (2) fulfill the mission and objectives of the Five-Year Strategic Plan of the Clean Energy Technology Exports Initiative; and (3) raise the oversight level of the Interagency Working Group to the heads of the federal departments and agencies that are participating in the Group. Directs the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, the Secretary of Commerce, and the Secretary of Energy to report to the appropriate congressional committees respecting such activities for each of FY2008-FY2012. Authorizes FY2008-FY2012 appropriations. Title III: International Clean Energy Foundation - (Sec. 302) Establishes the International Clean Energy Foundation which shall serve the long-term foreign policy and energy security goals of reducing global greenhouse gas emissions. Directs the Foundation to: (1) make grants for projects outside of the United States to reduce global greenhouse gas emissions through clean and efficient energy technologies, processes, and services; (2) seek contributions from foreign governments and private organizations to supplement funds made available under this title; (3) harness global expertise through collaborative partnerships with foreign governments and domestic and foreign private actors, by leveraging public and private capital, technology, expertise, and services towards innovative models to reduce global greenhouse gas emissions; (4) create a repository of best practices; and (5) promote the use of American-made clean and efficient energy technologies, processes, and services. Directs the Foundation to report annually to the appropriate congressional committees. Authorizes FY2008-FY2012 appropriations.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
