<bill session="110" type="h" number="2431" updated="2009-01-08T21:55:07-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179806400" datetime="2007-05-22"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179806400" datetime="2007-05-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Border Infrastructure and Technology Modernization Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize appropriations for border and transportation security personnel and technology, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400657"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400335" joined="2007-05-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179806400" datetime="2007-05-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text></action>
		<action date="1181188800" datetime="2007-06-07"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border, Maritime, and Global Counterterrorism.</text></action>
		<action date="1181188800" datetime="2007-06-07"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emerging Threats, Cybersecurity, and Science and Technology.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/22/2007--Introduced.<br/>Border Infrastructure and Technology Modernization Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to: (1) increase, during FY2008-FY2012, the number of agents in the U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement of the DHS and the number of officers and agricultural specialists in the U.S. Customs and Border Protection of the DHS; and (2) provide such agents, officers, and agricultural specialists new technology training to a level of proficiency acceptable to protect U.S. borders. Directs the Commissioner of the U.S. Customs and Border Protection to review and update, and submit to Congress, the Port of Entry Infrastructure Assessment Study and the nationwide strategy to prioritize and address the infrastructure needs at the land ports-of-entry. Directs the Secretary to prepare annually, and submit to Congress, a National Land Border Security Plan that includes a vulnerability assessment of each port of entry located on the U.S. northern and southern borders. Authorizes the Secretary to establish one or more port security coordinators at such ports of entry. Directs the Commissioner to: (1) develop a plan to expand the Customs-Trade Partnership Against Terrorism program or other voluntary government-private sector programs to improve overall international supply chain security, including security along the U.S. northern and southern borders; and (2) establish a demonstration program to develop a cooperative trade security system to improve supply chain security along the southern border. Directs the Secretary to carry out a technology demonstration program to test and evaluate new port of entry technologies that enhance port of entry inspections and the detection of weapons of mass destruction, and to train personnel in its use. Sets forth streamlining procedures and certain local employment requirements for projects and programs under this Act. 
	</summary>
</bill>
