<bill session="110" type="h" number="2442" updated="2009-01-08T21:56:23-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179806400" datetime="2007-05-22"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179806400" datetime="2007-05-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Rural America Job Assistance and Creation Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide job creation and assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400264"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179806400" datetime="2007-05-22"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1118-1119)</text></action>
		<action date="1179806400" datetime="2007-05-22"><text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, the Judiciary, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1179806400" datetime="2007-05-22"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1179806400" datetime="2007-05-22"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1179806400" datetime="2007-05-22"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1179806400" datetime="2007-05-22"><text>Referred to House Financial Services</text></action>
		<action date="1182744000" datetime="2007-06-25"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text></action>
		<action date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness.</text></action>
		<action date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/22/2007--Introduced.<br/>Rural America Job Assistance and Creation Act - Directs the Secretary of Labor to make matching grants to regional consortia meeting specified criteria to improve the job skills necessary for employment in specific industries. Directs the Secretary of Commerce to make grants to establish and support entities that provide business incubator services (necessary to initiate and sustain operations of a newly established business, including legal, intellectual property, and technology services and planning) for small- and medium-sized businesses. Directs the Comptroller General to study how rural infrastructure, venture capital, and federal programs can enhance rural areas. Amends the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act to require employer notification of federal and state elected officials (as well as local ones) before dislocation of workers. Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to require submission of H-1B labor condition applications at same time as H-1B nonimmigrant classification petitions.<br/>Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) exclude certain amounts of severance payments from gross income; and (2) expand the work opportunity tax credit to include qualified small business employees.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
