<bill session="110" type="h" number="244" updated="2009-01-08T17:14:27-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"/></status>

	<introduced date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Technology Retraining and Investment Now Act for the 21st Century</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow a credit against income for certain education and training expenses, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400429"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E27)</text></action>
		<action date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/5/2007--Introduced.<br/>Technology Retraining and Investment Now Act for the 21st Century - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a tax credit for 50 percent of the information and communications technology education and training program expenses of individuals and employees, up to $4,000 in a taxable year. Increases the allowable amount of such credit to $5,000 for expenses for a program operated: (1) in an empowerment zone, enterprise community, or renewal community; (2) in a school district in which at least 50 percent of the students are eligible for free or reduced-cost lunches; (3) in an federally-declared disaster area; (4) in certain rural areas receiving federal assistance; (5) in an Indian tribal jurisdiction; (6) by an employer with 200 or fewer employees during a specified period; or (7) for a disabled individual. Defines &quot;information technology education and training program expenses&quot; to include: (1) course work; (2) certification testing; (3) apprenticeship programs registered by the Department of Labor; and (4) other expenses essential to assessing skill acquisition. Redefines &quot;eligible educational institution&quot; to include a commercial information and communications technology training provider. Establishes an Information Technology Training Certification Advisory Board to develop: (1) guidelines for computer science, information technology, and related college courses; and (2) a list of the information technology training and certifications that qualify for the tax credit established by this Act.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
