<bill session="110" type="h" number="2446" updated="2009-01-08T21:56:54-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1181165520" datetime="2007-06-06T18:32:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="438"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179806400" datetime="2007-05-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Afghanistan Freedom and Security Support Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Afghanistan Freedom and Security Support Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Afghanistan Freedom and Security Support Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To reauthorize the Afghanistan Freedom Support Act of 2002, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400231"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400344" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400003" joined="2007-05-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179806400" datetime="2007-05-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23" ><text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1180043340" datetime="2007-05-24T18:49:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Crowley asked unanimous consent that the Committee on Foreign Affairs have until midnight on May 31 to file a report on H.R. 2446. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action date="1180556880" datetime="2007-05-30T17:28:00-04:00"><text>Reported by the Committee on Foreign Affairs. H. Rept. 110-170.</text></action>
		<calendar number="102" date="1180556880" datetime="2007-05-30T17:28:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 102.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1181087040" datetime="2007-06-05T20:44:00-04:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 453 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2446 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. A specified amendment is in order. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. Notwithstanding clause 11 of rule XVIII, no amendment to the bill shall be in order except those printed in the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution.</text></action>
		<action date="1181149680" datetime="2007-06-06T14:08:00-04:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 453 passed House.</text></action>
		<action date="1181151180" datetime="2007-06-06T14:33:00-04:00"><text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 453.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H6048-6073"/><reference label="text as reported in House" ref="CR H6054-6062"/></action>
		<action date="1181151180" datetime="2007-06-06T14:33:00-04:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2446 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. A specified amendment is in order. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. Notwithstanding clause 11 of rule XVIII, no amendment to the bill shall be in order except those printed in the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution.</text></action>
		<action date="1181151180" datetime="2007-06-06T14:33:00-04:00"><text>ORDER OF PROCEDURE - Mr. Lantos asked unanimous consent that during consideration of H.R. 2446 in the Committee of the Whole, pursuant to H. Res. 453, amendment no. 11 be permitted to be offered at any time. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action date="1181151240" datetime="2007-06-06T14:34:00-04:00"><text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 453 and Rule XVIII.</text></action>
		<action date="1181151300" datetime="2007-06-06T14:35:00-04:00"><text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Mike Ross to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text></action>
		<action date="1181151300" datetime="2007-06-06T14:35:00-04:00"><text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 2446.</text></action>
		<action date="1181154720" datetime="2007-06-06T15:32:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions in H. Res 453, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lantos amendment.</text></action>
		<action date="1181154780" datetime="2007-06-06T15:33:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 453, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ackerman amendment.</text></action>
		<action date="1181155380" datetime="2007-06-06T15:43:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Souder amendment.</text></action>
		<action date="1181155620" datetime="2007-06-06T15:47:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 453, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Costa amendment.</text></action>
		<action date="1181156280" datetime="2007-06-06T15:58:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 453, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Franks(AZ) amendment.</text></action>
		<action date="1181156700" datetime="2007-06-06T16:05:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 453, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson-Lee amendment numbered 5.</text></action>
		<action date="1181157120" datetime="2007-06-06T16:12:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 453, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson-Lee (TX) amendment.</text></action>
		<action date="1181157660" datetime="2007-06-06T16:21:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 453, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kirk amendment.</text></action>
		<action date="1181157960" datetime="2007-06-06T16:26:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Kirk amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Kirk demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text></action>
		<action date="1181158020" datetime="2007-06-06T16:27:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 453, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kucinich amendment.</text></action>
		<action date="1181158560" datetime="2007-06-06T16:36:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Kucinich amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Kucinich demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text></action>
		<action date="1181158680" datetime="2007-06-06T16:38:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 453, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Terry amendment.</text></action>
		<action date="1181158920" datetime="2007-06-06T16:42:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 453, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Van Hollen amendment.</text></action>
		<action date="1181159460" datetime="2007-06-06T16:51:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Lantos moved that the Committee rise.</text></action>
		<action date="1181159460" datetime="2007-06-06T16:51:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text></action>
		<action date="1181159460" datetime="2007-06-06T16:51:00-04:00"><text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2446 as unfinished business.</text></action>
		<action date="1181161080" datetime="2007-06-06T17:18:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H6073-6077"/></action>
		<action date="1181161080" datetime="2007-06-06T17:18:00-04:00"><text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text></action>
		<action date="1181161140" datetime="2007-06-06T17:19:00-04:00"><text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1181163180" datetime="2007-06-06T17:53:00-04:00"><text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2446.</text></action>
		<action date="1181163240" datetime="2007-06-06T17:54:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H6075"/></action>
		<action date="1181163300" datetime="2007-06-06T17:55:00-04:00"><text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text></action>
		<action date="1181163300" datetime="2007-06-06T17:55:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Pence moved to recommit with instructions to Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1181163480" datetime="2007-06-06T17:58:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Pence motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment inserting a new section concerning Congressional findings that the United States and Coalition forces have intercepted weapons in Afghanistan headed for the Taliban that were made in Iran.</text></action>
		<action date="1181163900" datetime="2007-06-06T18:05:00-04:00"><text>The previous question on the motion was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H6076"/></action>
		<action date="1181164860" datetime="2007-06-06T18:21:00-04:00"><text>On motion to recommit with instructions Agreed to by recorded vote: 345 - 71 (Roll no. 437).</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H6075-6076"/><reference label="text" ref="CR H6075"/></action>
		<vote date="1181165520" how="roll" roll="438" datetime="2007-06-06T18:32:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 406 - 10 (Roll no. 438).</text></vote>
		<action date="1181165520" datetime="2007-06-06T18:32:00-04:00"><text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 2446.</text></action>
		<action date="1181188800" datetime="2007-06-07"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
		<action date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"><text>Star Print ordered on the bill.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/6/2007--Passed House amended. Afghanistan Freedom and Security Support Act of 2007 - Title I: Economic and Democratic Development Assistance for Afghanistan - (Sec. 103) Amends the Afghanistan Freedom Support Act of 2002 to provide for assistance with respect to: (1) continuing humanitarian needs; (2) a pilot program of crop substitution for poppy production; (3) agriculture, health, and infrastructure reconstruction; (4) education and anti-corruption, including implementation of the Afghan action plan on transitional justice; (5) assistance to women and girls; (6) energy development and short-term energy supply; and (7) capacity building. Authorizes additional FY2008-FY2010 appropriations for: (1) contributions to the United Nations Drug Control Program; and (2) the crop substitution program. Directs the President to report to Congress every 180 days through FY2010 respecting implementation of the crop substitution program. Authorizes FY2008-FY2010 appropriations for: (1) the Afghan Ministry of Women's Affairs; (2) the Afghan Independent Human Rights Commission; (3) grants to Afghan-led nongovernmental organizations, including Afghan women-led nongovernmental organizations; and (4) short-term energy supply assistance. States that the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) should give priority to U.S. organizations for grants to aid in Afghanistan's revitalization. (Sec. 104) Directs the President to provide Congress with an annual certification of whether any senior official of the government of Afghanistan, at the provincial or local levels, is engaged in or benefits from the illicit narcotics trade or is engaged in terrorist or criminal activities. Prohibits, as of FY2009, assistance to a local or provincial government of Afghanistan if the President certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that one or more senior officials from such provincial or local government is engaged in or benefits from the narcotics trade or is engaged in terrorist or criminal activities. (Sec. 105) Directs the President to: (1) establish and implement a system to monitor and evaluate the effectiveness of assistance provided under this title on a program-by-program basis to maximize such assistance's long-term impact; (2) establish assistance performance goals; and (3) provide assistance to enhance the government of Afghanistan's capacity to monitor and evaluate programs carried out by Afghan national, provincial, and local governments. Obligates specified funds for such purposes. (Sec. 106) Directs the President to provide assistance to support the auditing and oversight capacities of the Offices of the Inspector General of the Department of State and USAID in Afghanistan. Requires such Offices to maintain a permanent in-country presence in Afghanistan. Provides FY2008-FY2010 funding. (Sec. 107) Directs the President to appoint a Coordinator for U.S. assistance programs for Afghanistan. (Sec. 108) Directs the Secretary of State to establish a FY2008-FY2010 pilot program to provide scholarships to Afghan university students for public policy internships in the United States. (Sec. 109) Authorizes FY2008-FY2010 appropriations for economic and democratic development assistance for Afghanistan. Title II: Assistance for a New Framework for Afghanistan - Subtitle A: Amendments to the Afghanistan Freedom Support Act of 2002 - (Sec. 201) Revises the cap on military drawdown assistance from $550 million aggregate to $300 million per fiscal year. Expresses the sense of Congress that such assistance to eligible foreign countries and international organizations should: (1) promote greater interoperability with and among the military forces of the International Security Assistance Force (ISAF), the United States, and the government of Afghanistan; and (2) be used in part to protect women legislators when they return to their respective provinces. (Sec. 203) Authorizes the President to provide a subsidy of up to 5% of the acquisition cost of U.S. defense items if the purchasing nation will use such items or comparable defense items it already possesses in military operations in Afghanistan for an extended period of time. Authorizes FY2008-FY2010 appropriations. (Sec. 204) Extends the Afghanistan Freedom Support Act of 2002 through FY2010. Subtitle B: Other Matters - (Sec. 211) Directs the U.S. Armed Forces to continue to support counter-narcotics interdiction operations in Afghanistan in coordination with Afghanistan and with support from the United Kingdom and other countries. Directs the President to: (1) enhance civilian counter-narcotics teams; and (2) ensure that assistance to the Afghan National Police includes vetting procedures. Authorizes the participation of foreign counter-narcotics personnel. (Sec. 212) States that is U.S. policy to encourage the governments of Pakistan and friendly Arab countries to increase reconstruction assistance to, and diplomatic support for, Afghanistan. Directs the President to encourage Afghanistan-Pakistan military cooperation. (Sec. 213) Authorizes the President to provide training for foreign military personnel who are to be deployed to Afghanistan, particularly in the areas of special operations, counter-insurgency, border security, counter-terrorism, and counter-narcotics. Authorizes additional FY2008-FY2010 appropriations. (Sec. 214) Expresses the sense of Congress that the President should be commended for and should continue ongoing assistance programs to innocent Afghan civilians who have suffered a serious loss during U.S. military operations. Directs the President to report to the appropriate congressional committees on the feasibility of specified additions to such assistance programs. (Sec. 215) Expresses the sense of Congress that the U.N. Security Council should expand the UN mandate in Afghanistan to: (1) authorize international civilian law enforcement missions as a part of the peace operations in Afghanistan; (2) authorize, with the government of Afghanistan's concurrence, ISAF to participate in counter-drug interdiction operations; (3) centralize authority within the United Nations Special Representative for Afghanistan; and (4) extend ISAF's authorization beyond October 13, 2007. (Sec. 216) Directs the Secretary of Defense to report to the appropriate congressional committees every six months on the sale and use of Iranian-made weapons for the Taliban in Afghanistan. Title III: Miscellaneous Provisions - (Sec. 301) Extends the donor contributions to Afghanistan reporting requirement through December 31, 2010. Revises the committees to which the Secretary of State must report. (Sec. 302) Replaces the existing Afghanistan reporting requirement of the Secretary of State with a comprehensive report by the President every six months through September 30, 2010, on progress and security in Afghanistan. (Sec. 303) Directs the President to formulate a comprehensive interagency strategy for long-term security and stability in Afghanistan which shall include strategies for reconstruction, counter-narcotics, and Afghanistan National Security Forces sustainability. (Sec. 304) Authorizes the President to appoint a special envoy to promote closer Afghanistan-Pakistan cooperation. (Sec. 305) States that it shall be U.S. policy to encourage Pakistan to permit Indian shipments across Pakistan's territory of equipment and material to Afghanistan in support of Indian reconstruction and development projects in Afghanistan. Directs the President to report annually until January 1, 2010, regarding actions taken by Pakistan to permit or impede such transit. (Sec. 306) Authorizes FY2008-FY2010 appropriations for Radio Free Afghanistan. (Sec. 307) Amends the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 to authorize under certain circumstances officers or employees of the government of Afghanistan or Pakistan to receive an award under the Department of State rewards program. (Sec. 308) States that nothing in this Act shall be construed to limit the ability of the United States to respond to Iranian-supported or facilitated attacks against U.S. Armed Forces or interests in Afghanistan.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
