<bill session="110" type="h" number="2466" updated="2009-01-08T21:59:28-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Violent Crime Reduction Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, to prevent gang crime, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400365"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400137" joined="2007-05-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400071" joined="2007-05-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23"><text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/23/2007--Introduced.<br/>Violent Crime Reduction Act of 2007 - Amends the federal criminal code to: (1) impose mandatory minimum prison terms for violent crimes committed to further racketeering activities; (2) increase penalties for using or carrying a firearm while committing a crime of violence or a drug trafficking crime; and (3) grant to off-duty law enforcement officers an exemption from the prohibition against possessing a firearm in a school zone.<br/>Amends the Controlled Substances Act to impose enhanced criminal penalties for committing a crime of violence (i.e., murder, kidnapping, aggravated sexual abuse, maiming, or assault resulting in serious bodily injury) during and in relation to a drug trafficking crime.<br/>Directs the Attorney General to establish and assist anti-gang task forces comprised of federal, state, and local law enforcement authorities to combat criminal gangs and offenders.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
