<bill session="110" type="h" number="2465" updated="2009-01-08T21:59:21-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Income-Dependent Education Assistance Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To allow for the consolidation of Federal student loans into a single direct income-contingent loan repayment program.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400318"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400254" joined="2007-06-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1136)</text></action>
		<action date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23"><text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/23/2007--Introduced.<br/>Income-Dependent Education Assistance Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of Education to conduct a direct income-dependent education assistance (IDEA) loan program, from July 1, 2008, through July 1, 2014, under which student borrowers of Federal Family Education Loans (FFELs) or Direct Loans (DLs), under parts B and D of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965, may elect to convert or consolidate such loans to direct IDEA loans. Provides that when a student defaults on a loan under the FFEL or DL programs and it is repaid or canceled by the Secretary, it is thereby converted to a direct IDEA loan. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide for collection of IDEA loan repayments through the income tax collection system.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
