<bill session="110" type="h" number="2473" updated="2009-01-08T22:00:20-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Voluntary Public Access and Wildlife Habitat Incentive Program Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Food Security Act of 1985 to encourage owners and operators of privately-held farm, ranch, and forest land to voluntarily make their land available for access by the public under programs administered by States and tribal governments.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400323"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400155" joined="2007-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400376" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="412210" joined="2007-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400274" joined="2008-01-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400264" joined="2007-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400284" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400321" joined="2007-07-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text></action>
		<action date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Credit, Energy, and Research.</text></action>
		<action date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"><text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/24/2007--Introduced.<br/>Voluntary Public Access and Wildlife Habitat Incentive Program Act of 2007 - Amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to establish a program under which states and tribal governments may apply for grants to encourage owners and operators of privately-held farm, ranch, and forest land to voluntarily make such land available for public access for wildlife-dependent recreation (including hunting or fishing) under state- and tribally-administered plans. Amends the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 to exclude from excess base acreage computation for direct and counter-cyclical payment purposes certain conservation enrolled farm land not planted in an agricultural commodity.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
