<bill session="110" type="h" number="2475" updated="2009-01-08T22:00:33-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Veteran Home Equity Conversation [sic] Mortgage Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to guarantee home equity conversion mortgages for elderly veteran homeowners.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400274"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400209" joined="2008-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400051" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400193" joined="2007-07-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/><text>Referred to House Financial Services</text></action>
		<action date="1180411200" datetime="2007-05-29"><committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text></action>
		<action date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"><committee name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1197262800" datetime="2007-12-10"><committee name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/24/2007--Introduced.<br/>Veteran Home Equity Conversation [sic] Mortgage Act of 2007 - Authorizes the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to guarantee any home equity conversion mortgage (mortgage) made to an elderly (62 or older) veteran homeowner, as long as the Secretary determines that the mortgage: (1) is likely to improve the financial situation or otherwise meet the special needs of the homeowner; (2) will include safeguards to offset special risks associated with such a mortgage; and (3) has appropriate terms to ensure its acceptance in the secondary mortgage market. Allows such mortgage to be guaranteed only if it is secured by a dwelling, farm residence, or manufactured home permanently affixed to a lot that is owned and occupied by the elderly veteran homeowner. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) guarantee any mortgage given to refinance an existing home equity conversion mortgage guaranteed by the Secretary; (2) establish a mortgage guarantee fee; and (3) waive the mortgage guarantee fee in certain circumstances.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
