<bill session="110" type="h" number="2480" updated="2009-01-08T22:01:08-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Gas Price Relief Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to suspend the Federal motor fuel excise taxes until the average price of unleaded gasoline is below $3 per gallon for at least 6 months.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400177"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412210" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412240" joined="2007-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="412233" joined="2007-06-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/24/2007--Introduced.<br/>Gas Price Relief Act of 2007 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to suspend certain federal motor fuel excise taxes until the average price of unleaded regular gasoline is less than $3.00 per gallon for a period of six consecutive months (suspension period). Provides for adjustments to such excise taxes for floor stocks of motor fuels held by dealers prior to or after the suspension period.<br/>Repeals provisions allowing a taxpayer election to expense the cost of qualified refinery property. Transfers to the Highway Trust Fund increased tax revenues resulting from such repeal.<br/>Requires the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to monitor gasoline prices in the United States and to report to Congress on its findings.<br/>Requires the Speaker of the House of Representatives to establish a Commission on Gas Price Relief to study the causes of high oil prices. 
	</summary>
</bill>
