<bill session="110" type="h" number="2498" updated="2009-01-08T22:03:13-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for a study regarding development of a comprehensive integrated regional water management plan that would address four general areas of regional water planning in both the San Joaquin River Hydrologic Region and the Tulare Lake Hydrologic Region, inclusive of Kern, Tulare, Kings, Fresno, Madera, Merced, Stanislaus, and San Joaquin Counties, California, and to provide that such plan be the guide by which those counties use as a mechanism to address and solve long-term water needs in a sustainable and equitable manner.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400618"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400330" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412190" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400065" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400297" joined="2007-05-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1180584000" datetime="2007-05-31"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text></action>
		<action date="1190692800" datetime="2007-09-25"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1192507200" datetime="2007-10-16"><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1192507200" datetime="2007-10-16"><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee Without Recommendation (Amended) by Unanimous Consent .</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/24/2007--Introduced.<br/>Directs the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Reclamation, to award a grant to the California Water Institute, located at California State University at Fresno, to conduct a study coordinating and integrating sub-regional integrated regional water management plans into a unified Integrated Regional Water Management Plan for Kern, Tulare, Kings, Fresno, Madera, Merced, Stanislaus, and San Joaquin counties in the San Joaquin River Hydrologic Region and the Tulare Lake Hydrologic Region that would address issues related to: (1) water quality, supply, conveyance, and reliability; (2) flood control; (3) water resource-related environmental enhancement; and (4) population growth. Provides that the Plan developed for the two hydrologic basins shall serve as a guide for the eight counties in the study area to use as a mechanism to address and solve long-term water needs in a sustainable and equitable manner. 
	</summary>
</bill>
