<bill session="110" type="h" number="2504" updated="2009-01-08T22:03:53-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">L-1 Nonimmigrant Reform Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act with respect to the admission of L-1 intra-company transferee nonimmigrants.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400103"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400233" joined="2007-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400309" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412233" joined="2007-05-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1182744000" datetime="2007-06-25"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/24/2007--Introduced.<br/>L-1 Nonimmigrant Reform Act - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to revise L-1 (intracompany transfers) nonimmigrant visa provisions. Prohibits entry of an L-1 worker unless the employer has filed a labor condition application with the Secretary of Labor which shall attest that: (1) wage and working condition comparability exists; (2) no strike or lockout exists in the occupational classification at the employment site; (3) the employer has notified the bargaining representative or the employees about the prospective L-1 hiring; (4) the L-1 application contains occupational classification and wage and working condition information; and (5) there has not been nor will there be any lay-off of U.S. workers 180 days before or after the L-1 hiring. Directs the Secretary and the Secretary of Homeland Security to: (1) establish processes for receipt, investigation, and disposition of violation claims; (2) establish a process to permit an L-1 alien who files a complaint to work for another employer; and (3) report annually on the use of L-1 workers. Sets forth employer violation provisions. Makes an employer liable for the return transportation costs of an L-1 worker dismissed from employment prior to the end of the authorized admission. Imposes a fee on an L-1 employer. Establishes in the Treasury the L-1 Nonimmigrant Petitioner Account, which shall be used for data processing, labor enforcement, and training and education of U.S. workers. Establishes an annual 35,000 L-1 visa limit. Eliminates L-1 blanket visa authority. Requires: (1) an L-1 worker to have a bachelor's degree or higher in his or her area of special knowledge; and (2) verification by the Secretary of State. Increases the prior foreign employment requirement.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
