<bill session="110" type="h" number="2535" updated="2009-01-08T22:07:34-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1221688920" datetime="2008-09-17T19:02:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Tule River Tribe Water Development Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Tule River Tribe Water Development Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Tule River Tribe Water Development Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a study on the feasibility and suitability of constructing a storage reservoir, outlet works, and a delivery system for the Tule River Indian Tribe of California to provide a water supply for domestic, municipal, industrial, and agricultural purposes, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400297"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400618" joined="2007-05-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1180584000" datetime="2007-05-31"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text></action>
		<action date="1190692800" datetime="2007-09-25"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1216094400" datetime="2008-07-15"><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1216094400" datetime="2008-07-15"><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee Without Recommendation by Unanimous Consent .</text></action>
		<action date="1216180800" datetime="2008-07-16"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1216180800" datetime="2008-07-16" ><text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1217540220" datetime="2008-07-31T18:37:00-04:00"><text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-812.</text></action>
		<calendar number="526" date="1217540220" datetime="2008-07-31T18:37:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 526.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1221498540" datetime="2008-09-15T14:09:00-04:00"><text>Ms. Bordallo moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text></action>
		<action date="1221498540" datetime="2008-09-15T14:09:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8053-8054"/></action>
		<action date="1221498540" datetime="2008-09-15T14:09:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2535.</text></action>
		<action date="1221499260" datetime="2008-09-15T14:21:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Bishop (UT) objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text></action>
		<action date="1221688920" datetime="2008-09-17T19:02:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8368-8369"/></action>
		<vote date="1221688920" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-09-17T19:02:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote. (text: CR 9/15/2008 H8053)</text></vote>
		<action date="1222056000" datetime="2008-09-22"><text>Received in the Senate.</text></action>
		<action date="1222920000" datetime="2008-10-02"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/17/2008--Passed House without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Tule River Tribe Water Development Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Reclamation, by the later of two years after funds are appropriated for this Act or the signing of a reserved water rights settlement agreement by the Tule River Tribe of California and other settling water users, to complete a feasibility study to evaluate alternatives for a domestic, commercial, municipal, industrial, and irrigation water supply for the Tule River Tribe of the Tule River Reservation. Prohibits any project conducted in relation to that study from providing water supplies for any other Tribal casino, except: (1) the casino in its current form and dimensions operated by the Tribe on the Tule River Reservation; and (2) any lodging, dining, entertainment, meeting space, parking, or other similar facilities which may be constructed in the future in support of current, or any future expansion of, on-Reservation gaming activities.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
