<bill session="110" type="h" number="255" updated="2009-01-08T17:15:50-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"/></status>

	<introduced date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Manufacturing Technology Competitiveness Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish an interagency committee to coordinate Federal manufacturing research and development efforts in manufacturing, strengthen existing programs to assist manufacturing innovation and education, and expand outreach programs for small and medium-sized manufacturers, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400119"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400123" joined="2007-03-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400228" joined="2007-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400196" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2007-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400040" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400264" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400652" joined="2007-03-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400285" joined="2007-04-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400152" joined="2007-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400147" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400218" joined="2007-03-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Science and Technology.</text></action>
		<action date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology and Innovation.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/5/2007--Introduced.<br/>Manufacturing Technology Competitiveness Act of 2007 - Directs the President to establish or designate an Interagency Committee to plan and coordinate Federal efforts in manufacturing research and development, with an Advisory Committee from the non-Federal sector. Amends the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act (NIST Act) to establish: (1) a pilot program of collaborative manufacturing research grants; (2) manufacturing sciences research fellowships; (3) manufacturing extension center competitive grants; and (4) standards education grants to develop higher education curricula on the role of standards in engineering, business, science, and economics. Revises requirements under the NIST Manufacturing Extension Partnership program. Authorizes appropriations to the Secretary of Commerce for the following NIST programs: (1) scientific and technical research and services laboratory activities; (2) the Malcolm Baldrige National Quality Award (under the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980); (3) construction and maintenance of facilities; (4) Teacher Science and Technology Enhancement Institute; (5) Manufacturing Extension Partnership (through the Secretary or other appropriate Federal agencies); (6) Collaborative Manufacturing Research Pilot Grants; and (7) Manufacturing Fellowships.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
