<bill session="110" type="h" number="2556" updated="2009-01-08T22:10:11-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Energy Savings Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Biofuels for Energy Security and Transportation Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Carbon Capture and Sequestration Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Energy Efficiency Promotion Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">United States Energy Storage Competitiveness Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance the energy security of the United States by promoting biofuels, energy efficiency, and carbon capture and storage, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400434"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Science and Technology, Transportation and Infrastructure, Oversight and Government Reform, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text></action>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text></action>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Referred to House Financial Services</text></action>
		<action date="1180065600" datetime="2007-05-25"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text></action>
		<action date="1180065600" datetime="2007-05-25"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text></action>
		<action date="1180065600" datetime="2007-05-25"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
		<action date="1180584000" datetime="2007-05-31"><committee name="House Science and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/24/2007--Introduced.<br/>Energy Savings Act of 2007 - Biofuels for Energy Security and Transportation Act of 2007 - Sets forth a schedule for motor vehicle fuel, home heating oil, and boiler fuel to contain specified volumes of renewable fuel by calendar year 2022.<br/>Prescribes a pilot program to establish refueling infrastructure corridors for gasoline blends containing renewable fuel.<br/>Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to: (1) increase funding for bioenergy research and development; (2) establish bioresearch centers that target biofuels; and (3) authorize loan guarantees for renewable fuel facilities.<br/>Establishes a grants program for: (1) renewable fuel production in states with low rates of ethanol production; and (2) transportation of biomass to local biorefineries.<br/>Directs the Secretary of Energy to establish a biorefinery information center.<br/>Amends the Energy Policy Act of 1992 to direct the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to impose a fuel tank cap labeling requirement for alternative fueled vehicles.<br/>Requires studies on specified renewable fuels and biofuels.<br/>Energy Efficiency Promotion Act of 2007 - Amends the National Energy Conservation Policy Act regarding advanced lighting technologies.<br/>Amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to prescribe new energy efficiency standards.<br/>Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 with respect to high efficiency vehicles, advanced batteries, and energy storage.<br/>United States Energy Storage Competitiveness Act of 2007 - Instructs the Secretary of Energy to: (1) implement a research and development program for energy storage systems for motor transportation and electricity transmission and distribution; and (2) establish an Energy Storage Advisory Council.<br/>Sets forth national goals for: (1) energy savings in transportation; and (2) national energy efficiency improvement.<br/>Amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act regarding federal fleet conservation requirements.<br/>Prescribes implementation of energy efficiency and renewable energy initiatives with respect to federal facilities.<br/>Extends programs assisting state and local governments with energy efficiency programs.<br/>Amends the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 regarding utility energy efficiency programs.<br/>Provides: (1) technical assistance to governmental entities for energy efficiency and demand response programs, including an energy and environmental block grant; and (2) energy efficiency grants to institutions of higher education.<br/>Carbon Capture and Sequestration Act of 2007 - Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to establish a carbon capture and storage research and demonstration program.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
