<bill session="110" type="h" number="2554" updated="2009-01-08T22:09:57-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">After Care Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18 of the United States Code to require HIV testing of Federal prisoners about to be released, to direct the Attorney General of the United States and the Secretary of Health and Human Services to provide HIV/AIDS treatment for recently released Federal prisoners, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400423"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1182744000" datetime="2007-06-25"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/24/2007--Introduced.<br/>After Care Act of 2007 - Amends the federal criminal code to require: (1) the Attorney General to provide for the testing of prisoners about to be released from a federal facility for the human immunodeficiency virus; and (2) courts to order defendants testing positive for the virus to accept HIV/AIDS treatment as a condition of supervised release and to notify any prospective sexual partner of HIV/AIDS status.<br/>Requires the Attorney General and the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish and maintain a program for HIV/AIDS treatment of prisoners for two years after release by the Bureau of Prisons.<br/>Prohibits individuals receiving HIV/AIDS medication, including antiretrovirals, through a federal program from selling or trading such medication.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
