<bill session="110" type="h" number="2569" updated="2009-01-08T22:11:41-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1181016000" datetime="2007-06-05"/></status>

	<introduced date="1181016000" datetime="2007-06-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Broadband Deployment Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To codify certain changes proposed by the Department of Agriculture to the rules governing eligibility for the rural broadband access program, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400158"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1181016000" datetime="2007-06-05"><text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1181016000" datetime="2007-06-05"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action date="1181016000" datetime="2007-06-05"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1181016000" datetime="2007-06-05"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and the Internet.</text></action>
		<action date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Credit, Energy, and Research.</text></action>
		<action date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Specialty Crops, Rural Development, and Foreign Agriculture.</text></action>
		<action date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/5/2007--Introduced.<br/>Rural Broadband Deployment Act - Amends the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 with respect to rural broadband access loan or loan guarantee eligibility to: (1) not require a market survey for an applicant who is projecting less than 15% penetration of households in a service area; and (2) replace the credit support requirement, including the cash on hand requirement, with a minimum 20% of loan equity position (10% in specified situations of a single provider or limited broadband service participation area).<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
