<bill session="110" type="h" number="2566" updated="2009-01-08T22:11:20-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1181016000" datetime="2007-06-05"/></status>

	<introduced date="1181016000" datetime="2007-06-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Digital Television Consumer Education Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide American consumers information about the broadcast television transition from an analog to a digital format.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400122"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400073" joined="2007-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400246" joined="2007-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400333" joined="2007-07-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400129" joined="2007-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400424" joined="2007-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400274" joined="2007-06-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="2007-09-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400355" joined="2007-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400316" joined="2007-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400347" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400001" joined="2007-07-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="412222" joined="2007-06-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400426" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400653" joined="2007-11-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="412239" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2007-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2007-06-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2007-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400090" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2007-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="2007-06-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="412206" joined="2007-10-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1181016000" datetime="2007-06-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1181016000" datetime="2007-06-05"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and the Internet.</text></action>
		<action date="1181102400" datetime="2007-06-06"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1207)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/5/2007--Introduced.<br/>National Digital Television Consumer Education Act - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to require retail distributors of television receiving equipment (TVs) to place adjacent to each unit displayed for sale a consumer alert in English and Spanish that the TV has only an analog broadcast tuner and will require a converter box after February 17, 2009, to receive over-the-air broadcasts with an antenna. Imposes similar requirements on sellers that use direct mail, catalog, or electronic means such as the Internet. Requires broadcaster public service announcements about the deadline for termination of analog TV broadcasting and the equipment options for consumers following such termination. Directs the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to create a DTV Transition Federal Advisory Committee to educate the public about the digital television transition. Requires such education to commence by January 1, 2008. Requires the FCC to use funds available for consumer information activities to obtain advertising in public transportation vehicles and facilities to provide information concerning the digital television transition. Amends the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act to authorize the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information to establish a temporary grant program to coordinate and lead a nationwide consumer education and outreach campaign regarding America's conversion to digital television.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
