<bill session="110" type="h" number="2576" updated="2009-01-08T22:12:41-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1181102400" datetime="2007-06-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1181102400" datetime="2007-06-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Help Identify Indicators of Potential Student Aggression Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to prepare concise written materials for use by school personnel to help to identify students with a high potential to commit aggressive and harmful behavior, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400067"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-06-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2007-06-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400048" joined="2007-06-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2007-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="2007-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="412219" joined="2007-07-31"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1181102400" datetime="2007-06-06"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1181102400" datetime="2007-06-06"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1181102400" datetime="2007-06-06"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1181102400" datetime="2007-06-06"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1185249600" datetime="2007-07-24"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/6/2007--Introduced.<br/>Help Identify Indicators of Potential Student Aggression Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, to prepare and periodically revise: (1) concise written materials to be used by school personnel in elementary schools, secondary schools, and institutions of higher education to help to identify the possible warning signs of a student with a high potential to be aggressive and harmful to property, themselves, or others, and report such behavior to designated school personnel; and (2) more detailed written materials to be used by designated school personnel to determine the appropriate actions to take with respect to such a student, including whether he or she should be referred to a mental health expert. Requires the first version of such materials to be provided to the Secretary of Education within 90 days of this Act's enactment for distribution to schools.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
