<bill session="110" type="h" number="2584" updated="2009-01-08T22:13:39-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1181102400" datetime="2007-06-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1181102400" datetime="2007-06-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">High-Need Physician Workforce Incentives Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to alleviate critical shortages of physicians in the fields of family practice, internal medicine, pediatrics, emergency medicine, general surgery, and obstetrics-gynecology, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400052"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400381" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400149" joined="2007-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400657" joined="2007-06-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400344" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400235" joined="2007-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400121" joined="2007-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400070" joined="2007-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400383" joined="2007-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400651" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400321" joined="2007-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400157" joined="2007-06-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1177473600" datetime="2007-04-25"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H4168-4173)</text></action>
		<action date="1181102400" datetime="2007-06-06"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1181102400" datetime="2007-06-06"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1181102400" datetime="2007-06-06"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1181102400" datetime="2007-06-06"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1188878400" datetime="2007-09-04"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H10062-10065)</text></action>
		<action date="1191297600" datetime="2007-10-02"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H1149-1155)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/6/2007--Introduced.<br/>High-Need Physician Workforce Incentives Act of 2007 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, to make grants to critical shortage health facilities for scholarships to individuals agreeing to serve as a physician at such facility after completing residency in the fields of family practice, internal medicine, pediatrics, emergency medicine, general surgery, or obstetrics-gynecology. Excludes such scholarship funds from an individual's gross income.<br/>Requires the Secretary, acting through the Administrator, to: (1) establish a loan repayment program for individuals agreeing to serve as physicians in specified fields in areas that are not health professional shortage areas, but that have a critical shortage of physicians in such field; (2) make grants to states to provide care management fees to physicians in medically underserved communities to support the provision of targeted, accessible, continuous, coordinated, and patient-centered care through a qualified medical home; and (3) make grants to board-certified entities to establish or expand geriatric fellowship programs to train physicians practicing in rural areas or in specified fields in geriatric medicine. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to exclude from an individual's gross income compensation received by a physician from a local government for medical care performed: (1) in a medically underserved community; and (2) under a contract with the local government for a period of not less than four years. 
	</summary>
</bill>
