<bill session="110" type="h" number="2598" updated="2009-01-08T22:15:30-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1181102400" datetime="2007-06-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1181102400" datetime="2007-06-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Independent Expenditure Opt Out Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to clarify that an expenditure made by a political party committee may not be considered to have been made in concert or cooperation with a candidate solely because the candidate has requested that the committee not make any expenditures in support of the candidate or in opposition to an opponent of the candidate.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400370"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400326" joined="2007-06-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1181102400" datetime="2007-06-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/6/2007--Introduced.<br/>Independent Expenditure Opt Out Act - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to modify the definition of &quot;independent expenditure,&quot; which currently means an expenditure by a person: (1) expressly advocating the election or defeat of a clearly identified candidate; and (2) that is not made in concert or cooperation with or at the request or suggestion of such candidate, the candidate's authorized political committee, or their agents, or a political party committee or its agents. Declares that an expenditure made by a political party committee may not be considered to have been made in concert or cooperation with a candidate or an agent or authorized committee of the candidate solely because the candidate has requested that the committee not make any expenditure in support of the candidate or in opposition to an opponent of the candidate. (That is, a political party committee expenditure in support of a candidate, or in opposition to an opponent, may not be disqualified as an independent expenditure solely because the candidate has communicated to the committee a request that it not make such expenditures.)<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
