<bill session="110" type="h" number="2600" updated="2009-01-08T22:15:47-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1181102400" datetime="2007-06-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1181102400" datetime="2007-06-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Border Tax Equity Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the imposition of a tax on imports from any country that employs indirect taxes and grants rebates of the same upon export and to authorize compensatory payments to eligible United States exporters to neutralize the discriminatory effect of such taxes paid by such exporters if United States trade negotiating objectives regarding border tax treatment in World Trade Organization negotiations are not met.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400309"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400627" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400004" joined="2007-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400209" joined="2007-06-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400191" joined="2007-06-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400116" joined="2007-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400274" joined="2007-06-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400288" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400386" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400346" joined="2007-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="412239" joined="2007-11-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400153" joined="2007-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="412228" joined="2007-11-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400391" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400016" joined="2007-11-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1181102400" datetime="2007-06-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action date="1182139200" datetime="2007-06-18"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/6/2007--Introduced.<br/>Border Tax Equity Act of 2007 - Requires the United States Trade Representative (USTR) to submit to Congress a report certifying whether or not U.S. objectives to revise World Trade Organization (WTO) rules on border tax treatment of goods and services from countries with indirect tax systems have been met in WTO negotiations. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) impose a tax on imports of goods and services from any country with an indirect tax system and deposits taxes so collected into a special account; and (2) upon request of a U.S. exporter, grant a rebate to such exporter from such account of indirect taxes paid. Imposes such requirements if the USTR fails to certify to Congress that U.S. objectives have been met.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
