<bill session="110" type="h" number="2608" updated="2009-01-08T22:17:03-05:00">
	<status><enacted date="1222747200" datetime="2008-09-30" /></status>

	<introduced date="1181188800" datetime="2007-06-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">SSI Extension for Elderly and Disabled Refugees Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">SSI Extension for Elderly and Disabled Refugees Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">SSI Extension for Elderly and Disabled Refugees Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="enacted">SSI Extension for Elderly and Disabled Refugees Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend section 402 of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 to provide, in fiscal years 2008 through 2010, extensions of supplemental security income for refugees, asylees, and certain other humanitarian immigrants, and to amend the Internal Revenue Code to collect unemployment compensation debts resulting from fraud.</title>
		<title type="official" as="amended by senate">An act to amend section 402 of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 to provide, in fiscal years 2009 through 2011, extensions of supplemental security income for refugees, asylees, and certain other humanitarian immigrants, and to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to collect unemployment compensation debts resulting from fraud.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400262"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400123" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400289" joined="2007-07-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2007-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400268" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400259" joined="2007-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400021" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400107" joined="2007-06-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2007-06-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400291" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400240" joined="2007-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400238" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400429" joined="2007-06-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1181188800" datetime="2007-06-07"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action date="1181620800" datetime="2007-06-12"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Income Security and Family Support.</text></action>
		<action date="1184181120" datetime="2007-07-11T16:12:00-04:00"><text>Mr. McDermott moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text></action>
		<action date="1184181180" datetime="2007-07-11T16:13:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H7559-7566"/></action>
		<action date="1184181180" datetime="2007-07-11T16:13:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2608.</text></action>
		<vote date="1184182260" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-07-11T16:31:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H7559-7560"/></vote>
		<action date="1184558400" datetime="2007-07-16"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
		<action date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"><text>Senate Committee on Finance discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text></action>
		<action date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"><text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S8003-8004"/></action>
		<vote date="1217563200" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2008-08-01" where="s" type="vote2" result="pass" ><text>Passed Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Unanimous Consent.</text></vote>
		<action date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<action date="1221707520" datetime="2008-09-17T12:12:00-04:00"><text>Mr. McDermott moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendments.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8298-8304"/></action>
		<action date="1221707580" datetime="2008-09-17T12:13:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on the motion to suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendments to H.R. 2608.</text></action>
		<action date="1221709020" datetime="2008-09-17T12:37:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendments Agreed to by voice vote.</text></action>
		<topresident date="1221624000" datetime="2008-09-17" ><text>Cleared for White House.</text></topresident>
		<topresident date="1222142400" datetime="2008-09-23" ><text>Presented to President.</text></topresident>
		<signed date="1222747200" datetime="2008-09-30" ><text>Signed by President.</text></signed>
		<enacted number="110-328" date="1222747200" datetime="2008-09-30" type="public" ><text>Became Public Law No: 110-328.</text></enacted>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/30/2008--Public Law. (This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the Senate on August 1, 2008. The summary of that version is repeated here.)<br/>SSI Extension for Elderly and Disabled Refugees Act - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act, as amended by the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996, to extend through FY2011 the supplemental security income (SSI) benefits eligibility of certain aliens (refugees, asylees, and elderly noncitizens with pending naturalization applications) and victims of trafficking in persons, including such aliens and victims whose SSI benefits ceased in prior fiscal years. Requires a sworn declaration from such aliens or victims (except children under age 18) that they have made a good faith effort to pursue U.S. citizenship.<br/>Amends the Internal Revenue Code to require the Secretary of the Treasury to offset overpayments of federal taxes by any amount owed to a state for a covered unemployment compensation debt. Defines &quot;covered unemployment compensation debt&quot; as a past-due debt (including penalties and interest) for erroneous payment of state unemployment compensation due to fraud which has become final under state law and remains uncollected for not more than 10 years. Terminates the Secretary's offset authority after 10 years.<br/>Requires states to notify by certified mail any individual who owes a covered unemployment compensation debt before taking action to offset such debt. Gives such individual 60 days to present evidence that such debt is not legally enforceable or was not incurred due to fraud. Authorizes the Secretary of the Treasury to issue regulations pertaining to such notices.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
