<bill session="110" type="h" number="260" updated="2009-01-08T17:16:28-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"/></status>

	<introduced date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Aquatic Invasive Species Research Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish marine and freshwater research, development, and demonstration programs to support efforts to prevent, control, and eradicate invasive species, as well as to educate citizens and stakeholders and restore ecosystems.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400119"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400123" joined="2007-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400420" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400414" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400149" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400342" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400058" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400129" joined="2007-02-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400264" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400412" joined="2007-05-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400007" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400642" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400324" joined="2007-03-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400001" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400110" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400259" joined="2007-05-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400346" joined="2007-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400070" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400013" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412240" joined="2007-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412204" joined="2007-06-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2007-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412200" joined="2007-02-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400328" joined="2007-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400617" joined="2007-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="412213" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400318" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400641" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400651" joined="2008-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412219" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400150" joined="2007-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400238" joined="2007-03-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400062" joined="2007-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400100" joined="2007-02-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"><text>Referred to the Committee on Science and Technology, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, Natural Resources, and House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"><text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text></action>
		<action date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text></action>
		<action date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text></action>
		<action date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"><text>Referred to House House Administration</text></action>
		<action date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"><committee name="House Science and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text></action>
		<action date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, and Oceans.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/5/2007--Introduced.<br/>Aquatic Invasive Species Research Act - Requires the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), the Smithsonian Institution, and the U.S. Geological Survey (administering agencies) to: (1) enter into a memorandum of understanding regarding the implementation and coordination of this Act; and (2) develop a marine and freshwater research program to support efforts to assess introduction rates and patterns of invasive nonnative species into the aquatic ecosystem, and efforts to detect, prevent, and eradicate them. Requires the administering agencies to: (1) develop standardized protocols for conducting ecological and pathway surveys of such species; (2) conduct research to identify the relationship between the introduction and establishment of such species; and (3) analyze the data collected and develop a profile that determines whether a species planned for importation is likely to invade an aquatic ecosystem. . Requires the U.S. Geological Survey to develop a central, national pathway and ecological surveys database of information. Makes the Invasive Species Council responsible for disseminating such information and develop a national strategy for how it will be shared with federal, state, and local entities. Requires the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to develop a grant program to fund research, development, demonstration and verification of environmentally sound, cost-effective technologies and methods to control and eradicate such species. Reauthorizes the ship pathway technology demonstration program. Requires the Coast Guard and the EPA to develop a research program to support implementation of ship pathway standards to prevent the introduction and spread of invasive species by ships. Requires the National Science Foundation to establish a grant program for researchers at institutions of higher education and museums to carry our research programs in systematics and taxonomy.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
