<bill session="110" type="h" number="2614" updated="2009-01-08T22:17:46-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1195013880" datetime="2007-11-13T12:18:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1181188800" datetime="2007-06-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to participate in certain water projects in California.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400057"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400239" joined="2007-06-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1181188800" datetime="2007-06-07"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1181534400" datetime="2007-06-11"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text></action>
		<action date="1195013760" datetime="2007-11-13T12:16:00-05:00"><text>Ms. Bordallo moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text></action>
		<action date="1195013820" datetime="2007-11-13T12:17:00-05:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H13528-13529"/></action>
		<action date="1195013820" datetime="2007-11-13T12:17:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2614.</text></action>
		<vote date="1195013880" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-11-13T12:18:00-05:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H13528"/></vote>
		<action date="1195016400" datetime="2007-11-14"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1207627200" datetime="2008-04-08"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="1019" date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1019.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/16/2008--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the House on November 13, 2007. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Amends the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to participate in the design, planning, and construction of: (1) projects to treat impaired surface water, reclaim and reuse impaired groundwater, and provide brine disposal within the Santa Ana Watershed, in cooperation with the Yucaipa Valley Water District; and (2) a project to reclaim and reuse wastewater, including degraded groundwaters, within and outside of the service area of the City of Corona Water Utility, in cooperation with the City of Corona Water Utility. Limits the federal share of each of the project costs to 25%. Prohibits the Secretary from using or providing funds under this Act for project operation or maintenance.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
