<bill session="110" type="h" number="2612" updated="2009-01-08T22:17:32-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1181188800" datetime="2007-06-07"/></status>

	<introduced date="1181188800" datetime="2007-06-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Mental Health Care for Our Wounded Warriors Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To improve mental health care for wounded members of the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400097"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400041" joined="2007-08-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2007-06-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400155" joined="2007-06-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400063" joined="2007-06-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400379" joined="2007-07-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412210" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="412188" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400331" joined="2007-07-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400356" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="412209" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400442" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="2007-06-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="412240" joined="2007-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400043" joined="2007-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400062" joined="2007-06-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1181188800" datetime="2007-06-07"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1241-1242)</text></action>
		<action date="1181188800" datetime="2007-06-07"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
		<action date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/7/2007--Introduced.<br/>Mental Health Care for Our Wounded Warriors Act - Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) members of the Armed Forces (members) deserve the best possible treatment for mental and physical illnesses and injuries sustained while in military service; (2) members should have access to mental health providers; (3) mental health disorders such as post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) should be treated with an urgency similar to physical ailments incurred by members; (4) there is a need to recruit, train, and retain more mental health care professionals to diagnose and treat members; and (5) there is a continued need for research, new treatments, and best practices for treating PTSD, as well as a long-term strategy for recruiting, training, and retaining the mental health workforce of the Department of Defense (DOD). Directs the Secretary of Defense to establish at least two centers of excellence in military mental health for, among other things, the development and implementation of DOD strategy for the prevention, identification, and treatment of combat-related mental health conditions, with an emphasis on PTSD and traumatic brain injury. Requires a report from the Secretary to the congressional defense committees on appropriate actions to address current personnel shortages in the DOD mental health workforce.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
