<bill session="110" type="h" number="2629" updated="2009-01-08T22:19:36-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1181188800" datetime="2007-06-07"/></status>

	<introduced date="1181188800" datetime="2007-06-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Agricultural Border Safeguard Protection Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To restore import and entry agricultural inspection functions to the Department of Agriculture.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400328"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400419" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400171" joined="2007-07-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1181188800" datetime="2007-06-07"><text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1181188800" datetime="2007-06-07"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action date="1181188800" datetime="2007-06-07"><text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text></action>
		<action date="1182744000" datetime="2007-06-25"><committee name="House Homeland Security"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border, Maritime, and Global Counterterrorism.</text></action>
		<action date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/7/2007--Introduced.<br/>Agricultural Border Safeguard Protection Act - Amends the Homeland Security Act to repeal the transfer of agricultural import and entry inspection functions from the Department of Agriculture to the Department of Homeland Security (DHS). Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to: (1) develop agricultural import and entry procedures for inspections, monitoring, and auditing; (2) ensure that the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service has an electronic system with real-time tracking capability for monitoring, tracking, and reporting inspection activities; (3) develop and maintain an integrated, real-time communication system with respect to import and entry agricultural inspections to alert state agriculture departments about significant Service findings; and (4) establish the International Trade Inspection Advisory Committee. 
	</summary>
</bill>
