<bill session="110" type="h" number="2637" updated="2009-01-08T22:20:36-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1181657100" datetime="2007-06-12T11:05:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1181275200" datetime="2007-06-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Child Labor Protection Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Child Labor Protection Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Fair Labor Standards Act, with respect to civil penalties for child labor violations.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400436"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400267" joined="2007-06-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400433" joined="2007-06-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412209" joined="2007-06-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412204" joined="2007-06-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412219" joined="2007-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="2007-06-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1181275200" datetime="2007-06-08"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1181656620" datetime="2007-06-12T10:57:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Hare moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text></action>
		<action date="1181656620" datetime="2007-06-12T10:57:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H6250-6251"/></action>
		<action date="1181656620" datetime="2007-06-12T10:57:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2637.</text></action>
		<vote date="1181657100" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-06-12T11:05:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H6250"/></vote>
		<action date="1181707200" datetime="2007-06-13"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/12/2007--Passed House without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Child Labor Protection Act of 2007 - Amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to increase civil penalties for violations of: (1) child labor requirements and prohibitions; and (2) minimum wage and maximum hours requirements. Increases from $10,000 to $11,000 the maximum employer penalty for each employee who was the subject of a child labor violation. Establishes a $50,000 civil penalty for each such violation that causes the death or serious injury of any employee under age 18. Allows the doubling of such a penalty where the violation is a repeated or willful violation. Defines &quot;serious injury&quot; as permanent: (1) loss or substantial impairment of one of the senses (sight, hearing, taste, smell, tactile sensation); (2) loss or substantial impairment of the function of a bodily member, organ, or mental faculty, including the loss of all or part of an arm, leg, foot, hand or other body part; or (3) permanent paralysis or substantial impairment that causes loss of movement or mobility of an arm, leg, foot, hand or other body part. Increases from $1,000 to $1,100 the civil penalty for any repeated or willful violation of specified minimum wage or maximum hours requirements of such Act.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
