<bill session="110" type="h" number="2630" updated="2009-01-08T22:19:43-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1185217140" datetime="2007-07-23T15:59:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1181188800" datetime="2007-06-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Campaign Expenditure Transparency Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Campaign Expenditure Transparency Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to prohibit authorized committees and leadership PACs of a candidate or an individual holding Federal office from making payments to the candidate's or individual's spouse, to require such committees and PACs to report on disbursements made to the immediate family members of the candidate or individual, and for other purposes.</title>
		<title type="official" as="amended by house">A bill to amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to prohibit certain political committees from compensating the spouse of the candidate for services provided to or on behalf of the committee, to require such committees to report on payments made to the spouse and the immediate family members of the candidate, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400361"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400031" joined="2007-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400137" joined="2007-06-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400412" joined="2007-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400245" joined="2007-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400634" joined="2007-06-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412187" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="412209" joined="2007-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400070" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400378" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400120" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400189" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400415" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400244" joined="2007-06-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400218" joined="2007-07-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400363" joined="2007-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400233" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400321" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400075" joined="2007-06-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1181188800" datetime="2007-06-07"><text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text></action>
		<action date="1185214740" datetime="2007-07-23T15:19:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Brady (PA) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1185214740" datetime="2007-07-23T15:19:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8230-8234"/></action>
		<action date="1185214740" datetime="2007-07-23T15:19:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2630.</text></action>
		<vote date="1185217140" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-07-23T15:59:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text as passed in House" ref="CR H8230"/></vote>
		<action date="1185217140" datetime="2007-07-23T15:59:00-04:00"><text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action date="1185249600" datetime="2007-07-24"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/23/2007--Passed House amended. Campaign Expenditure Transparency Act - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to prohibit authorized committees of a candidate or any other political committee established, maintained, or controlled by a candidate or an individual holding federal office (other than a political committee of a political party) from directly or indirectly compensating the spouse of the candidate or the individual (as the case may be) for services provided to or on behalf of the committee. Requires any such committee to report on disbursements to the spouse or an immediate family member of the candidate or individual. Requires any penalty imposed for violation of this Act to be imposed on the candidate or federal office holder whose spouse receives compensation. Prohibits the committee involved from reimbursing the candidate or office holder for any such penalty.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
