<bill session="110" type="h" number="263" updated="2009-01-08T17:16:49-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26" /></status>

	<introduced date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Cybersecurity Education Enhancement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Cybersecurity Education Enhancement Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish a program to award grants to institutions of higher education for the establishment or expansion of cybersecurity professional development programs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400199"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"><text>Referred to the Committee on Science and Technology, and in addition to the Committees on Education and Labor, and Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"><text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text></action>
		<action date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"><text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text></action>
		<action date="1169528400" datetime="2007-01-23"><committee name="House Homeland Security"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emerging Threats, Cybersecurity, and Science and Technology.</text></action>
		<action date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"><committee name="House Science and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology and Innovation.</text></action>
		<action date="1178683200" datetime="2007-05-09"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness.</text></action>
		<action date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"><committee name="House Homeland Security"/><text>Subcommittee on Emerging Threats, Cybersecurity, and Science and Technology Discharged.</text></action>
		<action date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"><committee name="House Homeland Security"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26" ><committee name="House Homeland Security"/><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1220902680" datetime="2008-09-08T16:38:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 110-829, Part I.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/8/2008--Reported to House amended, Part I. Cybersecurity Education Enhancement Act of 2008 - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security, acting through the Assistant Secretary of Cybersecurity, to establish a program awarding competitive grants to institutions of higher education (IHEs) and consortia of IHEs for: (1) cybersecurity professional development programs; (2) associate degree programs in cybersecurity; and (3) the purchase of equipment to provide training in cybersecurity for professional development and degree programs. Gives grant priority to consortia of IHEs and such consortia that include IHEs eligible to receive funds under title III (Institutional Aid) or V (Developing Institutions) of the Higher Education Act of 1965. Authorizes FY2009-FY2010 appropriations for the grant program. Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Secretary to establish a DHS Cybersecurity Fellows program to bring state, local, tribal, and private sector officials to participate in the work of the National Cybersecurity Division in order to assist with Department of Homeland Security's stated cybersecurity missions and capabilities. Urges the House of Representatives to designate a committee to serve as the single, principal point of cybersecurity oversight and review.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
