<bill session="110" type="h" number="2647" updated="2009-01-08T22:21:50-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1181534400" datetime="2007-06-11"/></status>

	<introduced date="1181534400" datetime="2007-06-11"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Mental Health and Substance Abuse Juvenile Services Improvement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to improve mental health and substance abuse services for juveniles.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400201"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1181534400" datetime="2007-06-11"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1181534400" datetime="2007-06-11"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/11/2007--Introduced.<br/>Mental Health and Substance Abuse Juvenile Services Improvement Act of 2007 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to support programs to promote mental health among all children and their families and to provide early intervention services to ameliorate identified mental health problems in children. Requires the Secretary to provide an equitable distribution of such grants by region. Directs the Attorney General and the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Center for Mental Health Services, to award grants for programs that address the service needs of juveniles by requiring the state or local juvenile system, the mental health system, and the substance abuse treatment system to work collectively to ensure: (1) the appropriate diversion of such juveniles from incarceration; (2) the provision of appropriate mental health and substance abuse services as an alternative to incarceration; and (3) the provision of follow-up services for juveniles who are discharged from the juvenile justice system. Provides funding for the provision of emergency mental health and substance abuse treatment and prevention services to children who are directly affected by public health emergencies. Allows the Secretary to award grants to enable eligible entities to increase the coordination and development of disaster preparedness efforts relating to the needs of children.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
