<bill session="110" type="h" number="2666" updated="2009-01-08T22:24:04-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1181534400" datetime="2007-06-11"/></status>

	<introduced date="1181534400" datetime="2007-06-11"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Blair Holt's Firearm Licensing and Record of Sale Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the implementation of a system of licensing for purchasers of certain firearms and for a record of sale system for those firearms, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400350"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400227" joined="2007-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="412221" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400333" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="2007-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400198" joined="2007-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400130" joined="2007-09-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400402" joined="2007-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400120" joined="2007-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400090" joined="2007-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="2007-09-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400163" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400233" joined="2007-11-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1181534400" datetime="2007-06-11"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1259)</text></action>
		<action date="1181534400" datetime="2007-06-11"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1184558400" datetime="2007-07-16"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/11/2007--Introduced.<br/>Blair Holt's Firearm Licensing and Record of Sale Act of 2007 - Amends the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act to prohibit a person from possessing a firearm unless that person has been issued a firearm license under this Act or a state system certified under this Act and such license has not been invalidated or revoked. Prescribes license application, issuance, and renewal requirements.<br/>Prohibits transferring or receiving a qualifying firearm unless the recipient presents a valid firearms license, the license is verified, and the dealer records a tracking authorization number. Prescribes firearms transfer reporting and record keeping requirements. Directs the Attorney General to establish and maintain a federal record of sale system.<br/>Prohibits: (1) transferring a firearm to any person other than a licensee, unless the transfer is processed through a licensed dealer in accordance with national instant criminal background check system requirements, with exceptions; (2) a licensed manufacturer or dealer from failing to comply with reporting and record keeping requirements of this Act; (3) failing to report the loss or theft of the firearm to the Attorney General within 72 hours; (4) failing to report to the Attorney General an address change within 60 days; or (5) keeping a loaded firearm, or an unloaded firearm and ammunition for the firearm, knowingly or recklessly disregarding the risk that a child is capable of gaining access, if a child uses the firearm and causes death or serious bodily injury.<br/>Prescribes criminal penalties for violations of firearms provisions covered by this Act.<br/>Directs the Attorney General to: (1) establish and maintain a firearm injury information clearinghouse; (2) conduct continuing studies and investigations of firearm-related deaths and injuries; and (3) collect and maintain current production and sales figures of each licensed manufacturer.<br/>Authorizes the Attorney General to certify state firearm licensing or record of sale systems.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
