<bill session="110" type="h" number="2660" updated="2009-01-08T22:23:20-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1181534400" datetime="2007-06-11"/></status>

	<introduced date="1181534400" datetime="2007-06-11"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">2007 Civil Rights Pay Fairness Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 to extend the period for filing charges of discrimination in violation of such title and to provide relief for certain current injuries arising from compensation calculations attributable to compensation decisions made at any time in violation of such title.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400349"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400623" joined="2007-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412208" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400350" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400217" joined="2007-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400067" joined="2007-06-21"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1181534400" datetime="2007-06-11"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1185249600" datetime="2007-07-24"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/11/2007--Introduced.<br/>2007 Civil Rights Pay Fairness Act - Amends the Civil Rights Act of 1964 to increase the length of time an aggrieved person has to file a charge of an alleged unlawful employment practice. Declares that, for enforcement of unlawful employment practices provisions, an unlawful employment practice occurs with respect to compensation when an aggrieved person is injured as a result of a compensation calculation attributable in whole or in part to the application or continuation of a compensation decision that was made at any time before a charge relating to such calculation is filed and was made for an intentionally discriminatory purpose.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
