<bill session="110" type="h" number="2675" updated="2009-01-08T22:25:09-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1207001160" datetime="2008-03-31T19:06:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="148"/></status>

	<introduced date="1181620800" datetime="2007-06-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">HALE Scouts Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Help to Access Land for the Education of Scouts</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">HALE Scouts Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Help to Access Land for the Education of Scouts</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">HALE Scouts Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Help to Access Land for the Education of Scouts</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the conveyance of approximately 140 acres of land in the Ouachita National Forest in Oklahoma to the Indian Nations Council, Inc., of the Boy Scouts of America, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400645"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1181620800" datetime="2007-06-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1181880000" datetime="2007-06-15"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action date="1204779600" datetime="2008-03-06"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1205294400" datetime="2008-03-12"><text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands Discharged.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1205294400" datetime="2008-03-12" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1205294400" datetime="2008-03-12"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1207018980" datetime="2008-03-31T12:03:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-553.</text></action>
		<calendar number="336" date="1207019040" datetime="2008-03-31T12:04:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 336.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1206985380" datetime="2008-03-31T14:43:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Abercrombie moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1206985440" datetime="2008-03-31T14:44:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H1784-1785"/></action>
		<action date="1206985440" datetime="2008-03-31T14:44:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2675.</text></action>
		<action date="1206985620" datetime="2008-03-31T14:47:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1207000560" datetime="2008-03-31T18:56:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H1790-1791"/></action>
		<vote date="1207001160" how="roll" roll="148" datetime="2008-03-31T19:06:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" suspension="1" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 370 - 2 (Roll no. 148).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H1784"/></vote>
		<action date="1207022400" datetime="2008-04-01"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/31/2008--Passed House amended. Help to Access Land for the Education of Scouts or HALE Scouts Act - Requires the conveyance of specified National Forest System land in the Ouachita National Forest in Oklahoma to the Indian Nations Council, Inc., of the Boy Scouts of America. Excludes from such conveyance the inclusion of any land within the Indian Nations National Scenic and Wildlife Area designated under the Winding Stair Mountain National Recreation and Wilderness Area Act. Requires the Council, as consideration for such land, to pay to the Secretary of Agriculture the fair market value of the land, as determined by an appraisal approved by the Secretary and done to conform with the Uniform Appraisal Standards for Federal Land Acquisitions and the provisions relating to exchanges of public lands and interests within the National Forest System under the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976. Provides for the deposit of such consideration into the fund established by the Sisk Act. Makes the deposited amount available for expenditure for the acquisition of land and interests in the Ouachita National Forest. States that access to the conveyed land shall be from the adjacent land of the Council or its successor. Bars the Secretary from being required to provide additional access to such land. Authorizes the Secretary to prescribe such terms and conditions on the conveyance as the Secretary considers in the public interest, including the reservation of access rights to the conveyed land for administrative purposes. 
	</summary>
</bill>
