<bill session="110" type="h" number="2673" updated="2009-01-08T22:24:55-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1181620800" datetime="2007-06-12"/></status>

	<introduced date="1181620800" datetime="2007-06-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Aviation Administration Fair Labor Management Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, to facilitate the resolution of disputes between the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration and employees of the Administration in the course of collective negotiations.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400273"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1181620800" datetime="2007-06-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text></action>
		<action date="1181707200" datetime="2007-06-13"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/12/2007--Introduced.<br/>Federal Aviation Administration Fair Labor Management Act of 2007 - Requires, after May 31, 2007, that where the services of the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service have led to an impasse between the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) and its employees in reaching an agreement with respect to the implementing of proposed changes to the FAA personnel management system: (1) the Service issue a written certification of such impasse; and (2) the negotiating parties request the Federal Service Impasses Panel to consider and resolve the matter not later than 60 days after issuance of the certification. (Currently, the FAA Administrator's proposed change shall not take effect until 60 days have elapsed after the Administrator transmits the proposed change, along with the objections of the exclusive bargaining representatives to the change, and the reasons for such objections, to Congress.)<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
