<bill session="110" type="h" number="2674" updated="2009-01-08T22:25:02-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1181620800" datetime="2007-06-12"/></status>

	<introduced date="1181620800" datetime="2007-06-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">CARE Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Children's Act for Responsible Employment of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to increase penalties for violations of child labor laws, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400347"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400290" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400620" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400337" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400080" joined="2007-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-06-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400302" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400430" joined="2007-06-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400384" joined="2007-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400152" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400355" joined="2007-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400339" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400103" joined="2007-06-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2007-06-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400021" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400009" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412186" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400310" joined="2007-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400090" joined="2007-06-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400238" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400025" joined="2007-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400163" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400179" joined="2007-11-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1181620800" datetime="2007-06-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1185249600" datetime="2007-07-24"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/12/2007--Introduced.<br/>Children's Act for Responsible Employment of 2007 or the CARE Act of 2007 - Amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (FLSA) to repeal certain exemptions from child labor prohibitions for agricultural employment. Allows an exemption only if: (1) the agricultural employment of an individual under 16 occurs outside of school hours; and (2) such individual is employed by a parent or a person standing in place of a parent on a farm owned or operated by such parent or person. Raises from 16 to 18 years old the minimum age for engaging in hazardous agricultural employment. Eliminates a waiver for hand-harvesting of certain crops.<br/>Increases civil and criminal penalties for child labor violations.<br/>Directs the Secretary of Labor to analyze data and report to Congress on work-related injuries to children and related matters. Requires employers to report on work-related serious injuries and illnesses, and deaths, of agricultural employees under 18 years of age. Incorporates into FLSA child labor requirements certain federal standards for protecting workers exposed to pesticides. Reconciles civil penalties for violations of such standards affecting child workers imposed by the Secretary under FLSA and by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency under the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act. 
	</summary>
</bill>
