<bill session="110" type="h" number="2681" updated="2009-01-08T22:25:52-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1181620800" datetime="2007-06-12"/></status>

	<introduced date="1181620800" datetime="2007-06-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the maintenance, management, and availability for research of assets of the Air Force Health Study.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400048"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1181620800" datetime="2007-06-12"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1270)</text></action>
		<action date="1181620800" datetime="2007-06-12"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1181620800" datetime="2007-06-12"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1181620800" datetime="2007-06-12"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1181620800" datetime="2007-06-12"><text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1182312000" datetime="2007-06-20"><committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/12/2007--Introduced.<br/>Directs the Medical Follow-Up Agency of the Institute of Medicine of the National Academy of Sciences (Agency) to maintain and manage the assets (including electronic data files and biological specimens of study participants) transferred to the Agency from the Air Force Health Study. Authorizes the Agency, during FY2007-FY2011, to conduct additional research on such assets toward the goal of understanding the determinants of health, and promoting wellness, in veterans. Requires an Agency report to Congress assessing the feasibility and advisability of conducting additional research on such assets after the end of FY2011.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
