<bill session="110" type="h" number="268" updated="2009-01-08T17:17:23-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"/></status>

	<introduced date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Energy Employees Occupational Illness Compensation Program Improvement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Energy Employees Occupational Illness Compensation Program Act of 2000 to clarify the roles and responsibilities of the agencies and actors responsible for the administration of such compensation program, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400199"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"><text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1170392400" datetime="2007-02-02"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text></action>
		<action date="1178683200" datetime="2007-05-09"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/5/2007--Introduced.<br/>Energy Employees Occupational Illness Compensation Program Improvement Act of 2007 - Amends the Energy Employees Occupational Illness Compensation Program Act of 2000 to instruct the Secretaries of Labor and of Health and Human Services (HHS) to include as part of their annual budget requests the administrative costs necessary to implement their responsibilities under the Energy Employees Occupational Illness Compensation Program (including, for the Secretary of HHS, costs for the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health and the Advisory Board on Radiation and Worker Health). Instructs the Secretary of Energy to designate annually as a beryllium vendor any vendor, processor, or producer of beryllium (or related products) not previously designated as such if the Secretary finds that such person has engaged in activities related to production or processing of beryllium sales. Transfers certain responsibilities from the President to the Secretary of HHS regarding: (1) Program administration; and (2) the Special Exposure Cohort. Revises requirements for: (1) the Advisory Board on Radiation and Worker Health (Board); and (2) the Special Exposure Cohort. Establishes within HHS a Special Exposure Cohort Appeals Board to hear appeals from an adverse Special Exposure Cohort designation. Sets forth conflicts of interest prohibitions. Expands the duties of the Office of Ombudsman to include: (1) assisting individuals in making claims; and (2) acting as advocate for individuals seeking benefits.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
