<bill session="110" type="h" number="2704" updated="2009-01-08T22:28:38-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1181707200" datetime="2007-06-13"/></status>

	<introduced date="1181707200" datetime="2007-06-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Gulf Coast All-Hazard Readiness Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To give the consent of Congress to an agreement or compact between Alabama, Florida, Louisiana, Mississippi, and Texas for the purpose of establishing an all-hazard mitigation, readiness, response, and recovery plan, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412250"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400051" joined="2007-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400131" joined="2007-08-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400108" joined="2007-06-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1181707200" datetime="2007-06-13"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1190174400" datetime="2007-09-19"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H10616)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/13/2007--Introduced.<br/>Gulf Coast All-Hazard Readiness Act of 2007 - Grants congressional consent to any number of the Gulf Coast states (Alabama, Florida, Louisiana, Mississippi, and Texas) to negotiate and enter into an agreement or compact that: (1) is consented to by the legislatures of the participating states by December 31, 2010; (2) is entered into primarily to establish a plan for all-hazard mitigation, readiness, response, and recovery; (3) establishes a multi-state all-hazard fund generated by participating states to be utilized when a disaster affects those states; (4) requires states to appoint commissioners to organize the operation, management, and disbursement of the fund; and (5) prohibits participating states from taking action prohibited by federal law.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
