<bill session="110" type="h" number="2707" updated="2009-01-08T22:28:59-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1185822480" datetime="2007-07-30T16:08:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1181707200" datetime="2007-06-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To reauthorize the Underground Railroad Educational and Cultural Program.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400227"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400030" joined="2007-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400103" joined="2007-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2007-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="412010" joined="2007-06-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400139" joined="2007-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2007-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400208" joined="2007-06-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400240" joined="2007-06-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1181707200" datetime="2007-06-13"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1185249600" datetime="2007-07-24"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Healthy Families and Communities.</text></action>
		<action date="1185822060" datetime="2007-07-30T16:01:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Kucinich moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1185822120" datetime="2007-07-30T16:02:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules. (consideration: CR 7/31/2007 H8882-8884)</text></action>
		<action date="1185822120" datetime="2007-07-30T16:02:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2707.</text></action>
		<vote date="1185822480" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-07-30T16:08:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote. (text: CR 7/31/2007 H8882)</text></vote>
		<action date="1185854400" datetime="2007-07-31"><text>Received in the Senate.</text></action>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/30/2007--Passed House amended. Authorizes the Secretary of Education to make grants to one or more nonprofit educational organizations established to research, display, interpret, and collect artifacts relating to the history of the Underground Railroad. Requires each grant agreement to require the organization to: (1) establish a facility to house, display, and interpret the artifacts related to the history of the Underground Railroad; (2) demonstrate substantial private support for the facility through the implementation of a public-private partnership between a state or local public entity and a private entity providing certain matching funds; (3) create an endowment to fund shortfalls in the costs of ongoing facility operations; (4) establish a network of satellite centers throughout the United States to help disseminate information regarding the Underground Railroad; (5) establish the capability to link the facility electronically with other local and regional facilities with interpretive Underground Railroad collections and programs; and (6) report annually to the Secretary. Authorizes appropriations for FY2008-FY2012.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
