<bill session="110" type="h" number="270" updated="2009-01-08T17:17:38-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"/></status>

	<introduced date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize appropriations for fiscal years 2008 through 2010 for the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400380"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400344" joined="2007-10-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400388" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400658" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400324" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400435" joined="2007-01-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1170392400" datetime="2007-02-02"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text></action>
		<action date="1170392400" datetime="2007-02-02"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/5/2007--Introduced.<br/>Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2007 - Amends the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 to authorize trafficking victims-related appropriations for activities of: (1) the Interagency Task Force to Monitor and Combat Trafficking; (2) the Secretary of Health and Human Services; (3) the Secretary of State; (4) the President; (5) the Secretary of Labor; (6) the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation; (7) the Secretary of Homeland Security; and (8) the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development. Makes juvenile victims of trafficking in persons eligible for interim assistance under such Act. Directs the Attorney General to prepare model legislation for state use to define and prohibit all acts relating to prostitution of children and trafficking in children for the purpose of labor or sexual exploitation. 
	</summary>
</bill>
