<bill session="110" type="h" number="2703" updated="2009-01-08T22:28:31-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1181707200" datetime="2007-06-13"/></status>

	<introduced date="1181707200" datetime="2007-06-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Private Security Officer Employment Authorization Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Private Security Officer Employment Authorization Act of 2004.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400008"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400219" joined="2008-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="2008-02-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1181707200" datetime="2007-06-13"><text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1181707200" datetime="2007-06-13"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1181707200" datetime="2007-06-13"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1184558400" datetime="2007-07-16"><committee name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text></action>
		<action date="1185249600" datetime="2007-07-24"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
		<action date="1204002000" datetime="2008-02-26"><committee name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/13/2007--Introduced.<br/>Private Security Officer Employment Authorization Act of 2007 - Amends the Private Security Officer Employment Authorization Act of 2004 to: (1) require a process to allow private security guard employees or applicants to challenge the accuracy and completeness of their criminal history records; (2) prohibit private security guard employers from hiring guards without obtaining certain state criminal history information; (3) specify the crimes for which states must provide conviction information to such employers; (4) impose confidentiality and recordkeeping requirements on such employers; and (5) protect such employers from liability for good faith employment determinations based upon available criminal history information.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
