<bill session="110" type="h" number="2710" updated="2009-01-08T22:29:20-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1181707200" datetime="2007-06-13"/></status>

	<introduced date="1181707200" datetime="2007-06-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To repeal and modify certain provisions of law relating to the review of the detention of enemy combatants.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412232"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1181707200" datetime="2007-06-13"><text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1181707200" datetime="2007-06-13"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1181707200" datetime="2007-06-13"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1184558400" datetime="2007-07-16"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/13/2007--Introduced.<br/>Amends federal law concerning the detention of suspected enemy combatants to: (1) repeal a provision that denies any court or judge jurisdiction to consider a writ of habeas corpus filed on behalf of an alien detained by the United States who has been determined to have been properly detained as an enemy combatant or is awaiting such determination; (2) repeal provisions of the Detainee Treatment Act of 2005 concerning limitations on the review of decisions of combatant status review tribunals on the propriety of detention of suspected enemy combatants; and (3) revise generally provisions concerning the limited review of military commission procedures and actions.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
