<bill session="110" type="h" number="2721" updated="2009-01-08T22:30:39-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1181793600" datetime="2007-06-14"/></status>

	<introduced date="1181793600" datetime="2007-06-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 10, United States Code, to require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to develop, and the Secretary of Defense to distribute to members of the Armed Forces upon their discharge or release from active duty, information in a compact disk read-only memory format that lists and explains the health, education, and other benefits for which veterans are eligible under the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400065"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400618" joined="2008-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-06-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="412224" joined="2008-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="412225" joined="2008-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400635" joined="2008-06-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2008-06-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400384" joined="2008-06-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412197" joined="2008-06-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400663" joined="2008-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="412223" joined="2008-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="412205" joined="2008-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="412199" joined="2008-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400255" joined="2008-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2008-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="412206" joined="2008-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="412233" joined="2008-06-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1181793600" datetime="2007-06-14"><text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1181793600" datetime="2007-06-14"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1181793600" datetime="2007-06-14"><text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1182312000" datetime="2007-06-20"><committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text></action>
		<action date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28"><committee name="House Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text></action>
		<action date="1213848000" datetime="2008-06-19"><committee name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"><committee name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity"/><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"><committee name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity"/><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/14/2007--Introduced.<br/>Directs: (1) the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (Secretary) to develop and maintain, in a compact disk (CD) read-only memory format, information that lists and explains the health, education, and other benefits for which veterans are eligible through the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA); (2) that a copy of such CD be included as part of the preseparation counseling provided to each member of the Armed Forces being discharged or released from duty; and (3) the Secretary, Secretary of Defense, and head of any other relevant government agency to each maintain an Internet website containing an explanation of the benefits administered by that Secretary or agency head to which veterans are entitled, and how veterans can secure those benefits.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
