<bill session="110" type="h" number="2735" updated="2009-01-08T22:32:21-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1181793600" datetime="2007-06-14"/></status>

	<introduced date="1181793600" datetime="2007-06-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Wildlife Refuge System Operations Enhancement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Wildlife Refuge Checkoff Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Wildlife Refuge System Semipostal Stamp Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide additional funding for operation of national wildlife refuges.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400440"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400403" joined="2007-06-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1181793600" datetime="2007-06-14"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1292-1293)</text></action>
		<action date="1181793600" datetime="2007-06-14"><text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1181793600" datetime="2007-06-14"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1181793600" datetime="2007-06-14"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1181793600" datetime="2007-06-14"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, and Oceans.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/14/2007--Introduced.<br/>National Wildlife Refuge System Operations Enhancement Act of 2007 - Increases the price of Migratory Bird Hunting and Conservation Stamps. Requires amounts received for such stamps sold in excess of $15.00 to be used by the Secretary of the Interior for the costs of national wildlife refuge operations. National Wildlife Refuge System Semipostal Stamp Act of 2007 - Sets forth provisions for the issuance and sale of a special postage stamp in order to afford a convenient way for the public to contribute toward funding the operations of the National Wildlife Refuge System. National Wildlife Refuge Checkoff Act of 2007 - Permits a taxpayer to designate that $1 of any tax overpayment, and any cash contribution which the taxpayer includes with such return, shall be deposited into the National Wildlife Refuge System Trust Fund established by this Act. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to make payments to the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service (USFWS) from such Fund.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
