<bill session="110" type="h" number="2745" updated="2009-01-08T22:33:34-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1181880000" datetime="2007-06-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1181880000" datetime="2007-06-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Passport and Travel Cost Reimbursement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To refund passport processing fees and international travel costs as a result of unreasonable delays in passport application processing times, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400081"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412229" joined="2007-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400229" joined="2007-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400006" joined="2007-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400311" joined="2007-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400179" joined="2007-07-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1181880000" datetime="2007-06-15"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1181880000" datetime="2007-06-15"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1181880000" datetime="2007-06-15"><text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text></action>
		<action date="1182744000" datetime="2007-06-25"><committee name="House Homeland Security"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border, Maritime, and Global Counterterrorism.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/15/2007--Introduced.<br/>Passport and Travel Cost Reimbursement Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of State to refund to a U.S. citizen, upon refund application: (1) passport processing fees for a passport applied for in 2007 if processing took 12 or more weeks for a regular application or three or more weeks for an expedited application; and (2) international air travel costs (economy or comparable, minus any airline refund) for U.S.-departing flights missed as a result of such processing delays. Authorizes the Secretary to provide additional assistance for an extraordinary hardship. Prohibits the Secretary and the Secretary of Homeland Security from implementing a specified plan for a single implementation date for sea and land borders until they have certified to Congress that Department of State passport agencies are able to process passport applications with minimal disruption.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
