<bill session="110" type="h" number="2749" updated="2009-01-08T22:34:02-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1181880000" datetime="2007-06-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1181880000" datetime="2007-06-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Voluntary Medicare Quality Reporting Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for a transition to a new voluntary quality reporting program for physicians and other health professionals.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400155"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400367" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400160" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400626" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400063" joined="2007-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400007" joined="2007-11-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400634" joined="2007-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400235" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400147" joined="2007-07-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400368" joined="2007-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400153" joined="2007-06-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1181880000" datetime="2007-06-15"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1181880000" datetime="2007-06-15"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1181880000" datetime="2007-06-15"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1181880000" datetime="2007-06-15"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"><committee name="House Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/15/2007--Introduced.<br/>Voluntary Medicare Quality Reporting Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to evaluate the quality reporting system under title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act as applied for 2007 before transition to a new voluntary Medicare quality reporting system. Allows eligible professionals to continue to report to the Secretary specified quality measures for covered professional services in order for the Secretary to refine systems for reporting them. Prohibits use of the Physician Assistance and Quality Initiative Fund for quality reporting bonus payments in 2008. Specifies quality measures for covered professional services for the voluntary Medicare quality reporting program. Revises requirements for medical registry-based reporting of quality measures. Directs the Secretary to treat quality measures data as confidential, unavailable to any other party or person. Shields such data from discovery or admission into evidence in any federal or state civil judicial or administrative proceeding.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
