<bill session="110" type="h" number="2740" updated="2009-01-08T22:32:56-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1191509340" datetime="2007-10-04T11:49:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="940"/></status>

	<introduced date="1181880000" datetime="2007-06-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">MEJA Expansion and Enforcement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">MEJA Expansion and Enforcement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">MEJA Expansion and Enforcement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require accountability for contractors and contract personnel under Federal contracts, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400326"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2007-06-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400031" joined="2007-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2007-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2007-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="2007-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400386" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2007-06-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="412222" joined="2007-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2007-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412200" joined="2007-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2007-06-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2007-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400100" joined="2007-06-20"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1181880000" datetime="2007-06-15"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1184558400" datetime="2007-07-16"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text></action>
		<action date="1185249600" datetime="2007-07-24"><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1185249600" datetime="2007-07-24"><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text></action>
		<action date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1190910360" datetime="2007-09-27T13:26:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 110-352.</text></action>
		<calendar number="217" date="1190910360" datetime="2007-09-27T13:26:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 217.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1191361440" datetime="2007-10-02T18:44:00-04:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 702 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2740 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on the Judiciary now printed in the bill.</text></action>
		<action date="1191467880" datetime="2007-10-03T12:18:00-04:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 702 passed House.</text></action>
		<action date="1191439560" datetime="2007-10-03T16:26:00-04:00"><text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 702.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H11214-11226"/><reference label="text of measure as reported in House" ref="CR H11222"/></action>
		<action date="1191439560" datetime="2007-10-03T16:26:00-04:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2740 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on the Judiciary now printed in the bill.</text></action>
		<action date="1191439560" datetime="2007-10-03T16:26:00-04:00"><text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 702 and Rule XVIII.</text></action>
		<action date="1191439560" datetime="2007-10-03T16:26:00-04:00"><text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Ellen O. Tauscher to act as Chairwoman of the Committee.</text></action>
		<action date="1191439560" datetime="2007-10-03T16:26:00-04:00"><text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 2740.</text></action>
		<action date="1191443460" datetime="2007-10-03T17:31:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 702, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Conyers amendment.</text></action>
		<action date="1191444120" datetime="2007-10-03T17:42:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 702, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Schakowsky amendment.</text></action>
		<action date="1191444540" datetime="2007-10-03T17:49:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 702, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hill (IN) amendment.</text></action>
		<action date="1191445020" datetime="2007-10-03T17:57:00-04:00"><text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2740 as unfinished business.</text></action>
		<action date="1191506640" datetime="2007-10-04T11:04:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H11261-11267"/></action>
		<action date="1191506640" datetime="2007-10-04T11:04:00-04:00"><text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text></action>
		<action date="1191506700" datetime="2007-10-04T11:05:00-04:00"><text>The Committee of the Whole adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1191506760" datetime="2007-10-04T11:06:00-04:00"><text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2740.</text></action>
		<action date="1191506820" datetime="2007-10-04T11:07:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H11261"/></action>
		<action date="1191506820" datetime="2007-10-04T11:07:00-04:00"><text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text></action>
		<action date="1191506880" datetime="2007-10-04T11:08:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Forbes moved to recommit with instructions to Judiciary.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H11262-11266"/><reference label="text" ref="CR H11262"/></action>
		<action date="1191506880" datetime="2007-10-04T11:08:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Forbes motion to recommit with instructions on H.R. 2740. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to not affect intelligence activities that are otherwise permissible prior to the enactment of this Act.</text></action>
		<action date="1191507180" datetime="2007-10-04T11:13:00-04:00"><text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H11266"/></action>
		<action date="1191508800" datetime="2007-10-04T11:40:00-04:00"><text>On motion to recommit with instructions Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 342 - 75 (Roll no. 939).</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H11266"/></action>
		<vote date="1191509340" how="roll" roll="940" datetime="2007-10-04T11:49:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 389 - 30 (Roll no. 940).</text></vote>
		<action date="1191470400" datetime="2007-10-04"><text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="413" date="1191556800" datetime="2007-10-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Read the second time. Ordered Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 413.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1192420800" datetime="2007-10-15"><text>Star Print ordered on the bill.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/4/2007--Passed House amended. MEJA Expansion and Enforcement Act of 2007 - Provides that persons who, while employed under a federal agency contract in, or in close proximity to, an area where the Armed Forces are conducting a contingency operation, engage in conduct that would constitute an offense punishable by imprisonment for more than one year if engaged in within U.S. jurisdiction, shall be punished as provided for that offense.<br/>Requires the Inspector General of the Department of Justice (DOJ) to report to Congress on: (1) the status of DOJ's investigations of alleged violations committed by contract personnel; (2) findings and recommendations about the number of criminal cases prosecuted by DOJ involving such violations; and (3) with respect to covered contracts where the work is carried out in Iraq or Afghanistan, a list of each charge brought against contractors or contract personnel and a description of any legal actions taken by the United States as a result of such a criminal charge or a complaint.<br/>Requires the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) to ensure that there are adequate personnel, through the creation of Theater Investigative Units, to investigate allegations of such criminal violations by contract personnel. Requires such a Unit to refer a case, if appropriate, to the Attorney General for further action. Requires the Director to request security assistance from the Secretary of Defense in any case in which a Unit does not have the resources or is otherwise unable to provide adequate security to ensure its safety. Authorizes the Attorney General to request assistance from the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Homeland Security, or the head of any other agency, including the assignment of additional personnel and resources to a Unit.<br/>Requires the Director to report annually to Congress on the number of reports received by Units relating to suspected criminal misconduct by contractors or to fatalities resulting from the use of force by contractors, the number of cases referred by the Units to the Attorney General for further investigation or action, and any recommended changes to federal law that the Director considers necessary to perform the duties of the Director under this Act.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
