<bill session="110" type="h" number="2754" updated="2009-01-08T22:34:41-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1181880000" datetime="2007-06-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1181880000" datetime="2007-06-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Sunshine in Monetary Policy Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to continue to make available to the public on a weekly basis information on the measure of the M3 monetary aggregate, and its components, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400311"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400209" joined="2007-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400163" joined="2007-06-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1181880000" datetime="2007-06-15"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1304-1305)</text></action>
		<action date="1181880000" datetime="2007-06-15"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/15/2007--Introduced.<br/>Sunshine in Monetary Policy Act - Requires the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to continue to compile and to publish on a weekly basis the measure of the M3 monetary aggregate and the components of the M3 that are not included in the measure of the M2 monetary aggregate. Defines &quot;M3 monetary aggregate&quot; as the inclusive measure of money compiled by: (1) currency in circulation (plus traveler's checks), demand deposits, Negotiable Order of Withdrawal (NOW) accounts, and similar interest-earning checking account balances; (2) household holdings of savings deposits, small time deposits, and retail money market mutual fund balances (exclusive of balances held in IRA and Keogh accounts); and (3) institutional money market mutual fund balances and managed liabilities of depositories consisting of large time deposits, repurchase agreements, and Eurodollars.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
