<bill session="110" type="h" number="2763" updated="2009-01-08T22:35:51-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1182139200" datetime="2007-06-18"/></status>

	<introduced date="1182139200" datetime="2007-06-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Biofuels Research and Development Enhancement Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance research, development, demonstration, and commercial application of biofuels related technologies, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400229"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1182139200" datetime="2007-06-18"><text>Referred to the Committee on Science and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1182139200" datetime="2007-06-18"><text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text></action>
		<action date="1182139200" datetime="2007-06-18"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1182139200" datetime="2007-06-18"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text></action>
		<action date="1182312000" datetime="2007-06-20"><committee name="House Science and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/18/2007--Introduced.<br/>Biofuels Research and Development Enhancement Act - Directs the Secretary of Energy to establish an information center on research, development, and commercial application of technologies related to biofuels and biorefineries, including: (1) biochemical and thermochemical conversion technologies to make fuels from lignocellulosic feedstocks; (2) biotechnology processes that emphasize enzyme-based processing systems; and (3) other advanced processes and technologies that will enable biofuel development. Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to instruct the Secretary to implement a research, development, and demonstration program relating to: (1) existing transportation fuel distribution infrastructure and new alternative distribution infrastructure, focusing on the physical and chemical properties of biofuels and prevention of or mitigation against certain adverse impacts; (2) bioresearch centers located in Petroleum Administration for Defense Districts, with a focus on biofuels; and (3) increased energy efficiency and reduced energy consumption in biorefinery facilities. Directs the Secretary to make grants for research, development, demonstration, and commercial application of biofuel production technologies in states with low rates of ethanol production and of cellulosic biomass ethanol. Requires the Secretary to study and report to Congress on: (1) research and development challenges in increasing to 5% biodiesel fuel sold in the United States; (2) the feasibility of increasing domestic consumption of ethanol-blended gasoline with specified levels of ethanol; (3) whether optimizing flexible fueled vehicles to use E-85 fuel would increase their fuel efficiency; and (4) the effects of biodiesel upon engine durability. 
	</summary>
</bill>
