<bill session="110" type="h" number="2769" updated="2009-01-08T22:36:38-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1182225600" datetime="2007-06-19"/></status>

	<introduced date="1182225600" datetime="2007-06-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Miner Health Enhancement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish improved mandatory standards to protect and enhance the health of miners.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400278"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400031" joined="2007-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="412229" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400227" joined="2007-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400102" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412224" joined="2007-10-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400184" joined="2007-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400355" joined="2007-09-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2007-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400331" joined="2007-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400442" joined="2007-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400001" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400103" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412211" joined="2007-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2007-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="412204" joined="2007-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400281" joined="2007-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="412228" joined="2007-09-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="412212" joined="2007-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400286" joined="2007-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="412219" joined="2007-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400025" joined="2007-10-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1182225600" datetime="2007-06-19"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1182312000" datetime="2007-06-20"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1347)</text></action>
		<action date="1185249600" datetime="2007-07-24"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/19/2007--Introduced.<br/>Miner Health Enhancement Act of 2007 - Expresses the sense of Congress that essential standards to protect miner health are out of date and congressional intervention is needed.<br/>Amends the Federal Mine Safety and Health Act of 1977 to require: (1) the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health (NIOSH) to forward to the Secretary of Labor its Recommended Exposure Limits for chemical and other hazards to miners; (2) the Secretary to require the Mine Safety and Health Administration (MSHA) to adopt such limits as the Permissible Exposure Limits (PELs) for the mining industry; (3) NIOSH to annually submit to the Secretary any additional or revised recommended exposure limits for hazardous substances utilized in the industry; (4) the Secretary to adopt such limits as PELs for the industry; (4) MSHA to adopt the health standard for asbestos established by the Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA); and (5) the Secretary to apply the provisions of the interim final rule of October 3, 2000, concerning hazard communication in lieu of the final rule of June 21, 2002, until there is additional rulemaking pursuant to the requirements of this Act.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
