<bill session="110" type="h" number="2775" updated="2009-01-08T22:37:21-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28" /></status>

	<introduced date="1182225600" datetime="2007-06-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to authorize funding for emergency management performance grants, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400299"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400295" joined="2007-06-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1182225600" datetime="2007-06-19"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1336)</text></action>
		<action date="1182225600" datetime="2007-06-19"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text></action>
		<action date="1182312000" datetime="2007-06-20"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text></action>
		<action date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Provision Incorporated into Title II of Public Law 110-53, (H.R. 1).</text></action>
		<action date="1189463160" datetime="2007-09-10T19:26:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation. H. Rept. 110-322.</text></action>
		<calendar number="203" date="1189463160" datetime="2007-09-10T19:26:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 203.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/10/2007--Reported to House amended. Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to direct the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to continue implementation of an emergency management performance grants program. Limits the federal share of the cost of a program funded activity to 50%. Sets forth guidelines for the Administrator to apportion funds to carry out the program among the states on the basis of population. Provides that if the total amount appropriated to carry out the program for a fiscal year equals or exceeds $200 million, no state shall receive an apportionment for that fiscal year that is less than the amount the state received in emergency management performance grants for FY2007. Authorizes appropriations. Authorizes the Administrator to make grants to states for equipping, upgrading, and constructing emergency operations centers and limits the federal share of the cost of any funded activity to 75% (current law prohibits using funds to construct emergency operating centers in any state that does not match the amount made available).<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
