<bill session="110" type="h" number="2786" updated="2009-01-08T22:39:04-05:00">
	<status><enacted date="1223956800" datetime="2008-10-14" /></status>

	<introduced date="1182312000" datetime="2007-06-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Reauthorization Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Reauthorization Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Reauthorization Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Reauthorization Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="enacted">Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Reauthorization Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To reauthorize the programs for housing assistance for Native Americans.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400216"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400336" joined="2007-06-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400313" joined="2007-06-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400077" joined="2007-06-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="2007-06-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400422" joined="2007-06-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400645" joined="2007-06-20"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1182312000" datetime="2007-06-20"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text></action>
		<action date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26" ><text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1186182960" datetime="2007-08-03T20:16:00-04:00"><text>Reported by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 110-295.</text></action>
		<calendar number="185" date="1186182960" datetime="2007-08-03T20:16:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 185.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1189024080" datetime="2007-09-05T17:28:00-04:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 633 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2786 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments.</text></action>
		<action date="1189088340" datetime="2007-09-06T11:19:00-04:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 633 passed House.</text></action>
		<action date="1189088580" datetime="2007-09-06T11:23:00-04:00"><text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 633.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H10182-10196"/></action>
		<action date="1189088580" datetime="2007-09-06T11:23:00-04:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2786 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments.</text></action>
		<action date="1189088580" datetime="2007-09-06T11:23:00-04:00"><text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 633 and Rule XVIII.</text></action>
		<action date="1189088580" datetime="2007-09-06T11:23:00-04:00"><text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Tim Holden to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text></action>
		<action date="1189089300" datetime="2007-09-06T11:35:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Watt amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action date="1189089900" datetime="2007-09-06T11:45:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committe of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Boren amendment to the Watt amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action date="1189090680" datetime="2007-09-06T11:58:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Pearce amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action date="1189134300" datetime="2007-09-06T12:05:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Westmoreland amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action date="1189135620" datetime="2007-09-06T12:27:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Westmoreland amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Westmoreland demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text></action>
		<action date="1189135680" datetime="2007-09-06T12:28:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the King (IA) amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action date="1189136160" datetime="2007-09-06T12:36:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the King (IA) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. King (IA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text></action>
		<action date="1189136220" datetime="2007-09-06T12:37:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Price (GA) amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action date="1189137360" datetime="2007-09-06T12:56:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Price (GA) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Price (GA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text></action>
		<action date="1189137420" datetime="2007-09-06T12:57:00-04:00"><text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1189096920" datetime="2007-09-06T13:42:00-04:00"><text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2786.</text></action>
		<action date="1189096980" datetime="2007-09-06T13:43:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H10195"/></action>
		<action date="1189096980" datetime="2007-09-06T13:43:00-04:00"><text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text></action>
		<vote date="1189098000" how="roll" roll="859" datetime="2007-09-06T14:00:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 333 - 75 (Roll no. 859).</text></vote>
		<action date="1189098000" datetime="2007-09-06T14:00:00-04:00"><text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 2786.</text></action>
		<action date="1189396800" datetime="2007-09-10"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1222315200" datetime="2008-09-25"><text>Senate Committee on Indian Affairs discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text></action>
		<action date="1222315200" datetime="2008-09-25"><text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S9474"/></action>
		<vote date="1222315200" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2008-09-25" where="s" type="vote2" result="pass" ><text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text></vote>
		<action date="1222315200" datetime="2008-09-25"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<action date="1222541400" datetime="2008-09-27T15:50:00-04:00"><text>Mrs. McCarthy (NY) moved that the House suspend the rules an agree to the Senate amendment.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H10216-10222"/></action>
		<action date="1222541400" datetime="2008-09-27T15:50:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2786.</text></action>
		<action date="1222542420" datetime="2008-09-27T16:07:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text as House agreed to Senate amendment" ref="CR H10216-10220"/></action>
		<topresident date="1222488000" datetime="2008-09-27" ><text>Cleared for White House.</text></topresident>
		<topresident date="1223006400" datetime="2008-10-03" ><text>Presented to President.</text></topresident>
		<signed date="1223956800" datetime="2008-10-14" ><text>Signed by President.</text></signed>
		<enacted number="110-411" date="1223956800" datetime="2008-10-14" type="public" ><text>Became Public Law No: 110-411.</text></enacted>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/14/2008--Public Law. Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Reauthorization Act of 2008 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 (NAHASDA) with respect to congressional findings to make mandatory the role of the federal government in providing housing assistance to Native Americans and in promoting the economic self-sufficiency and self-determination of Native Americans.<br/>(Sec. 3) Defines &quot;housing related community development&quot; to mean any facility, community building, business, activity, or infrastructure that: (1) is owned by an Indian tribe or a tribally designated housing entity; (2) is necessary to the provision of housing in an Indian area; and (3) would help an Indian tribe or tribally designated housing entity to reduce the cost of construction of Indian housing, would make housing more affordable, accessible, or practicable in an Indian area, or would otherwise advance the purposes of NAHASDA. Excludes from such term any activity conducted by any Indian tribe under the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act.<br/>Title I: Block Grants and Grant Requirements (Sec.101) Amends NAHASDA to: (1) provide for self-determined housing activities for tribal communities programs under the block grant program for Native American housing assistance; (2) deem a tribe or tribally designated housing entity to be an executive agency for procurement purposes; and (3) require, with respect to any grant made under NAHASDA that is intended to benefit one tribe, that the tribal employment or contract preference laws adopted by such tribe govern the administration of the grant or grant portion. (Sec. 102) Expands requirements for Indian housing plans to include a description of planned activities to identify the types of Indian households to be assisted under NAHASDA and the levels of such assistance.<br/>(Sec. 103) Revises provisions relating to review of Indian housing plans to require the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to review information included in an Indian housing plan only to determine compliance.<br/>(Sec. 104) Excludes from NAHASDA program income any income derived from a regular and customary developer's fee for any project that receives a low-income housing tax credit and is initially funded using NAHASDA grant funds if the developer's fee is approved by a state housing credit agency.<br/>(Sec. 105) Requires the Secretary to initiate a negotiated rulemaking to develop implementing regulations under NAHASDA.<br/>Title II: Affordable Housing Activities - (Sec. 201) Expands the exception for providing housing assistance to non-Indian families to include essential families (families that provide essential services such as law enforcement).<br/>(Sec. 202) Redefines &quot;affordable housing activities&quot; to include activities that develop, operate, maintain, or support affordable housing for rental or homeownership. Authorizes a tribe to establish reserve accounts to accumulate amounts for administration and planning of affordable housing activities. (Sec. 203) Authorizes the use of NAHASDA grant funds over a multiyear period. Exempts from competitive procurement rules an acquisition by a tribe of goods and services the value of which is less than $5,000. (Sec. 204) Provides that binding commitments under NAHASDA for the use of property as affordable housing shall not apply to a family or household member who subsequently takes ownership of a homeownership unit. (Sec. 205) Allows Indian tribes and tribally designated housing entities to access National Crime Information Center records related to criminal convictions for purposes of reviewing applications for employment.<br/>(Sec. 206) Establishes a program for self-determined housing activities to provide Indian tribes with flexibility in using grant funds for assisted housing. Limits the amount available for such purpose to the lesser of 20% of a recipient's total grant amount or $2 million, annually. Requires the Secretary, during 2011, to review and report to Congress on the effectiveness of such program.<br/>Title III: Allocation of Grant Amounts - (Sec. 301)Amends NAHASDA grant allocation provisions to provide that a housing unit that is no longer owned or operated by a grant recipient as affordable housing or that is lost by conveyance, demolition, or other means may not be counted in a funding formula under NAHASDA.<br/>Title IV: Compliance, Audits, and Reports - (Sec. 401)Amends NAHASDA provisions relating to remedies for noncompliance, monitoring of compliance, and performance reports. Title V: Termination of Assistance for Indian Tribes under Incorporated Programs - (Sec. 501) Declares that NAHASDA does not prohibit or prevent any participating jurisdiction from providing amounts to Indian tribes or tribally designated housing entities for use in accordance with the HOME Investment Partnership Act.<br/>Title VI: Guaranteed Loans to Finance Tribal Community and Economic Development Activities - (Sec. 601) Authorizes the Secretary to make loan guarantees to finance housing activities on Indian reservations and in other Indian areas under the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 for not more than four Indian tribes or tribally designated housing entities in a Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) region. Requires no less than 70% of the aggregate funding received by a tribe or entity to be be used for support of activities that benefit low-income Indian families. Requires the Secretary to: (1) establish underwriting criteria for loan guarantees; and (2) carry out training and information activities with respect to the program. Sets forth limits on the issuance of guarantees in FY2009-FY2013. Requires the Secretary to report to Congress within four years after the enactment of this Act on the use of the loan guarantee authority by Indian tribes and tribally designated housing entities.<br/>Terminates the Secretary's authority to make new guarantees on October 1, 2013.<br/>Title VII: Funding - (Sec. 701)Authorizes appropriations for FY2009-FY2013 for NAHASDA block grants and grant requirements, loan guarantees for tribal housing activities, and training and technical assistance. Title VIII: Miscellaneous - (Sec. 801) Prohibits the use of funds under this Act for the benefit of the Cherokee Nation unless the Temporary Order and Temporary Injunction issued on May 14, 2007, by the District Court of the Cherokee Nation remains in effect or there is a settlement agreement which ends litigation among the adverse parties. (Sec. 802) Prohibits the use of funds under this Act to employ unauthorized aliens. (Sec. 803) Directs the Comptroller General to study and report to specified congressional committees on the effectiveness of NAHASDA in meeting affordable housing needs for low-income Indian families in tribes of various sizes and types, specifically smaller tribes.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
