<bill session="110" type="h" number="2806" updated="2009-01-08T22:41:30-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"/></status>

	<introduced date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Safety Net Enhancement Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To reform the Federal unemployment benefits system, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400123"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400061" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400147" joined="2007-06-21"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"><text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1183348800" datetime="2007-07-02"><committee name="House Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Income Security and Family Support.</text></action>
		<action date="1189483200" datetime="2007-09-11"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/21/2007--Introduced.<br/>Safety Net Enhancement Act - Amends the Federal-State Extended Unemployment Compensation Act of 1970 to revise the federal-state extended unemployment compensation program established under the Social Security Act (SSA) to revise the formula for &quot;on&quot; and &quot;off&quot; indicators on the state level used to determine extended unemployment compensation benefit periods. Amends the SSA to require: (1) an increase in earnings credited to a state account in the Unemployment Trust Fund when a state meets funding goals; and (2) a decrease in such earnings credited to a state account when the state fails to meet funding goals. Excludes any interest premium or penalty from such requirement to the extent that it would result in an increase or decrease of more than $2.5 million in the amount creditable to any state account for any calendar quarter. Amends the SSA to restrict interest-free advances to state accounts in the Fund to states which meet funding goals. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to require: (1) state collection of federal unemployment tax; and (2) state distribution to unemployed individuals of state-specific information packets explaining unemployment insurance eligibility conditions. Repeals the tax on unemployment compensation. Requires the Secretary of Labor to establish a Safety Net Review Commission.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
