<bill session="110" type="h" number="2809" updated="2009-01-08T22:41:51-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"/></status>

	<introduced date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">New Apollo Energy Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Advanced Design in Energy for Living Efficiently Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Biofuels Security Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Ending Subsidies for Big Oil Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Get Real Incentives to Drive Plug-in Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Marine and Hydrokinetic Renewable Energy Promotion Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Royalty Relief for American Consumers Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Clean Energy Superhighways Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure that the United States leads the world baseline in developing and manufacturing next generation energy technologies, to grow the economy of the United States, to create new highly trained, highly skilled American jobs, to eliminate American overdependence on foreign oil, and to address the threat of global warming.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400193"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2008-04-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400102" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400430" joined="2008-09-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400647" joined="2007-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400379" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400361" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="412189" joined="2007-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400184" joined="2008-09-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="2007-07-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400130" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400663" joined="2007-07-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400230" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400259" joined="2008-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400013" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400426" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400195" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2007-07-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400120" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400638" joined="2007-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400415" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400201" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400218" joined="2007-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400100" joined="2008-05-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H42-43, H43, H44, H45, H46-47, H48, H49)</text></action>
		<action date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Rules, Ways and Means, Education and Labor, Foreign Affairs, the Judiciary, Financial Services, Science and Technology, Oversight and Government Reform, Natural Resources, Agriculture, and the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text></action>
		<action date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"><text>Referred to House Rules</text></action>
		<action date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"><text>Referred to House Financial Services</text></action>
		<action date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"><text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text></action>
		<action date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"><text>Referred to House Budget</text></action>
		<action date="1182744000" datetime="2007-06-25"><committee name="House Science and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text></action>
		<action date="1183348800" datetime="2007-07-02"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1209096000" datetime="2008-04-25"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Credit, Energy, and Research.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/21/2007--Introduced.<br/>New Apollo Energy Act of 2007 - Directs the President, when formulating and enforcing national energy policy, to consider the New Apollo Energy Act Performance Goals established by this Act. Advanced Design in Energy for Living Efficiently Act of 2007 - Sets forth requirements governing building enterprises, including: (1) green building design; (2) reduced carbon emissions in new buildings; (3) high-performance school buildings and green building; and (4) energy efficiency increases and carbon emission reductions in federal agencies. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) create an energy tax credit for combined heat and power system property; and (2) extend biodiesel and other specified energy-related tax credits. Get Real Incentives to Drive Plug-in Act - Directs the Secretary of Transportation to establish programs for plug-in hybrid electric vehicles. Biofuels Security Act of 2007 - Amends the Clean Air Act to: (1) prescribe reductions for greenhouse gas emissions from vehicles and aircraft; and (2) set forth global climate change requirements. Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 regarding low carbon renewable fuel and carbon capture and storage. Amends the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 regarding: (1) rate design modifications; (2) net metering and interconnection standards; (3) efficiency resource standards; and (4) a federal renewable portfolio standard. Rural Clean Energy Superhighways Act - Amends the Federal Power Act regarding designation of National Renewable Energy Zones. Marine and Hydrokinetic Renewable Energy Promotion Act of 2007 - Establishes: (1) a marine and hydrokinetic renewable energy research program; and (2) the Adaptive Management and Environmental Fund.<br/>Amends the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act to provide information sharing and planning assistance to small manufacturing firms to implement new green manufacturing technologies.<br/>Sets forth a Green Workforce Education Incentives grants program. Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to authorize loan forgiveness for green workforce members.<br/>Establishes the New Energy Technologies Commission.<br/>Authorizes a grant program to create clean energy business districts.<br/>Prescribes a clean energy technology exports program.<br/>Amends the Energy Policy Act of 1992 to prescribe an international energy technology deployment program.<br/>Directs the Export-Import Bank of the United States to meet renewable energy targets in its lending practices.<br/>Establishes the Renewable Energy and Technology Commission. Amends the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 to: (1) increase financing for renewable energy and energy efficiency transactions; and (2) establish an Office of Renewable Energy Promotion. Instructs the Secretary of Energy to establish the Emerging Clean Energy Technology Venture Capital Fund.<br/>Amends the Global Change Research Act of 1990 to prescribe climate change research initiatives.<br/>Ending Subsidies for Big Oil Act of 2007 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) deny a deduction for income attributable to domestic production of oil, natural gas, and appurtenant primary products; and (2) augment from five years to seven years the amortization schedule for geological and geophysical expenditures of major integrated oil companies.<br/>Royalty Relief for American Consumers Act of 2007 - Prescribes price thresholds for royalty suspension provisions. Sets prerequisites for new leases for oil or natural gas production in the Gulf of Mexico. Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to repeal certain federal subsidies for royalty relief for oil and gas, including ones related to Planning Areas Offshore Alaska. Creates a Strategic Energy Efficiency and Renewables Reserve.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
