<bill session="110" type="h" number="2803" updated="2009-01-08T22:41:08-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"/></status>

	<introduced date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Angels Nurture Growing Entrepreneurs into Long-term Successes (ANGELS) Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to establish the Angel Investment Program.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400416"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400661" joined="2007-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400657" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="412221" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="412208" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400631" joined="2007-06-21"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"><text>Referred to the Committee on Small Business, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"><text>Referred to House Small Business</text></action>
		<action date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/21/2007--Introduced.<br/>Angels Nurture Growing Entrepreneurs into Long-Term Successes (ANGELS) Act - Amends the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to establish within the Investment Division of the Small Business Administration (SBA) the Office of Angel Investment, headed by a Director, to provide support for the development of angel investment opportunities for small businesses. Requires the Director to: (1) establish and carry out a program, to be known as the Angel Finance Program, to provide financing to approved angel groups; (2) establish and maintain a searchable database, to be known as the Federal Angel Network, to assist small businesses in identifying angel investors; and (3) establish and carry out a program to make grants for the development of new or existing angel groups and to increase awareness and education about angel investing. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide a small business investment tax credit of 20 percent of the amount paid or incurred for qualified small business investment.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
