<bill session="110" type="h" number="282" updated="2009-01-08T17:19:08-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"/></status>

	<introduced date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Second Opinion Coverage Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act, the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to require that group and individual health insurance coverage and group health plans provide coverage for second opinions.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400097"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2007-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400350" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="412255" joined="2008-09-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E27)</text></action>
		<action date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Education and Labor, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1169096400" datetime="2007-01-18"><committee name="House Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1170392400" datetime="2007-02-02"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
		<action date="1178683200" datetime="2007-05-09"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/5/2007--Introduced.<br/>Second Opinion Coverage Act of 2007 - Amends the Public Health Service Act, the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA), and the Internal Revenue Code to require a group health plan and an issuer offering group coverage to provide coverage for second opinions upon request under certain circumstances, including if: (1) the participant questions the reasonableness or necessity of recommended surgical procedures or of a diagnosis or plan of care for a condition that threatens loss or substantial impairment of life, limb, or bodily function; (2) the clinical indications are not clear or are complex or confusing, a diagnosis is in doubt due to conflicting test results, or the treating health care professional is unable to diagnose the condition; (3) the treatment plan in progress is not improving the medical condition of the participant; and (4) the participant has attempted to follow the plan of care or has consulted with the initial provider concerning serious concerns about the diagnosis or plan of care. Applies such requirements to coverage offered in the individual market. 
	</summary>
</bill>
