<bill session="110" type="h" number="2821" updated="2009-01-08T22:43:25-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"/></status>

	<introduced date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Television Freedom Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend section 122 of title 17, United States Code, and the Communications Act of 1934 to permit satellite carriers and cable operators to retransmit the signals of local television broadcast stations to their adjacent markets, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400345"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400620" joined="2007-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400657" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400096" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="412210" joined="2008-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400176" joined="2007-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400040" joined="2007-06-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400030" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2007-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400316" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400339" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="412227" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400169" joined="2007-10-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400026" joined="2007-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400645" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="412201" joined="2007-12-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2007-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400201" joined="2007-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400042" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400088" joined="2007-06-21"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"><text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and the Internet.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/21/2007--Introduced.<br/>Television Freedom Act of 2007 - Requires statutory licensing for a satellite carrier's secondary transmission into a television broadcast station's adjacent market if the satellite carrier also makes secondary transmissions into that adjacent market of the adjacent market's television broadcast stations. Defines &quot;adjacent market,&quot; for both commercial and noncommercial television broadcast stations, as a market area adjacent to, and at least partially in the same state as, the designated market area in which the station is located. Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to allow such secondary transmissions. Requires the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to revise related regulations concerning network nonduplication protection, syndicated exclusivity protection, and sports blackout protection to permit such retransmission.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
