<bill session="110" type="h" number="2838" updated="2009-01-08T22:45:39-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1182484800" datetime="2007-06-22"/></status>

	<introduced date="1182484800" datetime="2007-06-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Insular Areas Energy Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance the Department of Energy Innovative Technology Loan Guarantee Program established under title XVII of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 by explicitly permitting its application on United States Government installations worldwide, in the Insular Areas of the United States, and in those nations in free association with the United States, as well as explicitly authorize loans for ocean thermal energy conversion projects.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400128"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400041" joined="2007-06-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412223" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400001" joined="2007-09-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1182484800" datetime="2007-06-22"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Science and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1182484800" datetime="2007-06-22"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1182484800" datetime="2007-06-22"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text></action>
		<action date="1182484800" datetime="2007-06-22"><text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text></action>
		<action date="1182744000" datetime="2007-06-25"><committee name="House Science and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/22/2007--Introduced.<br/>Insular Areas Energy Act of 2007 - Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to authorize the Secretary of Energy to make loan guarantees for target ocean thermal energy conversion systems projects. Authorizes such guarantees for any specified eligible innovative energy projects, including ocean thermal energy conversion systems, which are located in Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Marianas Islands, the U.S. Virgin Islands, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Republic of the Marshall Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, and the Republic of Palau, as well as any U.S. government installation worldwide (including military bases, embassies, other federally owned or leased facilities, and all territorial waters, seabed, and subsoil of submarine areas adjacent to such installations).<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
