<bill session="110" type="h" number="2843" updated="2009-01-08T22:46:17-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26" /></status>

	<introduced date="1182484800" datetime="2007-06-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Library of Congress Public Diplomacy Collection Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the establishment and maintenance of existing libraries and resource centers at United States diplomatic and consular missions to provide information about American culture, society, and history, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400423"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400344" joined="2007-07-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1182484800" datetime="2007-06-22"><text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1182484800" datetime="2007-06-22"><text>Referred to House House Administration</text></action>
		<action date="1182484800" datetime="2007-06-22"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"><committee name="House Foreign Affairs"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26" ><committee name="House Foreign Affairs"/><text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/22/2007--Introduced.<br/>Library of Congress Public Diplomacy Collection Act of 2007 - Directs the Librarian of Congress to create a collection of materials of various media, print, audio, and visual for public use in Department of State libraries and resource centers to provide insight into U.S. culture, principles and values, law and civics, and democracy. Includes in such collection a separate collection of U.S. films (Johnny Grant Film Series) to be made available for public viewing in host countries. Authorizes appropriations.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
