<bill session="110" type="h" number="2840" updated="2009-01-08T22:45:53-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1182484800" datetime="2007-06-22"/></status>

	<introduced date="1182484800" datetime="2007-06-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Financial Literacy Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Community Reinvestment Act of 1977 to allow the direct support by a financial institution of a qualified community-based financial literacy program provided to consumers and borrowers to be taken into account in assessing the institution's record of meeting the credit needs of its entire community, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400204"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400661" joined="2007-10-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400031" joined="2007-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400073" joined="2008-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-10-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2008-09-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400246" joined="2007-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="2007-10-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2007-06-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400030" joined="2007-07-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2007-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400001" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412204" joined="2007-10-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400653" joined="2008-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400111" joined="2007-10-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400201" joined="2007-07-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400163" joined="2007-07-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400067" joined="2007-06-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1182484800" datetime="2007-06-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text></action>
		<action date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/22/2007--Introduced.<br/>National Financial Literacy Act of 2007 - Amends the Community Reinvestment Act of 1977 to require federal financial supervisory agencies jointly to prescribe regulations establishing: (1) minimum standards to be met by a community-based financial literacy program in order to be eligible for consideration as a qualified community-based financial literacy program; (2) procedures for financial institutions to apply to a federal financial supervisory agency for approval of such a program; and (3) a requirement that financial institutions submit a regular report on how the institution supported and promoted financial literacy in its entire community, including low- and moderate-income neighborhoods. Authorizes a federal financial supervisory agency to take an institution's direct support of a qualified community-based financial literacy program into account when it assesses the institution's record of meeting the community's credit needs.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
