<bill session="110" type="h" number="2855" updated="2009-01-08T22:47:48-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1182744000" datetime="2007-06-25"/></status>

	<introduced date="1182744000" datetime="2007-06-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Wounded Heroes' Bill of Rights Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for transitional emergency assistance to certain members of the Armed Forces and veterans who are severely injured while serving on active duty, to expand and improve programs for caregiver services for those members and veterans, to require improved screening and care for traumatic brain injury for returning servicemembers and veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400339"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1182744000" datetime="2007-06-25"><text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1182744000" datetime="2007-06-25"><text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1182744000" datetime="2007-06-25"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1182744000" datetime="2007-06-25"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1183435200" datetime="2007-07-03"><committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1185336000" datetime="2007-07-25"><committee name="House Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/25/2007--Introduced.<br/>Wounded Heroes' Bill of Rights Act - Directs the Secretary of Defense to provide prompt emergency cash assistance to a member of the Armed Forces or veteran who, on or after September 11, 2001, was or is severely injured while serving on active duty (to be known as a Wounded Hero) and, due to such injury, is undergoing significant financial difficulty. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide a business tax credit for employers hiring Wounded Heroes. Amends the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act to provide increased protections under such Act for Wounded Heroes and persons in military service. Requires the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (Secretary) to ensure the provision of sufficient services to meet the needs of Wounded Heroes without regard to residential geographic location with respect to the following: (1) adult day health care; (2) home health care; (3) respite care; (4) home-based primary care; (5) hospice; and (6) such other noninstitutional extended care services as appropriate. Directs the Secretary to operate and maintain a program in caregiver education, training, and certification for family members of Wounded Heroes. Authorizes the Secretary to contract with non-Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) facilities to furnish care to a Wounded Hero, under certain conditions. Establishes: (1) in the VA an Office for Wounded Heroes Advocate; (2) in the Executive Office of the President an Office for Wounded Heroes; and (3) the Wounded Heroes Independent Review Board. Requires the Board to, among other things, review VA or other federal agency determinations with respect to the scope and intensity of benefits, especially health care or vocational rehabilitation, provided to Wounded Heroes.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
