<bill session="110" type="h" number="2859" updated="2009-01-08T22:48:16-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"/></status>

	<introduced date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Prepare All Kids Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To assist States in making voluntary high quality full-day prekindergarten programs available and economically affordable for the families of all children for at least 1 year preceding kindergarten.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400251"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400295" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400647" joined="2007-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2008-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400087" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2007-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2007-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2007-09-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400240" joined="2007-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400639" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400067" joined="2007-09-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="412233" joined="2007-09-20"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1415)</text></action>
		<action date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H7344)</text></action>
		<action date="1189483200" datetime="2007-09-11"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/26/2007--Introduced.<br/>Prepare All Kids Act of 2007 - Amends the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1981 to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a Prekindergarten Incentive Fund from which matching grants shall be awarded to states and, through them, subgrants to qualified prekindergarten providers to establish, expand, or enhance voluntary high quality full-day prekindergarten programs serving children ages three through five. Requires prekindergarten providers to target children from families with incomes at or below 200% of the poverty line and provide them with program services free of charge. Directs state grantees to set aside: (1) at least 10% of a grant for quality early childhood development programs for children ages zero through three; and (2) at least 10% of a grant to extend the hours of early childhood programs to create extended day and year programs. 
	</summary>
</bill>
