<bill session="110" type="h" number="2858" updated="2009-01-08T22:48:09-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"/></status>

	<introduced date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To promote the production and use of ethanol.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400400"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400405" joined="2007-12-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Science and Technology, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text></action>
		<action date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"><text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text></action>
		<action date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1184299200" datetime="2007-07-13"><committee name="House Science and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/26/2007--Introduced.<br/>Amends the Petroleum Marketing Practices Act to prohibit a franchisor from restricting a franchisee from: (1) installing on the marketing premises a renewable fuel pump or tank; (2) converting an existing tank or pump for renewable fuel use; (3) advertising the sale of renewable fuel; (4) selling renewable fuel; (5) purchasing renewable fuel from sources other than the franchisor if the franchisor does not offer its own renewable fuel for sale by the franchisee; (6) listing renewable fuel availability or prices; or (7) allowing for payment of renewable fuel with a credit card. Allows such franchisee activities so long as they do not constitute willful adulteration, mislabeling, or misbranding of motor fuels or other trademark violations. Instructs the Secretary of Energy to establish a grants program for universities to demonstrate replacing corn as an ethanol feedstock with sweet sorghum. Amends the Clean Air Act and the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to provide for loan guarantees for closed loop ethanol commercial demonstration projects. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) increase and extend the alternative fuel vehicle refueling property credit; (2) make refueling property for biodiesel and renewable biodiesel eligible for the income tax deduction for clean-fuel vehicles and certain refueling property; and (3) increase the credit amount for research relating to alternative and renewable energy processes.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
