<bill session="110" type="h" number="2874" updated="2009-01-08T22:50:08-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1185825900" datetime="2007-07-30T17:05:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1182916800" datetime="2007-06-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans' Health Care Improvement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Veterans' Health Care Improvement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Veterans' Health Care Improvement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to make certain improvements in the provision of health care to veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400274"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2007-06-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400620" joined="2007-06-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="412229" joined="2007-07-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="412224" joined="2007-06-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400443" joined="2007-06-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="412210" joined="2007-07-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="412231" joined="2007-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="412189" joined="2007-06-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="412214" joined="2007-06-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="412197" joined="2007-06-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400007" joined="2007-07-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400339" joined="2007-06-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="412187" joined="2007-06-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400048" joined="2007-06-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="412209" joined="2007-06-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="412205" joined="2007-06-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="412222" joined="2007-06-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="412204" joined="2007-06-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="412239" joined="2007-07-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400440" joined="2007-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400042" joined="2007-06-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400024" joined="2007-06-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="412233" joined="2007-06-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1182916800" datetime="2007-06-27"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1182916800" datetime="2007-06-27"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28"><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1184126400" datetime="2007-07-11"><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1184126400" datetime="2007-07-11"><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text></action>
		<action date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1185568740" datetime="2007-07-27T17:39:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 110-268.</text></action>
		<calendar number="170" date="1185568740" datetime="2007-07-27T17:39:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 170.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1185824760" datetime="2007-07-30T16:46:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Filner moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1185824760" datetime="2007-07-30T16:46:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules. (consideration: CR 7/31/2007 H8892-8897)</text></action>
		<action date="1185824760" datetime="2007-07-30T16:46:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2874.</text></action>
		<vote date="1185825900" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-07-30T17:05:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H8892-8895"/></vote>
		<action date="1185854400" datetime="2007-07-31"><text>Received in the Senate.</text></action>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/30/2007--Passed House amended. Veterans' Health Care Improvement Act of 2007 - (Sec. 2) Authorizes the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to make grants to private, nonprofit entities to conduct workshop programs to assist in the therapeutic readjustment and rehabilitation of veterans who served on active duty in a theater of combat operations after the Persian Gulf War, or in combat during a period of hostilities after November 11, 1998, and are discharged or released from active duty on or after September 11, 2001 (covered veterans). Limits grant amounts to $100,000. Requires annual reports from the Secretary to the congressional veterans committees on the use of such grants and their benefits to covered veterans. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 3) Directs the Secretary to establish a grant program to provide innovative transportation options to veterans in remote rural areas. Limits grant amounts to $50,000. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 4) Makes permanent (currently ends on December 31, 2007) the VA authority to treat participants in the Department of Defense (DOD) chemical biological testing conducted by Deseret Test Center. (Sec. 5) Extends through FY2009 VA authority to collect health care copayments and certain medical care cost recovery amounts from veterans receiving such care. (Sec. 6) Directs the Secretary to carry out a program to provide, through contracts with community mental health centers, peer outreach services, peer support services, and readjustment and mental health services to covered veterans. Requires training for covered veterans and clinicians providing services under the program. (Sec. 7) Revises provisions concerning a joint VA-Department of Labor demonstration program of referral and counseling for veterans transitioning from certain institutions (including penal institutions) and who are at-risk for homelessness to: (1) remove the &quot;demonstration&quot; designation; (2) require the program to be carried out in at least 12 (under current law, six) locations; and (3) extend the program through FY2011. (Sec. 8) Removes the FY2003-FY2004 limit on the authorization of appropriations for a VA program to provide domiciliary care programs for homeless veterans. Requires the Secretary to ensure that such programs are adequate, with respect to capacity and safety, to meet the needs of women veterans. (Sec. 9) Directs the Secretary to provide financial assistance to private nonprofit organizations or consumer cooperatives to provide and coordinate supportive services for very low-income (less than 50% of the median income for the area) veteran families residing in permanent housing. Provides a preference for families who are transitioning from homelessness to permanent housing. Requires: (1) the provision of such assistance to be equitably distributed across geographic regions, including rural communities and tribal lands; and (2) the Secretary to provide appropriate training and technical assistance to entities providing such services. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 10) Makes homeless veterans eligible for dental care through the VA after receiving certain other types of care (such as domiciliary or community residential care) through the VA for 30 (under current law, 60) consecutive days.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
