<bill session="110" type="h" number="2886" updated="2009-01-08T22:51:37-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1182916800" datetime="2007-06-27"/></status>

	<introduced date="1182916800" datetime="2007-06-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Japan Currency Manipulation Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To address the exchange-rate misalignment of the Japanese yen with respect to the United States dollar, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400225"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1182916800" datetime="2007-06-27"><text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1182916800" datetime="2007-06-27"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1182916800" datetime="2007-06-27"><text>Referred to House Financial Services</text></action>
		<action date="1183435200" datetime="2007-07-03"><committee name="House Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/27/2007--Introduced.<br/>Japan Currency Manipulation Act - Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to report to Congress on: (1) currency intervention by Japan with respect to the rate of exchange of the Japanese yen and the U.S. dollar and other currencies since 2000; and (2) any effort by Japan to create an exchange-rate misalignment of the Japanese yen with respect to the U.S. dollar and other currencies since March 2004. Requires the Secretary to submit to Congress a proposal for a comprehensive joint U.S.-European Union plan to address the exchange-rate misalignment of the Japanese yen with respect to the U.S. dollar and other currencies. Directs the Secretary to: (1) initiate consultations with Japan to decrease Japan's foreign currency reserve holdings to permit effective balance of payments adjustments and to eliminate its unfair competitive advantage in international trade; and (2) take appropriate action to dissuade, prevent, or object to currency intervention by Japan. Directs the United States to call for the convening of a special meeting of the International Monetary Fund (IMF) to reach a multilateral agreement regarding: (1) the exchange-rate misalignment of the Japanese yen with respect to the U.S. dollar and other currencies; (2) the destabilizing effects of the exchange-rate misalignment of the Japanese yen; and (3) Japan's excessive foreign currency reserve holdings. Directs the Secretary to report to Congress on: (1) progress made toward decreasing Japan's foreign currency reserve holdings; and (2) actions taken at meetings of the G-7 Leaders, G-7 Finance Ministers, and the IMF regarding the exchange-rate misalignment of the Japanese yen with respect to the U.S. dollar and other currencies, including any progress toward eliminating such misalignment.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
