<bill session="110" type="h" number="2884" updated="2009-01-08T22:51:23-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1194369720" datetime="2007-11-06T13:22:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1182916800" datetime="2007-06-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Kendell Frederick Citizenship Assistance Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Kendell Frederick Citizenship Assistance Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To assist members of the Armed Forces in obtaining United States citizenship, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400090"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400616" joined="2007-07-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400333" joined="2007-07-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400152" joined="2007-07-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400224" joined="2007-07-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412235" joined="2007-07-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400166" joined="2007-07-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412240" joined="2007-07-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400653" joined="2007-07-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2007-07-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2007-07-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400201" joined="2007-07-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2007-07-11"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1182916800" datetime="2007-06-27"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1184126400" datetime="2007-07-11"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1490)</text></action>
		<action date="1184558400" datetime="2007-07-16"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text></action>
		<action date="1190692800" datetime="2007-09-25"><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1190692800" datetime="2007-09-25"><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text></action>
		<action date="1193198400" datetime="2007-10-24"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1193198400" datetime="2007-10-24" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1194359880" datetime="2007-11-06T10:38:00-05:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 110-429.</text></action>
		<calendar number="270" date="1194361020" datetime="2007-11-06T10:57:00-05:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 270.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1194368760" datetime="2007-11-06T13:06:00-05:00"><text>Ms. Lofgren, Zoe moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1194368760" datetime="2007-11-06T13:06:00-05:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H12771-12773"/></action>
		<action date="1194368760" datetime="2007-11-06T13:06:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2884.</text></action>
		<vote date="1194369720" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-11-06T13:22:00-05:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H12771-12772"/></vote>
		<action date="1194498000" datetime="2007-11-08"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/6/2007--Passed House amended. Kendell Frederick Citizenship Assistance Act - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (Secretary) to use the fingerprints provided by an individual at the time of military enlistment to satisfy any naturalization fingerprint requirements if: (1) the individual may be naturalized under the Immigration and Nationality Act; (2) the individual was fingerprinted in accordance with Department of Defense (DOD) requirements; (3) the individual submits a naturalization application within 24 months of enlistment; and (4) the Secretary determines that the fingerprints are sufficient to adjudicate the naturalization application. Directs the Secretary to inform military naturalization applicants of their choice to provide new fingerprints if such submission would result in more timely and effective naturalization adjudication. Provides for cooperation between the Secretary and the Secretary of Defense to determine an appropriate fingerprint format. Directs the Secretary to update Department of Homeland Security (DHS) websites within 30 days of any change in naturalization law or regulation affecting members of the Armed Forces. Directs the Comptroller General to: (1) report to the congressional defense and judiciary committees on the naturalization application process for members of the Armed Forces; and (2) conduct a study of this Act's implementation by the Secretaries of Homeland Security and Defense.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
