<bill session="110" type="h" number="29" updated="2009-01-08T16:44:46-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1202843580" datetime="2008-02-12T15:13:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to construct facilities to provide water for irrigation, municipal, domestic, military, and other uses from the Santa Margarita River, California, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400196"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1169701200" datetime="2007-01-25"><committee name="House Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text></action>
		<action date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text></action>
		<action date="1191988800" datetime="2007-10-10"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1191988800" datetime="2007-10-10"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Subcommittee on Water and Power Discharged.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1191988800" datetime="2007-10-10" ><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1198105200" datetime="2007-12-19T19:00:00-05:00"><text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-503, Part I.</text></action>
		<action date="1198105260" datetime="2007-12-19T19:01:00-05:00"><text>House Committee on Armed Services Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Jan. 15, 2008.</text></action>
		<action date="1200373200" datetime="2008-01-15"><committee name="House Armed Services"/><text>Subcommittee on Readiness Discharged.</text></action>
		<action date="1200441600" datetime="2008-01-15T20:00:00-05:00"><text>Committee on Armed Services discharged.</text></action>
		<calendar number="309" date="1200441660" datetime="2008-01-15T20:01:00-05:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 309.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1202843400" datetime="2008-02-12T15:10:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Grijalva moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text></action>
		<action date="1202843400" datetime="2008-02-12T15:10:00-05:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H829-831"/></action>
		<action date="1202843400" datetime="2008-02-12T15:10:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 29.</text></action>
		<vote date="1202843580" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-02-12T15:13:00-05:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H829-830"/></vote>
		<action date="1202878800" datetime="2008-02-13"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1209009600" datetime="2008-04-24"><committee name="House Armed Services"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="1008" date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1008.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/12/2008--Passed House without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the House reported version is repeated here.) (Sec. 2) Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior (the Secretary) to construct, operate, and maintain a project to provide water for irrigation, municipal, domestic, military, and other uses from the Santa Margarita River, California, in accordance with the final feasibility report and this Act. Authorizes project construction only after the Secretary determines that: (1) the Fallbrook Public Utility District, San Diego County, and the Navy have entered into contracts to repay to the United States appropriate costs; (2) the authorized California officer or agency has granted water use permits to the Bureau of Reclamation; (3) the District has agreed that it will not assert against the United States any prior right to water in excess of the quantity deliverable under this Act and will share water based on equal priority and a specified ratio; and (4) the Secretary has determined that the project has economic, environmental, and engineering feasibility.<br/>(Sec. 3) Provides that, upon project completion, the Department of the Navy shall be responsible to repay only that portion of costs that the Secretary and the Navy Secretary determine reflects the extent to which the Department benefits from the project. (Sec. 4) Permits operation of the project by the Secretary, the District, or a third party consistent with this Act. Requires the Department and the District to participate in the project yield on the basis of equal priority, with 60% of the project's yield allotted to the Navy Secretary and 40% allotted to the District. Sets forth provisions governing the sale and delivery of excess water.<br/>(Sec. 5) Requires the District's general repayment obligation to be determined by the Secretary consistent with the Reclamation Project Act of 1939. (Sec. 6) Authorizes the Secretary to transfer operation of the project to the District or a mutually agreed upon third party. Provides that if such a transfer takes place, the District shall be entitled to an equitable credit for the costs associated with the Secretary's proportionate share of the project's operation and maintenance.<br/>(Sec. 7) Provides that the basis, measure, and limit of all U.S. rights pertaining to the use of water under this Act shall be California law.<br/>(Sec. 8) Prohibits the project from being administered or operated in any way that would impair or deplete the quantities of water the United States would have been entitled to use under California law had the project not been built, unless otherwise agreed by the Navy Secretary.<br/>(Sec. 9) Authorizes appropriations.<br/>(Sec. 10) Requires the Secretary and the Navy Secretary to report to Congress regarding whether and how the conditions specified by this Act have been met.<br/>(Sec. 11) Terminates the Secretary's authority to complete project construction 10 years after this Act's enactment.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
