<bill session="110" type="h" number="2947" updated="2009-01-08T22:59:19-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28"/></status>

	<introduced date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Energy Efficient Buildings Promotion Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the establishment of energy performance standards for new Federal or federally supported buildings, and major renovations of Federal or federally supported buildings, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400413"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1448)</text></action>
		<action date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text></action>
		<action date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1183089600" datetime="2007-06-29"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/28/2007--Introduced.<br/>Energy Efficient Buildings Promotion Act - Amends the Energy Conservation and Production Act to direct the Secretary of Energy to establish, by rule, revised building energy performance standards for new federal buildings and those undergoing major renovations. Amends the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to increase: (1) limitations for the nonbusiness energy property tax credit; (2) the applicable amount for the new energy efficient home credit; and (3) the per square footage dollar amount for the energy efficient commercial buildings deduction. Requires the Secretary to study and make recommendations to Congress on whether to conform certain Internal Revenue Code incentives, as provided in the Energy Policy Act of 2005, to the building energy performance goal established under this Act.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
