<bill session="110" type="h" number="2945" updated="2009-01-08T22:59:04-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28"/></status>

	<introduced date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Advantage Truth in Advertising Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend part C of title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide beneficiary protections against excessive cost-sharing under the Medicare Advantage Program.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400387"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1450)</text></action>
		<action date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28"><text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1183694400" datetime="2007-07-06"><committee name="House Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/28/2007--Introduced.<br/>Medicare Advantage Truth in Advertising Act of 2007 - Amends part C (Medicare+Choice) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to restrict cost-sharing under the Medicare Advantage (MA) Program to a level no greater (and permissably less) than the cost-sharing that would otherwise be imposed under the original Medicare fee-for-service program option. Declares that nothing regarding original Medicare fee-for-service program option benefits shall be construed as prohibiting an MA plan from using a flat copayment or per diem rate, under this Act, in lieu of the cost-sharing imposed under Medicare part A or part B.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
