<bill session="110" type="h" number="2955" updated="2009-01-08T23:00:16-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1184040000" datetime="2007-07-10"/></status>

	<introduced date="1184040000" datetime="2007-07-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Every Student Counts Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To improve calculation, reporting, and accountability for graduation rates.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400364"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-07-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400080" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="412221" joined="2007-07-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400271" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2007-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="2007-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400355" joined="2007-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400130" joined="2007-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2007-07-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400402" joined="2007-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400356" joined="2007-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400048" joined="2007-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2007-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="412204" joined="2007-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400653" joined="2007-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400217" joined="2007-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400120" joined="2008-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2007-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400201" joined="2007-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400090" joined="2007-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400363" joined="2007-10-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400179" joined="2007-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400067" joined="2007-07-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1184040000" datetime="2007-07-10"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1480)</text></action>
		<action date="1184040000" datetime="2007-07-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1190174400" datetime="2007-09-19"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/10/2007--Introduced.<br/>Every Student Counts Act - Requires states, local educational agencies (LEAs), and high schools annually to calculate and report, as part of the report cards required under title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA), the percentage of high school students: (1) graduating in four years and in five years with a regular high school diploma from each cohort graduating class; and (2) the percentage of students in each grade, except the graduating grade, prepared to advance to the next grade. Requires such data to be reported in the aggregate and disaggregated by race, ethnicity, gender, disability status, migrant status, English proficiency, and status as economically disadvantaged. Directs states that lack a statewide longitudinal data system with individual student identifiers to make certain interim graduation rate calculations, but requires all states to make the four and five-year adjusted cohort graduation rate calculations by 2012. Requires the use of such rates in determining the success of each high school and LEA in making adequate yearly progress (AYP) toward state academic performance standards under the ESEA. Requires schools and LEAs whose four and five-year adjusted cohort graduation rates fall below 90% overall or for any low-income, minority, disabled, migrant, or limited English proficient student subgroup, to make specified yearly progress in improving such rates or be deemed as failing to make AYP.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
