<bill session="110" type="h" number="2956" updated="2009-01-08T23:00:25-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1184274720" datetime="2007-07-12T18:12:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="624"/></status>

	<introduced date="1184040000" datetime="2007-07-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Responsible Redeployment from Iraq Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Responsible Redeployment from Iraq Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Defense to commence the reduction of the number of United States Armed Forces in Iraq to a limited presence by April 1, 2008, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400377"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412221" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400209" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412195" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412192" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412210" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400300" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412214" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400396" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412208" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412197" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412188" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400231" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400356" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412223" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412209" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412193" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400308" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412199" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400103" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400270" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400166" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412240" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412204" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400378" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400021" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412239" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400120" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412200" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400232" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400189" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400415" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412220" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400097" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400090" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412219" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400233" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400314" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412233" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400075" joined="2007-07-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1184040000" datetime="2007-07-10"><text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1184040000" datetime="2007-07-10"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1184040000" datetime="2007-07-10"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1184187420" datetime="2007-07-11T17:57:00-04:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 533 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2956 with 4 hours of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. All points of order against the bill and against its consideration are waived except thos arising under clause 9 or 10 or rule XXI.</text></action>
		<action date="1184296200" datetime="2007-07-12T12:10:00-04:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 533 passed House.</text></action>
		<action date="1184296680" datetime="2007-07-12T12:18:00-04:00"><text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 533.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H7674-7719"/></action>
		<action date="1184296680" datetime="2007-07-12T12:18:00-04:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2956 with 4 hours of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. All points of order against the bill and against its consideration are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 or rule XXI.</text></action>
		<action date="1184296800" datetime="2007-07-12T12:20:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with four hours of debate on H.R. 2956.</text></action>
		<action date="1184272080" datetime="2007-07-12T17:28:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H7719"/></action>
		<action date="1184272080" datetime="2007-07-12T17:28:00-04:00"><text>Mrs. Wilson (NM) moved to recommit with instructions to Armed Services.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H7717"/></action>
		<action date="1184272140" datetime="2007-07-12T17:29:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Wilson(NM) motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to insert a complete new text which includes Electronic Surveillance.</text></action>
		<action date="1184272260" datetime="2007-07-12T17:31:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Skelton raised a point of order against the motion to recommit with instructions. Mr. Skelton stated that the provisions contained in the motion to recommit are not germane to the bill. Sustained by the Chair.</text></action>
		<action date="1184272260" datetime="2007-07-12T17:31:00-04:00"><text>Point of order sustained against the motion to recommit with instructions.</text></action>
		<action date="1184272740" datetime="2007-07-12T17:39:00-04:00"><text>Mrs. Wilson (NM) appealed the ruling of the chair. The question was then put on sustaining the ruling of the chair.</text></action>
		<action date="1184272740" datetime="2007-07-12T17:39:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Skelton moved to table the motion to appeal the ruling of the chair</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H7718-7719"/></action>
		<action date="1184274120" datetime="2007-07-12T18:02:00-04:00"><text>On motion to table the motion to appeal the ruling of the chair Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 224 - 197 (Roll no. 623).</text></action>
		<vote date="1184274720" how="roll" roll="624" datetime="2007-07-12T18:12:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 223 - 201 (Roll no. 624).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H7674-7675"/></vote>
		<action date="1184558400" datetime="2007-07-16"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/12/2007--Passed House without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Responsible Redeployment from Iraq Act - Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the Authorization for Use of Military Force Against Iraq Resolution of 2002 authorized the President to use the Armed Forces as appropriate to defend U.S. national security against the continuing threat posed by the government of Iraq at the time; (2) the government of Iraq which was in power at that time has been removed; (3) the current Iraqi government does not pose a threat to the United States; and (4) after more than four years of efforts by members of the Armed Forces and U.S. civilians, the government of Iraq must now be responsible for Iraq's future course. Directs the Secretary of Defense to commence the reduction of the number of Armed Forces in Iraq beginning no later than 120 days after the enactment of this Act and complete the reduction and transition to a limited presence in Iraq by no later than April 1, 2008 Directs the President, by January 1, 2008, to transmit to the congressional defense, appropriations, and foreign relations committees a comprehensive U.S. strategy for Iraq. Requires the President to update such strategy no later than July 1, 2008, and every 90 days thereafter, including a description of the number of Armed Forces deployed to Iraq and the missions for which they are so deployed.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
