<bill session="110" type="h" number="2953" updated="2009-01-08T23:00:01-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1184040000" datetime="2007-07-10"/></status>

	<introduced date="1184040000" datetime="2007-07-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Broadband Access Enhancement Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 to improve the application process for the rural broadband program of the Department of Agriculture.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412229"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412255" joined="2008-04-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1184040000" datetime="2007-07-10"><text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1184040000" datetime="2007-07-10"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action date="1184040000" datetime="2007-07-10"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1184040000" datetime="2007-07-10"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and the Internet.</text></action>
		<action date="1209096000" datetime="2008-04-25"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/10/2007--Introduced.<br/>Rural Broadband Access Enhancement Act - Amends the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 to redefine &quot;eligible rural community.&quot; Permits a loan or loan guarantee applicant in an area where 40% of the residents are without broadband access to qualify with a 10% loan equity position. Provides for: (1) paperwork reduction; and (2) program outreach to underserved areas. Prohibits loan or loan guarantees for new broadband service in communities with three or more service providers. Provides that for each fiscal year: (1) not more than 10% of program funds shall be available to providers with more than 10% of national subscriber lines; and (2) 40% of program funds shall be available to providers with between 2%-10% of national subscriber lines. Revises the amortization period from the life of the asset to 35 years. Requires an annual broadband program report to Congress.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
