<bill session="110" type="h" number="2976" updated="2009-01-08T23:02:49-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1184040000" datetime="2007-07-10"/></status>

	<introduced date="1184040000" datetime="2007-07-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Saudi Arabia Accountability Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To halt Saudi support for institutions that fund, train, incite, encourage, or in any other way aid and abet terrorism, and to secure full Saudi cooperation in the investigation of terrorist incidents, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400426"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400289" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400430" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400132" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="2008-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400288" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400055" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400245" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400147" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400103" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400087" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400346" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400368" joined="2008-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2008-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2008-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400024" joined="2007-09-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1184040000" datetime="2007-07-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/10/2007--Introduced.<br/>Saudi Arabia Accountability Act of 2007 - Expresses the sense of Congress that the government of Saudi Arabia must: (1) cooperate fully with the United States in the investigation of terror groups and individuals; (2) close permanently all organizations in Saudi Arabia that fund, train, encourage, or in any way aid terrorism anywhere in the world; (3) end funding for terror organizations outside Saudi Arabia; and (4) block funding from private Saudi citizens and entities to Saudi-based or offshore terror organizations. Directs the President to prohibit certain exports to Saudi Arabia and restrict travel of certain Saudi diplomats if the President cannot certify to the appropriate congressional committees that the government of Saudi Arabia: (1) is fully cooperating with the United States in investigating and preventing terrorist attacks; (2) has closed permanently all Saudi-based terror organizations; (3) has ended funding for any offshore terror organization; and (4) has made all efforts to block funding from private Saudi citizens and entities to offshore terror organizations. Allows the President to waive such sanctions for national security reasons.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
