<bill session="110" type="h" number="2985" updated="2009-01-08T23:03:50-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1184040000" datetime="2007-07-10"/></status>

	<introduced date="1184040000" datetime="2007-07-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Arab Bank Accountability Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of the Treasury to take certain actions with regard to the Arab Bank, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400426"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1184040000" datetime="2007-07-10"><text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1184040000" datetime="2007-07-10"><text>Referred to House Financial Services</text></action>
		<action date="1184040000" datetime="2007-07-10"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/10/2007--Introduced.<br/>Arab Bank Accountability Act - Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to release certain documents and information relating to the Arab Bank (other than those which would impede any federal criminal or civil investigation of the Bank). Directs the President to block certain Bank assets within the United States which shall be made available for payment of any terrorism-related judgment against the Bank. States that after any such judgment becomes final the Board of Directors of the Federal Reserve System and the Comptroller of the Currency shall act to terminate any Bank branch or agency in the United States and to prohibit the Bank from maintaining any interest in any commercial lending company within the United States. 
	</summary>
</bill>
