<bill session="110" type="h" number="2997" updated="2009-01-08T23:05:14-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1184126400" datetime="2007-07-11"/></status>

	<introduced date="1184126400" datetime="2007-07-11"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Assured Food Safety Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Agriculture and the Commissioner of Food and Drugs to establish a program requiring a certificate of assured safety for imported food items.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400211"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400230" joined="2007-07-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400343" joined="2008-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="412232" joined="2007-09-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2008-02-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1184126400" datetime="2007-07-11"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H7636-7637)</text></action>
		<action date="1184126400" datetime="2007-07-11"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1184126400" datetime="2007-07-11"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1184126400" datetime="2007-07-11"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1184126400" datetime="2007-07-11"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action date="1184126400" datetime="2007-07-11"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1184558400" datetime="2007-07-16"><committee name="House Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/11/2007--Introduced.<br/>Assured Food Safety Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture and the Commissioner of Food and Drugs to jointly establish a program to require all food items imported into the United States to bear a certificate of assured safety issued by the government of the country from which the item is imported. Directs the Secretary and the Commissioner to: (1) establish certificate requirements; and (2) prohibit a food item that does not bear such certificate from being imported into the United States. Authorizes specified exemptions. Directs the Secretary and the Commissioner, upon a food item's failure to provide the assured safety level, to prohibit the importation of any similar food item produced by the same person in the same country until the Secretary or the Commissioner inspects the production place and determines that sufficient corrective steps have been taken. Requires: (1) heightened inspections for three years following the removal of a food item's import prohibition; and (2) inspection-related user fees on foods imported into the United States. Authorizes fee waiver or reduction. Provides: (1) a private right of action against an importer; and (2) criminal penalties against an importer who knowingly imports a non-complying food item.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
