<bill session="110" type="h" number="3000" updated="2009-01-08T23:05:39-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1184126400" datetime="2007-07-11"/></status>

	<introduced date="1184126400" datetime="2007-07-11"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Josephine Butler United States Health Service Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a United States Health Service to provide high quality comprehensive health care for all Americans and to overcome the deficiencies in the present system of health care delivery.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400237"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400073" joined="2007-07-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400227" joined="2007-07-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2007-07-11"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1184126400" datetime="2007-07-11"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Education and Labor, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1184126400" datetime="2007-07-11"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1184126400" datetime="2007-07-11"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1184126400" datetime="2007-07-11"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1184126400" datetime="2007-07-11"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1185249600" datetime="2007-07-24"><committee name="House Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1189483200" datetime="2007-09-11"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text></action>
		<action date="1189483200" datetime="2007-09-11"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/11/2007--Introduced.<br/>Josephine Butler United States Health Service Act - Establishes the United States Health Service as an independent executive branch entity to provide health care and supplemental health services to all individuals within the United States. Requires the President to appoint members to a National Health Board to exercise the authority of the Service. Establishes an Office of the Inspector General for Health Services. Requires the Service to ensure that every individual is given certain basic health rights, including the right to receive high quality care and supplemental services from any facility within the Service capable of providing such services without charge and without discrimination. Amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to provide employees with leave to receive necessary health care services. Requires the Board to: (1) establish any necessary health care facilities; (2) establish guidelines for the classification, certification, and employment of health workers by job category; (3) provide for the education of health workers through health team schools and loan repayment; (4) establish a health advocacy program to ensure the realization of patients' rights; (5) oversee occupational safety and health programs; and (6) conduct research concerning health and health care delivery. Transfers to the Board the agencies of the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) that conduct research on health and health care. Requires the Board to establish additional research institutes. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose a health services tax on the income of individuals and corporations to fund the Health Service Trust Fund (established under this Act). Transfers to the Service certain authority of the Secretary of HHS. 
	</summary>
</bill>
