<bill session="110" type="h" number="3001" updated="2009-01-08T23:05:52-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1184126400" datetime="2007-07-11"/></status>

	<introduced date="1184126400" datetime="2007-07-11"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">CLASS Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Community Living Assistance Services and Supports Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to help individuals with functional impairments and their families pay for services and supports that they need to maximize their functionality and independence and have choices about community participation, education, and employment, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400308"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2007-09-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412229" joined="2008-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400289" joined="2008-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400160" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400080" joined="2008-07-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="2007-10-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400384" joined="2008-01-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400130" joined="2008-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412209" joined="2008-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400103" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400110" joined="2007-07-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400346" joined="2007-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="2007-10-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400211" joined="2007-09-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400415" joined="2008-03-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400043" joined="2007-09-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400310" joined="2008-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400215" joined="2007-12-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1184126400" datetime="2007-07-11"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1184126400" datetime="2007-07-11"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1184126400" datetime="2007-07-11"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1184126400" datetime="2007-07-11"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1184126400" datetime="2007-07-11"><text>Referred to House Rules</text></action>
		<action date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"><committee name="House Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/11/2007--Introduced.<br/>Community Living Assistance Services and Supports Act or the CLASS Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to create a national, voluntary disability insurance program (CLASS program) under which: (1) all employees are automatically enrolled, but are allowed to waive enrollment; (2) payroll deductions pay monthly premiums; and (3) two-tiered benefits are provided, based on the level of disability, to purchase nonmedical services and supports that the beneficiary needs to maintain independence. Establishes the Independence Fund within the Treasury. Requires the CLASS program to be treated for tax purposes in the same manner as a qualified long-term care insurance contract. Amends the Social Security Act to require each state to: (1) assess the extent to which personal care services providers are serving or able to serve as fiscal agents, employers, and providers of employment-related benefits for personal care attendant workers, who provide personal care services to individuals receiving benefits under this Act; (2) designate or create entities to serve such purposes; and (3) ensure that such entities will not negatively alter or impede existing programs, models, methods, or administration of service delivery that provide for consumer controlled or self-directed home and community services, impede the ability of individuals to direct and control their home and community services, or inhibit individuals from relying on family members for such services. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a Personal Care Attendants Workforce Advisory Panel to examine and advise the Secretary and Congress on workforce issues related to personal care attendant workers. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow: (1) a deduction for premiums paid for the CLASS program; (2) a credit CLASS program enrollees with low income; and (3) a credit for employers for the cost incurred to automatically enroll employees and withhold monthly premiums.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
