<bill session="110" type="h" number="3018" updated="2009-01-08T23:07:55-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1222378140" datetime="2008-09-25T18:29:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1184212800" datetime="2007-07-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Family Self-Sufficiency Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Family Self-Sufficiency Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for payment of an administrative fee to public housing agencies to cover the costs of administering family self-sufficiency programs in connection with the housing choice voucher program of the Department of Housing and Urban Development.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400027"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1184212800" datetime="2007-07-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text></action>
		<action date="1206676800" datetime="2008-03-28"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Housing and Community Opportunity.</text></action>
		<action date="1222218840" datetime="2008-09-23T22:14:00-04:00"><text>Ms. Moore (WI) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text></action>
		<action date="1222218840" datetime="2008-09-23T22:14:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8703-8705"/><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR H8703"/></action>
		<action date="1222218840" datetime="2008-09-23T22:14:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3018.</text></action>
		<action date="1222219800" datetime="2008-09-23T22:30:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mrs. Biggert objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text></action>
		<action date="1222378140" datetime="2008-09-25T18:29:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text></action>
		<vote date="1222378140" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-09-25T18:29:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text></vote>
		<action date="1222401600" datetime="2008-09-26"><text>Received in the Senate.</text></action>
		<action date="1222920000" datetime="2008-10-02"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/25/2008--Passed House without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.) Family Self-Sufficiency Act of 2007 - Amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 to revise requirements for the administrative fee payable to public housing agencies (PHAs) to cover the costs of administering family self-sufficiency programs in connection with the housing choice voucher program of the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD). Prescribes: (1) a base fee for a PHA serving 25 or more program participants equal to the costs of employing one full-time family self-sufficiency coordinator (prorated for an agency serving fewer than 25 such participants); and (2) an additional fee for an agency meeting minimum performance standards to cover the costs of employing a second coordinator if the agency has 75 or more participating families, and a third coordinator if it has 125 or more participating families. Requires the Secretary to publish a proposed rule specifying the performance standards applicable to funding such additional fees and agencies that have received HUD funding for more than three such coordinators between FY1998-FY2007. Requires PHAs receiving such funds to collect and report to the Secretary information on the performance of their family self-sufficiency programs. Directs the Secretary to: (1) conduct a formal and scientific evaluation of the effectiveness of well-run family self-sufficiency programs, using random assignment of participants to the extent practicable; and (2) submit interim and final reports to Congress. Authorizes appropriations for the evaluation. Permits the Secretary to reserve up to 10% of the amounts available for administrative fees to provide support to or reward family self-sufficiency programs that are particularly innovative or highly successful in achieving program goals.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
