<bill session="110" type="h" number="3021" updated="2009-01-08T23:08:15-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1212623220" datetime="2008-06-04T20:47:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="379"/></status>

	<introduced date="1184212800" datetime="2007-07-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">21st Century High-Performing Public School Facilities Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">21st Century Green High-Performing Public School Facilities Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">21st Century Green High-Performing Public School Facilities Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Education to make grants and low-interest loans to local educational agencies for the construction, modernization, or repair of public kindergarten, elementary, and secondary educational facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
		<title type="official" as="amended by house">To direct the Secretary of Education to make grants to State educational agencies for the modernization, renovation, or repair of public school facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400442"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400290" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400661" joined="2007-09-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400253" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400041" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400620" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400031" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400073" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400227" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400177" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400364" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400257" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400289" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400160" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400155" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400407" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400092" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400080" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400657" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412221" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400102" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400282" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412234" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400122" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400403" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400635" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400623" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400096" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400430" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400129" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400065" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400443" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400198" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400379" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400361" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412192" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400630" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400323" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="412231" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400662" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412189" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400084" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412214" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400384" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400184" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400412" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400355" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412208" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400216" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400437" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412198" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400402" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="412253" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400663" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400352" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400339" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400331" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400230" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400008" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412227" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400356" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412187" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400048" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="412209" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400044" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412193" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400308" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412199" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400631" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400001" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400395" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400103" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400110" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="412211" joined="2007-09-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400259" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400383" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412222" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="412204" joined="2007-09-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400195" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400251" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400026" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412232" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400350" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400217" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400366" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400255" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400645" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="412239" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400281" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400120" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400628" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400638" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="412200" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400266" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400125" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400193" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400415" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="412254" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400009" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="412186" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400326" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="412228" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412212" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400201" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400204" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400097" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400090" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400042" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400208" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400218" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400240" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412219" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400215" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400363" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400301" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400345" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400114" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400062" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412194" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400233" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400179" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400100" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400186" joined="2008-02-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="2007-07-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1184212800" datetime="2007-07-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1189483200" datetime="2007-09-11"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text></action>
		<action date="1189483200" datetime="2007-09-11"><text>Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education Discharged.</text></action>
		<action date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 28 - 19.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1210269120" datetime="2008-05-08T14:52:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Education and Labor. H. Rept. 110-623.</text></action>
		<calendar number="388" date="1210269120" datetime="2008-05-08T14:52:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 388.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1212533340" datetime="2008-06-03T19:49:00-04:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1234 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3021 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text></action>
		<action date="1212607320" datetime="2008-06-04T16:22:00-04:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 1234 passed House.</text></action>
		<action date="1212608700" datetime="2008-06-04T16:45:00-04:00"><text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 1234.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H4927-4935, H4937-4961"/></action>
		<action date="1212608700" datetime="2008-06-04T16:45:00-04:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3021 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text></action>
		<action date="1212608700" datetime="2008-06-04T16:45:00-04:00"><text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 1234 and Rule XVIII.</text></action>
		<action date="1212608700" datetime="2008-06-04T16:45:00-04:00"><text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Madeleine Z. Bordallo to act as Chairwoman of the Committee.</text></action>
		<action date="1212608700" datetime="2008-06-04T16:45:00-04:00"><text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 3021.</text></action>
		<action date="1212613440" datetime="2008-06-04T18:04:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1234, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Kildee amendment.</text></action>
		<action date="1212614160" datetime="2008-06-04T18:16:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Kildee amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Kildee demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text></action>
		<action date="1212614220" datetime="2008-06-04T18:17:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1234, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Ehlers amendment.</text></action>
		<action date="1212614520" datetime="2008-06-04T18:22:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Ehlers amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Ehlers demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text></action>
		<action date="1212614520" datetime="2008-06-04T18:22:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1234, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with thirty minutes of debate on the Welch amendment.</text></action>
		<action date="1212615660" datetime="2008-06-04T18:41:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Welch amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Welch demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text></action>
		<action date="1212615720" datetime="2008-06-04T18:42:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1234, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Tom Davis amendment.</text></action>
		<action date="1212616080" datetime="2008-06-04T18:48:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1234, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Visclosky amendment.</text></action>
		<action date="1212616920" datetime="2008-06-04T19:02:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1234, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Matheson amendment.</text></action>
		<action date="1212617280" datetime="2008-06-04T19:08:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Matheson amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Matheson demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text></action>
		<action date="1212617280" datetime="2008-06-04T19:08:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1234, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Reichert amendment.</text></action>
		<action date="1212617640" datetime="2008-06-04T19:14:00-04:00"><text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings were postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1212620760" datetime="2008-06-04T20:06:00-04:00"><text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 3021.</text></action>
		<action date="1212620760" datetime="2008-06-04T20:06:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H4959"/></action>
		<action date="1212620820" datetime="2008-06-04T20:07:00-04:00"><text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H4946-4947"/></action>
		<action date="1212620880" datetime="2008-06-04T20:08:00-04:00"><text>Mrs. McMorris Rodgers moved to recommit with instructions toEducation and Labor.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H4959"/><reference label="text" ref="CR H4959"/></action>
		<action date="1212621060" datetime="2008-06-04T20:11:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the McMorris Rodgers motion to recommit. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment inserting an exception for local educational agencies whose energy expenditures have increased by at least 50 percent since January 4, 2007, with respect to payment of maintenance costs for any of the activities described in section 103.</text></action>
		<action date="1212621540" datetime="2008-06-04T20:19:00-04:00"><text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H4960"/></action>
		<action date="1212622680" datetime="2008-06-04T20:38:00-04:00"><text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 187 - 230 (Roll no. 378).</text></action>
		<vote date="1212623220" how="roll" roll="379" datetime="2008-06-04T20:47:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 250 - 164 (Roll no. 379).</text></vote>
		<action date="1212623220" datetime="2008-06-04T20:47:00-04:00"><text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action date="1212623220" datetime="2008-06-04T20:47:00-04:00"><text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 3021.</text></action>
		<action date="1212724800" datetime="2008-06-06"><text>Received in the Senate.</text></action>
		<action date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/4/2008--Passed House amended. 21st Century Green High-Performing Public School Facilities Act - Title I: Grants for Modernization, Renovation, or Repair of School Facilities - (Sec. 102) Requires the Secretary of Education to make grants to states for the modernization, renovation, or repair of public schools, including public charter schools, to make them safe, healthy, high-performing, and technologically up-to-date. Allocates grant funds among states on the basis of the relative portion of school improvement funds provided to local educational agencies (LEAs) in each state under part A of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965. Reserves 1% of the grant funds for assistance to outlying areas and Indian schools. Requires states to reallocate such grant funds to LEAs on the basis of each LEA's share of school improvement funds received by LEAs in the state for the previous fiscal year. Allows LEA grantees to give priority to projects in public secondary schools recognized as Science and Technology High Schools or as schools having science and technology programs. Title II: Supplemental Grants for Louisiana, Mississippi, and Alabama - (Sec. 202) Requires the Secretary to make grants to Louisiana, Mississippi, and Alabama for the construction, modernization, renovation, or repair of public schools, including public charter schools, to make them safe, healthy, high-performing, and technologically up-to-date. Allocates grant funds among such states on the basis of each state's share of schools closed for at least 60 days during the period between August 29 and December 31, 2005, due to Hurricane Katrina or Rita. Requires such states to reallocate such grant funds to LEAs on the basis of each LEA's share of such schools in the state. Title III: General Provisions - (Sec. 301) Prohibits LEAs from using this Act's grants: (1) for maintenance costs, stadiums, or facilities used primarily for events for which the public is charged admission; (2) to supplant funds otherwise available for school modernization, renovation, repair, and construction efforts; or (3) to purchase carbon offsets. Prohibits States from considering LEAs' receipt of this Act's grants in determining their eligibility for state aid or the amount of state aid they receive. (Sec. 303) Conditions LEA grant eligibility on LEA and state spending for free public education remaining above specified levels. Requires states to reduce the amount of grant funds available to LEAs by the proportion by which LEAs' spending falls below such levels. Directs the Secretary to waive such maintenance of effort requirements if such waiver is justified by exceptional or uncontrollable circumstances, or the precipitous decline in an LEA's financial resources. (Sec. 304) Requires grantees' contracting procedures for school modernization, renovation, repair, and construction to ensure the maximum number of qualified bidders through full and open competition. (Sec. 305) Requires the iron and steel used in projects funded under this Act to have been produced in this country, subject to specified exceptions. (Sec. 306) Requires all laborers and mechanics employed by contractors or subcontractors in the performance of work assisted under this Act to be paid wages at rates not less than those prevailing on similar work in the locality. (Sec. 307) Directs LEA grantees to use a percentage of their grant, rising in 10% increments from 50% in FY2009 to 90% in FY2013, for public school modernization, renovation, repairs, or construction that meet Leadership in Energy and Environmental Design (LEED) green building rating standards, Energy Star standards, Collaborative for High Performance Schools (CHPS) criteria, Green Building Initiative environmental design and rating standards (Green Globes), or equivalent standards adopted by the entities that have jurisdiction over such LEAs. Requires the Secretary to provide outreach and technical assistance to states and LEAs concerning the best practices in school modernization, renovation, repair, and construction. (Sec. 308) Directs: (1) LEAs to submit to their states, and make publicly available, annual reports describing their use of such grant funds; (2) states to submit annually to the Secretary a compilation of the information received from their LEAs; and (3) the Secretary to report to Congress annually on grants made under this Act. (Sec. 309) Authorizes appropriations for this Act's grant programs for FY2009-FY2013. (Sec. 310) Prohibits this Act's grants from being used: (1) to employ workers who are illegal aliens or whose status has not been ascertained using the employment verification system; or (2) by LEAs that do not require a criminal background check on all their employees.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
