<bill session="110" type="h" number="3038" updated="2009-01-08T23:10:46-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1184212800" datetime="2007-07-12"/></status>

	<introduced date="1184212800" datetime="2007-07-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Physician Payment Reform Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend section 1848 of the Social Security Act to establish standards for growth in Medicare expenditures for physicians' services based on categories of services.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400367"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1184212800" datetime="2007-07-12"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1184212800" datetime="2007-07-12"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1184212800" datetime="2007-07-12"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1184212800" datetime="2007-07-12"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1184558400" datetime="2007-07-16"><committee name="House Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/12/2007--Introduced.<br/>Medicare Physician Payment Reform Act of 2007 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to revise physician service fee schedule requirements, particularly the conversion factors in the formula for determining fees. Provides for separate conversion factors for service categories. Establishes specified update service categories and expenditure measurement categories. Prescribes a formula for establishing updates for conversion factors for update service categories. Replaces sustainable growth rates with service category growth rates Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to report to the appropriate congressional committees after the end of any year in which actual expenditures exceeded allowed expenditures for such year and the preceding year for either of the expenditure measurement categories: (1) clinical diagnostic laboratory tests; or (2) drugs, biologicals, and radiopharmaceuticals. Requires an analysis of the reasons for such excess expenditures and recommendations for addressing them in the future. 
	</summary>
</bill>
