<bill session="110" type="h" number="3058" updated="2009-01-08T23:13:08-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1212691500" datetime="2008-06-05T15:45:00-04:00" where="h" result="fail" how="roll" roll="387"/></status>

	<introduced date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Public Land Communities Transition Assistance Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Public Land Communities Transition Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend chapter 69 of title 31, United States Code, to provide full payments under such chapter to units of general local government in which entitlement land is located, to provide transitional payments during fiscal years 2008 through 2012 to those States and counties previously entitled to payments under the Secure Rural Schools and Community Self-Determination Act of 2000, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400100"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2007-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400620" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400659" joined="2007-10-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400177" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400092" joined="2007-12-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400336" joined="2007-10-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400330" joined="2007-12-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400660" joined="2007-10-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400282" joined="2007-12-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400419" joined="2007-10-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400403" joined="2007-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400113" joined="2007-10-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400267" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400176" joined="2007-10-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400040" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400274" joined="2007-10-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="412189" joined="2007-10-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400029" joined="2007-10-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400396" joined="2007-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400412" joined="2007-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400355" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400437" joined="2007-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400006" joined="2007-10-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400331" joined="2007-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="412235" joined="2007-10-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400044" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400335" joined="2007-12-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400255" joined="2007-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400299" joined="2007-12-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400232" joined="2007-10-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400193" joined="2007-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400171" joined="2007-10-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="412186" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400043" joined="2007-10-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2007-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400042" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400363" joined="2007-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400345" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400062" joined="2007-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400011" joined="2007-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400179" joined="2007-10-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400186" joined="2007-07-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"><text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action date="1184817600" datetime="2007-07-19"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action date="1185422400" datetime="2007-07-26"><committee name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1190779200" datetime="2007-09-26"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1190779200" datetime="2007-09-26"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands Discharged.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1190779200" datetime="2007-09-26" ><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1198105500" datetime="2007-12-19T19:05:00-05:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-505, Part I.</text></action>
		<action date="1198105560" datetime="2007-12-19T19:06:00-05:00"><text>House Committee on Agriculture Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Jan. 15, 2008.</text></action>
		<action date="1200441720" datetime="2008-01-15T20:02:00-05:00"><text>Committee on Agriculture discharged.</text></action>
		<calendar number="310" date="1200441780" datetime="2008-01-15T20:03:00-05:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 310.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1212598920" datetime="2008-06-04T14:02:00-04:00"><text>Mr. DeFazio moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1212598980" datetime="2008-06-04T14:03:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H4919-4927"/><reference label="text of measure as reported in House" ref="CR H4919-4921"/></action>
		<action date="1212598980" datetime="2008-06-04T14:03:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3058.</text></action>
		<action date="1212601860" datetime="2008-06-04T14:51:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1212690600" datetime="2008-06-05T15:30:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H5016-5017"/></action>
		<vote date="1212691500" how="roll" roll="387" datetime="2008-06-05T15:45:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" suspension="1" result="fail" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Failed by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 218 - 193, 2 Present (Roll no. 387).</text></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	12/19/2007--Reported to House amended, Part I. Public Land Communities Transition Act of 2007 - (Sec. 2) Authorizes appropriations for FY2008-FY2011 for the making of payments to units of general local government in which entitlement lands are located. Provides for 80% funding in FY2008, 90% funding in FY2009, and the making of full payments in FY2010 and FY2011. (Sec. 3) Sets forth provisions for the making of transition payments for FY2008-FY2011 to eligible states, U.S. territories, and counties previously receiving payments under the Secure Rural Schools and Community Self-Determination Act of 2000. Sets forth provisions concerning the election of payment amounts by affected counties. Requires each eligible county receiving a payment or a portion of a state's payment to reserve not less than 15% of the amount received for expenditure in accordance with titles II (Special Projects on Federal Lands) and III (County Projects) of such Act. Extends the authority to initiate such projects under titles II and III through September 30, 2012. (Sec. 4) Sets forth special requirements with regard to transition payments for FY2008-FY2011 applicable to the states of California, Louisiana, Oregon, Pennsylvania, South Carolina, South Dakota, Texas, and Washington and eligible counties in those states in lieu of the payments that otherwise would have been made under the above transition payment provisions. Requires each eligible county receiving such a transition payment or a portion of such payment as prescribed under such requirements, to reserve not less than 15% of the amount received for expenditure in accordance with titles II and III as required above. (Sec. 5) Sets forth provisions for the establishment of conservation of resources fees for producing and nonproducing federal oil and gas leases in the Gulf of Mexico. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to agree to a request by any lessee to amend any lease for Central and Western Gulf of Mexico tracts issued during the period of January 1, 1998, through December 31, 1999, to incorporate price thresholds applicable to royalty suspension provisions, or amend existing price thresholds, of a specified amount per barrel for oil and per million Btu for natural gas. (Sec. 6) Expresses the sense of Congress regarding the distribution of Secure Rural Schools transition payments to eligible counties under this Act. 
	</summary>
</bill>
