<bill session="110" type="h" number="3067" updated="2009-01-08T23:14:12-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1185836220" datetime="2007-07-30T19:57:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Small Public Housing Authority Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Small Public Housing Authority Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the United States Housing Act of 1937 to exempt small public housing agencies from the requirement of preparing an annual public housing agency plan.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400441"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text></action>
		<action date="1185835860" datetime="2007-07-30T19:51:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Frank (MA) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1185835860" datetime="2007-07-30T19:51:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules. (consideration: CR 7/31/2007 H8919-8920)</text></action>
		<action date="1185835860" datetime="2007-07-30T19:51:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3067.</text></action>
		<vote date="1185836220" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-07-30T19:57:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote. (text: CR 7/31/2007 H8919-8920)</text></vote>
		<action date="1185854400" datetime="2007-07-31"><text>Received in the Senate.</text></action>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/30/2007--Passed House amended. Small Public Housing Authority Act - Amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 to exempt a small public housing agency from the requirement to prepare an annual public agency plan if the agency: (1) administers not more than a total of 250 dwelling units and section 8 vouchers; and (2) is not a troubled agency. Requires an agency to: (1) continue to make an annual civil rights certification, and establish, and consult with, one or more resident advisory boards; and (2) conduct a public hearing to discuss agency goals and policies, and make the information available to the public at the agency's principal office. Declares that qualified small public housing agencies are not exempt from the requirements for amendments and modifications to five-year public housing agency plans. .<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
