<bill session="110" type="h" number="3068" updated="2009-01-08T23:14:19-05:00">
	<status><enacted date="1223438400" datetime="2008-10-08" /></status>

	<introduced date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Protective Service Guard Contracting Reform Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Federal Protective Service Guard Contracting Reform Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Federal Protective Service Guard Contracting Reform Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Federal Protective Service Guard Contracting Reform Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">Federal Protective Service Guard Contracting Reform Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="enacted">Federal Protective Service Guard Contracting Reform Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the award of contracts to provide guard services under the contract security guard program of the Federal Protective Service to a business concern that is owned, controlled, or operated by an individual who has been convicted of a felony.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400295"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1543)</text></action>
		<action date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text></action>
		<action date="1184731200" datetime="2007-07-18"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text></action>
		<action date="1185940800" datetime="2007-08-01"><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1185940800" datetime="2007-08-01"><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text></action>
		<action date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1189777680" datetime="2007-09-14T10:48:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation. H. Rept. 110-328.</text></action>
		<calendar number="204" date="1189777680" datetime="2007-09-14T10:48:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 204.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1191342000" datetime="2007-10-02T13:20:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Brady (PA) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1191342120" datetime="2007-10-02T13:22:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H11108-11109"/></action>
		<action date="1191342120" datetime="2007-10-02T13:22:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3068.</text></action>
		<vote date="1191342780" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-10-02T13:33:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H11108"/></vote>
		<action date="1191384000" datetime="2007-10-03"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1217390400" datetime="2008-07-30" ><text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11"><text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 110-455.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="953" date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 953.</text></calendar>
		<vote date="1222142400" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2008-09-23" where="s" type="vote2" result="pass" ><text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S9336"/><reference label="text as passed Senate" ref="CR S9336"/></vote>
		<action date="1222228800" datetime="2008-09-24"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<action date="1222315200" datetime="2008-09-25"><text>Senate requests return of papers with respect to H.R. 3068 by Unanimous Consent.</text></action>
		<action date="1222315200" datetime="2008-09-25"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<action date="1222401600" datetime="2008-09-26"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<action date="1222522560" datetime="2008-09-27T10:36:00-04:00"><text>Ms. Norton moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H10140-10141"/></action>
		<action date="1222522560" datetime="2008-09-27T10:36:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3068.</text></action>
		<action date="1222523160" datetime="2008-09-27T10:46:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text as House agreed to Senate amendment" ref="CR H10140"/></action>
		<topresident date="1222488000" datetime="2008-09-27" ><text>Cleared for White House.</text></topresident>
		<topresident date="1222747200" datetime="2008-09-30" ><text>Presented to President.</text></topresident>
		<signed date="1223438400" datetime="2008-10-08" ><text>Signed by President.</text></signed>
		<enacted number="110-356" date="1223438400" datetime="2008-10-08" type="public" ><text>Became Public Law No: 110-356.</text></enacted>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/8/2008--Public Law. Federal Protective Service Guard Contracting Reform Act of 2008 - Requires the Secretary of Homeland Security, acting through the Assistant Secretary of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, to promulgate regulations establishing guidelines for the prohibition of contract awards for the provision of guard services under the contract security guard program of the Federal Protective Service to any business concern that is owned, controlled, or operated by an individual who has been convicted of a felony. Authorizes the Secretary to consider permanent or interim prohibitions when promulgating the regulations.<br/>Requires such regulations to: (1) identify which serious felonies may prohibit a contractor from being awarded a contract; (2) require contractors to provide information regarding any relevant felony convictions when submitting bids or proposals; (3) provide guidelines for the contracting officer to assess present responsibility, mitigating factors, and the risk associated with the previous conviction and to award a contract under certain circumstances.<br/>Requires the Administrator for Federal Procurement Policy to report on establishing similar guidelines government-wide to the House Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform. 
	</summary>
</bill>
