<bill session="110" type="h" number="3062" updated="2009-01-08T23:13:38-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1189000380" datetime="2007-09-05T10:53:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">South Pacific Economic and Educational Development Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Pacific Island Economic and Educational Development Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize appropriations to provide for South Pacific exchanges, provide technical and other assistance to countries in the Pacific region through the United States Agency for International Development, and authorize appropriations to provide Fulbright Scholarships for Pacific Island students.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400128"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400041" joined="2007-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400073" joined="2007-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400122" joined="2007-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400271" joined="2007-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400087" joined="2007-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="412186" joined="2007-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2007-07-30"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1185854400" datetime="2007-07-31"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1185854400" datetime="2007-07-31" ><text>Committee Agreed to Seek Consideration Under Suspension of the Rules, (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1188999780" datetime="2007-09-05T10:43:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Faleomavaega moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1188999840" datetime="2007-09-05T10:44:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H10084-10085"/></action>
		<action date="1188999840" datetime="2007-09-05T10:44:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3062.</text></action>
		<vote date="1189000380" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-09-05T10:53:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H10084"/></vote>
		<action date="1189051200" datetime="2007-09-06"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/5/2007--Passed House amended. Pacific Island Economic and Educational Development Act of 2007 - Authorizes appropriations of $1 million for each of FY2008 and FY2009 for exchanges with Pacific Island countries carried out under the educational and cultural exchange programs of the Department of State. Authorizes the United States Agency for International Development (USAID), upon request, to provide technical and other assistance to Pacific Island countries, defined for the purposes of this Act as: (1) the Cook Islands; (2) the Federated States of Micronesia; (3) the Independent State of Samoa; (4) the Kingdom of Tonga; (5) Niue; (6) Papua New Guinea; (7) the Republic of Fiji; (8) the Republic of Kiribati; (9) the Republic of the Marshall Islands; (10) the Republic of Nauru; (11) the Republic of Palau; (12) the Republic of Vanuatu; (13) the Solomon Islands; and (14) Tuvalu. Directs the Secretary of State to review and report to Congress on the marginalization of students from Pacific Island countries in the awarding of Fulbright Scholarships. Requires the Secretary to establish a program within the J. William Fulbright Educational Exchange program providing scholarships to students from Pacific Island countries for study in the United States pursuant to the terms of such Exchange program. Authorizes appropriations of $500,000 for each of FY2008 and FY2009 to provide such scholarships to such students.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
