<bill session="110" type="h" number="3064" updated="2009-01-08T23:13:52-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"/></status>

	<introduced date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Emergency Immigration Workload Reduction and Homeland Security Enhancement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To suspend certain nonessential visas, in order to provide temporary workload relief critical to the successful reorganization of the immigration and naturalization functions of the Department of Homeland Security, to ensure that the screening and monitoring of arriving immigrants and nonimmigrants, and the deterrence of entry and settlement by illegal or unauthorized aliens, is sufficient to maintain the integrity of the sovereign borders of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400158"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1186718400" datetime="2007-08-10"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/17/2007--Introduced.<br/>Emergency Immigration Workload Reduction and Homeland Security Enhancement Act of 2007 - Suspends the following immigration-related authorities: (1) the visa waiver program; (2) adjustment to permanent resident status; (3) renewal of temporary protected status (TPS); (4) the diversity immigrant visa program; and (5) certain family-related immigrant visa programs. Authorizes specified waiver authority. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (Secretary) to establish a public listing of every alien subject to a final order of deportation for whom the appropriate country of return has refused or unreasonably delayed such action. Requires U.S. visa issuance to be discontinued in a country which has 24 or more listed individuals. Sets forth conditions for waiver of the temporary suspensions set forth in this Act (except for the suspension of TPS renewals). States that all such temporary suspensions shall cease to be effective after the Secretary certifies to Congress that certain security measures are in place, including an integrated entry-exit system at all ports of entry. Suspends the Secretary of State's authority to issue nonimmigrant visas and the Secretary's authority to admit nonimmigrant aliens, subject to specified waivers. Directs the Secretary to reimburse state and local law enforcement agencies for certain alien-related detention and removal costs.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
