<bill session="110" type="h" number="3071" updated="2009-01-08T23:14:40-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"/></status>

	<introduced date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Iraq Redeployment and Regional Security Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require the immediate redeployment of United States Armed Forces from Iraq.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400403"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400663" joined="2007-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400286" joined="2007-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="2007-07-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"><text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/17/2007--Introduced.<br/>Iraq Redeployment and Regional Security Act - Requires: (1) the President, within 30 days after the enactment of this Act, to commence the full redeployment of all U.S. Armed Forces from Iraq; and (2) such redeployment to be completed within one year after the enactment of this Act. Directs the President, as soon as practicable, to institute a regional diplomatic plan, in conjunction with the United Nations (UN) Security Council, to attempt to: (1) curtail the ongoing civil war in Iraq; (2) contain such civil war to prevent its spread into neighboring countries; (3) prevent the establishment of al Qaeda safe havens; (4) prevent regional war; and (5) prevent genocide. Requires a report from the President to Congress, within 30 days after the enactment of this Act and every 30 days thereafter, on the status and progress of the diplomatic plan.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
