<bill session="110" type="h" number="3084" updated="2009-01-08T23:16:12-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1184731200" datetime="2007-07-18"/></status>

	<introduced date="1184731200" datetime="2007-07-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Skin Cancer Prevention, Education, and Consumer Right-To-Know Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Food and Drug Administration to establish a standard for broad-spectrum protection in sunscreen products, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400246"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400070" joined="2007-09-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2007-08-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1184731200" datetime="2007-07-18"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1184731200" datetime="2007-07-18"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/18/2007--Introduced.<br/>Skin Cancer Prevention, Education, and Consumer Right-To-Know Act - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to deem a drug that is a sunscreen product whose labeling violates this Act to be adulterated.<br/>Prohibits the labeling of a drug that is a sunscreen product that fails to meet the standards adopted under this Act from: (1) describing the product using the term &quot;broad-spectrum&quot;; or (2) including a specified symbol adopted to indicate broad-spectrum.<br/>Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to adopt: (1) a standard for broad-spectrum protection in sunscreen products; and (2) an easily recognized symbol for inclusion in the labeling of sunscreen products meeting such standards.<br/>Sets forth minimum standards that the Secretary shall adopt for such broad-spectrum protection, including a minimum ratio of UVA protection factor to sun protection factor, a minimum level of UVB radiation protection, and specified truth in labeling requirements. Requires sun protection factors to be measured using standardized, reproducible testing methods that take photo-degradation into account.<br/>Requires the Secretary to implement an education campaign identifying the risks posed by sun exposure without the use of a sunscreen providing broad-spectrum protection.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
