<bill session="110" type="h" number="3100" updated="2009-01-08T23:18:14-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1184817600" datetime="2007-07-19"/></status>

	<introduced date="1184817600" datetime="2007-07-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Import Safety Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act and the Consumer Product Safety Act to increase the safety of food, toothpaste, and toys.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400222"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400232" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400215" joined="2007-07-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1184817600" datetime="2007-07-19"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1184817600" datetime="2007-07-19"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1184817600" datetime="2007-07-19"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text></action>
		<action date="1184904000" datetime="2007-07-20"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1585)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/19/2007--Introduced.<br/>Import Safety Act of 2007 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to increase civil monetary penalties for introducing into interstate commerce or delivering for introduction into interstate commerce food that is adulterated. Authorizes additional appropriations for the examination by the Secretary of Health and Human Services of processed food and toothpaste which is being imported or offered for import into the United States. Amends the Consumer Product Safety Act to: (1) increase fines for knowing and willful violations of prohibited acts related to consumer product safety standards; and (2) establish separate fines for offenses that result in death. Authorizes additional appropriations for inspection of toys imported or offered for import into the United States.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
