<bill session="110" type="h" number="3111" updated="2009-01-08T23:19:32-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1204654920" datetime="2008-03-04T14:22:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1184817600" datetime="2007-07-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Port Chicago Naval Magazine National Memorial Enhancement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Port Chicago Naval Magazine National Memorial Enhancement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Port Chicago Naval Magazine National Memorial Enhancement Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the administration of Port Chicago Naval Magazine National Memorial as a unit of the National Park System, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400278"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400257" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400102" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400403" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400396" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400384" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400663" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400356" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400383" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="412228" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400062" joined="2007-07-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1184817600" datetime="2007-07-19"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1572-1573)</text></action>
		<action date="1184817600" datetime="2007-07-19"><text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1184817600" datetime="2007-07-19"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1184817600" datetime="2007-07-19"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1185163200" datetime="2007-07-23"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action date="1187064000" datetime="2007-08-14"><committee name="House Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text></action>
		<action date="1190865600" datetime="2007-09-27"><committee name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1191988800" datetime="2007-10-10"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1191988800" datetime="2007-10-10"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands Discharged.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1191988800" datetime="2007-10-10" ><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1198105680" datetime="2007-12-19T19:08:00-05:00"><text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-506, Part I.</text></action>
		<action date="1198105740" datetime="2007-12-19T19:09:00-05:00"><text>House Committee on Armed Services Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Jan. 15, 2008.</text></action>
		<action date="1200441960" datetime="2008-01-15T20:06:00-05:00"><text>House Committee on Armed Services Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Feb. 1, 2008.</text></action>
		<action date="1201878720" datetime="2008-02-01T11:12:00-05:00"><text>Committee on Armed Services discharged.</text></action>
		<calendar number="319" date="1201878720" datetime="2008-02-01T11:12:00-05:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 319.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1204654740" datetime="2008-03-04T14:19:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Rahall moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1204654800" datetime="2008-03-04T14:20:00-05:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H1194-1195"/></action>
		<action date="1204654800" datetime="2008-03-04T14:20:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3111.</text></action>
		<vote date="1204654920" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-03-04T14:22:00-05:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H1194"/></vote>
		<action date="1204693200" datetime="2008-03-05"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/4/2008--Passed House amended. Port Chicago Naval Magazine National Memorial Enhancement Act of 2008 - Amends the Port Chicago National Memorial Act of 1992 to require the Secretary of the Interior to administer the Port Chicago Naval Magazine National Memorial as a unit of the National Park System. Directs the Secretary of Defense to transfer a parcel of land, consisting of approximately five acres, within the proposed boundary on the map entitled &quot;Port Chicago Naval Magazine National Memorial, Proposed Boundary,&quot; dated August 2005, to the administrative jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior if: (1) the land is excess to military needs; and (2) all environmental remediation actions necessary to respond to environmental contamination related to the land have been completed in accordance with the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 and other applicable laws. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to enter into an agreement with the city of Concord, California, and the East Bay Regional Park District to establish and operate a facility for visitor orientation and parking, administrative offices, and curatorial storage for the Memorial. Expresses the sense of Congress that the Secretary of Defense, in order to facilitate the land transfer under this Act, should promptly remediate remaining environmental contamination related to the land. Expresses the sense of Congress that, in order to preserve the Memorial for future generations, the Secretaries of Defense and the Interior should work together to: (1) repair storm damage to the Port Chicago site; and (2) develop a process by which future repairs and necessary modifications to the site can be achieved in as timely and cost-effective a manner as possible. 
	</summary>
</bill>
