<bill session="110" type="h" number="3115" updated="2009-01-08T23:20:08-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1184817600" datetime="2007-07-19"/></status>

	<introduced date="1184817600" datetime="2007-07-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Carbon Monoxide Treated Meat, Poultry, and Seafood Safe Handling, Labeling, and Consumer Protection Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to provide restrictions on the use of carbon monoxide in meat, poultry, and seafood, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400391"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400253" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2007-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400003" joined="2007-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400355" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="2007-10-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400103" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2007-09-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412186" joined="2007-09-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400215" joined="2007-09-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400062" joined="2007-09-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="2007-09-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1184817600" datetime="2007-07-19"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H8124)</text></action>
		<action date="1184817600" datetime="2007-07-19"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1184817600" datetime="2007-07-19"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/19/2007--Introduced.<br/>Carbon Monoxide Treated Meat, Poultry, and Seafood Safe Handling, Labeling, and Consumer Protection Act - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to make changes to the definition of &quot;color additive&quot; to include carbon monoxide that may impart, maintain, preserve, stabilize, fix, or otherwise affect the color of fresh meat, poultry products, or seafood, unless the label of such food bears, prominently and conspicuously, a specified statement that advises consumers: (1) that carbon monoxide has been used to preserve the color of the product; (2) not to rely on the color or the &quot;use or freeze by&quot; date alone to judge the freshness or safety of the product; and (3) to discard any product with an unpleasant odor, slime, or a bulging package.<br/>Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish alternative labeling requirements, not earlier than five years after the effective date of this Act, if: (1) such statement is no longer required to prevent consumer deception and other harms; and (2) such alternative requirements are shown to be adequate and effective in preventing consumer deception and other harms related to the conditions of use of carbon monoxide.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
