<bill session="110" type="h" number="3123" updated="2009-01-08T23:21:08-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1185835260" datetime="2007-07-30T19:41:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1185163200" datetime="2007-07-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To extend the designation of Liberia under section 244 of the Immigration and Nationality Act so that Liberians can continue to be eligible for temporary protected status under that section.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400215"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400034" joined="2007-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400080" joined="2007-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400332" joined="2007-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2007-07-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400406" joined="2007-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2007-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400245" joined="2007-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400230" joined="2007-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="412213" joined="2007-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400315" joined="2007-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="2007-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400108" joined="2007-07-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1185163200" datetime="2007-07-23"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1185834060" datetime="2007-07-30T19:21:00-04:00"><text>Ms. Lofgren, Zoe moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text></action>
		<action date="1185834120" datetime="2007-07-30T19:22:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules. (consideration: CR 7/31/2007 H8914-8917)</text></action>
		<action date="1185834120" datetime="2007-07-30T19:22:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3123.</text></action>
		<vote date="1185835260" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-07-30T19:41:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote. (text: CR 7/31/2007 H8914)</text></vote>
		<action date="1185854400" datetime="2007-07-31"><text>Received in the Senate.</text></action>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/30/2007--Passed House without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.) Extends: (1) the designation of Liberia under the Immigration and Nationality Act as a country whose nationals are eligible for temporary protected status through September 30, 2008; and (2) any related existing work authorization that is effective until October 1, 2007, until not earlier than April 1, 2008. Applies such extension to an alien who is a Liberian national or a person having no nationality whose last habitual residence was Liberia and who: (1) was granted temporary protected status under the designation of Liberia that is effective until October 1, 2007; (2) applied for such status and whose application remains pending; or (3) is eligible for late initial registration under the temporary protected status provision of the Immigration and Nationality Act and its implementing regulations.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
