<bill session="110" type="h" number="3130" updated="2009-01-08T23:21:59-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1185163200" datetime="2007-07-23"/></status>

	<introduced date="1185163200" datetime="2007-07-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Enhanced Methamphetamine Treatment Grants Assistance Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title V of the Public Health Service Act to provide for enhanced comprehensive methamphetamine treatment services.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400186"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400041" joined="2007-11-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="412234" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400377" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400111" joined="2007-11-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="412200" joined="2007-11-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400421" joined="2007-11-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2007-11-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400100" joined="2007-11-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400639" joined="2007-11-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1185163200" datetime="2007-07-23"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1597)</text></action>
		<action date="1185163200" datetime="2007-07-23"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1185163200" datetime="2007-07-23"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/23/2007--Introduced.<br/>Enhanced Methamphetamine Treatment Grants Assistance Act of 2007 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, to award grants for wraparound services, including medical services, job training service, housing assistance, and training in parenting, for methamphetamine infected individuals who: (1) resided in a residential treatment facility for the treatment of methamphetamine abuse or addiction; or (2) received treatment for methamphetamine abuse or addiction from an intensive outpatient treatment facility. Changes the program for substance abuse for pregnant and postpartum women to a program for treatment of substance abuse for caregiver parents, including pregnant women. Requires grantees to give priority to programs that provide services to caregiver parents who are pregnant and postpartum women.<br/>Requires the Secretary, acting through the Administrator, to award grants to assist local jails and detention facilities in providing comprehensive, family-based substance abuse treatment services to pregnant and parenting adults who are considered nonviolent offenders. Sets forth requirements if such a grant is used for a family drug treatment program that is an alternative to incarceration. Directs the Secretary, acting through the Administrator, to award grants for services in connection with the treatment of methamphetamine use or addiction to underserved populations.<br/>Requires the Secretary, through the National Clearinghouse for Alcohol and Drug Information, to conduct a study to identify and evaluate methamphetamine use and addiction treatment methodologies.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
