<bill session="110" type="h" number="3142" updated="2009-01-08T23:23:39-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1185249600" datetime="2007-07-24"/></status>

	<introduced date="1185249600" datetime="2007-07-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Violent Crime Prevention and Enforcement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide law enforcement critical tools and resources for preventing and enforcing violent crime.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400660"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400068" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400147" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400287" joined="2007-10-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1185249600" datetime="2007-07-24"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/24/2007--Introduced.<br/>Violent Crime Prevention and Enforcement Act of 2007 - Amends the federal criminal code to: (1) authorize the Attorney General to impose civil fines on firearms licensees who willfully violate federal firearms laws; (2) increase criminal penalties for transferring firearms for use in crimes of violence or drug trafficking and for conspiracies against the United States; (3) increase criminal penalties for felons with prior convictions for violent crimes and serious drug offenses who unlawfully possess firearms; (4) expand criteria for the detention for persons charged with firearms offenses prior to trial; (5) include other felony crimes of violence in the prohibition against interstate travel to commit murder-for-hire and increase criminal penalties for such crimes; (6) impose a 10-year limitation period for prosecutions of noncapital crimes of violence and terrorism; and (7) impose increased criminal penalties for illegal aliens who commit felony crimes of violence or drug trafficking.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
