<bill session="110" type="h" number="3147" updated="2009-01-08T23:24:14-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1185249600" datetime="2007-07-24"/></status>

	<introduced date="1185249600" datetime="2007-07-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Counter-Terrorism and National Security Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide additional tools and tough penalties to fight terrorism and protect America's national security.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400434"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400313" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400147" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400287" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400157" joined="2007-09-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1185249600" datetime="2007-07-24"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1186718400" datetime="2007-08-10"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/24/2007--Introduced.<br/>Counter-Terrorism and National Security Act of 2007 - Amends the federal criminal code to: (1) impose criminal penalties for providing material support to terrorists with the intent to facilitate, reward, or encourage terrorist activities; (2) include attempts and conspiracies in the prohibition against obtaining military-type training from a foreign terrorist organization and increase criminal penalties for such crime; (3) prohibit the kidnapping of a U.S. national overseas; (4) deny all federal benefits to anyone convicted of a federal crime of terrorism; (5) include federal crimes of terrorism in the prohibition against soliciting criminal activity; (6) provide enhanced penalties for terrorists offenses that result in the death of a person: (7) allow for the death penalty for terror-related crimes involving weapons of mass destruction (e.g., atomic and biological weapons); (8) increase criminal penalties for the murder of a U.S. national overseas and for providing financial support to terrorists; and (9) extend the authorization for wiretapping to all federal crimes of terrorism.<br/>Amends federal transportation law to impose a fine and/or prison term of up to 10 years for taking actions that seriously threaten the safety of an aircraft or individuals on such aircraft.<br/>Amends the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure to allow multi-district search warrants in terrorism investigations.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
