<bill session="110" type="h" number="3155" updated="2009-01-08T23:25:09-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1185249600" datetime="2007-07-24"/></status>

	<introduced date="1185249600" datetime="2007-07-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Intellectual Property Enhanced Criminal Enforcement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend titles 17 and 18, United States Code, to strengthen the protection of intellectual property, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400071"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400123" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400147" joined="2007-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400287" joined="2007-08-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1185249600" datetime="2007-07-24"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1186718400" datetime="2007-08-10"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, the Internet, and Intellectual Property.</text></action>
		<action date="1186718400" datetime="2007-08-10"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/24/2007--Introduced.<br/>Intellectual Property Enhanced Criminal Enforcement Act of 2007 - Makes copyright registration requirements applicable to only civil (not criminal) copyright infringement actions. Authorizes the court, in civil copyright infringement actions, to: (1) order the impounding of records documenting the manufacture, sale, or receipt of items; and (2) determine that parts of a compilation or derivative work constitute separate works in assessing statutory damages.<br/>Establishes criminal violations for any attempt or conspiracy to commit criminal copyright infringement, with the same penalties as prescribed for the offense.<br/>Deems the unauthorized importation or exportation of copies or phonorecords to be an infringement of the exclusive right to distribute, in certain circumstances.<br/>Includes within the definition of &quot;traffic in,&quot; for copyright infringement purposes, to import, export, or possess with intent to transport, transfer, or otherwise dispose of.<br/>Increases the penalties for criminal copyright offenses, including: (1) criminal copyright infringement; (2) unauthorized recording of a motion picture; and (3) trafficking in counterfeit goods or services.<br/>Provides for forfeiture of any property constituting or derived from proceeds of civil copyright infringement. Requires the court to order restitution for victims of criminal copyright infringement.<br/>Directs the Attorney General to: (1) create an operational unit of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) to assist in the investigation and coordination of intellectual property crimes; (2) implement a program to train FBI agents in the investigation and prosecution of such crimes; (3) assign federal prosecutors to Department of Justice (DOJ) offices in Hong Kong and Budapest to coordinate international enforcement of intellectual property laws; and (4) create a task force to implement a plan to investigate and prosecute international organized crime syndicates involved in theft of intellectual property.<br/>Authorizes additional funding through FY2011 to investigate and prosecute criminal activity involving computers.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
