<bill session="110" type="h" number="3163" updated="2009-01-08T23:26:08-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1185249600" datetime="2007-07-24"/></status>

	<introduced date="1185249600" datetime="2007-07-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Healthy Americans Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Enhanced Health Care Value for All Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide affordable, guaranteed private health coverage that will make Americans healthier and can never be taken away.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400011"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400121" joined="2007-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400081" joined="2007-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2007-07-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1185249600" datetime="2007-07-24"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, Education and Labor, and Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1185249600" datetime="2007-07-24"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1185249600" datetime="2007-07-24"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1185249600" datetime="2007-07-24"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1185249600" datetime="2007-07-24"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1185249600" datetime="2007-07-24"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1185854400" datetime="2007-07-31"><committee name="House Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1190174400" datetime="2007-09-19"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/24/2007--Introduced.<br/>Healthy Americans Act - Requires each adult individual to have the opportunity to purchase a Healthy Americans Private Insurance Plan (HAPI). Makes individuals who are not enrolled in another specified health plan and who are not opposed to coverage for religious reasons responsible for enrolling themselves and their dependent children in a HAPI plan offered through their state of residence. Sets forth penalties for failure to enroll. Establishes standardized coverage and state options for HAPI plans. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to promulgate guidelines concerning the benefits, items, and services to be covered. Sets forth requirements for setting premiums. Requires the Secretary to establish the Healthy America Advisory Committee to provide annual recommendations concerning modifications to the benefits, items, and services required. Requires the Secretary to establish Chronic Care Education Centers. Requires states to establish or designate a state Health Help Agency to carry out the administration of HAPI plans and to promote prevention and wellness for residents. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to require employers and individuals to each make shared responsibility payments for HAPI plan premiums. Sets forth requirements for health insurance issuers offering a HAPI plan. Establishes the Healthy Americans Public Health Trust Fund for the payment of premium subsidies. Terminates federal health benefits coverage, including coverage provided under the Federal Employees Health Benefits (FEHB) program and the State Children's Health Insurance program (SCHIP). Enhanced Health Care Value for All Act of 2007 - Provides for a Comparative Effectiveness Advisory Board and a Health Care Comparative Effectiveness Research Trust Fund.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
