<bill session="110" type="h" number="3172" updated="2009-01-08T23:27:17-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1185336000" datetime="2007-07-25"/></status>

	<introduced date="1185336000" datetime="2007-07-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Freedom to Save Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To exclude certain assets in determining eligibility under the food stamp program, the temporary assistance for needy families (TANF) program, the Supplemental Security Income (SSI) program, and the State children's health insurance program (SCHIP).</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400080"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400073" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400295" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400430" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400402" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400350" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400366" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2007-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2007-09-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1185336000" datetime="2007-07-25"><text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1185336000" datetime="2007-07-25"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1185336000" datetime="2007-07-25"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action date="1185336000" datetime="2007-07-25"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1185336000" datetime="2007-07-25"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1185854400" datetime="2007-07-31"><committee name="House Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Income Security and Family Support.</text></action>
		<action date="1185854400" datetime="2007-07-31"><committee name="House Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1209096000" datetime="2008-04-25"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/25/2007--Introduced.<br/>Freedom to Save Act of 2007 - Amends the Food Stamp Act of 1977 to modify the asset test for food stamp program eligibility by increasing the amounts of allowable financial resources, with annual inflation adjustments, and excluding from countable financial resources any retirement accounts, education accounts, and licensed vehicles. Prohibits the use of any asset test under the temporary assistance for needy families (TANF) program under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act. Prescribes an administrative penalty for any state imposing such a test. Eliminates any asset test for disabled persons under title XVI (Supplemental Security Income (SSI)) of the Social Security Act (SSA) and for any eligible individual under SSA title XXI (State Children's Health Insurance Program (SCHIP)).<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
