<bill session="110" type="h" number="3184" updated="2009-01-08T23:28:43-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1185826680" datetime="2007-07-30T17:18:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1185422400" datetime="2007-07-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Puget Sound Watershed Comprehensive Conservation Project Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Puget Sound Watershed Comprehensive Conservation Project Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of Agriculture to carry out a competitive grant program for the Puget Sound area to provide comprehensive conservation planning to address water quality.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400232"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400659" joined="2007-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400660" joined="2007-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400379" joined="2007-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="2007-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400193" joined="2007-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400171" joined="2007-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400109" joined="2007-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400011" joined="2007-07-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1185422400" datetime="2007-07-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text></action>
		<action date="1185826260" datetime="2007-07-30T17:11:00-04:00"><text>Ms. Herseth Sandlin moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text></action>
		<action date="1185826260" datetime="2007-07-30T17:11:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules. (consideration: CR 7/31/2007 H8898-8899)</text></action>
		<action date="1185826260" datetime="2007-07-30T17:11:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3184.</text></action>
		<vote date="1185826680" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-07-30T17:18:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote. (text: CR 7/31/2007 H8898)</text></vote>
		<action date="1185854400" datetime="2007-07-31"><text>Received in the Senate.</text></action>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/30/2007--Passed House without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.) Puget Sound Watershed Comprehensive Conservation Project Act of 2007 - Requires the Secretary of Agriculture to: (1) carry out a competitive grant program for the Puget Sound area to provide comprehensive conservation planning to address water quality; and (2) enter into cooperative agreements with state and local governments, Indian tribes, or non-governmental entities with a history of working with agricultural producers to carry out projects under the program. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) provide project demonstration grants, provide technical assistance, and carry out information and education programs to improve water quality in the area by reducing soil erosion and improving sediment control; and (2) provide a priority for projects and activities that directly reduce soil erosion or improve water quality. Authorizes appropriations.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
