<bill session="110" type="h" number="318" updated="2009-01-08T17:23:51-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"/></status>

	<introduced date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Impact Aid program under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to improve the distribution of school construction payments to better meet the needs of military and Indian land school districts.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400400"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400359" joined="2007-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400311" joined="2007-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400308" joined="2007-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400172" joined="2007-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400125" joined="2007-01-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400032" joined="2007-01-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E35)</text></action>
		<action date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1178683200" datetime="2007-05-09"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/5/2007--Introduced.<br/>Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to revise Impact Aid program requirements for distribution of school construction payments, and of school facility emergency and modernization grants, to local educational agencies (LEAs) impacted by military dependent children or by children residing on Indian lands. Makes LEAs which were eligible for Impact Aid for the preceding fiscal year, and experience an overall increase in student enrollment, eligible for school facility emergency and modernization grants if at least 250 extra children are, or at least 10% of such increase is, the direct result of: (1) base realignment and closure or global rebasing; (2) force structure changes or relocations; or (3) an action initiated by the Secretary of the Interior or other federal agency.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
