<bill session="110" type="h" number="3190" updated="2009-01-08T23:29:25-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1185422400" datetime="2007-07-26"/></status>

	<introduced date="1185422400" datetime="2007-07-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Opt Out of Iraq War Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow individuals to designate that their income, estate, or gift tax payments be spent other than for purposes of supporting the war in Iraq and to provide that amounts so designated shall be used to provide funding for Head Start, to reduce the national debt, and to provide college funding for children of Iraq war veterans.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400416"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1185422400" datetime="2007-07-26"><text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1185422400" datetime="2007-07-26"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1185422400" datetime="2007-07-26"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1190174400" datetime="2007-09-19"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text></action>
		<action date="1190174400" datetime="2007-09-19"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/26/2007--Introduced.<br/>Opt Out of Iraq War Act of 2007 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow taxpayers to designate that the percentage of their income, estate, or gift tax payments that would otherwise be used to fund the Iraq war be paid into a Future Fund from which funding will be provided, in equal amounts, to the Head Start program, to reduce the national debt, and for a Children of Iraq War Veterans College Fund. Requires amounts in the College Fund to be used to pay the college costs of students that had a parent in the Armed Forces who served in the Iraq war for at least 180 days, died as the result of service in such war, or was hospitalized and unable to return to duty due to such service.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
