<bill session="110" type="h" number="3199" updated="2009-01-08T23:30:34-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1185422400" datetime="2007-07-26"/></status>

	<introduced date="1185422400" datetime="2007-07-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">9/11 Can You Hear Me Now Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to procure the development and provision of improved and up-to-date communications equipment for the New York City Fire Department, including radios.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400251"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="2007-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400426" joined="2007-07-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1185422400" datetime="2007-07-26"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1633)</text></action>
		<action date="1185422400" datetime="2007-07-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1185422400" datetime="2007-07-26"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and the Internet.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/26/2007--Introduced.<br/>9/11 Can You Hear Me Now Act - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to procure development and provision of a communications system for the New York City Fire Department, including appropriate radios and upgrades to the Department's critical information dispatch system that allow communication in all locations and under all conditions in which firefighters can reasonably be expected to work, including all high-rise buildings and subways. Directs that any communications system procured include provision to each firefighter of a supplemental radio communication device that: (1) allows the firefighter to transmit emergency notification warning signals to other firefighters; and (2) has the capability to operate automatically by transmitting messages that will relay an incapacitated firefighter's identification and location. Requires that upgrades procured: (1) provide useful, detailed data concerning all likely terrorist target locations in the city; and (2) be capable of providing to responding firefighters, instantaneously, details about particular buildings and other locations to assist in making decisions about how to mitigate a terrorist attack. Requires that: (1) radios, any dispatch system upgrades, and supplemental communication devices procured be tested; and (2) the Secretary coordinate with the city to ensure that the communications system procured is compatible with city plans to upgrade its 911 system and interoperable with other public safety communications systems.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
