<bill session="110" type="h" number="3205" updated="2009-01-08T23:31:16-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1185508800" datetime="2007-07-27"/></status>

	<introduced date="1185508800" datetime="2007-07-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Homeless Education Improvement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend subtitle B of title VII of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act to provide education for homeless children and youths, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400027"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-07-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400130" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="412212" joined="2007-07-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="2007-09-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1185508800" datetime="2007-07-27"><text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1185508800" datetime="2007-07-27"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1185508800" datetime="2007-07-27"><text>Referred to House Financial Services</text></action>
		<action date="1189137600" datetime="2007-09-07"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H10248)</text></action>
		<action date="1190174400" datetime="2007-09-19"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/27/2007--Introduced.<br/>Homeless Education Improvement Act of 2007 - Amends the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act to require each state and local educational agency (LEA) to ensure that each homeless child and each homeless youth has access to the same free, appropriate public education, including state-funded or LEA-funded preschool programs, as is provided to other children and youths. Authorizes the Secretary of Education to make grants to states and U.S. territories for specified state and local activities, including mandatory establishment or designation of an Office of Coordinator for Education of Homeless Children and Youths in each state educational agency (SEA). Prohibits segregation of such children and youths into separate schools or programs within schools. Requires each SEA to make subgrants to LEAs to facilitate the identification, enrollment, attendance, and success in school of homeless children and youths. Directs the Secretary to make grants to states for transportation for school stability, readiness, and success for such children and youths.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
