<bill session="110" type="h" number="3210" updated="2009-01-08T23:31:51-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1185508800" datetime="2007-07-27"/></status>

	<introduced date="1185508800" datetime="2007-07-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Wounded Warriors Expansion of Care Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide medical care and other benefits for members and former members of the Armed Forces with severe injuries or illnesses.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412205"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400333" joined="2008-02-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1185508800" datetime="2007-07-27"><text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1185508800" datetime="2007-07-27"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1185508800" datetime="2007-07-27"><text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1187582400" datetime="2007-08-20"><committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1190692800" datetime="2007-09-25"><committee name="House Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/27/2007--Introduced.<br/>Wounded Warriors Expansion of Care Act of 2007 - Entitles any recovering member and any former member with a severe injury or illness to medical and dental care in any military medical facility or through any civilian health care provider authorized by the Secretary of Defense to provide health and mental health services, including services for traumatic brain injury and post-traumatic stress disorder. Authorizes such medical and dental care for three years beginning on the date: (1) of enactment of this Act, for those whose injury or illness was incurred on or after October 7, 2001, and before the enactment of this Act; and (2) on which the injury or illness is incurred, for those whose injury or illness occurs on or after the enactment of this Act. Authorizes the Secretary to waive any limitation on the provision of such care if considered appropriate to assure the maximum feasible recovery and rehabilitation of the member or former member. Prohibits the Secretary from providing such medical and dental care after December 31, 2012, if the Secretary has not provided such care to such member or former member before that date. Entitles members with a severe injury or illness to rehabilitation and vocational benefits from the Secretary of Veterans Affairs. Authorizes the Secretary of the military department concerned to reimburse recovering members and former members with a severe injury or illness for certain expenses incurred in connection with the receipt of required medical care.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
