<bill session="110" type="h" number="324" updated="2009-01-08T17:24:29-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1168318800" datetime="2007-01-09"/></status>

	<introduced date="1168318800" datetime="2007-01-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Working Families Wage and Access to Health Care Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Health Fairness Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To increase the minimum wage, to provide access to health care coverage to employees of small businesses, and to preserve American jobs.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400267"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400123" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400222" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400004" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="412218" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400142" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400027" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400336" joined="2007-01-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400242" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400058" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="412190" joined="2007-01-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400095" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400261" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400040" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400406" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400662" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400241" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400658" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400634" joined="2007-01-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400224" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400324" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400640" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400144" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400335" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400057" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="412010" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400617" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400012" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400318" joined="2007-01-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400636" joined="2007-01-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400654" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400321" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400157" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400429" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400656" joined="2007-01-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1168318800" datetime="2007-01-09"><text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1168318800" datetime="2007-01-09"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1168318800" datetime="2007-01-09"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1178683200" datetime="2007-05-09"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text></action>
		<action date="1178683200" datetime="2007-05-09"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/9/2007--Introduced.<br/>Working Families Wage and Access to Health Care Act - Amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to incrementally increase the federal minimum wage to $7.25. Small Business Health Fairness Act of 2007 - Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to provide for establishment and governance of association health plans (AHPs), which are group health plans whose sponsors are trade, industry, professional, chamber of commerce, or similar business associations, and which meet certain ERISA certification requirements. Establishes the Association Health Plan Fund to be used by the Secretary of Labor to make payments to an insurer to maintain coverage for a plan, if there is a reasonable expectation that, without such payments, claims would not be satisfied by reason of termination of coverage. Requires the Secretary to establish a Solvency Standards Working Group. Allows a state to impose a contribution tax on an association health plan, if the plan commenced operations in such state after the date of enactment of this Act. Preempts any state law that may preclude a health insurance issuer from: (1) offering health insurance coverage in connection with a certified AHP; or (2) offering health insurance coverage of the same policy type to other employers operating in the state which are eligible for coverage under such AHPs, whether or not such other employers are participating employers in such plan. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to extend through 2011 the increased expensing allowance for small business assets. Revises the definition of &quot;qualified restaurant property&quot; to eliminate the requirement that improvements to restaurant property must be placed in service more than three years after the original building is placed in service. 
	</summary>
</bill>
