<bill session="110" type="h" number="3240" updated="2009-01-08T23:35:38-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1186195920" datetime="2007-08-03T23:52:00-04:00" /></status>

	<introduced date="1185854400" datetime="2007-07-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance availability of critical energy information.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400043"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400110" joined="2007-07-31"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1185854400" datetime="2007-07-31"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1186195920" datetime="2007-08-03T23:52:00-04:00"><text>Reported by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 110-308.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1186195920" datetime="2007-08-03T23:52:00-04:00" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 195.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/3/2007--Reported to House without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.) Directs the Administrator of the Energy Information Administration to establish and submit to Congress: (1) a five-year plan to enhance the quality and scope of the data collection necessary to ensure the scope, accuracy, and timeliness of the information needed for efficient functioning of energy markets and related financial operations; and (2) an assessment of state-level data needs, including a plan to address such needs. Requires the Administrator to: (1) establish guidelines to ensure the quality, comparability, and scope of state energy data required to provide a comprehensive, accurate energy profile; (2) share company-level data collected at the state level with the state involved, provided it has agreed to the Administrator's guidelines; (3) assess any existing gaps in data compiled by the Energy Information Administration; and (4) evaluate the most cost effective ways to address any data quality and quantity issues in conjunction with state officials. Authorizes appropriations for FY2008-FY2012.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
