<bill session="110" type="h" number="3253" updated="2009-01-08T23:37:12-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1185854400" datetime="2007-07-31"/></status>

	<introduced date="1185854400" datetime="2007-07-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Measuring and Evaluating Trends for Reliability, Integrity, and Continued Success Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to provide for the use of longitudinal data systems.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400184"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400257" joined="2007-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400001" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="412204" joined="2007-08-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="412232" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="2007-12-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400179" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400067" joined="2007-09-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1185854400" datetime="2007-07-31"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1190174400" datetime="2007-09-19"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/31/2007--Introduced.<br/>Measuring and Evaluating Trends for Reliability, Integrity, and Continued Success Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to require each state receiving school improvement funds to implement, within four years of this Act's enactment, a pre- through high-school longitudinal data system that includes: (1) a unique and consistent statewide student identifier; (2) the ability to track student participation and performance over time; (3) a unique and consistent statewide teacher identifier that matches student records to the appropriate teacher; and (4) the ability to link its data to data from higher education, workforce development, unemployment insurance, child welfare, juvenile justice, and military services information systems. Allots funds to states to operate, upgrade, and optimize the use of their data systems. Reserves funds for competitive grants to nonprofit entities to support a state education data center.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
