<bill session="110" type="h" number="3269" updated="2009-01-08T23:39:05-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1185854400" datetime="2007-07-31"/></status>

	<introduced date="1185854400" datetime="2007-07-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Children's Health Insurance Program Reauthorization Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XXI of the Social Security Act to reauthorize the State Children's Health Insurance Program, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400434"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400123" joined="2007-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400420" joined="2007-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400149" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400660" joined="2007-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400264" joined="2007-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="2007-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400147" joined="2007-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400121" joined="2007-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400039" joined="2007-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400150" joined="2007-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400334" joined="2007-07-31"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1185854400" datetime="2007-07-31"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1185854400" datetime="2007-07-31"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1185854400" datetime="2007-07-31"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1185854400" datetime="2007-07-31"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1185854400" datetime="2007-07-31"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1186545600" datetime="2007-08-08"><committee name="House Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1190174400" datetime="2007-09-19"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/31/2007--Introduced.<br/>Children's Health Insurance Program Reauthorization Act of 2007 - Reauthorizes the State Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP) (also known as SCHIP) under title XXI of the Social Security Act (SSA) through FY2012. Provides allotments for the 50 states and the District of Columbia.<br/>Revises funding for the territories under CHIP and Medicaid (SSA title XIX).<br/>Provides incentive bonuses for states. Phases out coverage for nonpregnant childless adults under CHIP and sets conditions for coverage of parents. Gives states the option to cover low-income pregnant women under CHIP through a state plan amendment.<br/>Establishes in the Treasury the CHIP Contingency Fund.<br/>Provides for the two-year availability of allotments. Provides for limitation on matching rate for states that propose to cover children with effective family income exceeding 300% of the poverty line. Provides an option for qualifying states to receive the enhanced portion of the CHIP matching rate for Medicaid coverage of certain children. Outlines outreach and enrollment requirements, including ones for reducing administrative barriers to enrollment.. Gives states the option to verify declaration of citizenship or nationality for purposes of eligibility for Medicaid through verification of name and Social Security number. Provides for additional state option for providing premium assistance.<br/>Provides for special enrollment period under group health plans in case of termination of Medicaid or CHIP coverage or eligibility for assistance in purchase of employment-based coverage. Provides for development of an initial core set of health care quality measures for children enrolled in Medicaid or CHIP. Revises requirements related to payment error rate measurement and data collection. Provides for mental health parity in CHIP plans.<br/>Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to award dental health grants.<br/>Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide for an increase in excise tax rate on tobacco products.<br/>Amends the Tax Increase Prevention and Reconciliation Act of 2005 with respect to time for payment of corporate estimated taxes.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
