<bill session="110" type="h" number="3275" updated="2009-01-08T23:39:50-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1185940800" datetime="2007-08-01"/></status>

	<introduced date="1185940800" datetime="2007-08-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">U.S.-China Language Engagement Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To support programs that offer instruction in Chinese language and culture, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400097"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400222" joined="2007-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400195" joined="2007-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400232" joined="2007-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2008-07-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400636" joined="2007-08-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1185940800" datetime="2007-08-01"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1702)</text></action>
		<action date="1190174400" datetime="2007-09-19"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/1/2007--Introduced.<br/>U.S.-China Language Engagement Act - Directs the Secretary of Education to award competitive three-year grants to local educational agencies (LEAs) for innovative model programs establishing, improving, or expanding Chinese language and cultural studies instruction for their elementary school and secondary school students. Directs the Secretary to award grants to LEAs for use in acquiring communications technologies or equipment to improve Chinese language instruction in elementary schools and secondary schools through computer-assisted instruction, distance learning, and virtual exchanges with schools in China. Expresses the sense of Congress that increasing the number of students who receive substantial exposure to Chinese language and cultural studies before graduating from secondary school will enhance our global economic competitiveness in the 21st century.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
