<bill session="110" type="h" number="3273" updated="2009-01-08T23:39:35-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1185940800" datetime="2007-08-01"/></status>

	<introduced date="1185940800" datetime="2007-08-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">United States-China Market Engagement and Export Promotion Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize assistance to small- and medium-sized businesses to promote exports to the People's Republic of China, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400232"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400222" joined="2007-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400620" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400177" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400065" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="412192" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400229" joined="2008-06-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400254" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400396" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="2008-06-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400640" joined="2007-10-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400098" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400356" joined="2007-10-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400087" joined="2008-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400655" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400195" joined="2007-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412232" joined="2007-10-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400081" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400125" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400326" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400109" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2008-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400097" joined="2007-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400042" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400636" joined="2007-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400011" joined="2007-09-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1185940800" datetime="2007-08-01"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1185940800" datetime="2007-08-01"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1185940800" datetime="2007-08-01"><text>Referred to House Small Business</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/1/2007--Introduced.<br/>United States-China Market Engagement and Export Promotion Act - Directs the Secretary of Commerce to: (1) provide grants to states to establish and operate state offices in the People's Republic of China (PRC) to promote U.S. exports to PRC; (2) establish a program to create China market advocate positions in United States Export Assistance Centers in order to provide assistance to small- and medium-sized U.S. businesses in the export U.S. goods to PRC, including assistance for business-related expenses for trade missions to PRC; and (3) submit to Congress a plan to consolidate fees for Gold Key matching services provided to such U.S. businesses that export U.S. goods or services to more than one market in PRC. Amends the Small Business Act to require the Office of International Trade of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to provide guidance to U.S. small businesses with respect to the export of U.S. goods and services to PRC. Establishes in the Office a Director of China Program Grants. Directs the Administrator of SBA, acting through the Director of China Program Grants, to make grants to institutions of higher education to establish and operate Chinese business education programs.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
