<bill session="110" type="h" number="3299" updated="2009-01-08T23:42:45-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1222101780" datetime="2008-09-22T13:43:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1185940800" datetime="2007-08-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for a boundary adjustment and land conveyances involving Roosevelt National Forest, Colorado, to correct the effects of an erroneous land survey that resulted in approximately 7 acres of the Crystal Lakes Subdivision, Ninth Filing, encroaching on National Forest System land.</title>
		<title type="official" as="amended by house">To provide for a boundary adjustment and land conveyances involving Roosevelt National Forest, Colorado, to correct the effects of an erroneous land survey that resulted in approximately 7 acres of the Crystal Lakes Subdivision, Ninth Filing, encroaching on National Forest System land, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400287"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400017" joined="2007-11-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="412191" joined="2008-07-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1185940800" datetime="2007-08-01"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1186459200" datetime="2007-08-07"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action date="1215662400" datetime="2008-07-10"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1216180800" datetime="2008-07-16"><text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands Discharged.</text></action>
		<action date="1216180800" datetime="2008-07-16"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1216180800" datetime="2008-07-16" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1217370600" datetime="2008-07-29T19:30:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-793.</text></action>
		<calendar number="511" date="1217370600" datetime="2008-07-29T19:30:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 511.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1222101600" datetime="2008-09-22T13:40:00-04:00"><text>Ms. Bordallo moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1222101660" datetime="2008-09-22T13:41:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8501-8502"/></action>
		<action date="1222101660" datetime="2008-09-22T13:41:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3299.</text></action>
		<vote date="1222101780" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-09-22T13:43:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H8501"/></vote>
		<action date="1222101780" datetime="2008-09-22T13:43:00-04:00"><text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action date="1222142400" datetime="2008-09-23"><text>Received in the Senate.</text></action>
		<action date="1222920000" datetime="2008-10-02"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/22/2008--Passed House amended. Modifies the boundaries of Roosevelt National Forest, Colorado, to exclude from it a parcel of real property consisting of approximately seven acres within the Crystal Lakes Subdivision as depicted on a map dated July 15, 2008.<br/>Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to use the authority provided by the Small Tracts Act to convey all interest of the United States in and to the real property excluded from the boundaries of Roosevelt National Forest under this Act to the landowners whose real property adjoins the excluded land and who occupy the excluded land.<br/>Authorizes the Secretary of Commerce to sell or exchange to the city of Norfolk, Virginia, certain real property under the administrative jurisdiction of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), including land and improvements, located in Norfolk if the Secretary: (1) determines that such conveyance is in the best interests of NOAA and the federal government; and (2) has provided prior notification to the appropriate congressional committees.<br/>Requires the proceeds of any conveyance under this Act to be made available for: (1) activities related to the operations of, or capital improvements to, NOAA property; or (2) relocation and other costs associated with the sale or exchange.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
