<bill session="110" type="h" number="3302" updated="2009-01-08T23:43:07-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1185940800" datetime="2007-08-01"/></status>

	<introduced date="1185940800" datetime="2007-08-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Congressional Responsibility and Accountability Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 5, United States Code, to prohibit agencies from enforcing rules that result in a specified economic impact until the requirements of those rules are enacted into law by an Act of Congress, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400311"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1185940800" datetime="2007-08-01"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1702)</text></action>
		<action date="1189396800" datetime="2007-09-10"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/1/2007--Introduced.<br/>Congressional Responsibility and Accountability Act - Amends the Administrative Procedure Act to: (1) require each agency, before adopting a rule, to determine whether compliance with the rule will result in a specified economic impact; and (2) prohibit an agency from enforcing a rule it determines will result in such impact until its requirements are enacted into law.<br/>Requires each agency: (1) annually, to determine whether its rules have resulted in a specified economic impact in the preceding year; and (2) not later than 365 days after making such determination, to no longer enforce such a rule until its requirements are enacted into law.<br/>Defines &quot;specified economic impact&quot; as: (1) costs to any individual of $5,000 or more in a year; (2) costs to any partnership, corporation, association, or public or private organization of $25,000 or more in a year; (3) costs to all persons (not including the federal government or a state government) in the aggregate of $250,000 or more in a year; or (4) the loss by one or more U.S. citizens of existing employment in a year.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
