<bill session="110" type="h" number="3323" updated="2009-01-08T23:45:32-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1211397840" datetime="2008-05-21T16:24:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Goleta Water Distribution System Conveyance Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Goleta Water Distribution System Conveyance Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Goleta Water Distribution System Conveyance Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Goleta Water Distribution System Conveyance Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Goleta Water Distribution System Conveyance Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to convey a water distribution system to the Goleta Water District, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400062"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1186545600" datetime="2007-08-08"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text></action>
		<action date="1193198400" datetime="2007-10-24"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1208923200" datetime="2008-04-23"><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1208923200" datetime="2008-04-23"><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Unanimous Consent .</text></action>
		<action date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1210720500" datetime="2008-05-13T20:15:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-631.</text></action>
		<calendar number="393" date="1210720620" datetime="2008-05-13T20:17:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 393.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1211254680" datetime="2008-05-19T12:38:00-04:00"><text>Ms. Bordallo moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1211254680" datetime="2008-05-19T12:38:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H4073-4074"/></action>
		<action date="1211254680" datetime="2008-05-19T12:38:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3323.</text></action>
		<action date="1211254860" datetime="2008-05-19T12:41:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Issa objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text></action>
		<action date="1211397840" datetime="2008-05-21T16:24:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H4402"/></action>
		<vote date="1211397840" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-05-21T16:24:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote. (text: CR 5/19/2008 H4073-4074)</text></vote>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1215489600" datetime="2008-07-08"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="1022" date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1022.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/16/2008--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on May 13, 2008. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Goleta Water Distribution System Conveyance Act of 2008 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to convey all U.S. rights to the Goleta Water Distribution System of the Cachuma Project, California, consistent with the terms of the Agreement Between the United States and the Goleta Water District to Transfer Title of the Federally Owned Distribution System to the Goleta Water District.<br/>Shields the United States from liability for damages relating to the conveyed property, except those caused by negligent acts by U.S. employees or agents prior to conveyance. Provides that after the conveyance, the System shall not be considered to be part of a federal reclamation project. Requires: (1) the Secretary to complete all actions required under environmental and historic preservation laws prior to any conveyance; and (2) the District to comply with all applicable federal, state, and local laws in its operation of the transferred facilities. Provides that federal reclamation law shall continue to apply to project water provided to the District.<br/>(Sec. 7) Requires the Secretary to report to Congress if the conveyance has not been completed within 12 months.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
