<bill session="110" type="h" number="3336" updated="2009-01-08T23:49:14-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1222101420" datetime="2008-09-22T13:37:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Camp Hale Historic District Study Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Camp Hale Study Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Camp Hale Study Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to carry out a study to determine the suitability and feasibility of establishing a historic district to the Camp Hale on parcels of land in the State of Colorado.</title>
		<title type="official" as="amended by house">A bill to direct the Secretary of the Interior to carry out a study to determine the suitability and feasibility of establishing Camp Hale as a unit of the National Park System.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412191"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400412" joined="2007-08-02"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1186545600" datetime="2007-08-08"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action date="1215662400" datetime="2008-07-10"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1216180800" datetime="2008-07-16"><text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands Discharged.</text></action>
		<action date="1216180800" datetime="2008-07-16"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1216180800" datetime="2008-07-16" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1217371920" datetime="2008-07-29T19:52:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-798.</text></action>
		<calendar number="516" date="1217371980" datetime="2008-07-29T19:53:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 516.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1222101240" datetime="2008-09-22T13:34:00-04:00"><text>Ms. Bordallo moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1222101240" datetime="2008-09-22T13:34:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8500"/></action>
		<action date="1222101240" datetime="2008-09-22T13:34:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3336.</text></action>
		<vote date="1222101420" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-09-22T13:37:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H8500"/></vote>
		<action date="1222101420" datetime="2008-09-22T13:37:00-04:00"><text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action date="1222142400" datetime="2008-09-23"><text>Received in the Senate.</text></action>
		<action date="1222920000" datetime="2008-10-02"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/22/2008--Passed House amended. Camp Hale Study Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the National Park Service (NPS), to conduct a special resource study to determine: (1) the suitability and feasibility of designating Camp Hale, in Colorado, as a separate unit of the National Park System; and (2) the methods and means for the protection and interpretation of Camp Hale by the NPS, other government entities, or private or nonprofit organizations.<br/>Requires a report to Congress, not later than three years after the date on which funds are made available to carry out this Act, containing the results of the study and the Secretary's recommendations.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
