<bill session="110" type="h" number="3332" updated="2009-01-08T23:48:40-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1202842560" datetime="2008-02-12T14:56:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Kalaupapa Memorial Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Kalaupapa Memorial Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Kalaupapa Memorial Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the establishment of a memorial within Kalaupapa National Historical Park located on the island of Molokai, in the State of Hawaii, to honor and perpetuate the memory of those individuals who were forcibly relocated to the Kalaupapa Peninsula from 1866 to 1969, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412200"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400001" joined="2007-08-02"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1725-1726)</text></action>
		<action date="1186545600" datetime="2007-08-08"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action date="1202841300" datetime="2008-02-12T14:35:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Grijalva moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1202841360" datetime="2008-02-12T14:36:00-05:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H824-827"/></action>
		<action date="1202841360" datetime="2008-02-12T14:36:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3332.</text></action>
		<vote date="1202842560" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-02-12T14:56:00-05:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H824-825"/></vote>
		<action date="1202878800" datetime="2008-02-13"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1207713600" datetime="2008-04-09"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1210132800" datetime="2008-05-07" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1213588800" datetime="2008-06-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. With written report No. 110-389.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="821" date="1213588800" datetime="2008-06-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 821.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/16/2008--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the House on February 12, 2008. The summary of that version is repeated here.)<br/>Kalaupapa Memorial Act of 2008 - Requires the Secretary of the Interior to authorize Ka 'Ohana O Kalaupapa, a nonprofit organization consisting of patient residents at Kalaupapa National Historical Park, to establish a memorial at the location(s) approved by the Secretary at Kalawao or Kalaupapa within the boundaries of Kalaupapa National Historical Park on the island of Molokai, Hawaii, to honor those individuals who were forcibly relocated to Kalaupapa Peninsula from 1866 to 1969. Sets forth requirements concerning the design of the memorial. Requires that the location, size, design, and inscriptions of the memorial be subject to the approval of the Secretary.<br/>Makes Ka 'Ohana O Kalaupapa solely responsible for the acceptance of contributions for, and payment of, expenses associated with the establishment of the memorial. 
	</summary>
</bill>
