<bill session="110" type="h" number="3347" updated="2009-01-08T23:52:22-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"/></status>

	<introduced date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Student Credit Card Protection Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Truth in Lending Act to prevent credit card issuers from taking unfair advantage of college students and their parents, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400378"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400073" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400407" joined="2008-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="2008-06-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400116" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400316" joined="2008-06-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400245" joined="2007-12-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="412199" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400350" joined="2008-06-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400090" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="2007-11-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text></action>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1727)</text></action>
		<action date="1188964800" datetime="2007-09-05"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/2/2007--Introduced.<br/>Student Credit Card Protection Act of 2007 - Amends the Truth in Lending Act to limit by a specified formula the total credit which may be extended by a creditor during any full calendar year to a full time, traditional-aged college student under a college student credit card account, unless a parent, legal guardian, or spouse of the student assumes joint liability for debts incurred. Prohibits increasing the credit limit on an account for which a parent, guardian, or spouse has assumed joint liability without that person's written approval. States that a creditor must require adequate proof of income, income history, and credit history, before any such college student credit card account may be opened. Prohibits a creditor from opening a credit card account for, or issue any credit card to, any college student who: (1) has no verifiable annual gross income; and (2) already maintains a credit card account under an open end consumer credit plan with the same creditor or any affiliate. Directs the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to promulgate implementing regulations.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
