<bill session="110" type="h" number="3341" updated="2009-01-08T23:51:05-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"/></status>

	<introduced date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Quality Health Care Coalition Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure and foster continued patient safety and quality of care by exempting health care professionals from the Federal antitrust laws in their negotiations with health plans and health insurance issuers.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400311"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400279" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400626" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400151" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400017" joined="2008-04-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1728-1729)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/2/2007--Introduced.<br/>Quality Health Care Coalition Act of 2007 - Exempts health care professionals that are negotiating with a health plan regarding contract terms under which the professionals provide health care items or services for which plan benefits are provided from federal antitrust laws in connection with such negotiations. Declares that this Act: (1) applies only to health care professionals excluded from the National Labor Relations Act; and (2) does not apply to such negotiations relating to Medicare or Medicaid programs, the State Children's Health Insurance Program (SCHIP), medical and dental care for members of the uniformed services, veterans' medical care, the federal employees health benefits program, or the Indian Health Care Improvement Act.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
