<bill session="110" type="h" number="3366" updated="2009-01-08T23:55:05-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"/></status>

	<introduced date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Military Environmental Responsibility Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 10, United States Code, to require the Department of Defense and all other defense-related agencies of the United States to fully comply with Federal and State environmental laws, including certain laws relating to public health and worker safety, that are designed to protect the environment and the health and safety of the public, particularly those persons most vulnerable to the hazards incident to military operations and installations, such as children, members of the Armed Forces, civilian employees, and persons living in the vicinity of military operations and installations.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400133"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2008-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400227" joined="2008-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400129" joined="2008-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400198" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400101" joined="2008-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400152" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400130" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="2007-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400013" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400638" joined="2008-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="412200" joined="2008-06-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2007-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400310" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400240" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400639" joined="2008-06-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, Transportation and Infrastructure, Natural Resources, and Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text></action>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1186200000" datetime="2007-08-04"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text></action>
		<action date="1186200000" datetime="2007-08-04"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text></action>
		<action date="1186200000" datetime="2007-08-04"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text></action>
		<action date="1186200000" datetime="2007-08-04"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text></action>
		<action date="1190174400" datetime="2007-09-19"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text></action>
		<action date="1190692800" datetime="2007-09-25"><committee name="House Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/3/2007--Introduced.<br/>Military Environmental Responsibility Act - Requires the Department of Defense (DOD) and defense-related agencies (the Department of Energy, the Nuclear Regulatory Commission, the Office of Naval Nuclear Reactors, and any others as designated by the President) to fully comply with designated Federal and State environmental laws, including those related to public health and safety, to the same extent as any other entities subject to such laws. Waives any immunity of the United States with respect to such laws as applied to DOD and any defense-related agency. Provides for administrative enforcement actions.<br/>Requires the Secretary of Defense , for each weapon system for which congressional budget justification is required, to ensure that all development and procurement decisions comply with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969.<br/>Repeals: (1) a Federal provision prohibiting the use of certain military appropriation accounts for the payment of fines and penalties for environmental noncompliance; and (2) a provision of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2000 which prohibits the use of defense funds to conduct treatment, storage, or disposal activities at sites designated under the Formerly Utilized Site Remedial Action Program.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
