<bill session="110" type="h" number="3376" updated="2009-01-08T23:56:24-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"/></status>

	<introduced date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Witness Protection Enhancement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance witness protection.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412224"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1189396800" datetime="2007-09-10"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/3/2007--Introduced.<br/>Witness Protection Enhancement Act of 2007 - Amends the federal judicial code to establish in the U. S. Marshals Service a Short Term State Witness Protection Section to provide protection for witnesses in state and local trials involving homicide or other major violent crimes pursuant to cooperative agreements with state and local prosecutor's offices and the U.S. attorney for the District of Columbia.<br/>Directs the Section to give priority in awarding grants and providing services to prosecutor's offices in states with an average of at least 100 murders per year or with a violent crime rate above the national average.<br/>Authorizes: (1) the Attorney General to make grants to state and local prosecutors and to the U.S. attorney for the District of Columbia for providing such witness protection; and (2) each recipient to use the grant to provide witness protection or to credit the grant to the Section to cover the Section's costs of providing witness protection. Amends the federal criminal code to specify that federal witness relocation and protection services extend to witnesses in cases involving criminal street gangs, serious drug offenses, and homicide.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
