<bill session="110" type="h" number="3391" updated="2009-01-08T23:58:12-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"/></status>

	<introduced date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Military Family and Medical Leave Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 to expand family and medical leave for spouses, sons, daughters, and parents of servicemembers with combat-related injuries.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400196"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400128" joined="2008-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2007-09-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400316" joined="2007-09-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400331" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400350" joined="2007-12-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2007-10-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, and House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Referred to House House Administration</text></action>
		<action date="1190174400" datetime="2007-09-19"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/3/2007--Introduced.<br/>Military Family and Medical Leave Act - Amends the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 to entitle an eligible employee to up to 26 workweeks of leave during a 12-month period to care for a covered service member who is the employee's spouse, son, daughter, or parent. Defines covered service member as a member of the U.S. Armed Forces, including a member of the National Guard or a Reserve, who is undergoing medical treatment, recuperation, or therapy, or is otherwise in medical hold or medical holdover status, for a serious injury or illness. Declares that nothing in this Act shall be construed to limit the availability of such leave during any other 12-month period. Provides for the substitution of accrued paid vacation, personal, or family leave for any part of the 26-week period. Limits a husband and wife both working for the same employer to such 26 weeks altogether during a single 12-month period.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
