<bill session="110" type="h" number="3409" updated="2009-01-09T00:00:36-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"/></status>

	<introduced date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Place to Call Home Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Runaway and Homeless Youth Act Reauthorization of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To create the conditions, structures, and supports needed to ensure permanency for the Nation's unaccompanied youth, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400179"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400041" joined="2007-09-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2008-01-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400073" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-09-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400282" joined="2008-01-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400430" joined="2007-10-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400184" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412209" joined="2008-01-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400001" joined="2007-09-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400103" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412211" joined="2007-10-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400653" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2007-09-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400074" joined="2008-01-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400204" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400097" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400310" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2007-12-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="412219" joined="2007-10-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400024" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400067" joined="2007-08-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, Energy and Commerce, Financial Services, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Referred to House Financial Services</text></action>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1189396800" datetime="2007-09-10"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text></action>
		<action date="1189396800" datetime="2007-09-10"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text></action>
		<action date="1190174400" datetime="2007-09-19"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text></action>
		<action date="1190174400" datetime="2007-09-19"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Healthy Families and Communities.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/3/2007--Introduced.<br/>Place to Call Home Act - Amends and reauthorizes the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act. Amends part B (Child and Family Services) of title IV of the Social Security Act (SSA) to increase funding for the safe and stable families program. Amends the Public Health Service Act with respect to substance abuse prevention and the treatment performance partnership block grant program. Amends SSA title IV part E (Federal Payments for Foster Care and Adoption Assistance) with respect to the curtailment of involuntary separation of children from their families.<br/>Amends the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act to prohibit the involuntary separation of youth from their families. Provides for: (1) expanded eligibility for foster care and adoption assistance; (2) kinship guardianship assistance payments; (3) eligibility for foster care maintenance payments and adoption assistance payments through age 20; and (4) youth access to the child welfare system. Runaway and Homeless Youth Act Reauthorization of 2008 - Reauthorizes the Runaway and Homeless Youth Act. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to conduct a national homeless youth awareness campaign. Revises requirements for the use of funds under the John H. Chafee Foster Care Independence Program. Directs the Attorney General to establish a Youth Offender Reentry Grants program. Amends the Family Violence Prevention and Services Act to provide for transitional housing assistance for youth victims of commercial sexual exploitation. Amends the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to make qualified homeless youth a targeted group of the work opportunity credit. Amends the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 with respect to unaccompanied youth access to workforce investment activities.<br/>Amends the Public Health Service Act with respect to the prioritization of services for runaway, homeless, and street youth. Provides for enhanced youth access to medical assistance under SSA title XIX (Medicaid). Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act with respect to the access of homeless children and youths to elementary and secondary education, including grants to increase student attendance. Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 with respect to financial assistance for disconnected students and continued access to student housing for homeless youth. Amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 to provide for section 8 rental assistance (housing choice vouchers) for homeless youth. Amends SSA title IV (Temporary Assistance for Needy Families) (TANF) with regard to young family concerns. Outlines requirements for custody, release, family reunification, and detention of unaccompanied immigrant youth, including: (1) access to child advocates and counsel; and (2) children's asylum claims. Amends the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 with respect to the deinstitutionalization of status offenders.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
