<bill session="110" type="h" number="3416" updated="2009-01-09T00:01:26-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"/></status>

	<introduced date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">America's Energy Security Trust Fund Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to reduce carbon dioxide emissions in the United States domestic energy supply.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400233"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400246" joined="2007-10-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400129" joined="2008-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="2007-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="2008-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400245" joined="2007-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400103" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2007-10-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="2007-09-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/3/2007--Introduced.<br/>America's Energy Security Trust Fund Act of 2007 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose an excise tax on any taxable carbon substance sold by a manufacturer, producer, or importer. Defines &quot;taxable carbon substance&quot; as: (1) coal (including lignite and peat); (2) petroleum and any petroleum products; and (3) natural gas that is extracted, manufactured, or produced in the United States, or entered into the United States for consumption, use, or warehousing. Establishes in the Treasury the America's Energy Security Trust Fund to finance research in clean energy technology, assist industries negatively affected by this Act, and provide carbon tax rebates to individual taxpayers.<br/>Allows individual taxpayers a tax credit equal to carbon tax rebate amounts calculated by the Secretary of the Treasury.<br/>Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to study and report to Congress on the best methods to assess and collect taxes on non-carbon greenhouse gases.<br/>Expresses the sense of Congress that the major greenhouse gas emitting countries should join with the United States in reducing greenhouse gas emissions. 
	</summary>
</bill>
