<bill session="110" type="h" number="3425" updated="2009-01-09T00:02:46-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"/></status>

	<introduced date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Cancer Screening Coverage Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, Public Health Service Act, and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to require that group and individual health insurance coverage and group health plans provide coverage of screening for breast, prostate, and colorectal cancer.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400251"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400327" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412221" joined="2008-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400396" joined="2007-12-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400350" joined="2007-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2007-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="2007-12-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400639" joined="2007-10-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1731)</text></action>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Education and Labor, Ways and Means, and Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1187064000" datetime="2007-08-14"><committee name="House Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1190174400" datetime="2007-09-19"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/3/2007--Introduced.<br/>Cancer Screening Coverage Act of 2007 - Amends the Public Health Service Act, the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA), and the Internal Revenue Code to require a group health plan to provide coverage for certain types of cancer screening. Includes under such coverage mammograms, clinical breast examinations, pap tests and pelvic examinations, colorectal screening procedures, and prostate screening tests, at specified intervals and through specified procedures for certain age groups in appropriate genders. Prohibits related eligibility discrimination, monetary incentives to individuals, and penalties or incentives to providers. Requires such plans and issuers to provide certain disclosures to participants and beneficiaries, including regarding covered benefits, cost sharing, and participating providers. Applies the requirements of this Act to coverage offered in the individual market and under federal employees health benefits plan. Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services to modify coverage requirements under this Act to incorporate new scientific and technological advances, practice pattern changes, or other updated medical practices regarding cancer screening. 
	</summary>
</bill>
