<bill session="110" type="h" number="3426" updated="2009-01-09T00:02:53-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"/></status>

	<introduced date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Flexibility for Individual Excellence in Education Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To modify certain amendments made by the No Child Left Behind Act of 2001.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400255"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400155" joined="2007-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400084" joined="2007-12-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400043" joined="2008-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400345" joined="2007-12-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1190174400" datetime="2007-09-19"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/3/2007--Introduced.<br/>Flexibility for Individual Excellence in Education Act of 2007 - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to alter the requirement that teachers be highly qualified by: (1) applying it only to teachers of core subjects; (2) allowing new middle or secondary school teachers to teach subjects for which they earned a college minor; (3) allowing greater consideration to be given to the time experienced teachers have spent teaching a subject; and (4) extending the deadline for rural teachers to meet such requirements. Provides additional funding for rural teacher recruitment, retention, and professional development activities. Allows state determinations of students' adequate yearly progress (AYP) toward state academic performance standards to: (1) assess disabled students at the instructional level most closely corresponding to their individualized education plans; and (2) use growth models and multiple measures of student achievement. Requires local educational agencies (LEAs) to identify schools as needing improvement, corrective action, or restructuring only if they fail to make AYP in the same subject for the same group of students over the requisite period of time. Provides school transfers and supplemental services to students in the failing group, rather than to all students in an affected school. Gives LEAs the option of providing such students with supplemental services rather than transfers for the year following a school's identification as needing improvement.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
