<bill session="110" type="h" number="3437" updated="2009-01-09T00:04:34-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1221688920" datetime="2008-09-17T19:02:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Jackson Gulch Rehabilitation Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Jackson Gulch Rehabilitation Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Jackson Gulch Rehabilitation Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to carry out the Jackson Gulch rehabilitation project in the State of Colorado.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400620"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1186977600" datetime="2007-08-13"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text></action>
		<action date="1193198400" datetime="2007-10-24"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1216094400" datetime="2008-07-15"><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1216094400" datetime="2008-07-15"><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee Without Recommendation (Amended) by Unanimous Consent .</text></action>
		<action date="1216180800" datetime="2008-07-16"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1216180800" datetime="2008-07-16" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1217540280" datetime="2008-07-31T18:38:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-813.</text></action>
		<calendar number="527" date="1217540340" datetime="2008-07-31T18:39:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 527.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1221498240" datetime="2008-09-15T14:04:00-04:00"><text>Ms. Bordallo moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1221498240" datetime="2008-09-15T14:04:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8052-8053"/></action>
		<action date="1221498240" datetime="2008-09-15T14:04:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3437.</text></action>
		<action date="1221498480" datetime="2008-09-15T14:08:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Bishop (UT) objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text></action>
		<action date="1221688920" datetime="2008-09-17T19:02:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8368-8369"/></action>
		<vote date="1221688920" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-09-17T19:02:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote. (text: CR 9/15/2008 H8052)</text></vote>
		<action date="1222056000" datetime="2008-09-22"><text>Received in the Senate.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="1114" date="1222920000" datetime="2008-10-02" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1114.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/17/2008--Passed House amended. (This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on July 31, 2008. The summary of that version is repeated here.)<br/>Jackson Gulch Rehabilitation Act of 2008 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Commissioner of Reclamation to: (1) pay the federal share of the cost of carrying out the Jackson Gulch rehabilitation project in Colorado; and (2) use existing studies relating to the project, including engineering and resource information provided by, or at the direction of, federal, state, or local agencies and the Mancos Water Conservancy District.<br/>Directs the Secretary to: (1) recover the lesser of 35% of the project's cost or $2.9 million as reimbursable expenses from the District over a 15-year period; and (2) credit the District for any amounts it paid before enactment of this Act for engineering work and improvements directly associated with the project.<br/>Makes the District responsible for the operation and maintenance of any facility constructed or rehabilitated under this Act. Shields the United States from liability for damages arising out of any act, omission, or occurrence relating to such a facility. Authorizes appropriations.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
