<bill session="110" type="h" number="3445" updated="2009-01-09T00:05:47-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"/></status>

	<introduced date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Weather Mitigation Research and Technology Transfer Authorization Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Weather Mitigation Operations and Research Board, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400412"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR 8/4/2007 E1760)</text></action>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Science and Technology.</text></action>
		<action date="1187928000" datetime="2007-08-24"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/3/2007--Introduced.<br/>Weather Mitigation Research and Technology Transfer Authorization Act of 2007 - Establishes in the Department of Commerce the Weather Mitigation Advisory and Research Board to promote and fund research and development (R&amp;amp;D), studies, and investigations with respect to: (1) improved forecast and decisionmaking technologies for weather mitigation operations, including tailored computer workstations and software and new observation systems with remote sensors; and (2) assessments and evaluations of the efficacy of weather mitigation, both purposeful (including cloud-seeding operations) and inadvertent (including downwind effects and anthropogenic effects). Establishes within the U.S. Treasury the Weather Mitigation Research and Development Fund. Directs the Board, unless the use of the money is restricted or subject to any limitations provided by law, to use amounts in the Fund to: (1) pay its expenses in the administration of this Act; and (2) provide for R&amp;amp;D with respect to weather mitigations by grants to, or contracts or cooperative arrangements with, public or private agencies.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
