<bill session="110" type="h" number="3447" updated="2009-01-09T00:06:24-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"/></status>

	<introduced date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Surgeon General Independence Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to ensure the independence of the Surgeon General from political interference.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400425"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400073" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400101" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400384" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400013" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400378" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400081" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400240" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400062" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400186" joined="2007-08-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/3/2007--Introduced.<br/>Surgeon General Independence Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to add as requirements for appointment as Surgeon General that an individual be: (1) a licensed physician; and (2) nominated by the Secretary of Health and Human Services. Requires the Regular Corps to submit to the Secretary and the President a list of six qualified nominees to fill any vacancy in the Surgeon General position. Prohibits an individual from serving more than three full terms as Surgeon General.<br/>Allows the President to remove a Surgeon General during a term only for cause. Requires the Secretary to provide a written explanation of such a removal to the relevant congressional committees. Directs the Surgeon General, under the supervision and direction of the Secretary, to administer the Office of the Surgeon General, the Regular Corps, and the Reserve Corps. Requires the Surgeon General to submit to the President an annual budget estimate for the Office of the Surgeon General, after reasonable opportunity for comment (but without change) by the Secretary.<br/>Gives the Surgeon General authority to hire and terminate employees of and consultants to the Office of the Surgeon General without obtaining approval or clearance. Directs the Surgeon General to: (1) issue reports, calls to action, and other communications on matters of importance to the health of the American people; and (2) submit to Congress and make publicly available an annual report on the state of the nation's health. Gives the Secretary the exclusive authority to disapprove the issuance of a report, call to action, or other communication proposed by the Surgeon General. 
	</summary>
</bill>
