<bill session="110" type="h" number="3450" updated="2009-01-09T00:06:56-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"/></status>

	<introduced date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">College Student Success Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide grants to universities and colleges for the development of student success services that will improve college persistence and prepare students for the workplace.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412211"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400364" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400184" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412208" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412209" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412204" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412232" joined="2008-01-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412212" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400201" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="2007-12-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1190174400" datetime="2007-09-19"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/3/2007--Introduced.<br/>College Student Success Act - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to authorize the Secretary of Education to establish a pilot program awarding competitive, matching, Student Success grants to institutions of higher education in which, during the preceding three-year period, an average of at least 50% of entering first-year students were enrolled in developmental courses to bring their reading, writing, or mathematics skills up to college-level. Requires the grants to be used to help Pell grant eligible students persevere in postsecondary education, beginning from their first year of study. Requires such help to include the assignment of a Student Success Coach to every student participant to provide intensive career and academic advising, ongoing personal help in navigating college services, and assistance in connecting to community resources that can help students overcome family and personal challenges to success. Gives grant priority to schools proposing to replicate policies and practices that have proven effective in increasing persistence and completion by low-income students or students in need of developmental education. Provides that the size of each grant shall be based on the number of a grantee's student participants; but limits each school to no more than 200 participants each academic year. Directs the Secretary to provide technical assistance to grantees who, after three years, are not significantly improving their student participants' perseverance in their studies.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
