<bill session="110" type="h" number="3479" updated="2009-01-09T00:10:36-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1188964800" datetime="2007-09-05"/></status>

	<introduced date="1188964800" datetime="2007-09-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">ADA Notification Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title III of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 to require, as a precondition to commencing a civil action with respect to a place of public accomodation or a commercial facility, that an opportunity be provided to correct alleged violations.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400212"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400367" joined="2007-10-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400191" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400235" joined="2008-06-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400224" joined="2008-01-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400057" joined="2008-09-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400005" joined="2007-10-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1188964800" datetime="2007-09-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1192161600" datetime="2007-10-12"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/5/2007--Introduced.<br/>ADA Notification Act of 2007 - Amends the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 to deny jurisdiction to a court in a civil action for remedies for disability discrimination in public accommodations and certain services provided by private entities unless: (1) the plaintiff notified the defendant in writing of the alleged violations prior to filing the complaint; (2) the notice identified the specific facts that constitute the alleged violation; (3) 90 or more days has elapsed after the date on which the notice was provided; (4) the notice informed the defendant that the civil action could not be commenced for 90 days; and (5) the complaint states that the defendant has not corrected the alleged violation. Excludes civil actions seeking preliminary injunctive relief or temporary restraining orders from such notification requirements.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
