<bill session="110" type="h" number="3489" updated="2009-01-09T00:11:50-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1189051200" datetime="2007-09-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1189051200" datetime="2007-09-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Northwest Florida Veterans Health Care Improvement Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require that the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of Defense enter into a sharing agreement with Eglin Air Force Base Hospital for the provision of inpatient services to veterans in Northwest Florida, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400279"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1189051200" datetime="2007-09-06"><text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1189051200" datetime="2007-09-06"><text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1189051200" datetime="2007-09-06"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1189137600" datetime="2007-09-07"><committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1190692800" datetime="2007-09-25"><committee name="House Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/6/2007--Introduced.<br/>Northwest Florida Veterans Health Care Improvement Act - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (Secretary) to enter into a sharing agreement with the Secretary of Defense with respect to joint Department of Veterans Affairs (VA)-Department of Defense (DOD) use of the inpatient medical facility at Eglin Air Force Base, Florida. Requires the Secretary to construct a joint VA-DOD outpatient medical facility at such Base.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
