<bill session="110" type="h" number="3485" updated="2009-01-09T00:11:20-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1189051200" datetime="2007-09-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1189051200" datetime="2007-09-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">TRACE Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Tracing and Recalling Agricultural Contamination Everywhere Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act, the Federal Meat Inspection Act, the Poultry Products Inspection Act, and the Egg Products Inspection Act to improve the safety of food, meat, and poultry products through enhanced traceability, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400101"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400041" joined="2007-10-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400623" joined="2008-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412188" joined="2008-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400245" joined="2007-10-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400103" joined="2007-10-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2008-03-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412222" joined="2007-10-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400378" joined="2008-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2008-06-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1189051200" datetime="2007-09-06"><text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1189051200" datetime="2007-09-06"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action date="1189051200" datetime="2007-09-06"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1189051200" datetime="2007-09-06"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/6/2007--Introduced.<br/>Tracing and Recalling Agricultural Contamination Everywhere Act of 2007 or TRACE Act of 2007- Amends the Federal Meat Inspection Act to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to establish a traceability system for all stages of manufacturing, processing, packaging, and distribution of food. States that cattle, sheep, swine, goats, horses, mules and other equines, and poultry presented for slaughter for human consumption, and the carcasses or parts of carcasses and the meat and food products of those animals, shipped in interstate commerce shall be identified in a manner that enables the Secretary to trace: (1) each animal to any location at which the animal was held at any time before slaughter; and (2) each carcass or part of a carcass and food product forward from slaughter through processing and distribution to the ultimate consumer. Directs the Secretary to establish a traceability system for all stages of production, processing, and distribution of meat and meat food products produced through the slaughter of such animals. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) prohibit or restrict entry to a slaughtering establishment of an animal not so identified; and (2) require a person or entity to maintain records. Amends the Poultry Products Inspection Act and the Egg Products Inspection Act to establish similar provisions for poultry and poultry products and for eggs and egg products.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
