<bill session="110" type="h" number="3496" updated="2009-01-09T00:12:42-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1189137600" datetime="2007-09-07"/></status>

	<introduced date="1189137600" datetime="2007-09-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Border Control and Contractor Accountability Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To debar or suspend contractors from Federal contracting for unlawful employment of aliens, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400051"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400570" joined="2007-10-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400628" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400221" joined="2007-09-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1189137600" datetime="2007-09-07"><text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1189137600" datetime="2007-09-07"><text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text></action>
		<action date="1189137600" datetime="2007-09-07"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1189483200" datetime="2007-09-11"><committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Organization, and Procurement.</text></action>
		<action date="1190088000" datetime="2007-09-18"><committee name="House Homeland Security"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Management, Investigations, and Oversight.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/7/2007--Introduced.<br/>Border Control and Contractor Accountability Act of 2007 - Provides that a federal contractor who employs directly or through a subcontractor an alien who is not authorized to work shall: (1) be debarred or suspended from federal contracting for three years; and (2) have the contract terminated unless the contractor or subcontractor agrees to terminate the employment of any such alien. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish the position of Small Business Administration Liaison within U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement to ensure that the Small Business Administration (SBA) does not make or guarantee a loan to an alien who is unlawfully present in the United States. Authorizes the Secretary to contract with private entities for domestic transport from Border Patrol custody to detention facilities of aliens apprehended at or along U.S. international land or maritime borders. Prohibits the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) from contracting with a company that employs individuals unless the company agrees to participate in the basic pilot employment confirmation program (under the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996). 
	</summary>
</bill>
