<bill session="110" type="h" number="3514" updated="2009-01-09T00:15:17-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1189396800" datetime="2007-09-10"/></status>

	<introduced date="1189396800" datetime="2007-09-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Gender Bias Elimination Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize workshops to eliminate gender bias for women in careers in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400204"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2007-12-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400337" joined="2008-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400155" joined="2007-12-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400647" joined="2007-12-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400082" joined="2008-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400013" joined="2008-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400378" joined="2007-12-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2007-12-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400024" joined="2007-12-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400179" joined="2007-10-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1189396800" datetime="2007-09-10"><text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committees on Science and Technology, and Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1189396800" datetime="2007-09-10"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1189396800" datetime="2007-09-10"><text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text></action>
		<action date="1189396800" datetime="2007-09-10"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1190692800" datetime="2007-09-25"><committee name="House Science and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text></action>
		<action date="1190692800" datetime="2007-09-25"><committee name="House Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text></action>
		<action date="1192593600" datetime="2007-10-17"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/10/2007--Introduced.<br/>Gender Bias Elimination Act of 2007 - Requires the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH), the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of Defense, and the Director of the National Science Foundation (NSF) and the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) to separately host mandatory national meetings that educate members of review panels, university department chairs, and agency program officers about methods that minimize the effects of gender bias in evaluation. Requires that such meetings be held biennially for each major discipline. Instructs such agencies to enforce the federal anti-discrimination laws at universities and other higher education institutions through regular compliance reviews and prompt and thorough investigation of discrimination complaints. Requires enforcement efforts to evaluate whether universities have engaged in any discrimination banned under such laws. Requires the collection storage, and publication of specified grant data composite information. Requires submission by each agency of specified reports on: (1) workshop content and attendance, along with data on the participation of women in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics; and (2) the impact of such program to reduce gender bias towards women engaged in research funded by the agency.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
