<bill session="110" type="h" number="3520" updated="2009-01-09T00:16:00-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1189396800" datetime="2007-09-10"/></status>

	<introduced date="1189396800" datetime="2007-09-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Judgeship and Administrative Efficiency Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Enhanced Bankruptcy Judgeship Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Judgeship Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Judicial Administration and Improvements Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the appointment of additional Federal circuit and district judges, to improve the administration of justice, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400365"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1189396800" datetime="2007-09-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1192161600" datetime="2007-10-12"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, the Internet, and Intellectual Property.</text></action>
		<action date="1192161600" datetime="2007-10-12"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/10/2007--Introduced.<br/>Federal Judgeship and Administrative Efficiency Act of 2007 - Federal Judgeship Act of 2007 - Directs the President to: (1) appoint additional circuit judges for the first, second, sixth, and ninth circuit courts of appeals and temporary judges for the eighth and ninth circuit courts of appeals; and (2) appoint additional permanent and temporary district judges for districts in specified states. Establishes a federal judicial district in the Virgin Islands. Revises provisions relating to the jurisdiction of courts of the Virgin Islands.<br/>Enhanced Bankruptcy Judgeship Act of 2007 - Provides for additional permanent and temporary bankruptcy judgeships in specified states. Judicial Administration and Improvements Act of 2007 - Amends the federal judicial code to divide the Ninth Judicial Circuit into the Ninth Circuit (to be composed of California, Guam, Hawaii, and the Northern Mariana Islands) and the Twelfth Circuit (to be composed of Alaska, Arizona, Idaho, Montana, Nevada, Oregon, and Washington). Declares that the former Ninth Circuit shall cease to exist for administrative purposes two years after the enactment of this Act.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
