<bill session="110" type="h" number="3521" updated="2009-01-09T00:16:07-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1190692800" datetime="2007-09-25" /></status>

	<introduced date="1189396800" datetime="2007-09-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Public Housing Asset Management Improvement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Public Housing Asset Management Improvement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the Operating Fund for public housing of the Department of Housing and Urban Development.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412186"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400295" joined="2007-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="412227" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="2007-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400422" joined="2007-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="412204" joined="2007-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400641" joined="2007-10-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1189396800" datetime="2007-09-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text></action>
		<action date="1190692800" datetime="2007-09-25"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1190692800" datetime="2007-09-25" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1201653300" datetime="2008-01-29T20:35:00-05:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 110-521.</text></action>
		<calendar number="318" date="1201653360" datetime="2008-01-29T20:36:00-05:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 318.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1202861820" datetime="2008-02-12T20:17:00-05:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 974 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3521 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Financial Services now printed in the bill.</text></action>
		<action date="1204047720" datetime="2008-02-26T13:42:00-05:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 974 passed House.</text></action>
		<action date="1204048080" datetime="2008-02-26T13:48:00-05:00"><text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 974.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H1046-1056"/><reference label="text of measure as reported in House" ref="CR H1051"/></action>
		<action date="1204048080" datetime="2008-02-26T13:48:00-05:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3521 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Financial Services now printed in the bill.</text></action>
		<action date="1204048140" datetime="2008-02-26T13:49:00-05:00"><text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 974 and Rule XVIII.</text></action>
		<action date="1204048140" datetime="2008-02-26T13:49:00-05:00"><text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Jose E. Serrano to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text></action>
		<action date="1204048140" datetime="2008-02-26T13:49:00-05:00"><text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 3521.</text></action>
		<action date="1204049760" datetime="2008-02-26T14:16:00-05:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Sires amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Sires demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text></action>
		<action date="1204049760" datetime="2008-02-26T14:16:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to H. Res. 974, the House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Meek (FL) amendment to H.R. 3521.</text></action>
		<action date="1204049940" datetime="2008-02-26T14:19:00-05:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Meek (FL) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Roskam demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text></action>
		<action date="1204050000" datetime="2008-02-26T14:20:00-05:00"><text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1204052100" datetime="2008-02-26T14:55:00-05:00"><text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 3521.</text></action>
		<action date="1204052100" datetime="2008-02-26T14:55:00-05:00"><text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H1054"/></action>
		<action date="1204052100" datetime="2008-02-26T14:55:00-05:00"><text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text></action>
		<action date="1204052280" datetime="2008-02-26T14:58:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Smith (TX) moved to recommit with instructions to Financial Services.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H1054"/><reference label="text" ref="CR H1054"/></action>
		<action date="1204052400" datetime="2008-02-26T15:00:00-05:00"><text>Point of order sustained against the motion to recommit with instructions.</text></action>
		<action date="1204052400" datetime="2008-02-26T15:00:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Sires raised a point of order against the motion to recommit with instructions. Mr. Sires stated that the provisions of the amendment contained in the instructions accompanying the motion to recommit were not germane. Sustained by the Chair.</text></action>
		<action date="1204052520" datetime="2008-02-26T15:02:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Smith (TX) moved to appeal the ruling of the Chair.</text></action>
		<action date="1204052520" datetime="2008-02-26T15:02:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Sires moved to table the appeal of the ruling of the Chair.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H1054-1055"/></action>
		<action date="1204053600" datetime="2008-02-26T15:20:00-05:00"><text>On motion to table the appeal of the ruling of the Chair Agreed to by recorded vote: 218 - 195 (Roll no. 77).</text></action>
		<action date="1204053600" datetime="2008-02-26T15:20:00-05:00"><text>Mrs. Bachmann moved to recommit with instructions to Financial Services.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H1055-1056"/><reference label="text" ref="CR H1055"/></action>
		<action date="1204053660" datetime="2008-02-26T15:21:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Bachmann motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require that the bill be reported back to the House with an amendment inserting provisions that state that the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall not accept as reasonable any fees for enforcing any provision of a dwelling lease agreement or other similar agreement that requires the registration of or prohibits the possession of any firearm that is possessed by an individual for his or her personal protection or for sport the possession of which is not prohibited, or the registration of which is not required, by existing law.</text></action>
		<action date="1204054320" datetime="2008-02-26T15:32:00-05:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - The Chair announced that pursuant to section 2 of H. Res. 974, further proceedings on the bill H.R. 3521 would be postponed.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/29/2008--Reported to House amended. Public Housing Asset Management Improvement Act of 2007 - Prohibits the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development from imposing restrictions or limitations on the amount of management and related fees for a public housing project which the public housing agency (PHA) determines reasonable, unless such restriction or limitation: (1) is determined pursuant to a negotiated rulemaking convened by the Secretary no earlier than April 1, 2009, with representatives from interested parties; and (2) is effective only on or after January 1, 2011. Allows any PHA that owns or operates fewer than 500 public housing units under the United States Housing Act of 1937 to elect to be exempt from asset management requirements imposed by the Secretary. Prohibits the Secretary from imposing any requirement, regulation, or guideline relating to asset management that restricts or limits in any way the use by PHAs of amounts for Capital Fund assistance for costs of any PHA central office. Requires the Secretary to ensure that PHAs encourage the reasonable efforts of resident tenant organizations to represent their members and of tenants to organize. Requires guidance issued by the Secretary to encourage participation by residents in the implementation of asset management and the development of local policies for such purposes.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
