<bill session="110" type="h" number="3523" updated="2009-01-09T00:16:22-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1189483200" datetime="2007-09-11"/></status>

	<introduced date="1189483200" datetime="2007-09-11"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">I LEAD Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Improving the Leadership and Effectiveness of Administrators for Districts Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To develop a generation of school leaders who are committed to, and effective in, increasing student achievement and to ensure that all low-income, under-performing schools are led by effective school leaders who are well-prepared to foster student success.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400097"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400067" joined="2007-09-11"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1189483200" datetime="2007-09-11"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1192593600" datetime="2007-10-17"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/11/2007--Introduced.<br/>Improving the Leadership and Effectiveness of Administrators for Districts Act of 2007 or the I LEAD Act of 2007 - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (the Act) to direct the Secretary of Education to establish a program awarding competitive School Leadership Partnership grants to partnerships, each composed of a state and a consortium of high-need local educational agencies (LEAs), to: (1) contract with experienced external agencies for research-based evaluations of the effectiveness of state school leader certification or licensure requirements and methods of recruiting, training, and retaining effective school leaders who improve student achievement at schools receiving improvement funds under part A of title I of the Act; (2) use such evaluations, if the certification or licensure requirements are shown to be ineffective, to develop plans to improve such requirements and school leadership recruitment, training, and support programs; and (3) if required to develop a plan, create model School Leadership Initiatives by implementing such plans in an urban and/or rural high-need LEA participating in their partnerships. Requires grantees to contract with an independent research and evaluation firm to evaluate the effectiveness of their School Leadership Initiatives in recruiting, training, and retraining school leaders and improving student achievement. Directs the Secretary to award an additional grant to partnership grantees whose model School Leadership Initiatives are evaluated as effective so that they can implement such Initiatives in other LEAs within their states.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
