<bill session="110" type="h" number="3547" updated="2009-01-09T00:19:14-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1190001600" datetime="2007-09-17"/></status>

	<introduced date="1190001600" datetime="2007-09-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Gang Prevention, Intervention, and Suppression Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To increase and enhance law enforcement resources committed to investigation and prosecution of violent gangs, to deter and punish violent gang crime, to protect law-abiding citizens and communities from violent criminals, to revise and enhance criminal penalties for violent crimes, to expand and improve gang prevention programs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400361"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400123" joined="2007-10-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400290" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400219" joined="2008-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-09-24" withdrawn="2007-10-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400659" joined="2007-10-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400618" joined="2007-11-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400092" joined="2007-10-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412224" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400623" joined="2007-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400430" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400129" joined="2007-10-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400065" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400196" joined="2007-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400229" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="412189" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400030" joined="2007-10-25" withdrawn="2007-10-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400663" joined="2007-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400144" joined="2007-10-02" withdrawn="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412187" joined="2007-11-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400048" joined="2008-01-29" withdrawn="2008-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400442" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400057" joined="2007-12-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400631" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400039" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400166" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400426" joined="2007-10-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400378" joined="2008-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2007-09-25" withdrawn="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400371" joined="2007-10-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400090" joined="2007-09-17" withdrawn="2007-10-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="2007-10-25" withdrawn="2007-10-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400363" joined="2007-09-24" withdrawn="2007-10-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="412233" joined="2007-09-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1190001600" datetime="2007-09-17"><text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1190001600" datetime="2007-09-17"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1190001600" datetime="2007-09-17"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1192593600" datetime="2007-10-17"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Healthy Families and Communities.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/17/2007--Introduced.<br/>Gang Prevention, Intervention, and Suppression Act - Amends the federal criminal code to define &quot;criminal street gang&quot; and &quot;gang crime&quot; and to prohibit: (1) the commission of, or an attempt or conspiracy to commit, a gang crime to further the activities of a criminal street gang; and (2) the recruitment of another person to join a criminal street gang.<br/>Amends the Controlled Substances Act to impose criminal penalties for murder and other violent crimes committed in the course of a drug trafficking offense.<br/>Increases criminal penalties for possession of firearms by repeat criminal offenders. Prohibits the possession of firearms by individuals convicted of a gang-related misdemeanor or in contempt of a gang injunction order.<br/>Authorizes the Attorney General to deny the transfer of a firearm or a firearm permit to individuals who may use firearms for terrorist activities.<br/>Authorizes the Attorney General to: (1) designate certain areas in states as high intensity interstate gang activity areas and provide assistance to such areas; (2) expand the Project Safe Neighborhoods program to require U.S. attorneys to identify, investigate, and prosecute criminal street gangs operating in their districts; (3) expand the Safe Streets Program of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) to support criminal street gang enforcement teams; and (4) make grants to states to prevent abductions of children by family members.<br/>Establishes a grant program in the Office of Justice Programs of the Department of Justice (DOJ) for crime prevention, research, and intervention services designed for gang members and at-risk youth.<br/>Establishes in the U.S. Marshals Service a Short-Term State Witness Protection Section to provide protection for witnesses in state and local trials involving homicide or other violent crimes. Expands the federal witness relocation and protection program to include protection for witnesses against criminal street gangs.<br/>Directs the Secretary of Labor to make grants for juvenile offender reintegration projects and for employment programs for young adult gang members to reduce recidivism and promote long-term employability.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
