<bill session="110" type="h" number="3551" updated="2009-01-09T00:19:43-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1190001600" datetime="2007-09-17"/></status>

	<introduced date="1190001600" datetime="2007-09-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Merit System Reauthorization Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To reauthorize the Merit Systems Protection Board and the Office of Special Counsel, to modify the procedures of the Merit Systems Protection Board and the Office of Special Counsel, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400093"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400227" joined="2007-09-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400295" joined="2007-09-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400074" joined="2007-09-20"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1190001600" datetime="2007-09-17"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1899)</text></action>
		<action date="1190001600" datetime="2007-09-17"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text></action>
		<action date="1190001600" datetime="2007-09-17"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia.</text></action>
		<action date="1190088000" datetime="2007-09-18"><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1190088000" datetime="2007-09-18"><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by the Yeas and Nays: 5 - 3 .</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/17/2007--Introduced.<br/>Federal Merit System Reauthorization Act of 2007 - Amends the Whistleblower Protection Act of 1989 to authorize appropriations for FY2008-FY2010 for the Merit Systems Protection Board (MSPB) and the Office of Special Counsel (OSC).<br/>Repudiates assertions that federal employees are not protected from discrimination on the basis of sexual orientation. Expresses the sense of Congress that discrimination on such basis against federal employees and applicants is currently prohibited. Prohibits any federal employee who has authority to take, direct, recommend, or approve any personnel action from discriminating for or against any federal employee or applicant on such basis.<br/>Revises procedures of the MSPB and OSC, including by requiring the MSPB to use the National Labor Relations Board model for procedural due process and by requiring the OSC to prescribe regulations necessary to receive and investigate allegations of prohibited personnel practices.<br/>Requires the Special Counsel to have professional experience that demonstrates an understanding of and a commitment to protecting the merit based civil service.<br/>Requires the OSC to publish specified whistleblower disclosures and reports.<br/>Sets forth MSPB and OSC reporting requirements with respect to incidences of prohibited personnel practices.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
