<bill session="110" type="h" number="3550" updated="2009-01-09T00:19:36-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1190001600" datetime="2007-09-17"/></status>

	<introduced date="1190001600" datetime="2007-09-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">AMERICA Act of 2007: A Modest Effort to Read and Instill the Constitution Again</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require every Senator and Representative in, and Delegate and Resident Commissioner to, the Congress to obtain copies of the Constitution of the United States of America and distribute them to their staff and require that they all read such document.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400655"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400123" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400313" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400040" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400029" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400373" joined="2007-09-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400005" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400145" joined="2007-09-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1190001600" datetime="2007-09-17"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H10409-10410)</text></action>
		<action date="1190001600" datetime="2007-09-17"><text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text></action>
		<action date="1190088000" datetime="2007-09-18"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1839)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/17/2007--Introduced.<br/>AMERICA Act of 2007: A Modest Effort to Read and Instill the Constitution Again - Expresses the sense of Congress that since Members of Congress swear to uphold the Constitution of the United States, write laws regarding the powers granted to the government, and propose constitutional amendments, they should be required to read this important document, including its amendments. Directs every Senator and Representative to obtain copies of the Constitution, distribute them to their staff, and require the staff to read it at least once during each session of Congress. 
	</summary>
</bill>
