<bill session="110" type="h" number="3563" updated="2009-01-09T00:21:06-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1190088000" datetime="2007-09-18"/></status>

	<introduced date="1190088000" datetime="2007-09-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">PRIME Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Prostate Research, Imaging, and Men's Education Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for prostate cancer imaging research and education.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400090"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400073" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400160" joined="2007-10-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400155" joined="2008-02-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2008-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400183" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400302" joined="2008-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400295" joined="2008-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400271" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="2007-11-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400268" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400063" joined="2008-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400196" joined="2007-11-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400132" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400254" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="2008-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400152" joined="2008-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400055" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400030" joined="2007-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400007" joined="2008-02-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2008-06-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="2007-11-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400195" joined="2008-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400074" joined="2008-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400118" joined="2008-12-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400244" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2007-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400201" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2008-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400204" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400654" joined="2007-12-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400025" joined="2008-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400062" joined="2007-09-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1190088000" datetime="2007-09-18"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1190088000" datetime="2007-09-18"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/18/2007--Introduced.<br/>Prostate Research, Imaging, and Men's Education Act of 2007 or the PRIME Act of 2007 - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH), to: (1) carry out a program to expand and intensify research to develop advanced imaging technologies for prostate cancer detection, diagnosis, and treatment comparable to mammogram technology; and (2) utilize the National Institute of Biomedical Imaging and Bioengineering and the National Cancer Institute for advanced stages of research in prostate imaging. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, to: (1) carry out a grant program to encourage the early stages of research in prostate imaging to develop and implement new ideas, proof of concepts, and pilot studies for high-risk technologic innovation; and (2) establish interdisciplinary private-public partnerships to develop research strategies for expedited innovation in imaging and image-guided treatment. Directs the Secretary: (1) to carry out a national campaign to increase awareness and knowledge with respect to the need for prostate cancer screening and for improved detection technologies; (2) in carrying out the program and the campaign, to recognize and address the racial disparities in the incidences of prostate cancer and mortality rates and any racial barriers in access to care and participation in clinical trials; (3) establish a program to award grants to nonprofit private entities to test alternative outreach and education strategies; and (4) carry out research to develop an improved prostate cancer screening blood test using in-vitro detection.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
