<bill session="110" type="h" number="3560" updated="2009-01-09T00:20:45-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1190088000" datetime="2007-09-18"/></status>

	<introduced date="1190088000" datetime="2007-09-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Southeast Alaska Native Land Entitlement Finalization Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the completion of certain land selections under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400440"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400128" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400308" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400001" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400215" joined="2007-09-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1190088000" datetime="2007-09-18"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1913)</text></action>
		<action date="1190088000" datetime="2007-09-18"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1195016400" datetime="2007-11-14"><text>Committee Hearings Held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/18/2007--Introduced.<br/>Southeast Alaska Native Land Entitlement Finalization Act - Authorizes Sealaska Corporation to select and receive conveyance of its remaining Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (ANCSA) land entitlement from federal lands in southeast Alaska from each of the following categories: (1) specified economic development land; (2) specified sites with sacred, cultural, traditional, or historical significance; and (3) specified native enterprise sites with traditional and recreational use value. Requires the Secretary of Interior to complete the conveyance of land to Sealaska within 180 days of selection.<br/>Declares that upon the exhaustion of Sealaska's remaining land entitlement under ANCSA and the completion of the conveyances of the land selected, the original southeast Alaska withdrawals shall expire and the lands within the withdrawals that are not conveyed to a Southeast Alaska Regional or Village Corporation shall be returned to the unencumbered management of the U.S. Forest Service as a part of the Tongass National Forest.<br/>Prohibits Sealaska from selecting or receiving conveyance of lands from within any Conservation System Unit, federally designated wilderness areas, or Land Use Designation I or II Areas.<br/>Sets forth provisions concerning: (1) covenants and conditions on land conveyances to Sealaska, including subjecting conveyances of specified lands to a covenant prohibiting commercial timber harvesting; (2) authorized uses for the sacred, cultural, traditional, and historic sites; and (3) nonexclusive access and use rights that are required to be included in conveyances to Sealaska of native enterprise sites.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
