<bill session="110" type="h" number="3561" updated="2009-01-09T00:20:52-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1190088000" datetime="2007-09-18"/></status>

	<introduced date="1190088000" datetime="2007-09-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Community Coalitions for Access and Quality Improvement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to community health coalitions to assist in the development of integrated health care delivery, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400160"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-10-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400129" joined="2007-10-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400379" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400653" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400421" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400009" joined="2007-09-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1190088000" datetime="2007-09-18"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1190088000" datetime="2007-09-18"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/18/2007--Introduced.<br/>Community Coalitions for Access and Quality Improvement Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to award grants to assist in developing integrated health care delivery systems to serve defined communities of individuals to: (1) improve efficiency and coordination among providers; (2) assist local communities in developing programs targeted toward preventing and managing chronic diseases; and (3) expand and enhance services provided.<br/>Requires eligible entities to represent a balanced consortium whose principal purpose is to ensure sustained capacity for the provision of a broad range of coordinated services for all residents, including at least one of each of the following providers that serve the community (with exceptions): (1) a federally qualified health center; (2) rural health clinics and rural health networks; (3) a hospital with a low-income utilization rate that is greater than 25% or a critical access hospital; (4) a public health department; and (5) an interested public or private sector health care provider or an organization that has traditionally served medically uninsured and low-income individuals.<br/>Authorizes the Secretary, in awarding grants, to accord priority to applicants that demonstrate the greatest unmet need for a more coordinated system of care.<br/>Authorizes a grantee to use amounts provided only for: (1) direct expenses associated with achieving greater integration of a health care delivery system to directly provide or ensure the provision of a broad range of culturally competent services; and (2) direct patient care and service expansions to fill identified or documented gaps within an integrated delivery system.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
