<bill session="110" type="h" number="3574" updated="2009-01-09T00:22:25-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1190088000" datetime="2007-09-18"/></status>

	<introduced date="1190088000" datetime="2007-09-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Willamette River United Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To continue the work to enhance access to the Willamette River that has been initiated by the Willamette River Basin communities, State, regional, local, and Indian tribal governments and non-government partnerships, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400186"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400437" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400100" joined="2007-09-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1190088000" datetime="2007-09-18"><text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1190088000" datetime="2007-09-18"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1190088000" datetime="2007-09-18"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1190174400" datetime="2007-09-19"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text></action>
		<action date="1190260800" datetime="2007-09-20"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/18/2007--Introduced.<br/>Willamette River United Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to enter into cooperative agreements with the Oregon Parks and Recreation Department (OPRD) and the Oregon Watershed Enhancement Board to administer grants for recreation, historic, archeological, and cultural preservation or conservation projects. Specifies the general types of projects and specific projects for which grants may be made.<br/>Prohibits grant funds from being used: (1) to support regulatory actions or mitigation thereof; or (2) for operations and maintenance costs.<br/>Sets forth grant matching requirements.<br/>Provides that: (1) private property owners located in the Willamette Basin are not required to participate in programs established under this Act; and (2) funds appropriated to carry out this Act may be used to purchase land only from willing sellers.<br/>Requires private landowners voluntarily participating in this Act to permit access to their property to implement, inspect, monitor, or perform repairs or maintenance to funded projects.<br/>Authorizes federal agencies with jurisdiction over U.S. natural resources or parks to: (1) use funds to provide assistance to the grant programs of the Board and OPRD when a private investment has been identified and private funds have been committed to a project and to provide financial assistance to Willamette River restoration, recreation, heritage and tourism efforts if the partner can demonstrate strong support in the community; and (2) enter into an agreement with the Board or OPRD to administer federal assistance.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
