<bill session="110" type="h" number="3610" updated="2009-01-09T00:26:36-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1190260800" datetime="2007-09-20"/></status>

	<introduced date="1190260800" datetime="2007-09-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Food and Drug Import Safety Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act with respect to the safety of food and drugs imported into the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400110"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400102" joined="2007-12-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412210" joined="2007-11-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400101" joined="2007-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400308" joined="2007-09-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="412228" joined="2007-11-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400391" joined="2007-09-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400425" joined="2007-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="2007-10-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1190260800" datetime="2007-09-20"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1190260800" datetime="2007-09-20"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1190779200" datetime="2007-09-26"><text>Committee Hearings Held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/20/2007--Introduced.<br/>Food and Drug Import Safety Act of 2007 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to provide for research on the development of tests and sampling methodologies for use on imported food.<br/>Requires the Secretary to assess and collect fees on imported food and drugs.<br/>Directs the Secretary to restrict the importation of all food to metropolitan ports of entry with a Food and Drug Administration (FDA) laboratory for testing such food.<br/>Deems a food, drug, or device to be misbranded it its labeling fails to identify its country of origin. Requires the Secretary to establish a program under which: (1) persons importing food voluntarily agree to abide by specified food and security guidelines; and (2) the Secretary agrees to expedite the movement of such food through the inspection process. Increases civil penalties for the manufacturer or importer of adulterated food.Sets forth provisions governing the reorganization of FDA field laboratories and district offices. Requires the Secretary to issue an order requiring an immediate cease in the distribution of food that may cause serious, adverse health consequences or death.<br/>Subjects all imported food to U.S. food safety standards. Sets forth a certification system for a foreign facility seeking to import food.<br/>Requires the Secretary to require, as good manufacturing practices, that processed food undergo testing to detect substances that may render the food adulterated.<br/>Defines the term &quot;color additive&quot; to include carbon monoxide that may affect the color of fresh meat, poultry products, or seafood, unless the label bears a specified statement.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
