<bill session="110" type="h" number="3612" updated="2009-01-09T00:26:52-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1190260800" datetime="2007-09-20"/></status>

	<introduced date="1190260800" datetime="2007-09-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Local Law Enforcement Restoration Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide for no preemption of certain State and local laws regarding employment eligibility verification requirements.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400427"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400279" joined="2007-09-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400627" joined="2007-09-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400060" joined="2007-09-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="412252" joined="2007-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400137" joined="2007-12-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400151" joined="2007-09-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400441" joined="2007-10-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400652" joined="2007-10-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400288" joined="2007-09-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400055" joined="2007-10-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400658" joined="2007-10-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400017" joined="2007-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="412235" joined="2007-09-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400131" joined="2007-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400570" joined="2007-10-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400153" joined="2007-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400421" joined="2007-09-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400005" joined="2007-09-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400145" joined="2007-09-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400016" joined="2007-09-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400315" joined="2007-09-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400394" joined="2007-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="412011" joined="2007-09-20"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1190260800" datetime="2007-09-20"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1945)</text></action>
		<action date="1190260800" datetime="2007-09-20"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1192161600" datetime="2007-10-12"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/20/2007--Introduced.<br/>Local Law Enforcement Restoration Act - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to state that specified unlawful alien employment provisions shall not preempt any state or local law that imposes: (1) employment eligibility verification requirements imposed upon employers or employees consistent with or in addition to employment eligibility verification requirements; (2) civil or criminal penalties for violation of such state or local employment eligibility verification requirements; (3) civil or criminal penalties for prohibited acts; (4) licensing sanctions for violation of such state or local employment eligibility verification requirements; (5) licensing sanctions for prohibited acts; or (6) limitations on the private right to sue for up to treble damages. (Current law provides that such unlawful alien employment provisions shall preempt any state or local law imposing criminal or civil sanctions [other than through licensing or similar laws] upon those who employ, recruit or refer for a fee for employment, unauthorized aliens.) Applies such provisions to all applicable state or local laws that were enacted before, on, or after January 1, 2005. 
	</summary>
</bill>
