<bill session="110" type="h" number="3611" updated="2009-01-09T00:26:45-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1190260800" datetime="2007-09-20"/></status>

	<introduced date="1190260800" datetime="2007-09-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Bringing Success to Scale Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Bringing Success to Scale program in the Department of Education.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412219"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412220" joined="2007-09-20"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1190260800" datetime="2007-09-20"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1192593600" datetime="2007-10-17"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/20/2007--Introduced.<br/>Bringing Success to Scale Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to establish a Bringing Success to Scale program making academic achievement grant awards to local educational agencies (LEAs) and schools that: (1) significantly close the achievement gap between poor, minority, disabled, limited English proficient, and other students; (2) exceed the state's annual measurable academic objectives for two or more consecutive years; (3) make significant improvement on other meaningful data, such as graduation rates and the recruitment of high quality teachers and principals; and (4) demonstrate that they have established partnerships with the private sector and will provide matching funds to help bring results to scale. Designates such LEAs and schools as Distinguished School Districts and Distinguished Schools, respectively. Requires the program to award grants to school management or support organizations, nonprofit organizations, and human capital providers so that they can work in partnership with the private sector and philanthropic community to expand innovative programs that produce results and share best practices with schools and LEAs. Designates such entities as Distinguished School Support Organizations. 
	</summary>
</bill>
