<bill session="110" type="h" number="3626" updated="2009-01-09T00:28:39-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1190260800" datetime="2007-09-20"/></status>

	<introduced date="1190260800" datetime="2007-09-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for continued treatment for the reopening of certain facilities under the Medicare and Medicaid programs.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400373"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1190260800" datetime="2007-09-20"><text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1190260800" datetime="2007-09-20"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1190260800" datetime="2007-09-20"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1190260800" datetime="2007-09-20"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1190347200" datetime="2007-09-21"><committee name="House Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/20/2007--Introduced.<br/>Declares that certain closed critical access hospitals and adjoining skilled nursing facilities (SNFs) that seek to reopen on or after the enactment of this Act shall be deemed to continue to be designated as a critical access hospital, and both the hospital and the SNF shall be deemed to continue to meet the applicable life safety code standards, for purposes of titles XVIII (Medicare) and XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act. Confines the application of this Act to a hospital and an adjoining SNF that operated under common management before 1983 and closed during 2005, if before such closure the hospital was designated as a critical access hospital and the hospital and SNF both met the National Fire Protection Agency Life Health Safety Code as a facility existing as of March 16, 1982.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
