<bill session="110" type="h" number="3620" updated="2009-01-09T00:27:57-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1190260800" datetime="2007-09-20"/></status>

	<introduced date="1190260800" datetime="2007-09-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Homecoming Enhancement Research and Oversight Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for a comprehensive national research effort on the physical and mental health and other readjustment needs of the members of the Armed Forces and veterans who served in Operation Iraqi Freedom and Operation Enduring Freedom and their families.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400217"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1190260800" datetime="2007-09-20"><text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1190260800" datetime="2007-09-20"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1190260800" datetime="2007-09-20"><text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1190347200" datetime="2007-09-21"><committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1192766400" datetime="2007-10-19"><committee name="House Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/20/2007--Introduced.<br/>Homecoming Enhancement Research and Oversight Act - Directs the Secretary of Defense to enter into an agreement with the National Academy of Sciences for a study of the physical and mental health and other readjustment needs of members and former members of the Armed Forces who deployed in Operations Iraqi Freedom or Enduring Freedom, and their families. Requires: (1) reports, from the Academy to the Secretaries of Defense and Veterans Affairs and from the Secretary to Congress, on such study; (2) the public availability of the reports; (3) such Secretaries to develop a joint plan to address report findings; and (4) the public availability of the Secretaries' response.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
