<bill session="110" type="h" number="3638" updated="2009-01-09T00:30:03-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1190606400" datetime="2007-09-24"/></status>

	<introduced date="1190606400" datetime="2007-09-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Border Security and Elimination of Sanctuary for Illegal Aliens Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To end the cycle of illegal immigration in the United States.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400055"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1190606400" datetime="2007-09-24"><text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1190606400" datetime="2007-09-24"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1190606400" datetime="2007-09-24"><text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text></action>
		<action date="1190865600" datetime="2007-09-27"><committee name="House Homeland Security"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border, Maritime, and Global Counterterrorism.</text></action>
		<action date="1192161600" datetime="2007-10-12"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/24/2007--Introduced.<br/>Border Security and Elimination of Sanctuary for Illegal Aliens Act of 2007 - Expresses the sense of Congress that the worsening crisis of illegal immigration must be solved. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to: (1) increase incentives to recruit Border Patrol agents through repayment of higher education loans; (2) establish a retention program; and (3) make construction of border fencing a priority. Authorizes the Secretary to deploy newly-developed technology along the land and maritime borders. Requires that a state or local law enforcement agency that arrests an alien unlawfully in the United States for any reason shall notify United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement respecting such arrest and provide the identity of the arrested person. Provides for: (1) such person's expedited removal from the United States, and (2) criminal penalties and expedited removal for a subsequent unlawful presence. Makes inadmissible to the United States an alien who has been unlawfully present in the United States and who attempts to illegally enter or reenter the United States. (Under current law, such person must be unlawfully in the United States for an aggregate period exceeding one year.)<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
