<bill session="110" type="h" number="3642" updated="2009-01-09T00:30:33-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1190606400" datetime="2007-09-24"/></status>

	<introduced date="1190606400" datetime="2007-09-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Expanded Learning Time Demonstration Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to provide grants for expanded learning time schools and programs.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400312"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400364" joined="2008-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2008-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400407" joined="2008-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="412221" joined="2008-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400184" joined="2008-06-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400437" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400120" joined="2008-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2008-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="2008-06-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1190606400" datetime="2007-09-24"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1193112000" datetime="2007-10-23"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/24/2007--Introduced.<br/>Expanded Learning Time Demonstration Act - Amends title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to create a new part J (Expanded Learning Time Schools and Programs) authorizing the Secretary of Education to award competitive grants directly to local educational agencies (LEAs) or to states for competitive subgrants to LEAs for planning and implementing expanded learning time and school redesign efforts in a subset of their schools. Gives grant and subgrant priority to LEAs more than 25% of whose students are eligible for federal free or reduced-price meals and which, in turn, target high-need schools: (1) at least 50% of whose students are eligible for such meals; (2) identified as needing improvement, corrective action, or restructuring under title I; or (3) eligible for school improvement funds under part A of title I. Requires expanded learning time and school redesign efforts to add at least 360 hours to the schedule of each participating school each year in the form of longer or additional school days. Directs the Secretary to contract with independent organizations for: (1) a rigorous five-year evaluation of the impact and implementation of this Act's grant programs, particularly on student performance; and (2) the provision of technical assistance to states and LEAs that includes the dissemination of best practices for expanding learning time.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
