<bill session="110" type="h" number="3643" updated="2009-01-09T00:30:40-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1190606400" datetime="2007-09-24"/></status>

	<introduced date="1190606400" datetime="2007-09-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Coordinated Environmental Public Health Network Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to establish a Coordinated Environmental Public Health Network, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400314"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400253" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400041" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400227" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400160" joined="2008-02-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400102" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400122" joined="2008-02-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400623" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="2008-02-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400101" joined="2008-02-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400384" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400245" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400001" joined="2008-02-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400103" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400346" joined="2008-02-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="2008-02-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400013" joined="2008-02-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400378" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412232" joined="2008-02-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400366" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400097" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400208" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400062" joined="2008-02-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400425" joined="2008-02-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="2007-12-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1190606400" datetime="2007-09-24"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1194498000" datetime="2007-11-08"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/24/2007--Introduced.<br/>Coordinated Environmental Public Health Network Act of 2007 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) and with the involvement of other federal agencies, state and local health departments, and an advisory committee, to establish and operate a Coordinated Environmental Public Health Network.<br/>Directs the Secretary to: (1) identify, expand, and coordinate among existing data and surveillance systems, surveys, registries, and other federal public health and environmental infrastructure; (2) provide for public access to an electronic national database that accepts data from the State Environmental Public Health Network (established by this Act), subject to privacy requirements; (3) prepare and periodically publish a Coordinated Environmental Public Health Network Status Report and a Coordinated Network Health and Environment Report; (4) operate and maintain National Environmental Health Rapid Response Services; (5) provide technical assistance; and (6) develop minimum standards and procedures for data collection and reporting.<br/>Authorizes: (1) states to apply for grants to implement pilot projects to develop State Environmental Public Health Network enhancements and programs; and (2) the Secretary to award grants to at least five accredited schools or programs of public health for Centers of Excellence.<br/>Directs the Secretary: (1) to award John H. Chafee Public Health Scholarships to eligible students enrolled in accredited schools of public health or medicine; and (2) through the CDC Director, to enter into cooperative agreements to train and place applied epidemiology fellows in state and local health departments and to expand CDC biomonitoring data collection.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
