<bill session="110" type="h" number="3668" updated="2009-01-09T00:33:37-05:00">
	<status><enacted date="1191038400" datetime="2007-09-29" /></status>

	<introduced date="1190779200" datetime="2007-09-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">TMA, Abstinence Education, and QI Programs Extension Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">TMA, Abstinence Education, and QI Programs Extension Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">TMA, Abstinence Education, and QI Programs Extension Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="enacted">TMA, Abstinence Education, and QI Programs Extension Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the extension of transitional medical assistance (TMA), the abstinence education program, and the qualifying individuals (QI) program, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400110"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400333" joined="2007-09-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1190779200" datetime="2007-09-26"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1190779200" datetime="2007-09-26"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1190779200" datetime="2007-09-26"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1190828940" datetime="2007-09-26T14:49:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Green, Gene moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text></action>
		<action date="1190828940" datetime="2007-09-26T14:49:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H10932-10935"/></action>
		<action date="1190828940" datetime="2007-09-26T14:49:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3668.</text></action>
		<vote date="1190829600" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-09-26T15:00:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H10932-10933"/></vote>
		<action date="1190779200" datetime="2007-09-26"><text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text></action>
		<vote date="1190865600" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2007-09-27" where="s" type="vote2" result="pass" ><text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S12316"/></vote>
		<topresident date="1190865600" datetime="2007-09-27" ><text>Cleared for White House.</text></topresident>
		<action date="1190952000" datetime="2007-09-28"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<topresident date="1190952000" datetime="2007-09-28" ><text>Presented to President.</text></topresident>
		<signed date="1191038400" datetime="2007-09-29" ><text>Signed by President.</text></signed>
		<enacted number="110-90" date="1191038400" datetime="2007-09-29" type="public" ><text>Became Public Law No: 110-90.</text></enacted>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/29/2007--Public Law. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the House passed version is repeated here.) TMA, Abstinence Education, and QI Programs Extension Act of 2007 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Tax Relief and Health Care Act of 2006, as amended, to extend transitional medical assistance (TMA) and the abstinence education program through December 31, 2007. (Sec. 3) Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to extend through December 2007: (1) the qualifying individual (QI) program; and (2) a specified allocation of funds for state coverage of Medicare cost-sharing for additional low-income Medicare beneficiaries. (Sec. 4) Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services, for FY2008-FY2012, to provide for the application to asset eligibility determinations under the Medicaid program of the automated, secure, web-based asset verification request and response process being applied for determining eligibility for Supplemental Security Income benefits under a specified demonstration project authorized by SSA title XVI (Supplemental Security Income) (SSI) Limits such application to those states in which such a demonstration project is operating and only for the period in which it is otherwise provided. (Sec. 5) Amends the U.S. Troop Readiness, Veterans' Care, Katrina Recovery, and Iraq Accountability Appropriations Act, 2007 to delay for six months, from September 30, 2007, through March 31, 2008, the effective date of the requirement to use tamper-resistant prescription pads to prescribe covered outpatient drugs under the Medicaid program. (Sec. 6) Amends SSA title XVIII (Medicare) to provide additional funding for the Medicare Physician Assistance and Quality Initiative Fund for expenditures during FY2009 and during or after FY2013. (Sec. 7) Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in implementing a specified rule, to apply certain prospective documentation and coding (PDC) adjustments (made in response to the implementation of the Medicare Severity Diagnosis Related Group (MS-DRG) system under the Medicare prospective payment system (PPS) for inpatient hospital services) for discharges occurring during FY2008 and FY2009. Reduces the percentage specified in such rule for discharges occurring: (1) during FY2008 from 1.2% to 0.6%; and (2) during FY2009 from 1.8% to 0.9%. Directs the Secretary to make further specified PDC adjustments, as well as additional adjustments in FY2010-FY2012, if the implementation of the MS-DRG system resulted in changes in coding and classification that did not reflect real changes in case mix for FY2008 or FY2009 discharges that are different than the PDC adjustments applied under this section.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
