<bill session="110" type="h" number="3670" updated="2009-01-09T00:33:50-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1190779200" datetime="2007-09-26"/></status>

	<introduced date="1190779200" datetime="2007-09-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Public Diplomacy through International Travel Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of State to enhance diplomatic relations with foreign countries and to promote domestic business interests abroad by establishing a grant program to promote international travel to the United States.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400129"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400290" joined="2007-11-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2007-10-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400034" joined="2007-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400073" joined="2007-10-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400618" joined="2007-11-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400102" joined="2007-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400403" joined="2007-10-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400176" joined="2008-01-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400396" joined="2007-10-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400384" joined="2007-10-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400355" joined="2007-10-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400663" joined="2007-10-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400324" joined="2007-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400347" joined="2007-11-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400356" joined="2007-10-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400057" joined="2007-10-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2007-11-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2007-10-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400024" joined="2007-10-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400062" joined="2007-11-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400011" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400425" joined="2007-10-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="412011" joined="2008-05-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1190779200" datetime="2007-09-26"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1190779200" datetime="2007-09-26"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1190779200" datetime="2007-09-26"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1194498000" datetime="2007-11-08"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/26/2007--Introduced.<br/>Improving Public Diplomacy through International Travel Act - Directs the Secretary of State to enhance diplomatic relations with foreign countries and promote domestic business interests abroad by establishing a grant program to promote international travel to the United States. Directs a grant recipient to develop a promotion program to encourage international travel to the United States and to effectively communicate U.S. entry requirements, including required documentation, fees, and processes. Sets forth the following market phase-ins: (1) year one, Canada; (2) year two, Canada and Mexico; (3) year three, Canada, Mexico, and the United Kingdom; (4) year four, Canada, Mexico, the United Kingdom, and Japan; and (5) year five, Canada, Mexico, the United Kingdom, Japan, and Germany. Reserves 20% of grant funds for promotion programs for destinations that lack the resources to market themselves internationally.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
