<bill session="110" type="h" number="3674" updated="2009-01-09T00:34:24-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1190779200" datetime="2007-09-26"/></status>

	<introduced date="1190779200" datetime="2007-09-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Iraqi Refugee and Internally Displaced Persons Humanitarian Assistance, Resettlement, and Security Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To address the impending humanitarian crisis and security breakdown as a result of the mass influx of Iraqi refugees into neighboring countries, and the growing internally displaced population in Iraq, by increasing directed accountable assistance to these populations and their host countries, increasing border security, and facilitating the resettlement of Iraqis at risk.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400170"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400661" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2007-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400423" joined="2007-10-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="2008-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412193" joined="2008-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400110" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400087" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400259" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400195" joined="2007-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412200" joined="2007-10-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2007-10-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2007-10-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400301" joined="2007-12-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1190779200" datetime="2007-09-26"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1987-1988)</text></action>
		<action date="1190779200" datetime="2007-09-26"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1190779200" datetime="2007-09-26"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1190779200" datetime="2007-09-26"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1193976000" datetime="2007-11-02"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/26/2007--Introduced.<br/>Iraqi Refugee and Internally Displaced Persons Humanitarian Assistance, Resettlement, and Security Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of State, with respect to each country containing a significant population of Iraqi refugees or internally displaced persons including Iraq, Jordan, Syria, Turkey, Iran, and Lebanon, to provide bilateral assistance or funding to international aid organizations and nongovernmental organizations for humanitarian assistance, including adequate food, shelter, clean drinking water, sanitation, health care, education, and security. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish a program to assist Jordanian border police, immigration officers, and other individuals responsible for Jordanian border security in the security screening of Iraqi refugees. Authorizes special immigrant status for an alien (and accompanying or joining spouse and children) who: (1) is a national of Iraq; (2) was employed by, or worked for or with, the U.S. government, U.S. companies, or nongovernmental organizations in Iraq on or after March 19, 2003, for at least one year; and (3) fears reprisal, persecution, injury, or death to the alien or the alien's family due to such employment. Directs the Secretary of State to provide such alien with protection or immediate removal from Iraq. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to provide for expedited processing of Iraqi refugees, with priority for Iraqis who: (1) were employed by the U.S. government, U.S. companies, or nongovernmental organizations; or (2) are members of vulnerable refugee populations, including Iraqis from ethnically mixed families and Iraqis who are members of religious or other minority groups. Directs the Secretary of State to work with the international community to assist Iraqi refugees and internally displaced persons. 
	</summary>
</bill>
