<bill session="110" type="h" number="3686" updated="2009-01-09T00:35:48-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1190865600" datetime="2007-09-27"/></status>

	<introduced date="1190865600" datetime="2007-09-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit employment discrimination based on gender identity.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400140"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2007-10-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400623" joined="2007-10-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="2007-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400437" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400008" joined="2007-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400166" joined="2007-10-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2007-10-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2008-03-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="412254" joined="2008-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="2007-09-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1190865600" datetime="2007-09-27"><text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committees on House Administration, Oversight and Government Reform, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1190865600" datetime="2007-09-27"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1190865600" datetime="2007-09-27"><text>Referred to House House Administration</text></action>
		<action date="1190865600" datetime="2007-09-27"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1190865600" datetime="2007-09-27"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1192161600" datetime="2007-10-12"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text></action>
		<action date="1192593600" datetime="2007-10-17"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/27/2007--Introduced.<br/>Prohibits employment discrimination on the basis of actual or perceived gender identity by covered entities (employers, employment agencies, labor organizations, or joint labor-management committees). Prohibits preferential treatment or quotas. Allows only disparate treatment claims.<br/>Prohibits related retaliation. Makes this Act inapplicable to: (1) religious organizations; and (2) the relationship between the United States and members of the Armed Forces. Declares that this Act does not repeal or modify any federal, state, territorial, or local law creating a special right or preference concerning employment for a veteran.<br/>Provides for the construction of this Act with regard to: (1) enforcement by employers of rules and policies; (2) sexual harassment; (3) certain shared facilities such as showers or dressing facilities; (4) the construction of new or additional facilities; and (5) dress and grooming standards.<br/>Prohibits the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC) from collecting statistics from covered entities on actual or perceived gender identity or compelling the collection by covered entities of such statistics.<br/>Provides for enforcement, including giving the EEOC, the Librarian of Congress, the Attorney General, and U.S. courts the same enforcement powers as they have under specified provisions of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, the Government Employee Rights Act of 1991, and other specified laws.<br/>Allows actions and proceedings against state governments and, subject to limitation, the federal government.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
