<bill session="110" type="h" number="3747" updated="2009-01-09T00:43:01-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1191470400" datetime="2007-10-04"/></status>

	<introduced date="1191470400" datetime="2007-10-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Workforce Investment Improvement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance the workforce investment system of the Nation by strengthening one-stop career centers, providing for more effective governance arrangements, promoting access to a more comprehensive array of employment and training, integrating existing employment and training programs to avoid duplication and overlap, establishing a targeted approach to serving youth, and improving performance accountability, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400267"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400385" joined="2007-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400662" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400224" joined="2007-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400212" joined="2007-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="412235" joined="2007-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2008-06-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400636" joined="2007-10-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1191470400" datetime="2007-10-04"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1193112000" datetime="2007-10-23"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness.</text></action>
		<action date="1193112000" datetime="2007-10-23"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/4/2007--Introduced.<br/>Workforce Investment Improvement Act of 2007 - Amends the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 (WIA) to revise requirements and reauthorize appropriations for: (1) WIA title I, workforce investment systems for job training and employment services; and (2) WIA title II, adult basic skills and family literacy education programs (renamed as the Adult Education, Basic Skills, and Family Literacy Education Act). Revises and reauthorizes workforce investment systems with respect to: (1) state and local planning, allocation, work force investment board membership, and performance accountability; (2) one-stop centers; (3) consolidated funding for adult program activities, including job training, dislocated worker retraining, the employment service system, and reemployment grants; (4) training programs for both out-of-school and in-school youth, including challenge grants; and (5) national job training programs, including the Job Corps and programs for Native Americans, migrant and seasonal farmworkers, and veterans. Exempts religious organizations, with respect to their employment of individuals of a particular religion, from WIA nondiscrimination requirements. Sets forth provisions for the approval of state Workforce Innovation in Regional Economic Development (WIRED) plans for the carrying out of certain workforce development activities. Repeals Wagner-Peyser Act provisions relating to the U.S. Employment Service. Revises requirements and reauthorizes appropriations for: (1) vocational rehabilitation services under the Rehabilitation Act of 1973; and (2) the Helen Keller National Center Act.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
