<bill session="110" type="h" number="3749" updated="2009-01-09T00:43:15-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1191470400" datetime="2007-10-04"/></status>

	<introduced date="1191470400" datetime="2007-10-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Methamphetamine Prevention Enhancement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for the establishment of a Drug-Free Workplace Information Clearinghouse, to authorize programs to prevent and improve treatment of methamphetamine addiction, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400186"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400041" joined="2007-11-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400177" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400160" joined="2008-07-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="412234" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400122" joined="2008-07-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400377" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400437" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400663" joined="2008-07-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400166" joined="2008-07-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400111" joined="2007-11-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2008-07-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400628" joined="2008-07-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="412200" joined="2007-11-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400421" joined="2007-11-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2007-11-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2008-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400062" joined="2008-07-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400100" joined="2007-11-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400639" joined="2007-11-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1191470400" datetime="2007-10-04"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1191470400" datetime="2007-10-04"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/4/2007--Introduced.<br/>Methamphetamine Prevention Enhancement Act of 2007 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration to establish a Drug-Free Workplace Information Clearinghouse.<br/>Requires the Clearinghouse Director to: (1) serve as a resource for employers maintaining or attempting to establish a drug-free workplace policy; (2) provide assistance to employers and employees in resolving complaints, grievances, and requests for information regarding drug-free workplaces and in understanding rights and responsibilities under federal employment laws pertaining to drug-free workplace policies; and (3) conduct an educational campaign for employers on federal drug-free workplace standards or guidelines and on federal assistance available to employers to establish or maintain a drug-free workplace. Requires the Director of the Center for Substance Abuse Treatment to: (1) make grants to medical associations, health care providers, and health care facilities to conduct training for health care providers on recognizing the signs of methamphetamine addiction and recognizing vulnerable populations for purposes of preventing and treating such addiction; (2) conduct an educational campaign on the public health effects of methamphetamine addiction; and (3) make grants to schools, community organizations, and local governmental entities to establish or maintain a methamphetamine awareness project consisting of after-school or extracurricular activities in which students learn about the dangers of methamphetamine through hands-on advertising or video production exercises. 
	</summary>
</bill>
