<bill session="110" type="h" number="376" updated="2009-01-08T17:30:58-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1173121140" datetime="2007-03-05T14:59:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1168405200" datetime="2007-01-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a special resource study to determine the suitability and feasibility of including the battlefields and related sites of the First and Second Battles of Newtonia, Missouri, during the Civil War as part of Wilson's Creek National Battlefield or designating the battlefields and related sites as a separate unit of the National Park System, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400034"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1168405200" datetime="2007-01-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action date="1173120660" datetime="2007-03-05T14:51:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Grijalva moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text></action>
		<action date="1173120720" datetime="2007-03-05T14:52:00-05:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2133-2134"/></action>
		<action date="1173120720" datetime="2007-03-05T14:52:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 376.</text></action>
		<vote date="1173121140" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-03-05T14:59:00-05:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H2133-2134"/></vote>
		<action date="1173157200" datetime="2007-03-06"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1179201600" datetime="2007-05-15"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. With written report No. 110-102.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="232" date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 232.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1213156800" datetime="2008-06-11"><text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S5530"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/26/2007--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the House passed version is repeated here.) Directs the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a special resource study relating to the First and Second Battles of Newtonia (Missouri) during the Civil War, including evaluating the suitability and feasibility of adding the battlefields and related sites as part of Wilson's Creek National Battlefield or designating such battlefields and sites as a unit of the National Park System. Makes the criteria for the study of areas for potential inclusion in the National Park System applicable to such study. Requires the Secretary to submit to specified congressional committees a report containing the results of such study and any conclusions and recommendations of the Secretary. 
	</summary>
</bill>
