<bill session="110" type="h" number="3768" updated="2009-01-09T00:45:29-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1191470400" datetime="2007-10-04"/></status>

	<introduced date="1191470400" datetime="2007-10-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">San Joaquin River Settlement Water Management Goal Implementation Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of the Interior to study and construct all projects and programs that are included in the Friant Water Users Authority document titled &quot;San Joaquin River Restoration Program: Water Management Goal-Recirculation, Recapture of Restoration Flows and Mitigation of Water Supply Reductions&quot;, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400297"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400618" joined="2007-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400330" joined="2007-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="412190" joined="2007-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400065" joined="2007-10-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1191470400" datetime="2007-10-04"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1192075200" datetime="2007-10-11"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/4/2007--Introduced.<br/>San Joaquin River Settlement Water Management Goal Implementation Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior, through the Bureau of Reclamation, to: (1) prepare feasibility studies for the design, planning, and construction of all projects and programs that are included in the Friant Water Users Authority document titled &quot;San Joaquin River Restoration Program: Water Management Goal-Recirculation, Recapture of Restoration Flows and Mitigation of Water Supply Reductions&quot;; and (2) carry out any projects and programs determined to be feasible pursuant to any such completed study.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
