<bill session="110" type="h" number="3776" updated="2009-01-09T00:46:25-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1193082600" datetime="2007-10-22T16:50:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1191902400" datetime="2007-10-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Energy Storage Technology Advancement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Energy Storage Technology Advancement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Energy Storage Technology Advancement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for a research, development, and demonstration program by the Secretary of Energy to support the ability of the United States to remain globally competitive in energy storage systems for vehicles, stationary applications, and electricity transmission and distribution.</title>
		<title type="official" as="amended by house">To provide for research, development, and demonstration programs in advanced energy storage systems for electric drive vehicles, stationary applications, and electricity transmission and distribution applications, to support the ability of the United States to remain globally competitive in this field, and to promote the efficient delivery and use of energy.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400155"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1191902400" datetime="2007-10-09"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Science and Technology.</text></action>
		<action date="1191902400" datetime="2007-10-09"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text></action>
		<action date="1191988800" datetime="2007-10-10"><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1191988800" datetime="2007-10-10"><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text></action>
		<action date="1192507200" datetime="2007-10-16"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1192507200" datetime="2007-10-16" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1193081700" datetime="2007-10-22T16:35:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science and Technology. H. Rept. 110-402.</text></action>
		<calendar number="256" date="1193081700" datetime="2007-10-22T16:35:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 256.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1193082180" datetime="2007-10-22T16:43:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Gordon moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1193082240" datetime="2007-10-22T16:44:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H11814-11816"/></action>
		<action date="1193082240" datetime="2007-10-22T16:44:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3776.</text></action>
		<vote date="1193082600" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-10-22T16:50:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H11814-11815"/></vote>
		<action date="1193082600" datetime="2007-10-22T16:50:00-04:00"><text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action date="1193112000" datetime="2007-10-23"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1210046400" datetime="2008-05-06"><text>Hearing Held by Subcommittee by Energy and Environment Prior to Introduction and Referral (October 3, 2007).</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/22/2007--Passed House amended. Energy Storage Technology Advancement Act of 2007 - (Sec. 3) Directs the Secretary of Energy to: (1) conduct programs of basic and applied research to support the development of energy storage systems for electric drive vehicles, stationary applications, and electricity transmission and distribution; and (2) award funds to, and coordinate activities with, stakeholders in the public, private, and academic sectors. Authorizes appropriations for FY2009-FY2014. (Sec. 5) Directs the Secretary to implement a program of new regionally diversified demonstrations of advanced energy storage systems to expand upon the existing technology demonstration program of the Department of Energy (DOE). Urges such demonstrations to include the participation of a range of stakeholders, such as rural electric cooperatives, investor owned utilities, municipally owned electric utilities, energy storage systems manufacturers, electric drive vehicle manufacturers, the renewable energy production industry, state or local energy offices, the fuel cell industry, and universities. Authorizes appropriations for FY2009-FY2014. (Sec. 6) Directs the Secretary to implement a demonstration program of electric drive vehicle energy storage technology, including integration of such systems on a prototype vehicular platform with drivetrain systems for passenger, commercial, and nonroad electric drive vehicles. Requires such demonstrations to be conducted through consortia, which may include the same range of stakeholders suggested for the advanced energy storage systems demonstration program. Authorizes appropriations for FY2009-FY2014. (Sec. 7) Instructs the Secretary to carry out a program of research, development, and demonstration of: (1) secondary applications of energy storage devices following service in electric drive vehicles; and (2) technologies and processes for final recycling and disposal of these devices. Authorizes appropriations for FY2009-FY2014. (Sec. 8) Requires the Secretary to carry out the programs under this Act in compliance with the requirements of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (EPACT 2005) for cost sharing and impartial review of the scientific and technical merit of award proposals. 
	</summary>
</bill>
