<bill session="110" type="h" number="378" updated="2009-01-08T17:31:11-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1168405200" datetime="2007-01-10"/></status>

	<introduced date="1168405200" datetime="2007-01-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Nurse and Patient Safety &amp; Protection Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Labor to issue an occupational safety and health standard to reduce injuries to patients, direct-care registered nurses, and other health care providers by establishing a safe patient handling standard.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400080"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412232" joined="2008-06-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1168405200" datetime="2007-01-10"><text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1168405200" datetime="2007-01-10"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1168405200" datetime="2007-01-10"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1170392400" datetime="2007-02-02"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1178683200" datetime="2007-05-09"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/10/2007--Introduced.<br/>Nurse and Patient Safety &amp;amp; Protection Act of 2007 - Requires the Secretary of Labor, acting through the Director of Occupational Safety and Health Administration, to establish a Federal Safe Patient Handling Standard to prevent musculoskeletal disorders for direct-care registered nurses and other health care providers working in health care facilities by requiring the elimination of manual lifting of patients through the use of mechanical devices, except during a declared state of emergency. Requires health care facilities to: (1) develop and implement a safe patient handling plan consistent with such standard; and (2) post a uniform notice that explains the standard and the procedures to report patient handling-related injuries. Requires the Secretary to direct the Occupational Safety and Health Administration to conduct audits of plan implementation and compliance. Authorizes health care providers to: (1) refuse to accept an assignment in a health care facility if the assignment would violate the standard or if such provider is not prepared to fulfill the assignment without compromising the patient safety or jeopardizing the provider's license; and (2) file complaints against facilities that violate this Act. Requires the Secretary to investigate complaints and to prohibit retaliation if violations occur. Prohibits health care facilities from retaliating with respect to employment against providers for such refusal or against any individual who in good faith reports a violation, participates in an investigation or proceeding, or discusses violations. Authorizes health care providers who have been retaliated against in violation of this Act to bring a cause of action in a U.S. district court. Entitles providers that prevail to reinstatement, reimbursement of lost compensation, attorneys' fees, court costs, and/or other damages. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a grant program for purchasing safe patient handling equipment for health care facilities.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
