<bill session="110" type="h" number="3795" updated="2009-01-09T00:48:43-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1191988800" datetime="2007-10-10"/></status>

	<introduced date="1191988800" datetime="2007-10-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">You Were There, You Get Care Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide that veterans of service in the 1991 Persian Gulf War and subsequent conflicts shall be considered to be radiation-exposed veterans for purposes of the service-connection of certain diseases and disabilities, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400133"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1191988800" datetime="2007-10-10"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2120)</text></action>
		<action date="1191988800" datetime="2007-10-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1192420800" datetime="2007-10-15"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1213243200" datetime="2008-06-12"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/10/2007--Introduced.<br/>You Were There, You Get Care Act of 2007 - Presumes specified diseases, and any other disease found by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to result from exposure to depleted uranium or the byproducts of the burn-off that occurs when a depleted uranium munition penetrates a target, among those diseases that will be presumed to be service-connected (and therefore compensable) when appearing in radiation-exposed veterans. Includes, for purposes of such coverage, service during the Persian Gulf War or any subsequent conflict in which depleted uranium munitions are used. Directs the Secretary to provide for an independent medical study to determine other diseases that may result from exposure to depleted uranium. Requires study results to be submitted to the congressional veterans' committees.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
