<bill session="110" type="h" number="3796" updated="2009-01-09T00:48:50-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1192680000" datetime="2007-10-18" /></status>

	<introduced date="1191988800" datetime="2007-10-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Early Warning and Health Care for Workers Affected by Globalization Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Early Warning and Health Care for Workers Affected by Globalization Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act to minimize the adverse effects of employment dislocation, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400278"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400031" joined="2007-10-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400227" joined="2007-10-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400257" joined="2007-10-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-10-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400355" joined="2007-10-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400216" joined="2007-10-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2007-10-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="412204" joined="2007-10-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400211" joined="2007-10-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="412200" joined="2007-10-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2007-10-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="412212" joined="2007-10-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="412219" joined="2007-10-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1191988800" datetime="2007-10-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1192680000" datetime="2007-10-18"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1192680000" datetime="2007-10-18" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 26 - 18.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1193343480" datetime="2007-10-25T17:18:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Education and Labor. H. Rept. 110-410.</text></action>
		<calendar number="258" date="1193343540" datetime="2007-10-25T17:19:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 258.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/25/2007--Reported to House amended. Early Warning and Health Care for Workers Affected by Globalization Act - Amends the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act (the Act) to redefine the terms &quot;employer,&quot; &quot;plant closing,&quot; &quot;mass layoff&quot;, and &quot;employees&quot; for purposes of the Act. Requires an employer to: (1) give 90-day written notice (under current law, 60-day) to employees (including part-time employees) and appropriate state and local governments before ordering a plant closing or mass layoff; (2) notify the Secretary of Labor (Secretary) of such closing or layoff; and (3) provide affected employees with information regarding benefits and services available to them, including unemployment compensation, trade adjustment assistance, COBRA benefits, and certain other services. Requires the Secretary to notify the appropriate U.S. Senators and Members of the House of Representatives who represent the area where such closing or mass layoff is to occur. Makes an employer who violates such notice requirements liable to the employee for, among other things, two days pay (under current law, back pay for each day of violation) multiplied by the number of days short of the required 90 day notice that was not given, including interest on such pay. Authorizes an affected employee to file a complaint against the employer individually and/or with the Secretary alleging a violation of the notice requirements. Requires the Secretary to investigate and attempt to resolve complaints of violations committed by an employer. Authorizes the Secretary to bring an action in court to recover on behalf of an affected employee any backpay, interest, benefits, and liquidated damages due to the employee. Requires an employer to post conspicuously upon its premises pertinent provisions of this Act and information on the filing of a complaint. Sets forth a civil penalty for willful violation of such requirement. Provides that the rights and remedies provided in this Act can't be waived. Requires the Secretary to maintain a guide on the benefits and services available to affected employees. Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to extend COBRA continuation coverage for certain qualified Trade Adjustment Assistance (TAA) eligible employees. 
	</summary>
</bill>
