<bill session="110" type="h" number="3806" updated="2009-01-09T00:49:59-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1191988800" datetime="2007-10-10"/></status>

	<introduced date="1191988800" datetime="2007-10-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Supporting Prosecutions of International Espionage Schemes Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, with respect to certain crimes affecting national security, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400137"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400381" joined="2007-10-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400144" joined="2007-10-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400076" joined="2007-10-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400141" joined="2007-10-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400435" joined="2007-10-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1191988800" datetime="2007-10-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1193976000" datetime="2007-11-02"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/10/2007--Introduced.<br/>Supporting Prosecutions of International Espionage Schemes Act of 2007 - Amends the federal criminal code to: (1) revise criminal prohibitions against unauthorized gathering and disclosure of national defense information and recklessly losing such information; (2) increase maximum prison terms for the crimes of misprision of treason, rebellion, and thefts of classified information and financial records by computer; (3) impose a fine and/or prison term of up to 30 years for damaging or impeding the operation of a nuclear facility or attempting or conspiring to do so; and (4) impose a fine and/or prison term of up to 20 years for violations of certain export control requirements.<br/>Directs the Attorney General to: (1) notify appropriate officials at the Departments of Homeland Security (DHS), State, and Commerce of any indictments, convictions, or dispositions of any criminal investigations under the Arms Export Control Act or the Export Administration Act; (2) develop an Internet import and export control database; and (3) provide technical assistance to investigators and prosecutors to improve and increase enforcement and prosecution of export control laws. 
	</summary>
</bill>
