<bill session="110" type="h" number="3814" updated="2009-01-09T00:50:55-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1191988800" datetime="2007-10-10"/></status>

	<introduced date="1191988800" datetime="2007-10-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Nuclear Gold Standard Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for a &quot;gold standard&quot; for the security of nuclear materials worldwide, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400289"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1191988800" datetime="2007-10-10"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1191988800" datetime="2007-10-10"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1191988800" datetime="2007-10-10"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/10/2007--Introduced.<br/>Nuclear Gold Standard Act of 2008 - Directs the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of State, and the Secretary of Defense to develop a framework for a global alliance against nuclear terrorism that would incorporate the &quot;gold standard&quot; developed under this Act for the security of nuclear materials. Directs the Secretary of Energy to work with: (1) the Secretary's Russian counterpart to develop a formal set of verifiable and enforceable standards to which all U.S. and Russian nuclear materials shall be secured and against which inspectors can test (&quot;gold standard&quot;); and (2) the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) to extend such standards to all other countries with nuclear materials. Directs the Secretary of Energy and the Secretary of State to: (1) separately and jointly, provide assistance to other countries to implement the measures required by U.N. Security Council Resolution 1540; and (2) jointly develop a set of incentives as part of such assistance. Authorizes, subject to specified conditions, appropriations for: (1) specified Department of Energy and Department of Defense (DOD) nuclear materials safety and weapons reduction programs; and (2) securing nuclear materials in Russia.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
