<bill session="110" type="h" number="3815" updated="2009-01-09T00:51:02-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1217457840" datetime="2008-07-30T19:44:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1191988800" datetime="2007-10-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Homeland Security Open Source Information Enhancement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Homeland Security Open Source Information Enhancement Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Homeland Security Open Source Information Enhancement Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Homeland Security Open Source Information Enhancement Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Secretary of Homeland Security to make full and efficient use of open source information to develop and disseminate open source homeland security information products, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412192"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2008-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="412221" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400336" joined="2007-10-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="412234" joined="2007-10-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400246" joined="2007-10-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400379" joined="2007-10-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="2007-10-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400402" joined="2007-10-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="412253" joined="2008-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400166" joined="2007-10-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400617" joined="2007-10-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400109" joined="2007-11-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2007-10-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1191988800" datetime="2007-10-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text></action>
		<action date="1192161600" datetime="2007-10-12"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Intelligence, Information Sharing, and Terrorism Risk Assessment.</text></action>
		<action date="1213156800" datetime="2008-06-11"><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1213156800" datetime="2008-06-11"><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Unanimous Consent .</text></action>
		<action date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1216698600" datetime="2008-07-21T12:50:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 110-763.</text></action>
		<calendar number="486" date="1216698600" datetime="2008-07-21T12:50:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 486.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1217348940" datetime="2008-07-29T13:29:00-04:00"><text>Ms. Harman moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1217348940" datetime="2008-07-29T13:29:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H7189-7191"/></action>
		<action date="1217348940" datetime="2008-07-29T13:29:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3815.</text></action>
		<action date="1217349360" datetime="2008-07-29T13:36:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Bilirakis objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text></action>
		<action date="1217457840" datetime="2008-07-30T19:44:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H7596"/></action>
		<vote date="1217457840" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-07-30T19:44:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote. (text: CR 7/29/2008 H7189-7190)</text></vote>
		<action date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1222142400" datetime="2008-09-23" ><text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1222228800" datetime="2008-09-24"><text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="1051" date="1222228800" datetime="2008-09-24" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1051.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/24/2008--Reported to Senate amended. Homeland Security Open Source Information Enhancement Act of 2008 - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Secretary of Homeland Security, in coordination with the Assistant Deputy Director of National Intelligence for Open Source and the Director of National Intelligence, to establish an open source collection, analysis, and dissemination program within the Office of Intelligence and Analysis. Defines &quot;open source information&quot; to mean publicly available information that can be lawfully obtained by a member of the public by request, purchase, or observation. Requires the program to make full and efficient use of open source information to develop and disseminate open source alerts, warnings, and other intelligence products relating to the mission of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS).<br/>Requires the Secretary to: (1) ensure that DHS makes full and efficient use of such information in intelligence analysis to identify terrorist threats; and (2) make DHS open source information available to federal, state, local, tribal, and private-sector entities, using systems and networks for the dissemination of homeland security information. Directs: (1) the Secretary to ensure that the manner in which open source information is gathered and disseminated complies with all relevant federal laws; and (2) the Chief Privacy Officer of DHS to include in such Officer's annual report submitted to Congress an assessment of compliance by federal departments and agencies with laws relating to the use of open source information.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
