<bill session="110" type="h" number="3827" updated="2009-01-09T00:52:26-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1192420800" datetime="2007-10-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1192420800" datetime="2007-10-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Active Duty Military Tax Relief Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide tax relief to active duty military personnel and employers who assist them, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412231"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400087" joined="2007-10-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2007-10-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1192420800" datetime="2007-10-15"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/15/2007--Introduced.<br/>Active Duty Military Tax Relief Act of 2007 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) allow certain small business owners (businesses having 100 or fewer employees) and self-employed individuals a tax credit for wages paid to members of the Ready Reserve of the Armed Forces and to temporary replacement employees for such members while on active military duty; (2) treat differential wage payments made to members of the Ready Reserve as earned income for tax withholding and retirement plan purposes; (3) allow the rollover of military death gratuities to individual retirement accounts, health savings accounts, Archer medical savings accounts, and education savings accounts; (4) increase the standard tax deduction by $1,000 in 2007 and 2008 for members of the uniformed services on active duty for more than 30 days; and (5) make permanent the taxpayer election to treat combat pay as earned income for purposes of computing the earned income tax credit and tax-free retirement plan distributions to individuals called to active duty. 
	</summary>
</bill>
