<bill session="110" type="h" number="3845" updated="2009-01-09T00:54:30-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1195061040" datetime="2007-11-14T13:24:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="1091"/></status>

	<introduced date="1192507200" datetime="2007-10-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">PROTECT Our Children Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Providing Resources, Officers, and Technology to Eradicate Cyber Threats to Our Children Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">PROTECT Our Children Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Providing Resources, Officers, and Technology to Eradicate Cyber Threats to Our Children Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a Special Counsel for Child Exploitation Prevention and Interdiction within the Office of the Deputy Attorney General, to improve the Internet Crimes Against Children Task Force, to increase resources for regional computer forensic labs, and to make other improvements to increase the ability of law enforcement agencies to investigate and prosecute child predators.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400623"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400041" joined="2007-10-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400031" joined="2007-10-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="412229" joined="2007-10-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-10-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400177" joined="2007-10-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400289" joined="2007-10-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400282" joined="2007-10-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="412224" joined="2007-10-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="412225" joined="2007-10-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400302" joined="2007-10-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400361" joined="2007-10-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400018" joined="2007-10-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400116" joined="2007-10-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400323" joined="2007-10-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="412189" joined="2007-10-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="2007-10-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400101" joined="2007-10-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400396" joined="2007-10-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400030" joined="2007-10-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="412198" joined="2007-10-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="412188" joined="2007-10-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400007" joined="2007-10-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400147" joined="2007-11-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400631" joined="2007-10-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="412240" joined="2007-10-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400195" joined="2007-10-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400255" joined="2007-10-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400120" joined="2007-10-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400299" joined="2007-10-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400118" joined="2007-10-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400415" joined="2007-10-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="412228" joined="2007-10-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400240" joined="2007-10-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400024" joined="2007-10-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400654" joined="2007-10-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="412206" joined="2007-10-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400349" joined="2007-10-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="412233" joined="2007-10-16"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1192507200" datetime="2007-10-16"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1193976000" datetime="2007-11-02"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text></action>
		<action date="1194984540" datetime="2007-11-13T16:09:00-05:00"><text>Ms. Wasserman Schultz moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1194984600" datetime="2007-11-13T16:10:00-05:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H13582-13589"/></action>
		<action date="1194984600" datetime="2007-11-13T16:10:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3845.</text></action>
		<action date="1194986100" datetime="2007-11-13T16:35:00-05:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1195060620" datetime="2007-11-14T13:17:00-05:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H13884-13885"/></action>
		<vote date="1195061040" how="roll" roll="1091" datetime="2007-11-14T13:24:00-05:00" where="h" type="vote" suspension="1" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 415 - 2 (Roll no. 1091). (text: CR 11/13/007 H13582-13585)</text></vote>
		<action date="1195102800" datetime="2007-11-15"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/14/2007--Passed House amended. Providing Resources, Officers, and Technology to Eradicate Cyber Threats to Our Children Act of 2007 or the PROTECT Our Children Act of 2007 - Title I: Special Counsel For Child Exploitation Prevention And Interdiction - (Sec. 101) Directs the Attorney General to appoint a Special Counsel for Child Exploitation Prevention and Interdiction within the Office of the Deputy Attorney General. Sets forth the duties of the Special Counsel, including: (1) coordination of the policies and strategies of the Department of Justice (DOJ) related to the prevention and investigation of child exploitation cases; (2) coordination with other federal agencies, including the Bureau of Immigration and Customs Enforcement, to combat child exploitation crimes; (3) coordination and oversight of the National Internet Crimes Against Children Task Force Program and the National Internet Crimes Against Children Data Network Center established by this Act; (4) providing training and technical assistance for law enforcement agencies to combat child exploitation crimes; and (5) developing and overseeing research programs for child exploitation prevention. (Sec. 102) Establishes with DOJ a National Internet Crimes Against Children (ICAC)Task Force Program consisting of state and local task forces (including at least one ICAC Task Force for each state) to address online enticement of children, child exploitation, and child obscenity and pornography cases. (Sec. 103) Sets forth the purposes of the Program, including: (1) increasing the investigative capabilities of state and local law enforcement officers in the detection, investigation, and apprehension of child exploitation crimes facilitated by the Internet; (2) providing training and technical assistance to ICAC task forces and other federal, state, and local law enforcement agencies; (3) increasing the number of Internet crimes against children offenses to be investigated and prosecuted; (4) enhancing nationwide response to Internet crimes against children offenses; and (5) developing and delivering Internet crimes against children public awareness and prevention programs. (Sec. 104) Sets forth the duties and functions of state and local ICAC task forces relating to investigations, forensic examinations, and prosecutions of Internet crimes against children, (Sec. 105) Directs the Attorney General to establish a National Internet Crimes Against Children Data Network Center to assist the National ICAC Task Force Program and federal, state, local, and tribal agencies investigating and prosecuting child exploitation. Requires the Center to develop and maintain an technology and training program to provide: (1) a secure system of online communications between ICAC task forces and federal, state, and local law enforcement agencies regarding ongoing investigations; (2) a secure online system for resolving case conflicts; (3) a secure data storage and analysis system; and (4) guidelines and technical assistance for the use of the Center by federal, state, and local law enforcement agencies.<br/>Directs the Attorney General to establish an ICAC Data Network Center Steering Committee. Authorizes appropriations for FY2009-FY2016.<br/>(Sec. 106) Authorizes the Office of Justice Programs to award grants to state and local ICAC task forces. Sets forth criteria for the distribution of ICAC grants funds.<br/>Requires state or local ICAC task forces receiving grants to submit annual reports to the Attorney General on the operations of such task forces.<br/>Requires the Attorney General to report to Congress on: (1) the progress of ICAC task forces; and (2) the number of federal and state investigations, prosecutions, and convictions in the prior 12-month period related to child exploitation. (Sec. 107) Authorizes appropriations for FY2009-FY2016.<br/>Title II: Additional Measures to Combat Child Exploitation - (Sec. 201) Requires the Attorney General to: (1) establish additional computer forensic capacity to address the current backlog for computer forensics, including for child exploitation investigations; and (2) report to Congress annually on the use of funds for such purpose. Authorizes appropriations for FY2009-FY2016. (Sec. 202) Authorizes appropriations for FY2009-FY2016 for the hiring of additional Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) agents and personnel to work solely on child exploitation cases as part of the FBI's Innocent Images National Initiative. (Sec. 203) Authorizes appropriations for FY2009-FY2006 for the hiring of additional full-time personnel in the Bureau of Immigration and Customs Enforcement and the U.S. Postal Service to work solely on child exploitation and child obscenity cases. (Sec. 205) Requires the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Postmaster General, to report annually to the House and Senate Judiciary Committees on the resources used by federal agencies to investigate and prosecute child exploitation and child obscenity cases.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
