<bill session="110" type="h" number="3844" updated="2009-01-09T00:54:23-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1192507200" datetime="2007-10-16"/></status>

	<introduced date="1192507200" datetime="2007-10-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Eradication of Slavery in Sudan Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the United States Commission to Monitor Slavery and its Eradication in Sudan.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400380"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400280" joined="2008-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2008-07-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400385" joined="2007-10-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400423" joined="2007-10-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400640" joined="2007-10-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="2007-10-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="412232" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400284" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400141" joined="2007-10-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400394" joined="2007-10-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400435" joined="2007-10-16"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1192507200" datetime="2007-10-16"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/16/2007--Introduced.<br/>Eradication of Slavery in Sudan Act of 2007 - Establishes the United States Commission to Monitor Slavery and its Eradication in Sudan, which shall have as its primary responsibility: (1) reporting on progress made by the government of Sudan and nongovernmental organizations in identifying the location of slaves in Sudan and ensuring their freedom; (2) working with the government of Sudan to ensure safe passage of freed slaves and family reunification; (3) documenting existing cases of slavery and working to prevent new cases from occurring; (4) ensuring that former slaves have access to basic education and skill training, as well as medical, social, and psychological support needed for their rehabilitation and reintegration into society; (5) ensuring that those individuals responsible for slavery are brought to justice; and (6) recommending U.S. government actions in response to the Sudanese government's inaction to eradicate slavery. Terminates the Commission six years after the initial appointment of all of the members. 
	</summary>
</bill>
