<bill session="110" type="h" number="3851" updated="2009-01-09T00:55:21-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1192507200" datetime="2007-10-16"/></status>

	<introduced date="1192507200" datetime="2007-10-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Non-Citizen Enforcement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend various laws imposing criminal penalties to double the maximum penalty for illegal aliens who commit those crimes, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400068"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400367" joined="2007-11-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400441" joined="2007-10-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="2007-12-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400288" joined="2007-10-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400570" joined="2007-11-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400421" joined="2007-10-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400654" joined="2007-10-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400157" joined="2007-12-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1192507200" datetime="2007-10-16"><text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Homeland Security, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1192507200" datetime="2007-10-16"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1192507200" datetime="2007-10-16"><text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text></action>
		<action date="1192507200" datetime="2007-10-16"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1193976000" datetime="2007-11-02"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text></action>
		<action date="1193976000" datetime="2007-11-02"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text></action>
		<action date="1201755600" datetime="2008-01-31"><committee name="House Homeland Security"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border, Maritime, and Global Counterterrorism.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/16/2007--Introduced.<br/>Non-Citizen Enforcement Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to increase the number of Border Patrol agents by at least 2,000 in each post-FY2010 fiscal year year until effective control of the border has been achieved through the Secure Border Initiative. Empowers state or local officers and employees to arrest an alien unlawfully present in the United States who has been ordered removed in abstentia. Provides for such aliens' listing on the absconder category of the national criminal information center database. Increases funding for the state criminal alien assistance program (SCAAP). Subject an individual unlawfully present in the United States to criminal penalties. Increases penalties for firearms possession and controlled substance distribution violations by aliens unlawfully present in the United States. Provides a 20-year maximum penalty for smuggling into the United States an alien previously deported on criminal conviction grounds.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
