<bill session="110" type="h" number="3857" updated="2009-01-09T00:56:03-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1192507200" datetime="2007-10-16"/></status>

	<introduced date="1192507200" datetime="2007-10-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish requirements for the consideration of supplemental appropriation bills.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400441"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400659" joined="2007-10-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400060" joined="2007-10-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400626" joined="2007-10-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400151" joined="2007-10-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400662" joined="2007-10-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400433" joined="2007-10-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400288" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400642" joined="2007-10-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400224" joined="2007-10-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400287" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400320" joined="2007-10-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400175" joined="2007-10-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400368" joined="2007-10-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400153" joined="2007-10-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400643" joined="2007-10-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="412201" joined="2007-10-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400617" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400221" joined="2007-10-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="412213" joined="2007-10-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400315" joined="2007-10-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="412011" joined="2007-10-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="412202" joined="2007-10-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400252" joined="2007-10-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1192507200" datetime="2007-10-16"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/16/2007--Introduced.<br/>Makes it out of order in the House of Representatives or the Senate to consider any measure making supplemental appropriations for two or more unrelated emergencies. Prohibits any provisions containing spending that is not designated as emergency spending from being reported in a measure making supplemental appropriations. Makes it out of order in the House or the Senate to consider: (1) the conference report on a measure making supplemental appropriations if such measure contains such spending; or (2) any bill, joint resolution, or conference report if the accompanying report or joint statement of managers does not comply with this Act. Requires the Committee on Appropriations or any other House or Senate committee that reports any bill or joint resolution that provides budget authority for any emergency, the accompanying report, or the joint explanatory statement accompanying the conference report on the measure to: (1) identify all provisions that provide budget authority and the resulting outlays for such emergency; (2) state the reasons why such budget authority meets the definition of an emergency; and (3) justify why such funding is in a supplemental appropriation and not the regular appropriation for the next fiscal year. Prohibits a provision containing an earmark from being reported in a measure making supplemental appropriations. Makes it out of order in the House or the Senate to consider the conference report on any measure making supplemental appropriations containing earmarks. 
	</summary>
</bill>
