<bill session="110" type="h" number="3892" updated="2009-01-09T01:00:19-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1192680000" datetime="2007-10-18"/></status>

	<introduced date="1192680000" datetime="2007-10-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Labor-Management Partnership Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Federal Labor-Management Partnership Council.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400093"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2007-12-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400227" joined="2007-10-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400080" joined="2008-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400295" joined="2007-10-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400379" joined="2008-06-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400152" joined="2008-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400355" joined="2008-04-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="412208" joined="2007-10-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400249" joined="2007-10-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400437" joined="2008-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400402" joined="2007-11-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400259" joined="2008-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="2008-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400415" joined="2008-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412212" joined="2007-10-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400201" joined="2007-10-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400641" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="2007-10-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400310" joined="2008-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400090" joined="2007-10-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="2007-10-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1192680000" datetime="2007-10-18"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2174-2175)</text></action>
		<action date="1192680000" datetime="2007-10-18"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text></action>
		<action date="1193284800" datetime="2007-10-25"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/18/2007--Introduced.<br/>Federal Labor-Management Partnership Act of 2007 - Establishes the Federal Labor-Management Partnership Council to advise the President on matters involving labor-management relations in the executive branch. Includes among the Council's activities: (1) supporting the creation of local labor-management partnership councils that promote partnership efforts; (2) collecting and disseminating information about and providing guidance on such efforts; (3) using the expertise of individuals, inside and outside the federal government, to foster partnership arrangements in the executive branch; and (4) proposing statutory changes to improve the civil service to better serve the public and carry out the mission of the various agencies.<br/>Requires the President to designate a Council Chairperson.<br/>Requires the President to direct the head of each agency which is subject to labor-management relations provisions or any other authority permitting employees to select an exclusive representative, to: (1) create labor-management partnerships by forming labor-management committees or councils at appropriate levels or adapting existing committees or councils if such groups exist; (2) involve employees and their representatives as full partners with management representatives to improve the civil service to better serve the public and carry out the mission of the agency; (3) provide systemic training of appropriate employees in consensual methods of dispute resolution; (4) negotiate, at the request of the labor organization, on specified subjects and instruct subordinate officials to do the same; and (5) evaluate progress and improvements in organizational performance resulting from such labor-management partnerships.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
