<bill session="110" type="h" number="3903" updated="2009-01-09T01:01:33-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1192680000" datetime="2007-10-18"/></status>

	<introduced date="1192680000" datetime="2007-10-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Kids' Toys Safety Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Consumer Product Safety Act to require the development of a multi-stage product testing process to ensure compliance of children's products with consumer product safety standards, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400255"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400177" joined="2007-10-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400155" joined="2007-10-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400030" joined="2008-01-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="412205" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400631" joined="2007-10-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2007-11-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1192680000" datetime="2007-10-18"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1193025600" datetime="2007-10-22"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/18/2007--Introduced.<br/>Kids' Toys Safety Act - Amends the Consumer Product Safety Act to require the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) to prescribe a comprehensive testing program for articles intended for children under five. Requires the CPSC, after receiving notice of a voluntary recall by a manufacturer or retailer, to post notice on the CPSC's website and notify the health department of each state. Requires the manufacturer of a product for children under five to label the product or its packaging to enable the purchaser to determine production information. Requires the CPSC to establish a database as a clearinghouse for information regarding factories, warehouses, or other facilities where consumer products which have been subject to a recall were manufactured.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
