<bill session="110" type="h" number="3912" updated="2009-01-09T01:02:35-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1193112000" datetime="2007-10-23" /></status>

	<introduced date="1193025600" datetime="2007-10-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Naval Vessel Transfer Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the transfer of naval vessels to certain foreign recipients.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400231"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400344" joined="2007-10-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1193025600" datetime="2007-10-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1193112000" datetime="2007-10-23"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1193112000" datetime="2007-10-23" ><text>Committee Agreed to Seek Consideration Under Suspension of the Rules, by Unanimous Consent.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/22/2007--Introduced.<br/>Naval Vessels Transfer Act of 2007 - Authorizes the President to transfer on a grant basis to: (1) Turkey, the OLIVER HAZARD PERRY class guided missile frigates GEORGE PHILIP and SIDES; and (2) Lithuania, the OSPREY class minehunter coastal ships CORMORANT and KINGFISHER. Authorizes the President to transfer on a sale basis to: (1) Taiwan, the OSPREY class minehunter coastal ships ORIOLE and FALCON; and (2) Turkey, the OSPREY class minehunter coastal ship SHRIKE. States that: (1) the value of such vessels transferred on a grant basis shall not be counted against the aggregate value of excess defense articles transferred to countries in any fiscal year under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961; (2) transfer costs shall be charged to the recipient; and (3) to the maximum extent practicable, the country to which a vessel is transferred shall have necessary vessel repair and refurbishment carried out at U.S. shipyards (including U.S. Navy shipyards). Terminates transfer authority two years after enactment of this Act.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
