<bill session="110" type="h" number="3937" updated="2009-01-09T01:05:33-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1193112000" datetime="2007-10-23"/></status>

	<introduced date="1193112000" datetime="2007-10-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Food Import Safety Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to ensure the safety of imported food.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400103"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400111" joined="2007-11-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1193112000" datetime="2007-10-23"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1193198400" datetime="2007-10-24"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/23/2007--Introduced.<br/>Food Import Safety Act of 2007 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (FFDCA) to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to prohibit the importation of food from a particular country if there is a pattern of FFDCA violations.<br/>Requires the Secretary to establish a certification program to ensure that imported food meets U.S. food safety standards. Prohibits food from being imported unless there are facility and country certifications in effect.<br/>Directs the Commissioner of Food and Drugs and other appropriate federal agencies to work with foreign countries that are major U.S. trading partners to establish certification programs.<br/>Authorizes the Secretary to provide technical assistance to assist small businesses in developing countries in complying with this Act.<br/>Requires a person that has reason to believe that any food introduced into interstate commerce may be in violation of the FFDCA to immediately notify the Secretary of the identity and location of the food.<br/>Requires the Secretary, upon a determination that such food is in violation of the FFDCA and that there is a reasonable probability that the food, if consumed, would present a threat to the public health, to give appropriate persons an opportunity to: (1) cease distribution of the food; (2) notify all relevant persons to cease distribution of the food; (3) recall the food; and (4) provide notice to consumers and public health officials. Authorizes the Secretary to control and possess the food and to order the person to immediately cease distribution of the food if the person refuses or does not adequately carry out such actions. 
	</summary>
</bill>
