<bill session="110" type="h" number="393" updated="2009-01-08T17:33:24-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1168405200" datetime="2007-01-10"/></status>

	<introduced date="1168405200" datetime="2007-01-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="popular" as="">Draft Reinstatement bill</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Universal National Service Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require all persons in the United States between the ages of 18 and 42 to perform national service, either as a member of the uniformed services or in civilian service in furtherance of the national defense and homeland security, to authorize the induction of persons in the uniformed services during wartime to meet end-strength requirements of the uniformed services, to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to make permanent the favorable treatment afforded combat pay under the earned income tax credit, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400333"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412221" joined="2007-03-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="2007-03-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1168405200" datetime="2007-01-10"><text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1168405200" datetime="2007-01-10"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1168405200" datetime="2007-01-10"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1172466000" datetime="2007-02-26"><committee name="House Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/10/2007--Introduced.<br/>Universal National Service Act of 2007 - Declares that it is the obligation of every U.S. citizen, and every other person residing in the United States, between the ages of 18 and 42 to perform a two-year period of national service, unless exempted, either as a member of an active or reserve component of the armed forces or in a civilian capacity that promotes national defense. Requires induction into national service by the President. Allows persons to be inducted only: (1) under a declaration of war or national emergency; or (2) when members of the Armed Forces are engaged in a contingency operation. Requires each person, before induction, to be examined physically and mentally for classification for fitness to perform. Sets forth provisions governing: (1) induction deferments, postponements, and exemptions, including exemption of a conscientious objector from military service that includes combatant training; and (2) discharge following national service. Amends the Military Selective Service Act to authorize the military registration of females. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to permit combat pay otherwise excluded from gross income to be treated as earned income for purposes of the earned income tax credit.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
