<bill session="110" type="h" number="394" updated="2009-01-08T17:33:37-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1168405200" datetime="2007-01-10"/></status>

	<introduced date="1168405200" datetime="2007-01-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for payment of certain claims against the Government of Iran.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400344"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400122" joined="2007-01-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400049" joined="2007-10-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2007-03-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400071" joined="2007-01-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400241" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400433" joined="2007-01-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400087" joined="2007-01-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400207" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400371" joined="2007-01-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400109" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400016" joined="2007-03-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1168405200" datetime="2007-01-10"><text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1168405200" datetime="2007-01-10"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1168405200" datetime="2007-01-10"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1170392400" datetime="2007-02-02"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/10/2007--Introduced.<br/>States that: (1) it is U.S. policy to seek justice for American victims of terrorism and to hold terrorists and their state-sponsors accountable for their actions; and (2) any provision of the Algiers Accords, entered into with Iran on January 19, 1981, that purports to bar a U.S. citizen from prosecuting any claim in any U.S. court or to limit the jurisdiction of any U.S. court is hereby abrogated and deemed nonapplicable. Directs the the Secretary of the Treasury to begin payments to a common fund to be: (1) established and administered by the certified class representatives for the former American hostages in Iran and their survivors (case number 1:00CV03110 (EGS) of the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia); and (2) funded from the liquidation of blocked Iranian assets and from amounts in the Iran Foreign Military Sales Fund account (Foreign Military Sales Fund). Sets forth fund payment amounts for each former hostage and spouse and child identified as a class member.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
