<bill session="110" type="h" number="3944" updated="2009-01-09T01:06:22-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1193112000" datetime="2007-10-23"/></status>

	<introduced date="1193112000" datetime="2007-10-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Hepatitis B Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish, promote, and support a comprehensive prevention, education, research, and medical management program that will lead to a marked reduction in liver cirrhosis and a reduction in the cases of, and improved survival of, liver cancer caused by chronic hepatitis B infection.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400185"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400290" joined="2008-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400198" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400268" joined="2007-10-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400361" joined="2007-10-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="2007-10-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400384" joined="2008-05-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400245" joined="2008-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400648" joined="2007-10-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400147" joined="2007-10-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400001" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2008-05-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400009" joined="2008-05-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400024" joined="2008-04-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1193112000" datetime="2007-10-23"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1193198400" datetime="2007-10-24"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/23/2007--Introduced.<br/>National Hepatitis B Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to develop a plan for hepatitis B prevention, control, and medical management. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to: (1) support the integration of testing, counseling, immunization, and medical referral activities into existing clinical and public health programs at state, local, and tribal levels; and (2) provide hepatitis B coordinators to health departments in order to ensure the success of such integration. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of CDC, the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA), and the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, to implement programs to increase awareness and enhance knowledge and understanding of hepatitis B. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of CDC, to: (1) support the establishment of a national hepatitis B surveillance program; and (2) report on population-based seroprevalence studies and hepatitis B's economic and clinical impact and its impact on quality of life. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Directors of CDC, the National Cancer Institute, and the National Institutes of Health (NIH), to conduct research on hepatitis B. Requires the Secretary to give priority in carrying out this Act to individuals with limited access to health education, testing, and health care services and groups that may be disproportionately affected by hepatitis B.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
