<bill session="110" type="h" number="3955" updated="2009-01-09T01:07:38-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1193198400" datetime="2007-10-24"/></status>

	<introduced date="1193198400" datetime="2007-10-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Science Museum and National Laboratory Partnership Demonstration Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for educational partnerships between science museums and National Laboratories.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400630"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400222" joined="2007-10-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400413" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400228" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400027" joined="2007-10-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400198" joined="2007-10-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400063" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400361" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400147" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400082" joined="2007-10-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400169" joined="2007-10-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412204" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400125" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400421" joined="2008-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412257" joined="2008-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400097" joined="2007-11-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1193198400" datetime="2007-10-24"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Science and Technology.</text></action>
		<action date="1193716800" datetime="2007-10-30"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/24/2007--Introduced.<br/>Science Museum and National Laboratory Partnership Demonstration Act - Authorizes the award of up to five grants only to partnerships that include science museums, or consortia thereof serving at least 1,000,000 visitors annually and with an existing partnership with one or more national laboratories, for the purposes of : (1) increasing public understanding of scientific work occurring at the national laboratories; (2) developing exhibits and informal education programs featuring advances in the physical sciences; and (3) increasing public understanding of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics disciplines. Disallows such science museums or consortia from receiving more than 60% of a grant award for any fiscal year, with the remaining funds allocated to National Laboratory partners.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
