<bill session="110" type="h" number="395" updated="2009-01-08T17:33:52-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1168405200" datetime="2007-01-10"/></status>

	<introduced date="1168405200" datetime="2007-01-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Cellulosic Ethanol Development and Implementation Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Clean Air Act to require the Secretary of Energy to provide grants to eligible entities to carry out research, development, and demonstration projects of cellulosic ethanol and construct infrastructure that enables retail gas stations to dispense cellulosic ethanol for vehicle fuel to reduce the consumption of petroleum-based fuel.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400620"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400420" joined="2007-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400031" joined="2007-01-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400618" joined="2007-01-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400241" joined="2007-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400254" joined="2007-01-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400264" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="412204" joined="2007-01-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400266" joined="2007-01-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400150" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400363" joined="2007-01-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1168405200" datetime="2007-01-10"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Science and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1168405200" datetime="2007-01-10"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1168405200" datetime="2007-01-10"><text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text></action>
		<action date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"><committee name="House Science and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text></action>
		<action date="1170392400" datetime="2007-02-02"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/10/2007--Introduced.<br/>Cellulosic Ethanol Development and Implementation Act of 2007 - Amends the Clean Air Act to direct the Secretary of Energy to establish: (1) a grants program for eligible entities to implement research, development, and demonstration projects relating to the use of cellulosic ethanol fuel for motor vehicles; and (2) a pilot program to provide grants to eligible entities for use in installing infrastructure (such as pumps) that would enable retail gas stations to sell and dispense ethanol fuel. Requires an eligible entity to provide matching funds in the amount of 20% of the total amount of the grant.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
