<bill session="110" type="h" number="3969" updated="2009-01-09T01:09:15-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1193284800" datetime="2007-10-25"/></status>

	<introduced date="1193284800" datetime="2007-10-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to authorize the President to dispose of excess materials, supplies, and equipment acquired pursuant to that Act to assist victims of major disasters, emergencies, and incidents, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400273"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400158" joined="2008-06-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400345" joined="2007-10-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1193284800" datetime="2007-10-25"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text></action>
		<action date="1193371200" datetime="2007-10-26"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/25/2007--Introduced.<br/>Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to authorize the President to transfer excess materials, supplies, or equipment acquired for response or recovery efforts in connection with a major disaster or emergency to a state, governmental entity, or voluntary organization to assist victims of other major disasters and emergencies or other incidents.<br/>Authorizes the use and disposal of temporary housing for disaster victims in incidents that do not result in a declaration of a major disaster or emergency.<br/>Directs the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to review and revise the factors considered to measure the severity, magnitude, and impact of a disaster to provide more objective criteria for evaluating the need for assistance to individuals and to speed a declaration of a major disaster or emergency.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
