<bill session="110" type="h" number="3981" updated="2009-01-09T01:10:38-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1215554160" datetime="2008-07-08T18:56:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="471"/></status>

	<introduced date="1193630400" datetime="2007-10-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Preserve America and Save America's Treasures Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Preserve America and Save America's Treasures Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Preserve America and Save America's Treasures Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Preserve America Program and Save America's Treasures Program, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400280"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400041" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400327" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400073" joined="2007-12-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400337" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400659" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400289" joined="2007-11-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400155" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2008-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400149" joined="2008-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400137" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400246" joined="2008-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400333" joined="2008-03-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400096" joined="2007-12-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400129" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400443" joined="2007-11-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2008-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412210" joined="2007-10-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400077" joined="2007-10-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400003" joined="2008-03-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400049" joined="2007-10-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400101" joined="2008-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400152" joined="2008-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="2008-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400352" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400006" joined="2008-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400230" joined="2007-10-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412187" joined="2007-11-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412223" joined="2007-12-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400442" joined="2007-11-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400001" joined="2007-11-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400259" joined="2007-10-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400251" joined="2007-10-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400378" joined="2007-10-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400411" joined="2007-10-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400366" joined="2007-12-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412239" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400281" joined="2007-11-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400338" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400266" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400319" joined="2008-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2007-12-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400326" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412228" joined="2008-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400641" joined="2007-10-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400032" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="2007-10-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400215" joined="2007-12-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400238" joined="2007-12-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400345" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400163" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400114" joined="2008-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412194" joined="2008-07-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400425" joined="2008-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400639" joined="2007-12-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1193630400" datetime="2007-10-29"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1194670800" datetime="2007-11-10"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action date="1209009600" datetime="2008-04-24"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1213156800" datetime="2008-06-11"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1213156800" datetime="2008-06-11" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1213156800" datetime="2008-06-11"><text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands Discharged.</text></action>
		<action date="1215537600" datetime="2008-07-08T14:20:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-738.</text></action>
		<calendar number="469" date="1215537600" datetime="2008-07-08T14:20:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 469.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1215538020" datetime="2008-07-08T14:27:00-04:00"><text>Ms. Bordallo moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1215538020" datetime="2008-07-08T14:27:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H6182-6187"/></action>
		<action date="1215538020" datetime="2008-07-08T14:27:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3981.</text></action>
		<action date="1215539460" datetime="2008-07-08T14:51:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1215552720" datetime="2008-07-08T18:32:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H6199"/></action>
		<vote date="1215554160" how="roll" roll="471" datetime="2008-07-08T18:56:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" suspension="1" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 360 - 23 (Roll no. 471).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H6182-6184"/></vote>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="867" date="1215576000" datetime="2008-07-09" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 867.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/8/2008--Passed House amended. Preserve America and Save America's Treasures Act - Title I: Preserve America's Program - (Sec. 103) Establishes the Preserve America Program, under which the Secretary of the Interior, in partnership with the Advisory Council on Historic Preservation, may provide competitive grants to specified entities to support preservation efforts through heritage tourism, education, and historic preservation planning activities. Requires the Secretary to: (1) consult the Council in the preparation of the list of projects that are to be provided grants under the Program; and (2) submit to specified congressional committees a list of any eligible projects that are to be provided grants. Requires the non-federal share for the cost of carrying out a project to be at least 50% of the project's total cost. Requires the non-federal share to be in the form of cash or donated supplies and related services. Instructs the Secretary to ensure that each applicant for a grant has the capacity to secure, and a feasible plan for securing, the non-federal share before a grant is provided. (Sec. 104) Sets forth provisions regarding the designation of communities, tribal areas, and neighborhoods as Preserve America Communities.<br/>Requires the Council to establish an expedited process for Preserve America Community designation for local governments previously certified for historic preservation activities under the National Historic Preservation Act. (Sec. 105) Requires the Secretary to develop any guidelines and issue any regulations that are necessary to carry out this title. (Sec. 106) Authorizes appropriations. Title II: Save America's Treasures Program - (Sec. 203) Establishes the Save America's Treasures Program, under which the Secretary, in consultation with the National Endowment for the Arts, the National Endowment for the Humanities, the Institute of Museum and Library Services, the National Trust for Historic Preservation, the National Conference of State Historic Preservation Officers, the National Association of Tribal Historic Preservation Officers, and the President's Committee on the Arts and the Humanities, shall provide grants to eligible entities for projects to preserve nationally significant collections (collections of intellectual and cultural artifacts, including documents, sculpture, and works of art) and historic properties. Provides for, of the amounts available for such grants, not less than 50% to be available for projects to preserve collections and historic properties, which shall be distributed through a competitive grant process. Requires a collection or historic property to be provided a competitive grant only if such collection or property is: (1) nationally significant; and (2) threatened or endangered. Provides that, a determination regarding the national significance of collections shall be made in consultation with the entities specified above, as appropriate. Requires historic properties, to be eligible for a grant, to be: (1) listed in the National Register of Historic Places at the national level of significance; or (2) designated as a National Historic Landmark. Sets forth grant selection criteria.<br/>Requires the Secretary to: (1) consult with the organizations specified above in the preparation of the list of projects to be provided grants under the Program, and that if such an organization has submitted an application for a grant under the Program, such entity shall be recused from consultation; and (2) submit to specified congressional committees a list of any eligible projects that are to be provided grants.<br/>Requires the non-federal share for the cost of carrying out a project to be at least 50% of the project's total cost. Requires the non-federal share to be in the form of cash or donated supplies and related services. Instructs the Secretary to ensure that each applicant for a grant has the capacity to secure, and a feasible plan for securing, the non-federal share before a grant is provided.<br/>(Sec. 204) Requires the Secretary to develop any guidelines and issue any regulations that are necessary to carry out this title. (Sec. 205) Authorizes appropriations. Title III: General Provisions - (Sec. 301) Bars the use of any of the funds provided pursuant to this Act to study or establish a National Heritage Area or fund a National Heritage Area management entity. 
	</summary>
</bill>
