<bill session="110" type="h" number="3993" updated="2009-01-09T01:12:04-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1193716800" datetime="2007-10-30"/></status>

	<introduced date="1193716800" datetime="2007-10-30"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Military Family Job Protection Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for a prohibition on discrimination in employment against certain family members caring for recovering members of the Armed Forces.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412231"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1193716800" datetime="2007-10-30"><text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, and House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1193716800" datetime="2007-10-30"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1193716800" datetime="2007-10-30"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1193716800" datetime="2007-10-30"><text>Referred to House House Administration</text></action>
		<action date="1200373200" datetime="2008-01-15"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/30/2007--Introduced.<br/>Military Family Job Protection Act - Prohibits a covered family member who is caring for a servicemember who is undergoing medical treatment for an injury, illness, or disease incurred or aggravated while on active military duty from being denied retention in employment, promotion, or any employment benefit by an employer on the basis of the family member's absence from such employment for a period of not more than 52 weeks. Includes as a covered family member one who, while caring for the recovering servicemember, is: (1) on invitational orders; (2) a non-medical attendee; or (3) receiving per diem payments from the Department of Defense (DOD).<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
