<bill session="110" type="h" number="3998" updated="2009-01-09T01:12:39-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1196808900" datetime="2007-12-04T18:55:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="1123"/></status>

	<introduced date="1193716800" datetime="2007-10-30"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">America's Historical and Natural Legacy Study Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">America's Historical and Natural Legacy Study Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Battle of Camden Study Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Battle of Matewan Study Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Butterfield Overland Trail Study Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Fort San Geronimo Study Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Harry S Truman Birthplace Study Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Lewis and Clark National Historic Trail Extension Study Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Mississippi River Study Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Rim of the Valley Corridor Study Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Stranahan House, Trading Post and Campsite Study Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Wolf House Study Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">America's Historical and Natural Legacy Study Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Battle of Camden Study Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Battle of Matewan Study Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Butterfield Overland Trail Study Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Fort San Geronimo Study Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Harry S Truman Birthplace Study Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Lewis and Clark National Historic Trail Extension Study Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Mississippi River Study Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Rim of the Valley Corridor Study Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Wolf House Study Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">America's Historical and Natural Legacy Study Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to conduct special resources studies of certain lands and structures to determine the appropriate means for preservation, use, and management of the resources associated with such lands and structures.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400162"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1193716800" datetime="2007-10-30"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1194411600" datetime="2007-11-07"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1194411600" datetime="2007-11-07" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1196792460" datetime="2007-12-04T14:21:00-05:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-462.</text></action>
		<calendar number="286" date="1196792460" datetime="2007-12-04T14:21:00-05:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 286.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1196792580" datetime="2007-12-04T14:23:00-05:00"><text>Ms. Bordallo moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1196792580" datetime="2007-12-04T14:23:00-05:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H14091-14095"/></action>
		<action date="1196792580" datetime="2007-12-04T14:23:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3998.</text></action>
		<action date="1196793300" datetime="2007-12-04T14:35:00-05:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1196807460" datetime="2007-12-04T18:31:00-05:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H14128-14129"/></action>
		<vote date="1196808900" how="roll" roll="1123" datetime="2007-12-04T18:55:00-05:00" where="h" type="vote" suspension="1" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 326 - 79 (Roll no. 1123).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H14091-14092"/></vote>
		<action date="1196830800" datetime="2007-12-05"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1207713600" datetime="2008-04-09"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1210132800" datetime="2008-05-07" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1213588800" datetime="2008-06-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 110-390.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="822" date="1213588800" datetime="2008-06-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 822.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/16/2008--Reported to Senate amended. America's Historical and Natural Legacy Study Act - (Sec. 3) Directs the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a special resource study of the Harry S Truman Birthplace State Historic Site in Lamar, Missouri, to determine: (1) the suitability and feasibility of adding the birthplace site to the Harry S Truman National Historic Site or designating the site as a separate unit of the National Park System; and (2) the methods and means for the protection and interpretation of the Harry S Truman Birthplace State Historic Site by the National Park Service (NPS), other federal, state, or local government entities, or private or nonprofit organizations. Requires submission of a report on the results of such study and any recommendations of the Secretary with respect to the birthplace site. (Sec. 4) Directs the Secretary to conduct a special resource study of the sites and resources at Matewan, West Virginia, associated with the Battle of Matewan (the Matewan Massacre) of May 19, 1920, to determine: (1) the suitability and feasibility of designating certain historic areas of Matewan as a unit of the National Park System; and (2) the methods and means for the protection and interpretation of the historic areas by the NPS, other federal, state, or local government entities, or private or nonprofit organizations. Requires submission of a report on the results of such study and any recommendations of the Secretary with respect to the historic areas. (Sec. 5) Directs the Secretary to conduct a special resource study along the Ox-Bow Route of the Butterfield Overland Trail in Missouri, Tennessee, Arkansas, Oklahoma, Texas, New Mexico, Arizona, and California to evaluate: (1) a range of alternatives for protecting and interpreting the resources of the route, including alternatives for potential addition of the Trail to the National Trails System; and (2) the methods and means for the protection and interpretation of the route by the NPS, other federal, state, or local government entities, or private or nonprofit organizations. Requires submission of a report on the results of such study and any recommendations of the Secretary with respect to the route. 
	</summary>
</bill>
