<bill session="110" type="h" number="4011" updated="2009-01-09T01:14:10-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1193716800" datetime="2007-10-30"/></status>

	<introduced date="1193716800" datetime="2007-10-30"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Good Samaritan Cleanup of Abandoned Hardrock Mines Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To facilitate the reclamation of abandoned hardrock mines, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400412"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400620" joined="2007-12-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400659" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400413" joined="2007-12-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400336" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400403" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400313" joined="2007-10-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="412192" joined="2007-12-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400101" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400287" joined="2007-12-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400440" joined="2007-12-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400088" joined="2008-01-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412191" joined="2007-12-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1193716800" datetime="2007-10-30"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2276-2277)</text></action>
		<action date="1193716800" datetime="2007-10-30"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text></action>
		<action date="1193803200" datetime="2007-10-31"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/30/2007--Introduced.<br/>Good Samaritan Cleanup of Abandoned Hardrock Mines Act of 2007- Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) to authorize the permitting authority, with the concurrence of the state in which an abandoned or inactive mine remediation project is proposed or a federal agency or the Indian tribe which owns or has jurisdiction over the site on which a remediation project is proposed, to issue a Good Samaritan discharge permit to a Good Samaritan to carry out a project to remediate an inactive or abandoned mine site to reduce pollution caused by historic mine residue. Outlines the permit process, including requirements governing remediation plans, investigative sampling, and application review and approval.<br/>Defines the term &quot;Good Samaritan&quot; to mean a person that, with respect to historic mine residue at an inactive or abandoned mine site: (1) had no role in the creation of the mine residue; (2) had no role and is not related to a person who had a role in creating the environmental pollution caused by the mine residue; and (3) is not liable under any law for the remediation of the mine residue.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
