<bill session="110" type="h" number="4020" updated="2009-01-09T01:15:14-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1193803200" datetime="2007-10-31"/></status>

	<introduced date="1193803200" datetime="2007-10-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Military Success in Iraq Commemoration Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To recognize the extraordinary performance of the Armed Forces in achieving the military objectives of the United States in Iraq, to encourage the President to issue a proclamation calling upon the people of the United States to observe a national day of celebration commemorating military success in Iraq, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400199"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2007-10-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400657" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="2007-10-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400229" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400130" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400402" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400048" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412199" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400217" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400201" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400090" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400208" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400024" joined="2007-11-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1193803200" datetime="2007-10-31"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H12355-12356, H12362)</text></action>
		<action date="1193803200" datetime="2007-10-31"><text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committees on Foreign Affairs, and Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1193803200" datetime="2007-10-31"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1193803200" datetime="2007-10-31"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1193803200" datetime="2007-10-31"><text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1193976000" datetime="2007-11-02"><committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1194584400" datetime="2007-11-09"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H13513)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/31/2007--Introduced.<br/>Military Success in Iraq Commemoration Act of 2007 - States that the Authorization for Use of Military Force Against Iraq Resolution of 2002 (P.L. 107-243) is the basis of authority under which the President launched the invasion of Iraq in March 2003, and that such Resolution authorized the President to use military force against Iraq to defend U.S. national security and to enforce all relevant United Nations (UN) Security Council resolutions regarding Iraq. Encourages the President to issue a proclamation calling upon the United States to observe a national day of celebration commemorating military success in Iraq. Authorizes the Secretary of Defense to award grants to state and local governments for suitable activities to commemorate such success. Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to award to each veteran of Operation Iraqi Freedom a grant of $5,000 to facilitate the veteran's transition to civilian life. 
	</summary>
</bill>
