<bill session="110" type="h" number="4047" updated="2009-01-09T01:18:26-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1193889600" datetime="2007-11-01"/></status>

	<introduced date="1193889600" datetime="2007-11-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Private Sector Whistleblower Protection Streamlining Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To streamline the administration of whistleblower protections for private sector employees.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400436"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400253" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400031" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400227" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400257" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400407" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400355" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400216" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400008" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412204" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412219" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="2007-11-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1193889600" datetime="2007-11-01"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1200978000" datetime="2008-01-22"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/1/2007--Introduced.<br/>Private Sector Whistleblower Protection Streamlining Act of 2007 - Sets forth whistleblower protections for private sector, state, and municipal employees who are retaliated or discriminated against by an employer for disclosing threats to public safety or violations of federal law. Authorizes a whistleblower who has been discharged or discriminated against by an employer to seek appropriate relief either by: (1) filing a complaint with the Secretary of Labor; or (2) bringing an action at law or equity in the appropriate U.S. district court. Prohibits restrictions on whistleblowing and relief provided under this Act. Establishes the Whistleblower Protection Office within the Employment Standards Administration of the Department of Labor. Makes conforming whistleblower amendments to the Occupational Safety and Health Act and the Federal Mine Safety and Health Act of 1977.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
