<bill session="110" type="h" number="4052" updated="2009-01-09T01:19:01-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1193889600" datetime="2007-11-01"/></status>

	<introduced date="1193889600" datetime="2007-11-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Atomic Veterans Relief Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to revise the eligibility criteria for presumption of service-connection of certain diseases and disabilities for veterans exposed to ionizing radiation during military service, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400001"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400041" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400420" joined="2008-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400155" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412224" joined="2008-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400313" joined="2008-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412210" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2008-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400274" joined="2007-12-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400264" joined="2008-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400074" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400266" joined="2008-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400201" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400391" joined="2008-10-02"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1193889600" datetime="2007-11-01"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1193976000" datetime="2007-11-02"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/1/2007--Introduced.<br/>Atomic Veterans Relief Act - Includes within the definition of a &quot;radiation-risk activity&quot; for purposes of eligibility criteria for veterans' disability compensation the exposure to ionizing radiation due to residual contamination resulting from participation in a nuclear detonation. Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to include in regulations pertaining to the service-connection of veterans' disabilities additional provisions to ensure, in the case of a claim by a radiation-exposed veteran for service-connection of a nonpresumptive disability, that the procedures for establishment of whether the disability is service-connected do not require imputation to the veteran, through a process known as dose reconstruction, of any particular level of exposure to ionizing radiation.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
