<bill session="110" type="h" number="4053" updated="2009-01-09T01:19:07-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1193889600" datetime="2007-11-01"/></status>

	<introduced date="1193889600" datetime="2007-11-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Mental Health Improvements Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the treatment and services provided by the Department of Veterans Affairs to veterans with post-traumatic stress disorder and substance use disorders, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400024"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400290" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400128" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400102" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412225" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400423" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412189" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412227" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400048" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412240" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412222" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412204" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400638" joined="2008-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400009" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412228" joined="2007-11-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400204" joined="2008-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400215" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400025" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400425" joined="2008-03-31"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1193889600" datetime="2007-11-01"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1193976000" datetime="2007-11-02"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/1/2007--Introduced.<br/>Mental Health Improvements Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to ensure the provision of specified substance use disorder treatment services at each Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) medical center and community-based outpatient clinic. Requires the Secretary to ensure that treatment for a substance use disorder and a comorbid mental health disorder is provided concurrently by a team of experienced clinicians. Requires the Secretary to: (1) carry out a program of enhanced care and treatment for veterans with substance use disorders and post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD); and (2) establish at least six national centers of excellence on PTSD and substance use disorders. Requires a report on residential mental health care facilities of the Veterans Health Administration (VHA). Pays tribute to Justin Bailey. Requires a: (1) pilot program on peer outreach and support services, readjustment counseling services, and other mental health services for veterans of Operations Iraqi Freedom and Enduring Freedom; (2) program of research into comorbid PTSD and substance use disorder; and (3) pilot program on the provision of readjustment and transition assistance to veterans and their families in cooperation with Vet Centers.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
