<bill session="110" type="h" number="4067" updated="2009-01-09T01:20:47-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1193889600" datetime="2007-11-01"/></status>

	<introduced date="1193889600" datetime="2007-11-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Bridges from Jobs to Careers Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide grants to colleges to improve remedial education (including English language instruction), to customize remediation to student career goals, and to help students move rapidly from remediation into for-credit occupation program courses and through program completion.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400436"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412231" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-06-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412209" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412204" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2007-11-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412212" joined="2007-11-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1193889600" datetime="2007-11-01"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1200373200" datetime="2008-01-15"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/1/2007--Introduced.<br/>Bridges from Jobs to Careers Act - Directs the Secretary of Education to award competitive grants to institutions of higher education (IHEs) to improve remedial education, customize remediation to student career goals, and help remedial students progress into and through for-credit occupational programs. Gives grant priority to IHEs: (1) in which at least 50% of the first-year students are enrolled in remedial courses designed to give them collegiate reading, writing, or mathematics skills; and (2) that propose to collaborate with adult education providers and replicate practices that have proven effective with adults.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
