<bill session="110" type="h" number="4071" updated="2009-01-09T01:21:14-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1194238800" datetime="2007-11-05"/></status>

	<introduced date="1194238800" datetime="2007-11-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Disabled Veterans Right to Commissaries and Space Available Travel Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 10, United States Code, to support disabled veterans by extending military commissary and exchange store privileges to such veterans and their dependents and by authorizing space-available travel on military aircraft for such veterans and their dependents.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400133"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400073" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400155" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="412225" joined="2008-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400380" joined="2008-07-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400274" joined="2008-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400331" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400244" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400310" joined="2008-03-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1194238800" datetime="2007-11-05"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2320)</text></action>
		<action date="1194238800" datetime="2007-11-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
		<action date="1196830800" datetime="2007-12-05"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/5/2007--Introduced.<br/>Disabled Veterans Right to Commissaries and Space Available Travel Act - Requires veterans with disabilities rated at 30% or more to be permitted to use commissary and exchange stores on the same basis as members of the Armed Forces eligible for retired or retainer pay. Extends such benefit to dependents on the same basis. Directs the Secretary of Defense to provide transportation on Department of Defense aircraft on a space-available basis for any veteran with a service-connected disability rated at 50% or more on the same basis as members entitled to retired or retainer pay. Extends such benefit to dependents on the same basis.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
