<bill session="110" type="h" number="4073" updated="2009-01-09T01:21:28-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1194238800" datetime="2007-11-05"/></status>

	<introduced date="1194238800" datetime="2007-11-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Non-Citizen Identification Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title II of the Social Security Act to provide for the issuance of Social Security cards with enhanced security features, to provide that wages earned, and self-employment income derived, by individuals while such individuals were not citizens or nationals of the United States and were illegally in the United States shall not be credited for coverage under the old-age, survivors, and disability insurance program under such title, and to provide for the issuance of Social Security cards to illegal aliens, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400068"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="2007-12-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400570" joined="2007-11-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400421" joined="2007-11-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400654" joined="2007-12-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1194238800" datetime="2007-11-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action date="1194584400" datetime="2007-11-09"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/5/2007--Introduced.<br/>Non-Citizen Identification Act - Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act to require the issuance of Social Security cards with specified enhanced security features. Allows the Commissioner of Social Security to charge a reasonable fee to the recipient as a condition for issuance of such a card. Provides that, in the computation of an individual's average indexed monthly earnings, or in certain circumstances an individual's average monthly wage, the individual shall not be credited with any wages paid, or any self-employment income derived, while such individual was not a U.S. citizen or national and was illegally in the United States. Requires issuance of special Social Security cards to adult illegal aliens. Prescribes criminal penalties for illegal aliens who do not possess such a Social Security card. Directs the Commissioner of Social Security to plan and implement a campaign to educate the people of the United States about the new Social Security cards provided for in this Act, and the requirement that illegal alien adults have such a card.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
