<bill session="110" type="h" number="4080" updated="2009-01-09T01:22:15-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1210737600" datetime="2008-05-14" /></status>

	<introduced date="1194238800" datetime="2007-11-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to establish a separate nonimmigrant classification for fashion models.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400426"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1194238800" datetime="2007-11-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1196658000" datetime="2007-12-03"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text></action>
		<action date="1210651200" datetime="2008-05-13"><text>Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law Discharged.</text></action>
		<action date="1210737600" datetime="2008-05-14"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1210737600" datetime="2008-05-14" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 20 - 3.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1212697260" datetime="2008-06-05T17:21:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 110-699.</text></action>
		<calendar number="442" date="1212697260" datetime="2008-06-05T17:21:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 442.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/5/2008--Reported to House amended. Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to replace the current nonimmigrant (H-1B) visa category for fashion models with a new (P-4) visa category. Defines such category as a fashion model who is of distinguished merit and ability and who is seeking to enter the United States temporarily to perform fashion modeling services that involve events or productions which have a distinguished reputation or that are performed for an organization or establishment that has a distinguished reputation for, or a record of, utilizing prominent modeling talent. Provides that such entrants may not: (1) exceed 1,000 in any fiscal year, not including accompanying spouses or children; and (2) stay in the United States for more than 10 years (initial five-year period with one five-year extension). Makes an employer petition for such alien models eligible for expedited consultation procedures. States that applicable H-1B regulations, guidelines, and precedents in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act for the adjudication of fashion model petitions shall be applied to P-4 petitions, except to the extent modified by the Secretary of Homeland Security. 
	</summary>
</bill>
