<bill session="110" type="h" number="4096" updated="2009-01-09T01:24:13-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1194325200" datetime="2007-11-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1194325200" datetime="2007-11-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Wild Fire Prevention Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To facilitate the ability of private property owners and local communities that manage public land to clear brush or make other modifications to their property for the purpose of creating fire breaks in order to protect human lives and property.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400191"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400113" joined="2007-11-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400239" joined="2007-11-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400144" joined="2007-11-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400277" joined="2007-11-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400057" joined="2007-11-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400343" joined="2007-11-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="412011" joined="2007-11-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1194325200" datetime="2007-11-06"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2333)</text></action>
		<action date="1194325200" datetime="2007-11-06"><text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1194325200" datetime="2007-11-06"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1194325200" datetime="2007-11-06"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action date="1194498000" datetime="2007-11-08"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action date="1209096000" datetime="2008-04-25"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/6/2007--Introduced.<br/>Wild Fire Prevention Act - Bars any federal law from prohibiting or restricting private property owners or local communities that manage public land from clearing brush or making other modifications to their property to create fire breaks for the protection of human lives and property. 
	</summary>
</bill>
