<bill session="110" type="h" number="4107" updated="2009-01-09T01:25:35-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1194411600" datetime="2007-11-07"/></status>

	<introduced date="1194411600" datetime="2007-11-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Women Veterans Health Care Improvement Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to expand and improve health care services available to women veterans, especially those serving in Operation Iraqi Freedom and Operation Enduring Freedom, from the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400443"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400290" joined="2007-12-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400623" joined="2008-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="412210" joined="2007-12-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400274" joined="2008-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400254" joined="2008-04-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="2008-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400184" joined="2008-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400007" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400051" joined="2007-11-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400346" joined="2008-06-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412204" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400638" joined="2008-09-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412200" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400284" joined="2008-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400125" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400043" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400042" joined="2007-12-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400215" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400114" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400062" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400190" joined="2008-09-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1194411600" datetime="2007-11-07"><text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1194411600" datetime="2007-11-07"><text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1194411600" datetime="2007-11-07"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1194584400" datetime="2007-11-09"><committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1196830800" datetime="2007-12-05"><committee name="House Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/7/2007--Introduced.<br/>Women Veterans Health Care Improvement Act - Requires the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to: (1) conduct a long-term epidemiological study on the health of women veterans who served on active duty in Operations Iraqi Freedom and Enduring Freedom; (2) assess barriers encountered by women veterans to the provision by the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) of comprehensive health care; (3) assess all health care services and programs provided by the VA for women veterans; (4) provide training for mental health professionals who provide counseling to women veterans suffering from sexual trauma; (5) develop a plan for the identification, development, and dissemination of treatments for post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) and other conditions attributable to combat or sexual trauma that are proven effective for women veterans; (6) conduct a study of the provision of readjustment counseling and related mental health services for women veterans at vet centers; (7) carry out a pilot program for child care for certain women veterans receiving health care from VA facilities; and (8) carry out a pilot program to evaluate the feasibility and advisability of providing counseling and transition adjustment assistance for women veterans who are newly separated from active duty service. Requires women veterans recently separated from active duty service to be included on the Advisory Committee on Women Veterans.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
