<bill session="110" type="h" number="4100" updated="2009-01-09T01:24:41-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1194325200" datetime="2007-11-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1194325200" datetime="2007-11-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to establish an instructional level assessment pilot program.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400436"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400222" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400155" joined="2007-11-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400355" joined="2007-11-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2007-11-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400402" joined="2007-11-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412209" joined="2007-11-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412211" joined="2007-11-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412204" joined="2007-11-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412200" joined="2008-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2007-11-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2007-11-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1194325200" datetime="2007-11-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1200978000" datetime="2008-01-22"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/6/2007--Introduced.<br/>Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to require the Secretary of Education to: (1) award competitive grants to up to 10 states for pilot programs to determine the effectiveness of assessing disabled students who are achieving significantly below grade-level proficiency at their instructional level; and (2) provide quality instruction to such students. Requires each grantee to identify a minimum of five local educational agencies (LEAs) to participate in its pilot program and limit student participation to 0.5% of the students assessed in each participating LEA. Requires such states and LEAs to ensure that each participating student's individualized education program team: (1) administers, after securing parental consent, a scientifically-valid and reliable assessment based on the student's instructional level in reading and/or math; and (2) based on such assessment, develops a series of targeted interventions designed to close identified gaps in the student's instructional and grade-level content knowledge. Prohibits the use of such assessment results in determinations of adequate yearly progress (AYP) toward state academic performance standards.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
