<bill session="110" type="h" number="4120" updated="2009-01-09T01:27:05-05:00">
	<status><enacted date="1223438400" datetime="2008-10-08" /></status>

	<introduced date="1194498000" datetime="2007-11-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Effective Child Pornography Prosecution Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Effective Child Pornography Prosecution Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">Effective Child Pornography Prosecution Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">Enhancing the Effective Prosecution of Child Pornography Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="enacted">Effective Child Pornography Prosecution Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="enacted">Enhancing the Effective Prosecution of Child Pornography Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, to provide for more effective prosecution of cases involving child pornography, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412210"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400027" joined="2007-11-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1194498000" datetime="2007-11-08"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1194987120" datetime="2007-11-13T16:52:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Conyers moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text></action>
		<action date="1194987120" datetime="2007-11-13T16:52:00-05:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H13591-13593"/></action>
		<action date="1194987120" datetime="2007-11-13T16:52:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4120.</text></action>
		<action date="1194987900" datetime="2007-11-13T17:05:00-05:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1195081320" datetime="2007-11-14T19:02:00-05:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H13916-13917"/></action>
		<vote date="1195081680" how="roll" roll="1105" datetime="2007-11-14T19:08:00-05:00" where="h" type="vote" suspension="1" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 409 - 0 (Roll no. 1105). (text: CR 11/13/2007 H13591)</text></vote>
		<action date="1195102800" datetime="2007-11-15"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1222142400" datetime="2008-09-23"><text>Senate Committee on the Judiciary discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text></action>
		<action date="1222142400" datetime="2008-09-23"><text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S9343-9344"/></action>
		<vote date="1222142400" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2008-09-23" where="s" type="vote2" result="pass" ><text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text></vote>
		<action date="1222228800" datetime="2008-09-24"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<action date="1222398780" datetime="2008-09-25T12:13:00-04:00"><text>Ms. Lofgren, Zoe moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H9887-9889"/></action>
		<action date="1222398780" datetime="2008-09-25T12:13:00-04:00"><text>The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4120.</text></action>
		<action date="1222398900" datetime="2008-09-25T12:15:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Cannon objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text></action>
		<action date="1222453680" datetime="2008-09-26T15:28:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 418 - 0 (Roll no. 656). (consideration: CR H10058-10059; text as House agreed to Senate amendment: CR 9/25/2008 H9887-9888)</text></action>
		<topresident date="1222401600" datetime="2008-09-26" ><text>Cleared for White House.</text></topresident>
		<topresident date="1222747200" datetime="2008-09-30" ><text>Presented to President.</text></topresident>
		<signed date="1223438400" datetime="2008-10-08" ><text>Signed by President.</text></signed>
		<enacted number="110-358" date="1223438400" datetime="2008-10-08" type="public" ><text>Became Public Law No: 110-358.</text></enacted>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/8/2008--Public Law. (This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the Senate on September 23, 2008. The summary of that version is repeated here.)<br/>Title I: Effective Child Pornography Prosecution Act of 2007 - Effective Child Pornography Prosecution Act of 2007 - Amends the federal criminal code to expand the jurisdictional basis for prosecutions of sexual exploitation of children, selling or buying of children, or child pornography crimes to include activities that use any means or facility of interstate or foreign commerce to complete such crimes. Title II: Enhancing the Effective Prosecution of Child Pornography Act of 2007 - Enhancing the Effective Prosecution of Child Pornography Act of 2007 - Amends the federal criminal code to: (1) include child pornography that contains a visual depiction of an actual minor engaging in sexually explicit conduct and the production of such pornography for importation into the United States as predicate crimes for money laundering prosecutions; and (2) define &quot;possess&quot; with respect to crimes of child sexual exploitation and child pornography to include accessing by computer visual depictions of child pornography with the intent to view. 
	</summary>
</bill>
