<bill session="110" type="h" number="4122" updated="2009-01-09T01:27:19-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1194498000" datetime="2007-11-08"/></status>

	<introduced date="1194498000" datetime="2007-11-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">American Investment in Safe, Reliable High-Speed Rail Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To support the development of high-speed rail in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400618"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400065" joined="2008-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400152" joined="2008-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2008-04-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1194498000" datetime="2007-11-08"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text></action>
		<action date="1194584400" datetime="2007-11-09"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/8/2007--Introduced.<br/>American Investment in Safe, Reliable High-Speed Rail Act - Declares that the purpose of this Act is to establish high-speed rail systems in the United States. Amends federal transportation law to authorize the Secretary of Transportation (Secretary) to make grants to a state, an Interstate Compact, a public agency, or a public-private entity to finance high-speed capital projects that improve intercity passenger rail transportation service. Prohibits Secretary approval of a grant project without a state rail plan and a project management plan. Requires each state to prepare for Secretary approval a state rail plan that includes a long-range rail investment program. Establishes: (1) a Next Generation Corridor Equipment Pool Committee; (2) a rail cooperative research program; and (3) an advisory board. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to, and enter into cooperative agreements with, the National Academy of Sciences to carry out research, technology, and technology transfer activities to improve intercity rail passenger and freight service. 
	</summary>
</bill>
