<bill session="110" type="h" number="4136" updated="2009-01-09T01:28:55-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1195174980" datetime="2007-11-15T21:03:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="1121"/></status>

	<introduced date="1194584400" datetime="2007-11-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Enhancing the Effective Prosecution of Child Pornography Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Enhancing the Effective Prosecution of Child Pornography Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18 of the United States Code to clarify the scope of the child pornography laws, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412234"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1194584400" datetime="2007-11-09"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1194988380" datetime="2007-11-13T17:13:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Conyers moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1194988440" datetime="2007-11-13T17:14:00-05:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H13594-13595"/></action>
		<action date="1194988440" datetime="2007-11-13T17:14:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4136.</text></action>
		<action date="1194988800" datetime="2007-11-13T17:20:00-05:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1195174440" datetime="2007-11-15T20:54:00-05:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H14062-14063"/></action>
		<vote date="1195174980" how="roll" roll="1121" datetime="2007-11-15T21:03:00-05:00" where="h" type="vote" suspension="1" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 416 - 0 (Roll no. 1121). (text: CR 11/13/2007 H13594)</text></vote>
		<action date="1195174980" datetime="2007-11-15T21:03:00-05:00"><text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 3773.</text></action>
		<action date="1196658000" datetime="2007-12-03"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/15/2007--Passed House amended. Enhancing the Effective Prosecution of Child Pornography Act of 2007 - Amends the federal criminal code to: (1) include child pornography activities and the production of such pornography for importation into the United States as predicate crimes for money laundering prosecutions; and (2) define &quot;possess&quot; with respect to crimes of child sexual exploitation and child pornography to include accessing by computer visual depictions of child pornography with the intent to view. 
	</summary>
</bill>
