<bill session="110" type="h" number="4156" updated="2009-01-09T01:31:17-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1195092060" datetime="2007-11-14T22:01:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="1108"/></status>

	<introduced date="1194930000" datetime="2007-11-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Orderly and Responsible Iraq Redeployment Appropriations Act, 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Orderly and Responsible Iraq Redeployment Appropriations Act, 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Making emergency supplemental appropriations for the Department of Defense for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2008, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400300"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400286" joined="2007-11-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1194930000" datetime="2007-11-13"><text>Referred to the Committee on Appropriations, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1194930000" datetime="2007-11-13"><text>Referred to House Appropriations</text></action>
		<action date="1194930000" datetime="2007-11-13"><text>Referred to House Budget</text></action>
		<action date="1195001700" datetime="2007-11-13T20:55:00-05:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 818 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4156 with 2 hours of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI.</text></action>
		<action date="1195081320" datetime="2007-11-14T19:02:00-05:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 818 passed House.</text></action>
		<action date="1195081740" datetime="2007-11-14T19:09:00-05:00"><text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 818.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H13917-13937, H13938-13943"/></action>
		<action date="1195081800" datetime="2007-11-14T19:10:00-05:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4156 with 2 hours of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI.</text></action>
		<action date="1195081800" datetime="2007-11-14T19:10:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 818, the House proceeded with 2 hours of debate on H.R. 4156.</text></action>
		<action date="1195088580" datetime="2007-11-14T21:03:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House resumed debate on H.R. 4156.</text></action>
		<action date="1195089600" datetime="2007-11-14T21:20:00-05:00"><text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text></action>
		<action date="1195089660" datetime="2007-11-14T21:21:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Young (FL) moved to recommit with instructions to Appropriations.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H13941-13943"/><reference label="text" ref="CR H13941"/></action>
		<action date="1195089660" datetime="2007-11-14T21:21:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Young(FL) motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require that the bill be reported back to the House forthwith with sundry amendments.</text></action>
		<action date="1195090020" datetime="2007-11-14T21:27:00-05:00"><text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H13942"/></action>
		<action date="1195091100" datetime="2007-11-14T21:45:00-05:00"><text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 192 - 231 (Roll no. 1107).</text></action>
		<vote date="1195092060" how="roll" roll="1108" datetime="2007-11-14T22:01:00-05:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 218 - 203, 1 Present (Roll no. 1108).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H13917-13920"/></vote>
		<action date="1195102800" datetime="2007-11-15"><text>Received in the Senate. Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 507, all pursuant to the order of November 14, 2007.</text></action>
		<action date="1195102800" datetime="2007-11-15"><text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure made in Senate.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S14474-14475"/></action>
		<action date="1195102800" datetime="2007-11-15"><text>Cloture motion on the motion to proceed presented in Senate.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S14474"/><reference label="text" ref="CR S14474"/></action>
		<action date="1195102800" datetime="2007-11-15"><text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure withdrawn in Senate.</text></action>
		<action date="1195189200" datetime="2007-11-16"><text>Motion to proceed to measure considered in Senate.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S14590, S14591-14592"/></action>
		<vote-aux date="1195189200" how="roll" roll="411" datetime="2007-11-16" where="s" type="cloture" result="fail" ><text>Cloture on the motion to proceed not invoked in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 53 - 45. Record Vote Number: 411.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S14591"/><reference label="text" ref="CR S14591"/></vote-aux>
		<action date="1195189200" datetime="2007-11-16"><text>Motion by Senator Dodd to reconsider the vote by which cloture on the motion to proceed was not invoked [Record Vote Number 411] entered in Senate.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/14/2007--Passed House without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.) Orderly and Responsible Iraq Redeployment Appropriations Act, 2008 - Title I: Policy on Redeployment and Conduct of Operations in Iraq - (Sec. 101) Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the war in Iraq should end as safely and quickly as possible, and our troops should be brought home; (2) the performance of U.S. military personnel in Iraq and Afghanistan should be commended, and their service should be appropriately recognized; and (3) the primary purpose of funds from this Act should be to transition the mission of U.S. Armed Forces in Iraq and undertake their redeployment, and not to extend or prolong the war. (Sec. 102) Prohibits any person in the custody or control of the U.S. government from being subject to any treatment or technique of interrogation not authorized by and listed in the U.S. Army Field Manual of Human Intelligence Collector Operations. (Sec. 103) Prohibits funds from being used: (1) in contravention of specified laws implementing the United Nations Convention Against Torture and Other Cruel, Inhuman, or Degrading Treatment or Punishment; or (2) to deploy any U.S. military unit to Iraq unless the President has certified to the defense and appropriations committees, at least 15 days in advance, that such unit as &quot;fully mission capable.&quot; Allows the President to waive the latter prohibition on a unit-by-unit basis for national security purposes. (Sec. 105) Makes funds from this Act immediately available to plan and execute a safe and orderly redeployment of U.S. Armed Forces from Iraq. Directs the President to commence such redeployment within 30 days after this Act's enactment, beginning with units that have been deployed in excess of 365 days. Sets as a goal to realize a limited presence and missions (protection of diplomatic facilities and American citizens, limited training and support of Iraqi Security Forces, and engaging in counterterrorism operations against al-Qaeda and other terrorist organizations in Iraq) by December 15, 2008. Requires quarterly reports from the Secretary of Defense (Secretary) to the congressional defense committees on the current plan, status, and efforts with respect to the reduction of U.S. forces in Iraq and their transition to a limited presence. Requires the President to submit to Congress a regional stability plan for the Middle East. (Sec. 106) States that the amounts appropriated by this Act are sufficient to fully meet the immediate needs of the U.S. Armed Forces deployed to Iraq and defers congressional consideration of additional funding until the first quarterly report required by section 105 is submitted to the Congress. Title II: Supplemental Appropriations - Makes supplemental appropriations for the Department of Defense (DOD) for: (1) military personnel; (2) operation and maintenance (O&amp;amp;M); (3) the Afghanistan Security Forces Fund; (4) the Iraq Security Forces Fund; (5) the Iraq Freedom Fund; (6) the Joint Improvised Explosive Device Defeat Fund; (7) procurement; and (8) the Defense Health Program. (Sec. 202) Authorizes the Secretary, in the national interest, to transfer between appropriations up to $4 billion of the funds made available to DOD in this Act. Requires congressional notification of each transfer. (Sec. 205) Earmarks specified DOD O&amp;amp;M funds to fund the Commander's Emergency Response Program (urgent humanitarian relief and reconstruction in Iraq). (Sec. 206) Allows FY2008 DOD O&amp;amp;M funds to be used to provide supplies, services, transportation, and other logistical support to Coalition forces supporting military and stability operations in Iraq and Afghanistan. Requires quarterly reports from the Secretary to the defense committees on the use of such funds. (Sec. 208) Designates each amount appropriated in this title as an emergency requirement pursuant to provisions of the concurrent resolution on the budget for fiscal year 2008. (Sec. 209) Directs the Secretary to report quarterly to Congress a comprehensive set of performance indicators and measures for progress toward military and political stability in Iraq. (Sec. 210) Prohibits any funds from being used to: (1) establish any military installation or base for providing for the permanent stationing of U.S. Armed Forces in Iraq; or (2) exercise U.S. control over any oil resource of Iraq.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
