<bill session="110" type="h" number="4173" updated="2009-01-09T01:33:28-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1195016400" datetime="2007-11-14"/></status>

	<introduced date="1195016400" datetime="2007-11-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">OVERSEAS Vote Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Overseas Voting Education and Reform, Safeguarding Every American's Vote Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act to promote the participation of absent overseas voters in elections for Federal office, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400185"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400073" joined="2007-12-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="2008-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400184" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="2008-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400001" joined="2008-01-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400653" joined="2008-05-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400251" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="412232" joined="2008-11-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400074" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412200" joined="2008-07-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2008-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412194" joined="2008-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400349" joined="2008-05-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1195016400" datetime="2007-11-14"><text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1195016400" datetime="2007-11-14"><text>Referred to House House Administration</text></action>
		<action date="1195016400" datetime="2007-11-14"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/14/2007--Introduced.<br/>Overseas Voting Education and Reform, Safeguarding Every American's Vote Act, or OVERSEAS Vote Act - Amends the Uniformed and Overseas Citizen Absentee Voting Act (UOCAVA) to prohibit a state from refusing to accept or process any otherwise valid absentee ballot submitted by an absent uniformed services voter or overseas voter on the grounds that the envelope in which the ballot is submitted is not notarized or witnessed by a notary public or other official authorized to administer oaths. Repeals the requirement to apply for state absentee ballot as a condition for use of a federal write-in absentee ballot. Permits voters to request absentee ballots in all subsequent elections. Directs the Election Assistance Commission (EAC) to establish and operate a program of grants to eligible nonpartisan organizations for activities to: (1) assist overseas civilian voters in voting in federal elections; and (2) increase turnout by providing them with information in advance of an election on how to cast absentee ballots. Requires the head of each office of the federal government with employees whose designated post of duty is outside the United States to notify them of the rights provided by UOCAVA to absent uniformed services voters and overseas voters. Directs the Secretary of State to ensure that each passport issued after enactment of this Act describes such rights. Extends application of UOCAVA to certain individuals who have never resided in the United States.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
