<bill session="110" type="h" number="4179" updated="2009-01-09T01:34:11-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1213798140" datetime="2008-06-18T11:09:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1195016400" datetime="2007-11-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Fair, Accurate, Secure and Timely Redress Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">FAST Redress Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Fair, Accurate, Secure, and Timely Redress Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">FAST Redress Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Fair, Accurate, Secure, and Timely Redress Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">FAST Redress Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish an appeal and redress process for individuals wrongly delayed or prohibited from boarding a flight, and for other purposes.</title>
		<title type="official" as="amended by house">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish an appeal and redress process for individuals wrongly delayed or prohibited from boarding a flight, or denied a right, benefit, or privilege, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412221"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400073" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400657" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412234" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400246" joined="2008-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400295" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412192" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400152" joined="2008-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400355" joined="2008-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400245" joined="2008-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400402" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400356" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400653" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400641" joined="2008-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400309" joined="2007-11-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1195016400" datetime="2007-11-14"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text></action>
		<action date="1201755600" datetime="2008-01-31"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation Security and Infrastructure Protection.</text></action>
		<action date="1209614400" datetime="2008-05-01"><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1211256000" datetime="2008-05-20"><text>Subcommittee on Transportation Security and Infrastructure Protection Discharged.</text></action>
		<action date="1211256000" datetime="2008-05-20"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1211256000" datetime="2008-05-20" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1212684120" datetime="2008-06-05T13:42:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 110-686.</text></action>
		<calendar number="430" date="1212684180" datetime="2008-06-05T13:43:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 430.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1213796520" datetime="2008-06-18T10:42:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Thompson (MS) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1213796520" datetime="2008-06-18T10:42:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H5491-5496"/></action>
		<action date="1213796520" datetime="2008-06-18T10:42:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4179.</text></action>
		<vote date="1213798140" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-06-18T11:09:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H5491-5492"/></vote>
		<action date="1213798140" datetime="2008-06-18T11:09:00-04:00"><text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action date="1213848000" datetime="2008-06-19"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/18/2008--Passed House amended. (This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on June 5, 2008. The summary of that version is repeated here.)<br/>Fair, Accurate, Secure, and Timely Redress Act of 2008 or the FAST Redress Act of 2008 - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish: (1) a timely and fair process for individuals who believe they were delayed or prohibited from boarding a commercial aircraft because they were wrongly identified as a threat when screened against any terrorist watchlist or database used by the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) or any component of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS); and (2) an Office of Appeals and Redress within DHS to implement, coordinate, and execute the process. Requires the process to include the establishment of a method for maintaining and appropriately disseminating a Comprehensive Cleared List of individuals who: (1) were misidentified; (2) completed an appeal and redress request and provided required information to verify their identity; and (3) permit their personally identifiable information to be shared between DHS components. Directs the Secretary to: (1) transmit information necessary to resolve misidentifications, improve administration of the advanced passenger prescreening system, and reduce false positives to TSA or any other appropriate DHS component, other federal, state, local, and tribal entities, and domestic and foreign air carriers that use any terrorist watchlist or database; and (2) ensure that the List is considered when assessing an individual's security risk. Terminates the transmission of the List to domestic and foreign air carriers on the date the federal government assumes terrorist watchlist or database screening functions. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) enter into memoranda of understanding with federal, state, local, and tribal entities to improve the appeal and redress process and for other purposes, such as to verify an individual's identity and personally identifiable information; and (2) work with other entities that use any terrorist watchlist or database to ensure that the List is considered when assessing an individual's security risk.<br/>Directs the Secretary, in conjunction with DHS's Chief Privacy Officer, to: (1) require that DHS employees complete mandatory privacy and security training before being authorized to handle personally identifiable information; (2) ensure that the information maintained is secured by encryption,; (3) limit the information collected from misidentified passengers or other individuals to the minimum amount necessary to resolve an appeal and redress request; (4) ensure that the information maintained is shared or transferred via an encrypted data network that has been audited to ensure that security related software functions perform properly and are updated as necessary; (5) ensure that any DHS employee receiving the information handles it in accordance with the Privacy Act of 1974 and other specified law; (6) retain the information for only as long as needed to assist the individual traveler in the appeal and redress process; (7) engage in cooperative agreements with appropriate federal entities to ensure that legal name changes are properly reflected in any terrorist watchlist or database and the List; and (8) conduct, publish, and report to specified congressional committees on a privacy impact assessment of the process. Requires the Office of Appeals and Redress, at each airport at which: (1) DHS has a presence, to provide written information to air carrier passengers to begin the appeal and redress process; and (2) DHS has a significant presence, to provide that information and ensure the availability of a TSA supervisor who is trained in such process to provide support to air carrier passengers in need of guidance. Sets forth reporting requirements on the status of information sharing among users at DHS of any terrorist watchlist or database.<br/>Incorporates the appeals and redress process into the Secure Flight Program.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
