<bill session="110" type="h" number="4174" updated="2009-01-09T01:33:34-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1215619800" datetime="2008-07-09T13:10:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1195016400" datetime="2007-11-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Ocean Acidification Research And Monitoring Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">FOARAM Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Federal Ocean Acidification Research And Monitoring Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">FOARAM Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Federal Ocean Acidification Research And Monitoring Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">FOARAM Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish an interagency committee to develop an ocean acidification research and monitoring plan and to establish an ocean acidification program within the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400007"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400041" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400073" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400149" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400102" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400129" joined="2008-06-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400184" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412198" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400356" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2007-12-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400193" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400119" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400204" joined="2008-07-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400301" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400062" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400011" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400349" joined="2007-11-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1195016400" datetime="2007-11-14"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Science and Technology.</text></action>
		<action date="1201496400" datetime="2008-01-28"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text></action>
		<action date="1212638400" datetime="2008-06-05"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1213761600" datetime="2008-06-18"><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1213761600" datetime="2008-06-18"><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text></action>
		<action date="1214366400" datetime="2008-06-25"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1214366400" datetime="2008-06-25" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1215659100" datetime="2008-07-09T12:05:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science and Technology. H. Rept. 110-749.</text></action>
		<calendar number="475" date="1215659100" datetime="2008-07-09T12:05:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 475.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1215661740" datetime="2008-07-09T12:49:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Baird moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1215661740" datetime="2008-07-09T12:49:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H6261-6266"/></action>
		<action date="1215661740" datetime="2008-07-09T12:49:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4174.</text></action>
		<vote date="1215619800" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-07-09T13:10:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H6261-6263"/></vote>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="873" date="1215662400" datetime="2008-07-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 873.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/9/2008--Passed House amended. Federal Ocean Acidification Research And Monitoring Act of 2008 or FOARAM Act - (Sec. 3) Defines &quot;ocean acidification,&quot; for this Act, as the decrease in pH of the Earth's oceans and changes in ocean chemistry caused by chemical inputs from the atmosphere, including carbon dioxide. (Sec. 4) Requires that the Joint Subcommittee on Ocean Science and Technology of the National Science and Technology Council: (1) coordinate federal activities on ocean acidification; (2) report biennially to specified congressional committees; (3) transmit the strategic research plan developed under this Act to those committees; and (4) submit a revised plan at least once every five years. (Sec. 5) Requires the Subcommittee to develop a strategic plan for federal ocean acidification research and monitoring that provides for an assessment of ocean acidification impacts on marine organisms and ecosystems and the development of adaptation and mitigation strategies to conserve marine organisms and ecosystems. Directs the Secretary of Commerce, through the administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), to enter into an agreement with the National Academy of Sciences (NAS) to review the plan. (Sec. 6) Directs the Secretary to conduct research and monitoring and authorizes the Secretary to establish an ocean acidification program in NOAA consistent with the strategic research plan, including: (1) providing grants for critical research projects exploring the effects of ocean acidification on ecosystems and the socioeconomic impacts of increased ocean acidification that are relevant to the plan's goals and priorities; and (2) incorporating a competitive merit-based process for awarding grants that may be conducted jointly with other participating agencies or under the National Oceanographic Partnership Program. (Sec. 7) Requires the NSF director to continue to carry out ocean acidification research supporting competitive, merit-based, peer-reviewed proposals for research and monitoring of ocean acidification and its impacts. (Sec. 8) Requires the administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) to ensure that space-based monitoring assets are used in as productive a manner as possible for monitoring of ocean acidification and its impacts. (Sec. 9) Authorizes appropriations to NOAA and to NASA to carry out this Act.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
