<bill session="110" type="h" number="4177" updated="2009-01-09T01:33:58-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1195016400" datetime="2007-11-14"/></status>

	<introduced date="1195016400" datetime="2007-11-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Airport Security Enhancement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, to authorize the Assistant Secretary of Homeland Security (Transportation Security Administration) to designate Federal special security zones at airports, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400222"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400228" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400027" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412202" joined="2007-11-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1195016400" datetime="2007-11-14"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H13864, E2422-2423)</text></action>
		<action date="1195016400" datetime="2007-11-14"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text></action>
		<action date="1201755600" datetime="2008-01-31"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation Security and Infrastructure Protection.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/14/2007--Introduced.<br/>Airport Security Enhancement Act of 2007 - Amends federal transportation law to authorize the Assistant Secretary of Homeland Security (Transportation Security Administration) to: (1) designate certain airport areas (tarmacs, aircraft, baggage handling areas, baggage loading areas, and such other areas as the Assistant Secretary determines appropriate) as Federal Special Security Zones; and (2) issue a badge authorizing certain qualified individuals access to such zones. Restricts access to a Federal Special Security Zone to individuals who require access because of their employment and who have obtained a badge. Prohibits the use of a state issued badge to gain access to a Federal Special Security Zone.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
