<bill session="110" type="h" number="4183" updated="2009-01-09T01:34:39-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1195016400" datetime="2007-11-14"/></status>

	<introduced date="1195016400" datetime="2007-11-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Urban Search and Rescue Response System Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish the National Urban Search and Rescue Response System.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400356"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400073" joined="2008-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2008-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400657" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412221" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400344" joined="2008-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400274" joined="2008-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400355" joined="2008-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400245" joined="2007-12-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400648" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400251" joined="2008-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2008-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400654" joined="2007-11-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1195016400" datetime="2007-11-14"><text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1195016400" datetime="2007-11-14"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1195016400" datetime="2007-11-14"><text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text></action>
		<action date="1195102800" datetime="2007-11-15"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text></action>
		<action date="1195102800" datetime="2007-11-15"><committee name="House Homeland Security"/><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2435)</text></action>
		<action date="1201755600" datetime="2008-01-31"><committee name="House Homeland Security"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emergency Communications, Preparedness, and Response.</text></action>
		<action date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30"><committee name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Emergency Communications, Preparedness, and Response"/><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30"><committee name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Emergency Communications, Preparedness, and Response"/><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by the Yeas and Nays: 7 - 0 .</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/14/2007--Introduced.<br/>National Urban Search and Rescue Response System Act of 2007 - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to codify provisions establishing in the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) the National Urban Search and Rescue Response System, under which the Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide for a national network of standardized search and rescue resources to assist state and local governments in responding to structural collapses resulting from terrorist acts and other incidents.<br/>Directs the Secretary to: (1) select and designate task forces to participate in the System and determine criteria for participation; (2) enter into an agreement with the sponsoring agency of each task force regarding participation; and (3) maintain such management and technical teams as the Secretary deems necessary. Authorizes a task force to include states, local governments, private nonprofit organizations, and for-profit entities.<br/>Directs the Secretary (subject to specified limitations) to enter into, with each sponsoring agency: (1) an annual preparedness cooperative agreement; and (2) a response cooperative agreement, under which the Secretary agrees to reimburse agency costs incurred in responding to incidents.<br/>Authorizes the Secretary to appoint a System member for sponsored or sanctioned exercises, pre-incident staging, or major disaster, emergency response, or training events. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) appointment into federal service, including employment status, compensation, treatment as an employee in the event of personal injury, illness, disability, or death, liability, and employment and re-employment rights; and (2) licenses and permits. Directs the Secretary to establish and maintain an advisory subcommittee of the National Advisory Council.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
