<bill session="110" type="h" number="419" updated="2009-01-08T17:38:29-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1168491600" datetime="2007-01-11"/></status>

	<introduced date="1168491600" datetime="2007-01-11"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Natural Disaster Relief Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide assistance to agricultural producers for crop and livestock losses in 2005, 2006, or 2007 as a result of natural disasters, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400247"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400077" joined="2007-03-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412217" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400432" joined="2007-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400287" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400404" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400284" joined="2007-01-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1168491600" datetime="2007-01-11"><text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1168491600" datetime="2007-01-11"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action date="1168491600" datetime="2007-01-11"><text>Referred to House Budget</text></action>
		<action date="1172811600" datetime="2007-03-02"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on General Farm Commodities and Risk Management.</text></action>
		<action date="1172811600" datetime="2007-03-02"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Horticulture and Organic Agriculture.</text></action>
		<action date="1172811600" datetime="2007-03-02"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry.</text></action>
		<action date="1172811600" datetime="2007-03-02"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Specialty Crops, Rural Development, and Foreign Agriculture.</text></action>
		<action date="1172811600" datetime="2007-03-02"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/11/2007--Introduced.<br/>Natural Disaster Relief Act - Defines &quot;hurricane-affected county&quot; as: (1) a county covered by a natural disaster declaration related to Hurricanes Katrina, Rita, or Wilma, or related condition; and (2) a contiguous county. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to provide emergency financial assistance to eligible agricultural producers (other than sugar cane and sugar beet producers) who have incurred qualifying 2005-2007 crop losses due to weather or related conditions (including crop disease, insects, and delayed harvest) with respect to which a natural disaster declaration has been made. Requires a producer who suffered qualifying losses to elect assistance for only one of such years. Directs the Secretary to provide: (1) payments through the 2002 livestock compensation program for livestock disaster losses during calendar years 2005-2007 for losses that occurred prior to of enactment of this Act (including wildfire disaster losses in Texas and other states, and blizzard losses in Colorado, Kansas, Nebraska, New Mexico, and Oklahoma); and (2) livestock indemnity payments to producers who have incurred 2005-2007 livestock disaster losses prior to enactment of this Act (including wildfire disaster losses in Texas and other states, and blizzard losses in Colorado, Kansas, Nebraska, New Mexico, and Oklahoma), including losses due to hurricanes, floods, wildfires, blizzards, and anthrax. Requires a livestock producer who suffered qualifying losses to elect assistance for only one of such years. Directs the Secretary to hire additional county Farm Service Agency personnel to assist in agricultural disaster and economic assistance programs.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
