<bill session="110" type="h" number="4199" updated="2009-01-09T01:36:28-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1215555360" datetime="2008-07-08T19:16:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="473"/></status>

	<introduced date="1195102800" datetime="2007-11-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Dayton Aviation Heritage Preservation Act of 1992 to add sites to the Dayton Aviation Heritage National Historical Park, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400411"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400280" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400227" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400180" joined="2008-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412256" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400352" joined="2008-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="412227" joined="2008-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400172" joined="2008-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400211" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400074" joined="2008-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="412228" joined="2008-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400208" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400334" joined="2008-06-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1195102800" datetime="2007-11-15"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1195534800" datetime="2007-11-20"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action date="1212638400" datetime="2008-06-05"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1213156800" datetime="2008-06-11"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1213156800" datetime="2008-06-11" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1213156800" datetime="2008-06-11"><text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands Discharged.</text></action>
		<action date="1215539280" datetime="2008-07-08T14:48:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-739.</text></action>
		<calendar number="470" date="1215539280" datetime="2008-07-08T14:48:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 470.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1215540780" datetime="2008-07-08T15:13:00-04:00"><text>Ms. Bordallo moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1215540780" datetime="2008-07-08T15:13:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H6189-6191"/></action>
		<action date="1215540780" datetime="2008-07-08T15:13:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4199.</text></action>
		<action date="1215541380" datetime="2008-07-08T15:23:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1215554940" datetime="2008-07-08T19:09:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H6200-6201"/></action>
		<vote date="1215555360" how="roll" roll="473" datetime="2008-07-08T19:16:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" suspension="1" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 368 - 18 (Roll no. 473).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H6189-6190"/></vote>
		<action date="1215576000" datetime="2008-07-09"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/8/2008--Passed House amended. Title I: Additional Areas Included In Dayton Aviation Heritage National Historical Park - (Sec. 101) Amends the Dayton Aviation Heritage Preservation Act of 1992 to provide for the acquisition and inclusion of the following additional sites in the Dayton Aviation Heritage National Historical Park: (1) Hawthorn Hill, Oakwood, Ohio; and (2) the Wright Company factory and associated land and buildings, Dayton, Ohio. (Sec. 102) Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to enter into a cooperative agreement with a partner or partners, including the Wright Family Foundation, to operate and provide programming for Hawthorn Hill and charge reasonable fees to defray park operation and programming costs. Title II: Wright Brothers-Dunbar National Historical Park Designation - (Sec. 201) Renames the Dayton Aviation Heritage National Historical Park as the Wright Brothers-Dunbar National Historic Park. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to partners of the park, including the Aviation Trail, Inc., the Ohio Historical Society, and Dayton History, for projects not requiring federal involvement other than providing financial assistance. Limits projects to construction and development on non-federal property within park boundaries. (Sec. 202) Amends Title V of division J of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2005 to remove the Neil Armstrong Air &amp;amp; Space Museum, Wapakoneta, Ohio, from inclusion in the boundaries of the the National Aviation Heritage Area.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
