<bill session="110" type="h" number="4191" updated="2009-01-09T01:35:33-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1204776600" datetime="2008-03-05T12:10:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="91"/></status>

	<introduced date="1195102800" datetime="2007-11-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Wright Brothers-Dunbar National Historical Park Designation Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Wright Brothers-Dunbar National Historical Park Designation Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To redesignate Dayton Aviation Heritage National Historic Park in the State of Ohio as &quot;Wright Brothers-Dunbar National Historic Park&quot;, and for other purposes.</title>
		<title type="official" as="amended by house">To redesignate the Dayton Aviation Heritage National Historical Park in the State of Ohio as the &quot;Wright Brothers-Dunbar National Historical Park&quot;, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400411"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1195102800" datetime="2007-11-15"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1195534800" datetime="2007-11-20"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action date="1204656420" datetime="2008-03-04T14:47:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Rahall moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text></action>
		<action date="1204656420" datetime="2008-03-04T14:47:00-05:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H1203-1204"/></action>
		<action date="1204656420" datetime="2008-03-04T14:47:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4191.</text></action>
		<action date="1204656840" datetime="2008-03-04T14:54:00-05:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1204731900" datetime="2008-03-05T11:45:00-05:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H1239-1240"/></action>
		<vote date="1204776600" how="roll" roll="91" datetime="2008-03-05T12:10:00-05:00" where="h" type="vote" suspension="1" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 407 - 4 (Roll no. 91). (text: CR 3/4/2008 H1203)</text></vote>
		<action date="1204776600" datetime="2008-03-05T12:10:00-05:00"><text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action date="1204779600" datetime="2008-03-06"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/5/2008--Passed House without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Wright Brothers-Dunbar National Historic Park Designation Act - Amends the Dayton Aviation Heritage Preservation Act of 1992 to: (1) rename the Dayton Aviation Heritage National Historical Park as the Wright Brothers-Dunbar National Historic Park; and (2) authorize the Secretary of the Interior to make grants to partners of the Park, including the Aviation Trail, Inc., the Ohio Historical Society, and Dayton History, for projects not requiring federal involvement other than providing financial assistance and which shall be limited to construction and development on non-federal property within the boundaries of the Park for projects that support the purposes of the Park.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
