<bill session="110" type="h" number="4201" updated="2009-01-09T01:36:41-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1195102800" datetime="2007-11-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1195102800" datetime="2007-11-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Justice for the Newark College Students Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require State and local law enforcement agencies to determine the immigration status of all individuals arrested by such agencies for a felony, to require such agencies to report to the Secretary of Homeland Security when they have arrested for a felony an alien unlawfully present in the United States, to require mandatory Federal detention of such individuals pending removal in cases where they are not otherwise detained, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400648"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400627" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400061" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400367" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400183" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400660" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412234" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400385" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400633" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400332" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400116" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2008-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="409888" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400662" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400254" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400652" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400433" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400288" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400285" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400359" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400147" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400051" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400220" joined="2008-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400131" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400570" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400076" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400244" joined="2008-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400032" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400651" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400321" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400656" joined="2007-11-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1195102800" datetime="2007-11-15"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1203915600" datetime="2008-02-25"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/15/2007--Introduced.<br/>Justice for the Newark College Students Act - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to require: (1) the Secretary of Homeland Security (current law refers to the Attorney General) to make investigative resources available to state and local law enforcement agencies to determine whether an individual arrested for a felony or an aggravated felony (current law refers to only an aggravated felony) is unlawfully in the United States; (2) state and local agencies to use such information to determine whether an arrested individual is unlawfully in the United States and to provide the appropriate court with such information; (3) the court to report such case's disposition to the Department of Homeland Security (DHS); and (4) mandatory federal detention of such individuals pending removal, and release only in furtherance of the felony case for which the arrest was made. 
	</summary>
</bill>
