<bill session="110" type="h" number="4214" updated="2009-01-09T01:38:10-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1195102800" datetime="2007-11-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1195102800" datetime="2007-11-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Community and Healthcare-Associated Infections Reduction Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the prevention, detection, and treatment of community and healthcare-associated infections (CHAI), with a focus on antibiotic-resistant bacteria.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400090"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412212" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400043" joined="2007-12-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400349" joined="2007-12-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1195102800" datetime="2007-11-15"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1195102800" datetime="2007-11-15"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/15/2007--Introduced.<br/>Community and Healthcare-Associated Infections Reduction Act of 2007 - Directs the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ), in collaboration with the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to develop best-practices guidelines for internal infection control plans to prevent, detect, control, and treat community and healthcare-associated infections at hospitals.<br/>Requires AHRQ to: (1) establish best practices with supporting justification, including the establishment of an infection control oversight committee; (2) collaborate with other agencies and organizations whose area of expertise is the identification, treatment, and prevention of infectious disease; (3) publish proposed guidelines; (4) provide for a comment period of not less than 90 days; and (5) establish final guidelines. Directs the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services to: (1) consult best practices guidelines in evaluating hospitals' infection control plans as a condition of participation in the Medicare program; and (2) report to Congress on the feasibility of reducing healthcare-associated infection rates through a Quality Improvement Payment Program. Requires: (1) hospitals to report information about community and healthcare-associated infections to the CDC National Healthcare Safety Network, which shall be used by the CDC to develop a national database of infection rates in hospitals; (2) the Director of the CDC to award grants to states to carry out public awareness campaigns; (3) the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to expand and intensify NIH programs regarding research and related activities concerning such infections; (4) the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish an interagency working group on community and healthcare-associated infections; and (5) the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to report to Congress on this Act's impact.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
