<bill session="110" type="h" number="4219" updated="2009-01-09T01:38:48-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1195102800" datetime="2007-11-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1195102800" datetime="2007-11-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Immediate Benefits for Wounded Warriors Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to assign a temporary disability rating to certain members of the Armed Forces upon separation, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412205"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400414" joined="2007-11-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1195102800" datetime="2007-11-15"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1195189200" datetime="2007-11-16"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/15/2007--Introduced.<br/>Immediate Benefits for Wounded Warriors Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, for purposes of the laws administered by the Secretary and at the request of an eligible member of the Armed Forces who has served on active duty in support of Operation Iraqi Freedom or Operation Enduring Freedom, to assign to that member a 30% temporary disability rating upon such member's separation from the Armed Forces, or in the case of an eligible member who has received a medical diagnosis of post traumatic stress disorder or traumatic brain injury, upon receipt of such diagnosis. States that upon assignment of a permanent disability rating to a member who has received such temporary rating: (1) if the permanent rating exceeds 30% payments shall be made for such &quot;temporary rating months&quot; to equal the payments under the higher permanent rating; and (2) if the permanent rating is less than 30% the member shall not be required to repay such amounts. States that disability compensation payments received by a member who receives such temporary disability rating are not subject to offset even though the member also receives separation or disability severance pay.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
