<bill session="110" type="h" number="423" updated="2009-01-08T17:39:08-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1168491600" datetime="2007-01-11"/></status>

	<introduced date="1168491600" datetime="2007-01-11"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Kristen's Act Reauthorization of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Attorney General to provide grants for organizations to find missing adults.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400288"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400219" joined="2007-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400257" joined="2007-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400380" joined="2007-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400342" joined="2008-06-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400332" joined="2008-06-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400344" joined="2007-03-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400063" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400196" joined="2007-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2008-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400071" joined="2008-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400264" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="2008-07-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400652" joined="2007-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400051" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400172" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400110" joined="2008-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2007-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="2008-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="412240" joined="2007-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400422" joined="2008-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400400" joined="2008-06-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400328" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400009" joined="2007-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="412213" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400310" joined="2007-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400182" joined="2008-06-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400435" joined="2008-06-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1168491600" datetime="2007-01-11"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1170392400" datetime="2007-02-02"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text></action>
		<action date="1216094400" datetime="2008-07-15"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/11/2007--Introduced.<br/>Kristen's Act Reauthorization of 2007- Directs the Attorney General, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance, to make grants to public agencies and/or nonprofit private organizations to: (1) maintain a national resource center and information clearinghouse for missing and unidentified adults; (2) maintain a national, interconnected database for tracking missing adults who are determined by law enforcement to be endangered due to age, diminished mental capacity, or the circumstances of disappearance, when foul play is suspected or circumstances are unknown; (3) coordinate public and private programs that locate or recover missing adults or reunite missing adults with their families; (4) provide assistance and training to law enforcement agencies, State and local governments, elements of the criminal justice system, nonprofit organizations, and individuals in the prevention, investigation, prosecution, and treatment of cases involving missing adults; (5) provide assistance to families in locating and recovering missing adults; and (6) assist in public notification and victim advocacy related to missing adults.<br/>Directs the Attorney General, through the Director, to: (1) coordinate Government-funded programs relating to missing adults; and (2) provide the public agencies or nonprofit private organizations receiving grants to maintain a national resource center and information clearinghouse for missing and unidentified adults with access to the Federal Bureau of Investigation's National Crime Information Center.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
