<bill session="110" type="h" number="4245" updated="2009-01-09T01:41:58-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1195102800" datetime="2007-11-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1195102800" datetime="2007-11-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Saving American Lives and Investing in Protecting Land And Nature Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003 to provide for the categorical exclusion of certain projects on Federal land located adjacent to non-Federal land from documentation in an environmental impact statement or environmental assessment when conditions on the Federal land pose a serious risk to the non-Federal land, to authorize the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior to enter into contracts or agreements for forest projects on Federal land with non-Federal entities that own adjacent land, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412201"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400330" joined="2008-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400176" joined="2008-06-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412191" joined="2008-06-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1195102800" datetime="2007-11-15"><text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1195102800" datetime="2007-11-15"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action date="1195102800" datetime="2007-11-15"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1195534800" datetime="2007-11-20"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action date="1209096000" datetime="2008-04-25"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/15/2007--Introduced.<br/>Saving American Lives and Investing in Protecting Land and Nature Act - Amends the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003 to allow the categorical exclusion of authorized hazardous fuel reduction projects and other forest projects that are proposed to be conducted on adjacent federal land or that are recommended in community wildfire protection plans from documentation in an environmental impact statement or environmental assessment when: (1) the project is consistent with the resource management plan; and (2) the decision to categorically exclude the project is made according to extraordinary circumstances procedures. Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior to enter into contracts and agreements with non-federal entities to conduct authorized hazardous fuel reduction projects and other projects that are proposed to be conducted on federal land that is within not more than 1 1/2 miles of non-federal land owned by the non-federal entity or that is covered by community wildfire protection plans that also cover such non-federal land when: (1) the conditions on the federal land, such as the risk of wildfire, an insect or disease epidemic, or the presence of invasive species, pose a risk to the adjacent federal land; (2) the contract or agreement is in the government's and landowner's interest and will promote the goals of this Act; and (3) the project is consistent with the resource management plan. 
	</summary>
</bill>
