<bill session="110" type="h" number="4246" updated="2009-01-09T01:42:05-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1195102800" datetime="2007-11-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1195102800" datetime="2007-11-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Defense Trade Controls Performance Improvement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the performance of the defense trade controls functions of the Department of State, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400371"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400034" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400122" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400271" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400040" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400055" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400087" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412239" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400363" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400252" joined="2007-11-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1195102800" datetime="2007-11-15"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/15/2007--Introduced.<br/>Defense Trade Controls Performance Improvement Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of State to: (1) perform a strategic review and assessment of the U.S. export controls system; (2) provide for specified performance requirements respecting license applications to export or import United States Munitions List items; (3) ensure that the Directorate of Defense Trade Controls of the Department of State has the necessary staff and resources; (4) ensure that all items on the Missile Technology Control Regime Annex are subject to stringent government control. Requires that the Directorate establish a secure Internet-based system for tracking the progress of munitions list license applications. Directs the President, under specified conditions, to waive certain licensing requirements for exports of spare and replacement parts or components and related services of defense items exported to North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) member states, Australia, Japan, and New Zealand. Sets forth Department of Commerce and Department of State export controls for civil aircraft products.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
