<bill session="110" type="h" number="4255" updated="2009-01-09T01:43:06-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1217544780" datetime="2008-07-31T19:53:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1196744400" datetime="2007-12-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">United States Olympic Committee Paralympic Program Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">United States Olympic Committee Paralympic Program Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">United States Olympic Committee Paralympic Program Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide assistance to the Paralympic Program of the United States Olympic Committee, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400133"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400414" joined="2008-06-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400040" joined="2008-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412189" joined="2008-06-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400230" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400172" joined="2008-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400013" joined="2008-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412222" joined="2008-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400350" joined="2008-01-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400056" joined="2008-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400266" joined="2008-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2007-12-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1196744400" datetime="2007-12-04"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2485)</text></action>
		<action date="1196744400" datetime="2007-12-04"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1197003600" datetime="2007-12-07"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30"><text>Subcommittee on Health Discharged.</text></action>
		<action date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text></action>
		<action date="1213848000" datetime="2008-06-19"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text></action>
		<action date="1216180800" datetime="2008-07-16"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1216180800" datetime="2008-07-16" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1216934040" datetime="2008-07-24T18:14:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 110-774.</text></action>
		<calendar number="493" date="1216934040" datetime="2008-07-24T18:14:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 493.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1217362500" datetime="2008-07-29T17:15:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Hare moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1217362500" datetime="2008-07-29T17:15:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H7246-7248"/></action>
		<action date="1217362500" datetime="2008-07-29T17:15:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4255.</text></action>
		<action date="1217363040" datetime="2008-07-29T17:24:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Boozman objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text></action>
		<action date="1217544780" datetime="2008-07-31T19:53:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H7707"/></action>
		<vote date="1217544780" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-07-31T19:53:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote. (text: CR 7/29/2008 H7246-7247)</text></vote>
		<action date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/31/2008--Passed House amended. United States Olympic Committee Paralympic Program Act of 2008 - Authorizes the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to make a grant to the U.S. Olympic Committee (USOC) to plan, develop, manage, and implement the Paralympic Program (Program) for disabled veterans and disabled members of the Armed Forces (members). Directs the USOC to use a grant to recruit, support, encourage, schedule, facilitate, supervise, and implement paralympic instruction and competition activities, training and technical assistance, and coordination and program development activities for such disabled veterans and members. Requires: (1) the Secretary to conduct an outreach program to inform eligible veterans and separating members about the Program; and (2) a memorandum of understanding or cooperative agreement between the Secretary and the USOC regarding Program implementation. Authorizes appropriations. Establishes in the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) an Office of National Veterans Sports Programs and Special Events, headed by a Director, to carry out qualifying programs and events for disabled veterans and members. Authorizes the Director to provide an allowance for a disabled veteran for each month in which the veteran is training or competing in a USOC-sanctioned event or residing at a USOC training center. Authorizes appropriations. Requires the Secretary to direct the VA's Under Secretary for Health to: (1) make VA medical staff available to facilitate veteran participation in USOC sporting events; (2) allow such personnel to participate in the Program without requiring the use of personal leave; and (3) support other similar activities or events.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
