<bill session="110" type="h" number="4280" updated="2009-01-09T01:45:55-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1196830800" datetime="2007-12-05"/></status>

	<introduced date="1196830800" datetime="2007-12-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Aerial Firefighter Relief Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 to provide death and disability benefits for aerial firefighters who work on a contract basis for the Forest Service or an agency of the Department of the Interior and suffer death or disability in the line of duty, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400088"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400620" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400257" joined="2007-12-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400403" joined="2007-12-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400313" joined="2008-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400297" joined="2008-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400396" joined="2007-12-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400245" joined="2007-12-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400039" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412206" joined="2008-02-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1196830800" datetime="2007-12-05"><text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1196830800" datetime="2007-12-05"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1196830800" datetime="2007-12-05"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action date="1196830800" datetime="2007-12-05"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1197262800" datetime="2007-12-10"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action date="1200286800" datetime="2008-01-14"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text></action>
		<action date="1209096000" datetime="2008-04-25"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	12/5/2007--Introduced.<br/>Aerial Firefighter Relief Act of 2007 - Amends the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 to provide for death and disability benefits for aerial firefighters who serve the Forest Service or any agency of the Department of the Interior and suffer death or disability in the line of duty. Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to provide for similar eligibility of aerial firefighters for public safety officer death benefits, applicable to a public agency.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
