<bill session="110" type="h" number="4331" updated="2009-01-09T01:52:14-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1196917200" datetime="2007-12-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1196917200" datetime="2007-12-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Attacking Viral Influenza Across Nations Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act with respect to preparation for an influenza pandemic, including an avian influenza pandemic, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400246"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1196917200" datetime="2007-12-06"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1196917200" datetime="2007-12-06"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1196917200" datetime="2007-12-06"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1196917200" datetime="2007-12-06"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action date="1209096000" datetime="2008-04-25"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry.</text></action>
		<action date="1209096000" datetime="2008-04-25"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Horticulture and Organic Agriculture.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	12/6/2007--Introduced.<br/>Attacking Viral Influenza Across Nations Act of 2008 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to submit to the Director of the World Health Organization (WHO) a proposal related to establishing a Pandemic Fund for countries affected by pandemic influenza. Establishes the Pandemic Influenza Preparedness Policy Coordinating Committee to develop an Interagency Preparedness Plan. Requires the Secretary to strengthen, expand, and coordinate domestic pandemic influenza preparedness activities. Requires states to have an approved state preparedness plan as a condition of receiving funds related to bioterrorism from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) or the Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA). Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of CDC and the Administrator of HRSA, to integrate and coordinate public and private influenza surveillance activities. Directs the Secretary to: (1) procure doses of antivirals and developed vaccines needed during pandemic influenza for the Strategic National Stockpile; and (2) assist other counties in preparation for, and response to, pandemic influenza. Allows the Secretary to provide vaccines, antiviral medications, and supplies from the Stockpile to foreign countries. Requires the Secretary to develop and disseminate pandemic influenza training curricula for health professionals and non-medical volunteers. Requires the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) and the Director of CDC to expand and intensify influenza research. Directs the Secretary to contract with the Institute of Medicine to study topics related to the pandemic influenza. Establishes the National Pandemic Influenza Economics Advisory Committee. Requires the Secretary of Agriculture to expand and intensify efforts to prevent pandemic influenza.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
