<bill session="110" type="h" number="4336" updated="2009-01-09T01:52:49-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1196917200" datetime="2007-12-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1196917200" datetime="2007-12-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Safe Aviation and Flight Enhancement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Transportation to issue a regulation requiring the installation of a second cockpit voice recorder and digital flight data recorder system that utilizes combination deployable recorder technology in certain commercial passenger aircraft.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400326"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400080" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400063" joined="2007-12-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400116" joined="2007-12-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400040" joined="2007-12-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400152" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400442" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400001" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400346" joined="2007-12-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400340" joined="2007-12-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400400" joined="2007-12-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400125" joined="2007-12-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2008-01-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400309" joined="2007-12-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1196917200" datetime="2007-12-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text></action>
		<action date="1196917200" datetime="2007-12-06"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	12/6/2007--Introduced.<br/>Safe Aviation and Flight Enhancement Act of 2007 - Amends federal transportation law to direct the Secretary of Transportation to issue regulations requiring all commercial aircraft in extended-range operations that must carry fixed cockpit voice recorder and digital flight data recorder units to also be equipped with a second recorder system that utilizes deployable combination cockpit voice and digital flight data recording technology. Requires the second deployable recorder system to be mounted as far rear on the airframe as practicable. Sets forth minimum deployable recorder capabilities. Directs the Secretary to reimburse an air carrier for the costs of purchasing and installing such deployable recorder systems for it to comply with regulations.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
