<bill session="110" type="h" number="4462" updated="2009-01-09T02:07:49-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1197435600" datetime="2007-12-12"/></status>

	<introduced date="1197435600" datetime="2007-12-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Code Talkers Recognition Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the award of a congressional gold medal on behalf of the Native Americans who served as Code Talkers during foreign conflicts in which the United States was involved during the 20th Century in recognition of their heroic and dramatic contributions to the Nation, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400157"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400041" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400336" joined="2007-12-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="412225" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400295" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400129" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400316" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400010" joined="2008-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400068" joined="2007-12-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400399" joined="2007-12-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400440" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400042" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400218" joined="2007-12-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400215" joined="2007-12-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400088" joined="2008-01-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400435" joined="2007-12-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1197435600" datetime="2007-12-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text></action>
		<action date="1206676800" datetime="2008-03-28"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy, Trade, and Technology.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	12/12/2007--Introduced.<br/>Code Talkers Recognition Act - Directs the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate to arrange for: (1) the award on behalf of Congress of a single gold medal of appropriate design to honor the Native American members of the U.S. Armed Forces, collectively, who served as Code Talkers in any foreign conflict in which the United States was involved during the 20th century for display in the Smithsonian Institution; and (2) presentation of a gold duplicate of such medal to each Indian tribe that had tribal members who served as such Code Talkers. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to strike: (1) silver duplicates for transmittal to each individual who served as a Code Talker (or next of kin); and (2) bronze duplicates for public sale.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
