<bill session="110" type="h" number="446" updated="2009-01-08T17:42:29-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1168578000" datetime="2007-01-12"/></status>

	<introduced date="1168578000" datetime="2007-01-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Christopher and Dana Reeve Quality of Life for Persons with Paralysis Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance and further research into paralysis and to improve rehabilitation and the quality of life for persons living with paralysis and other physical disabilities, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412250"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400160" joined="2007-01-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400271" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400268" joined="2007-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400406" joined="2007-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2007-01-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-04-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="412204" joined="2007-06-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412219" joined="2007-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400179" joined="2007-01-30"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1168578000" datetime="2007-01-12"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1168578000" datetime="2007-01-12"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1168578000" datetime="2007-01-12"><text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1170392400" datetime="2007-02-02"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1172811600" datetime="2007-03-02"><committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/12/2007--Introduced.<br/>Christopher and Dana Reeve Quality of Life for Persons with Paralysis Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to permit the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH): (1) acting through the Director of the National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke, to expand and coordinate NIH activities on paralysis research; (2) to award grants to plan, establish, improve, and provide basic operating support for Christopher Reeve Paralysis Research Consortia; (3) to educate and disseminate information and receive public comment on NIH programs and research regarding paralysis; (4) acting through the Director of the National Institute on Child Health and Human Development and the National Center for Rehabilitation Research, to expand and coordinate NIH research with implications for enhancing daily function for persons with paralysis; and (5) to make grants to plan, establish, improve, and provide basic operating support for multicenter clinical trial networks to design clinical rehabilitation intervention protocols and measures of outcomes on paralysis. Permits the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to study the health challenges associated with paralysis and other physical disabilities and carry out projects and interventions to improve the quality of life and long-term health status of individuals with such conditions. Permits the Secretary to award grants for activities related to paralysis, including to: (1) establish paralysis registries; and (2) disseminate information to the public. Allows the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to: (1) establish Paralysis Research, Education and Clinical Care Centers; and (2) award grants to medical centers of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to translate clinical findings and recommendations on paralysis into evidence-based best practices.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
