<bill session="110" type="h" number="4541" updated="2009-01-09T02:17:05-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1197522000" datetime="2007-12-13"/></status>

	<introduced date="1197522000" datetime="2007-12-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Part D Long-Term Care Patient Protection Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for patient protections under the Medicare prescription drug program for residents of long term care facilities.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400633"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400421" joined="2008-02-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1197522000" datetime="2007-12-13"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1197522000" datetime="2007-12-13"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1197522000" datetime="2007-12-13"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1197522000" datetime="2007-12-13"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	12/13/2007--Introduced.<br/>Medicare Part D Long-Term Care Patient Protection Act of 2007 - Amends part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to provide a long-term care pharmacy benefit under Medicare part D. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a process for the immediate enrollment of part D eligible individuals in a prescription drug plan upon the individual's establishment as a resident of a long-term care facility. Eliminates part D cost-sharing for certain non-institutionalized full-benefit dual eligible individuals.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
