<bill session="110" type="h" number="455" updated="2009-01-08T17:43:37-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1168578000" datetime="2007-01-12"/></status>

	<introduced date="1168578000" datetime="2007-01-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Protect the Troops and Bring Them Home Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the protection of members of the United States Armed Forces and for their withdrawal from Iraq by December 31, 2007.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400289"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400063" joined="2007-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="2007-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400130" joined="2007-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="2007-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="412222" joined="2007-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400251" joined="2007-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2007-01-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2007-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400366" joined="2007-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400301" joined="2007-02-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1168578000" datetime="2007-01-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/12/2007--Introduced.<br/>Protect the Troops and Bring Them Home Act of 2007 - Allows funds made available to the Department of Defense (DOD) to be obligated or expended within the Republic of Iraq only for providing: (1) the continued protection of members of the Armed Forces in Iraq pending their withdrawal; and (2) the safe and orderly withdrawal of such troops pursuant to a schedule that provides for withdrawal commencement no later than 30 days after the enactment of this Act and withdrawal completion no later than December 31, 2007. Prohibits any DOD funds from being obligated or expended to increase the number of Armed Forces serving in Iraq at any time. Permits the obligation or expenditure of funds to ensure the security of Iraq and its transition to democratic rule through specified consultations, financial or equipment assistance, or economic or reconstruction assistance.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
