<bill session="110" type="h" number="4652" updated="2009-01-09T02:38:19-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1197522000" datetime="2007-12-13"/></status>

	<introduced date="1197522000" datetime="2007-12-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Environmental Justice Access and Implementation Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To direct each Federal agency to establish an Environmental Justice Office, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400170"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400661" joined="2008-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400073" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400227" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400257" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400289" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400080" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412221" joined="2008-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400623" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400430" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400424" joined="2008-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="2008-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400101" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400384" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400412" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400048" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400308" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400270" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400259" joined="2008-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400251" joined="2008-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412232" joined="2008-06-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400217" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2008-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400366" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400074" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400638" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412228" joined="2008-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400208" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400024" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400025" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400179" joined="2007-12-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1197522000" datetime="2007-12-13"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2568)</text></action>
		<action date="1197522000" datetime="2007-12-13"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1197522000" datetime="2007-12-13"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1197522000" datetime="2007-12-13"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
		<action date="1197522000" datetime="2007-12-13"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	12/13/2007--Introduced.<br/>Environmental Justice Access and Implementation Act of 2007 - Requires specified federal agencies to establish an Office of Environmental Justice pursuant to Executive Order 12898 (concerning federal actions to address environmental justice in minority and low-income populations).<br/>Defines &quot;environmental justice&quot; as the fair treatment and meaningful involvement of all people regardless of race, color, national origin, educational level, or income in the development, implementation, and enforcement of environmental laws and regulations. Requires the inclusion of minority and low-income populations with health vulnerabilities and exposure to certain environmental conditions in criteria for defining an environmental justice community. Requires federal agencies to integrate the environmental justice strategy developed under Executive Order 12898 into their operations and missions and explicitly address compliance with this Act. Directs the Interagency Federal Working Group on Environmental Justice (Working Group) to coordinate an integrated environmental justice training plan for federal agencies.<br/>Requires federal agencies subject to the requirements of this Act to carry out certain outreach activities relating to environmental justice and to report on such activities to the Working Group.<br/>Directs federal agencies to fund and establish community technology centers to provide technical assistance and other services in the environmental justice area.<br/>Requires the President and the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to provide certain reports to Congress relating to environmental justice. 
	</summary>
</bill>
