<bill session="110" type="h" number="4660" updated="2009-01-09T02:39:18-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1197522000" datetime="2007-12-13"/></status>

	<introduced date="1197522000" datetime="2007-12-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Detainee Interrogation Recording Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require the videotaping of strategic interrogations and certain other interactions between detainees and members of the Armed Forces, intelligence operatives, and contractors, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400184"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-01-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400129" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400396" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2008-01-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="2007-12-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1197522000" datetime="2007-12-13"><text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1197522000" datetime="2007-12-13"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1197522000" datetime="2007-12-13"><text>Referred to House Intelligence (Permanent Select)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	12/13/2007--Introduced.<br/>Detainee Interrogation Recording Act of 2007 - Requires the President to take such actions as are necessary, in accordance with specified laws and treaties, to ensure the videotaping of each strategic interrogation and other pertinent interaction between detainees or prisoners under the effective control of the U.S. and members of the Armed Forces, U.S. intelligence operatives, or U.S. contractors. Directs the President to provide for the appropriate classification of videotapes or recordings made under that requirement. Requires such videotapes to be made available, under seal if appropriate, to both prosecution and defense attorneys to the extent that they are material to any military or civilian criminal proceeding. Defines strategic interrogation as an interrogation at: (1) a corps or theater-level detention facility; or (2) a detention facility outside of the area where the detainee or prisoner was initially captured, including one owned, operated, borrowed, or leased by the U.S. government and a detention facility of a foreign government. Prohibits construing this Act to require videotaping during direct tactical combat operations. Requires the President to ensure that representatives of the Red Cross and the Red Crescent are granted access to detainees or prisoners in the custody or effective control of the Armed Forces. Directs the Judge Advocates General to jointly develop guidelines to ensure that the videotaping required by this Act is sufficiently expansive to prevent any abuse of detainees and prisoners and violations of specified laws and treaties.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
