<bill session="110" type="h" number="466" updated="2009-01-08T17:44:56-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1168578000" datetime="2007-01-12"/></status>

	<introduced date="1168578000" datetime="2007-01-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Congressional Pension Accountability Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 5, United States Code, to deny Federal retirement benefits to individuals convicted of certain offenses, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400368"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400134" joined="2007-01-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400385" joined="2007-01-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400320" joined="2007-01-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400145" joined="2007-01-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400351" joined="2007-01-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400182" joined="2007-01-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400434" joined="2007-01-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1168578000" datetime="2007-01-12"><text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1168578000" datetime="2007-01-12"><text>Referred to House House Administration</text></action>
		<action date="1168578000" datetime="2007-01-12"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/12/2007--Introduced.<br/>Congressional Pension Accountability Act - Prohibits a Member of Congress, or a survivor or beneficiary, from receiving an annuity or retired pay if such Member is: (1) convicted of bribery of public officials and witnesses, conspiracy either to commit any offense against the United States or to defraud the United States, perjury, or subornation of perjury; or (2) indicted or has outstanding charges under the Uniform Code of Military Justice. Defines &quot;Member of Congress&quot; as the Vice President, a member of the Senate or the House of Representatives, a Delegate to the House of Representatives, and the Resident Commissioner from Puerto Rico.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
