<bill session="110" type="h" number="467" updated="2009-01-08T17:45:02-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1173118860" datetime="2007-03-05T14:21:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1168578000" datetime="2007-01-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Southern Idaho Bureau of Reclamation Repayment Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Southern Idaho Bureau of Reclamation Repayment Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize early repayment of obligations to the Bureau of Reclamation within the A &amp; B Irrigation District in the State of Idaho.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400376"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1168578000" datetime="2007-01-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text></action>
		<action date="1173118680" datetime="2007-03-05T14:18:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Grijalva moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1173118740" datetime="2007-03-05T14:19:00-05:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2126"/></action>
		<action date="1173118740" datetime="2007-03-05T14:19:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 467.</text></action>
		<vote date="1173118860" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-03-05T14:21:00-05:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H2126"/></vote>
		<action date="1173157200" datetime="2007-03-06"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/5/2007--Passed House amended. Southern Idaho Bureau of Reclamation Repayment Act of 2007 - Authorizes any owner of land within the A&amp;amp;B Irrigation District in Idaho to repay at any time the construction costs of District project facilities that are allocated to such land. Provides that, upon full payment of such costs, the parcels shall not be subject to specified ownership and full-cost pricing limitations under federal reclamation law, for which the Secretary shall, upon request, provide the landowner a certificate.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
