<bill session="110" type="h" number="4688" updated="2009-01-09T02:42:34-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1197522000" datetime="2007-12-13"/></status>

	<introduced date="1197522000" datetime="2007-12-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Tribal Foster Care and Adoption Access Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend part E of title IV of the Social Security Act to provide equitable access for foster care and adoption services for Indian children in tribal areas, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400323"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400123" joined="2008-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400041" joined="2008-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400336" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400058" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2008-02-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400124" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400003" joined="2008-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400412" joined="2008-02-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400130" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400316" joined="2008-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400324" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="412204" joined="2008-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2008-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400310" joined="2008-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400240" joined="2008-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400024" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400186" joined="2008-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400429" joined="2007-12-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1197522000" datetime="2007-12-13"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	12/13/2007--Introduced.<br/>Tribal Foster Care and Adoption Access Act of 2007 - Amends part E (Federal Payments for Foster Care and Adoption Assistance) of title IV of the Social Security Act to authorize an Indian tribe, tribal organization, or tribal consortium (tribe) operating a foster care program to receive federal foster care maintenance payments for children placed in its custody if the tribe: (1) operates a foster care program under part E; (2) has a cooperative agreement with the state for such purpose; or (3) submits a description of the arrangements made for the payment of funds and the provision of the required child welfare services and protections. Specifies provisions for the modification of plans and certain other requirements regarding the operation of foster care programs. Authorizes, with respect to the John H. Chafee Foster Care Independence Program: (1) a tribe with an approved part E plan to receive a prescribed allotment to administer, supervise, or oversee plan programs; and (2) each tribe in a state that does not receive such an allotment to enter into a cooperative agreement with the state to administer, supervise, or oversee the programs to be carried out under the state's plan with respect to Indian children and to receive a portion of the state's allotment for the cost of such administration, supervision, and oversight. 
	</summary>
</bill>
