<bill session="110" type="h" number="4690" updated="2009-01-09T02:42:49-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1197522000" datetime="2007-12-13"/></status>

	<introduced date="1197522000" datetime="2007-12-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Bluffton University Safety Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration to issue motor vehicle safety standards for motorcoaches, and to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a tax credit for associated expenses incurred by motorcoach operators complying with such standards.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="409888"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400116" joined="2008-06-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400426" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412186" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400204" joined="2008-03-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1197522000" datetime="2007-12-13"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, Small Business, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1197522000" datetime="2007-12-13"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1197522000" datetime="2007-12-13"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text></action>
		<action date="1197522000" datetime="2007-12-13"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1197522000" datetime="2007-12-13"><text>Referred to House Small Business</text></action>
		<action date="1197522000" datetime="2007-12-13"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1197608400" datetime="2007-12-14"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	12/13/2007--Introduced.<br/>Bluffton University Safety Act of 2007 - Amends federal transportation law to direct the Secretary of Transportation (Secretary) to prescribe federal motor vehicle safety standards for occupant protection systems for new and existing motorcoaches. Directs the Secretary to carry out, and submit to Congress, an independent study on the passenger safety benefits of three-point passenger safety restraints and compartmentalization in motorcoaches and whether the use of one methodology reduces or enhances passenger safety benefits of the other methodology. Expresses the sense of Congress that it is in the public interest for states to adopt and enforce mandatory seat belt use laws that require the use of seat belts. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide a qualified motorcoach safety credit to a taxpayer for the costs of new and existing motorcoaches to comply with the federal motor vehicle safety standards. Requires the Secretary to provide grants (not to exceed $20,000) to motorcoach operators to assist with the cost of retrofitting motorcoaches in order to comply with such federal standards. Amends the Small Business Act to grant the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) the authority to make SBA loans and loan guarantees to motorcoach operators to retrofit their buses and motorcoaches for occupant protection.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
