<bill session="110" type="h" number="481" updated="2009-01-08T17:46:49-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1168923600" datetime="2007-01-16"/></status>

	<introduced date="1168923600" datetime="2007-01-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Election Integrity Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to require each individual who desires to vote in an election for Federal office to provide the appropriate election official with a government-issued photo identification, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400113"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400123" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400061" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400060" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400626" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400089" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400242" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400151" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400633" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400049" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400071" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400040" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400264" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400029" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400433" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400055" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400206" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400017" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412235" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400287" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400220" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400131" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412216" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400570" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400643" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400005" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400221" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400145" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400016" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400315" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400651" joined="2007-11-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1168923600" datetime="2007-01-16"><text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/16/2007--Introduced.<br/>Federal Election Integrity Act of 2007 - Amends the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to prohibit the appropriate state or local election official from providing a federal election ballot to an individual who desires to vote in person unless the individual presents to the official: (1) a government-issued, current, and valid photo identification (ID); or (2) for regularly scheduled federal general elections held in November 2010 and subsequent years, a government-issued, current, and valid photo ID for which the individual was required to provide proof of U.S. citizenship as a condition for issuance of the ID. Requires an individual who does not present such an ID to be permitted to cast a provisional ballot in such an election. Requires such individual, however, to present the required ID within 48 hours after casting the provisional ballot, or the appropriate state or local election official may not determine the individual's eligibility to vote.<br/>Requires individuals who vote other than in person in a federal election (for example, by mail) to submit a copy of such a photo ID with a ballot, or the appropriate official may not accept the ballot. Exempts from this requirement the absentee ballot of any eligible overseas military voter absent from the United States by reason of active duty or service.<br/>Requires states to establish a program to provide photo IDs in accordance with this Act to individuals who desire to vote but do not otherwise possess a government-issued photo ID. Prescribes requirements for any state fee for providing such a photo ID. Requires the Election Assistance Commission to make payments to states to cover the costs incurred in providing photo IDs to individuals unable to afford the fee.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
