<bill session="110" type="h" number="4828" updated="2009-01-09T02:58:51-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1222300620" datetime="2008-09-24T20:57:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1197954000" datetime="2007-12-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Palo Alto Battlefield National Historic Site Boundary Expansion Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Palo Alto Battlefield National Historical Park Boundary Expansion and Redesignation Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Palo Alto Battlefield National Historic Site Act of 1991 to expand the boundaries of the historic site, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400302"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400152" joined="2008-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400009" joined="2008-07-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1197954000" datetime="2007-12-18"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1199250000" datetime="2008-01-02"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action date="1212638400" datetime="2008-06-05"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1216180800" datetime="2008-07-16"><text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands Discharged.</text></action>
		<action date="1216180800" datetime="2008-07-16"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1216180800" datetime="2008-07-16" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1217368020" datetime="2008-07-29T18:47:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-791.</text></action>
		<calendar number="509" date="1217368080" datetime="2008-07-29T18:48:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 509.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1222099860" datetime="2008-09-22T13:11:00-04:00"><text>Ms. Bordallo moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1222099860" datetime="2008-09-22T13:11:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8495-8496"/></action>
		<action date="1222099860" datetime="2008-09-22T13:11:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4828.</text></action>
		<action date="1222100280" datetime="2008-09-22T13:18:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Young (AK) objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text></action>
		<action date="1222300620" datetime="2008-09-24T20:57:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H9406"/></action>
		<vote date="1222300620" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-09-24T20:57:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote. (CR 9/22/2008 H8495)</text></vote>
		<action date="1222315200" datetime="2008-09-25"><text>Received in the Senate.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/29/2008--Reported to House amended. Palo Alto Battlefield National Historical Park Boundary Expansion and Redesignation Act of 2008 - Redesignates the Palo Alto Battlefield National Historic Site (located in Brownsville, Texas, and dedicated to the preservation and interpretation of the Mexican-American War) as the &quot;Palo Alto Battlefield National Historical Park.&quot; Amends the Palo Alto Battlefield National Historic Site Act of 1991 to expand the boundaries of the Park to include certain land. 
	</summary>
</bill>
