<bill session="110" type="h" number="4832" updated="2009-01-09T02:59:25-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1197954000" datetime="2007-12-18"/></status>

	<introduced date="1197954000" datetime="2007-12-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Wildland Fire Safety and Transparency Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To promote wildland firefighter safety.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400412"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1197954000" datetime="2007-12-18"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2599)</text></action>
		<action date="1197954000" datetime="2007-12-18"><text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1197954000" datetime="2007-12-18"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1197954000" datetime="2007-12-18"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action date="1199250000" datetime="2008-01-02"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action date="1209096000" datetime="2008-04-25"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	12/18/2007--Introduced.<br/>Wildland Fire Safety and Transparency Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Directors of the Bureau of Land Management (BLM), U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service (FWS), and the Bureau of Indian Affairs (BIA), and the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service, (the Secretaries) to jointly submit annual reports to Congress on the wildland firefighter safety practices of the Secretaries, including training programs and activities for wildland fire suppression, prescribed burning, and wildland fire use. 
	</summary>
</bill>
