<bill session="110" type="h" number="4836" updated="2009-01-09T02:59:53-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1197954000" datetime="2007-12-18"/></status>

	<introduced date="1197954000" datetime="2007-12-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Diabetes Coordinator Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To reduce the incidence, progression, and impact of diabetes and its complications and establish the position of National Diabetes Coordinator.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400193"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400253" joined="2008-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400160" joined="2008-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400122" joined="2008-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400662" joined="2008-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400101" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400384" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400437" joined="2008-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400007" joined="2008-09-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400663" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400352" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400044" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400631" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400013" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400074" joined="2008-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400266" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400291" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="2007-12-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="412206" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400345" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400639" joined="2008-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400075" joined="2008-06-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1197954000" datetime="2007-12-18"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, Agriculture, and Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1197954000" datetime="2007-12-18"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1197954000" datetime="2007-12-18"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1197954000" datetime="2007-12-18"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action date="1197954000" datetime="2007-12-18"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1202187600" datetime="2008-02-05"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Healthy Families and Communities.</text></action>
		<action date="1209096000" datetime="2008-04-25"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	12/18/2007--Introduced.<br/>National Diabetes Coordinator Act of 2008 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to establish within the Office of the Secretary of the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) the position of National Diabetes Coordinator, whose duties shall be to: (1) serve as the Secretary's principal advisor on reducing the rates of diabetes and its complications; (2) develop a measurement for the incidence of diabetes; (3) develop and coordinate implementation of a national strategy to reduce the incidence, progression, and impact of diabetes and its complications; (4) provide leadership and coordination to ensure that diabetes-related programs and policies of HHS are coordinated internally and with those of relevant federal, state, and local agencies with a goal of avoiding duplication of effort, maximizing impact, and marshaling all government resources; and (5) coordinate public and private resources to develop and lead a public awareness campaign regarding the prevention and control of diabetes and its complications.<br/>Requires reports to the President: (1) from the HHS Secretary on a national strategy to reduce the incidence, progression, and impact of diabetes and its complications; (2) from the Director of the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) on negotiations with health plans to include appropriate standards and activities to reduce risk factors for diabetes and encourage prevention and early treatment; and (3) from the Secretary of Agriculture on ways in which food programs and nutritional support can be better targeted at concerns specific to those at risk for diabetes or those already diagnosed whose complications could be reduced by more effective diet.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
