<bill session="110" type="h" number="4837" updated="2009-01-09T03:00:01-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"/></status>

	<introduced date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">SPACE Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Spacefaring Priorities for America's Continued Exploration Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Space Shuttle to be flown from 2010 through 2015, and to authorize appropriations for the National Aeronautics and Space Administration for this purpose.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400427"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400123" joined="2008-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400131" joined="2007-12-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Science and Technology.</text></action>
		<action date="1201496400" datetime="2008-01-28"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Space and Aeronautics.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	12/19/2007--Introduced.<br/>Spacefaring Priorities for America's Continued Exploration Act or SPACE Act - Prohibits the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) from relying solely on the Russian government for astronaut transport or cargo resupply services, except for the current Soyuz emergency escape services for astronauts on the International Space Station. Authorizes appropriations to NASA for: (1) exploration systems; and (2) emergency funding for Columbia return-to-flight costs. Requires NASA to fly at least two space shuttle missions per year for crew transport, instead of Russian crew and cargo services, for the period 2010-2015, or until Orion is operational. Authorizes appropriations to carry out such operations. Requires NASA to report to Congress on the specific costs and actions needed to extend the operation of the space shuttle. Requires NASA, by March 31, 2011, to investigate areas of reduced operations and enhanced cost savings and implement those that do not impinge on the safe operation of the space shuttle program. Directs NASA to define achievable and attainable requirements for the operation of such program beyond 2010, as recommended by the Columbia Accident Investigation Board. Requires: (1) NASA to report to Congress on such requirements; and (2) NASA to immediately begin satisfying those requirements and to satisfy all of them by March 31, 2010. 
	</summary>
</bill>
