<bill session="110" type="h" number="4846" updated="2009-01-09T03:01:05-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"/></status>

	<introduced date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">First Line of Defense Infrastructure Improvement Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 to authorize the Administrator of the United States Fire Administration to provide grants for infrastructure improvements to fire first responders.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412253"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Science and Technology.</text></action>
		<action date="1201496400" datetime="2008-01-28"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology and Innovation.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	12/19/2007--Introduced.<br/>First Line of Defense Infrastructure Improvement Act - Amends the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 to direct the Administrator of the United States Fire Administration to establish a competitive grant program to improve first responder incident response and firefighter livability by making improvements to the infrastructure of fire stations. Requires the Administrator to award grants in each of FY2009-FY2013 to eligible fire services for: (1) repairing a station if the condition of the infrastructure prevents the service from performing incident response duties in a timely manner because the station is either decaying or contains structural impairments that impede egress of equipment or personnel; or (2) renovating a station if it does not properly accommodate all fire service personnel through the use of gender-equitable facilities.<br/>Prohibits the use of grant funds for activities related to the planning or design of infrastructure improvements. Directs the Administrator to give priority to a fire service seeking assistance for a fire station located not more than 25 miles from: (1) a facility that produces nuclear power; (2) a facility that produces, treats, or refines more than 20,000 barrels of oil per day; or (3) a location with at least one critical infrastructure, such as an international seaport, airport, refinery, or treatment plant.<br/>Prohibits the Administrator from awarding a grant exceeding 40% of the reasonable cost of carrying out the project. Conditions receipt of a grant on the fire service funding the remaining amount using non-federal funds.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
