<bill session="110" type="h" number="4857" updated="2009-01-09T03:02:23-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"/></status>

	<introduced date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To limit liability under the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 for service station dealers with respect to the release or threatened release of recycled oil.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400063"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400367" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400405" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400152" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400074" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400016" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400114" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400309" joined="2007-12-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
		<action date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1198126800" datetime="2007-12-20"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	12/19/2007--Introduced.<br/>Amends the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980, with respect to abatement actions because of the release of recycled oil and liability for costs or damages resulting from such oil's release in the course of disposal or transport, to limit liability of a service station dealer with respect to any period between November 8, 1986, and the effective date of certain corrective action regulations or standards promulgated under the Solid Waste Disposal Act if the dealer complied with all applicable laws and regulations relating to disposal. 
	</summary>
</bill>
