<bill session="110" type="h" number="4851" updated="2009-01-09T03:01:41-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"/></status>

	<introduced date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Davis-Bacon Enforcement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the enforcement of Davis-Bacon Act.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400008"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-09-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400355" joined="2008-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2008-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412204" joined="2008-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2008-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="2008-09-16"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"><text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1202187600" datetime="2008-02-05"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	12/19/2007--Introduced.<br/>Davis-Bacon Enforcement Act of 2007 - Amends the Davis-Bacon Act to require that any provisions of federal law that require payment of prevailing wages be construed to include the Act's debarment requirements (prohibiting for three years any award of federal contracts to persons or related firms, corporations, partnerships, or associations listed by the Comptroller General as having disregarded their obligations to employees and subcontractors under the Act). Requires each federal agency to make available to the public the complete payroll records (including all information in them except Social Security numbers) established under contracts subject to the Davis-Bacon Act.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
