<bill session="110" type="h" number="4880" updated="2009-01-09T03:04:59-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"/></status>

	<introduced date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act to provide for the implementation of protection and services for children and youths in out of home care, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400093"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400130" joined="2008-05-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"><text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"><text>Referred to House Financial Services</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	12/19/2007--Introduced.<br/>Amends the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act to require each state through its state educational agency (SEA) and its local educational agency (LEA), in collaboration with its state and local child welfare agencies, to provide children and youths in out of home care with certain educational protection and services, including: (1) guarantee that they will not be segregated in a separate or stigmatized school or separate program within a school based on their status of being in out of home care; and (2) equal access to the state-funded and LEA-funded preschool programs, appropriate secondary education and support services, and before- and after-school programs for which they are eligible, including extracurricula activities. Requires SEA- or LEA-provided transportation to the school of origin for such a child or youth only in certain circumstances, and only if the SEA or LEA is reimbursed by the responsible child welfare agency or other entity. 
	</summary>
</bill>
