<bill session="110" type="h" number="4889" updated="2009-01-09T03:06:18-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30" /></status>

	<introduced date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">The Guard and Reserves Are Fighting Too Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to recodify as part of that title chapter 1607 of title 10, United States Code.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400133"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400042" joined="2008-02-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"><text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"><text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1198213200" datetime="2007-12-21"><committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text></action>
		<action date="1201064400" datetime="2008-01-23"><committee name="House Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text></action>
		<action date="1208318400" datetime="2008-04-16"><committee name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1208923200" datetime="2008-04-23"><committee name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity"/><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1208923200" datetime="2008-04-23"><committee name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity"/><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text></action>
		<action date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30"><committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30" ><committee name="House Veterans' Affairs"/><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	12/19/2007--Introduced.<br/>The Guard and Reserves Are Fighting Too Act of 2008 - Recodifies under federal veterans' benefits provisions former federal armed forces provisions relating to educational assistance programs for members of the Ready Reserve ordered to active duty by reason of war or national emergency. Revises the amount of assistance available for licensing or certification tests. Includes under such recodification provisions concerning an educational assistance allowance for members of the Ready Reserve for flight training. Repeals the authority for accelerated payment of such assistance. Provides for program administration through the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) for FY2010 and thereafter (with transition provisions). Extends the time limitation for the use of the Ready Reserve educational assistance entitlement to ten years after separation from the Ready Reserve.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
