<bill session="110" type="h" number="4899" updated="2009-01-09T03:07:27-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"/></status>

	<introduced date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Community-Based Mental Health Infrastructure Improvements Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide grants for community-based mental health infrastructure improvement.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400215"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400290" joined="2008-09-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400041" joined="2008-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2008-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400039" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2008-09-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	12/19/2007--Introduced.<br/>Community-Based Mental Health Infrastructure Improvements Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to award grants to eligible entities for the construction or modernization of facilities to provide mental health and behavioral health services to individuals. Defines an &quot;eligible entity&quot; as: (1) a state that is the recipient of a Community Mental Health Services Block Grant and a Substance Abuse Prevention and Treatment Block Grant under such Act; or (2) an Indian tribe or a tribal organization. Includes among grant application requirements assurances that facilities will be used for not less than 10 years for community-based mental health or substance abuse services for those who cannot pay for such services. Permits a grant recipient to request permission to transfer such 10-year obligation to another facility.<br/>Authorizes a state that receives a grant to award a subgrant to a qualified community program for activities such as: (1) the construction, expansion, and modernization of mental and behavioral health facilities; and (2) the construction and structural modification of facilities to permit the integrated delivery of behavioral health and primary care of specialty medical services to individuals with co-occurring mental illnesses and chronic medical or surgical diseases at a single service site.<br/>Requires a grant recipient to agree to make available nonfederal contributions matching federal funds provided.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
