<bill session="110" type="h" number="4897" updated="2009-01-09T03:07:12-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"/></status>

	<introduced date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Senior Suicide Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Social Security Act and the Public Health Service Act to improve elderly suicide early intervention and prevention strategies, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400186"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400290" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400257" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400155" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400332" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400285" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2008-02-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="412198" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400663" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400103" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400350" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2008-02-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2008-02-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400208" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400240" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400215" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="412206" joined="2008-05-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1198126800" datetime="2007-12-20"><committee name="House Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	12/19/2007--Introduced.<br/>Stop Senior Suicide Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish an Interagency Geriatric Mental Health Planning Council to coordinate and collaborate on the planning for the delivery of mental health services, to include suicide prevention, to older adults.<br/>Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to increase, through 2014 (when it will not be limited), payment for the treatment of mental, psychoneurotic, and personality disorders of an individual who is not an inpatient of a hospital at the time such expenses are incurred.<br/>Requires the Secretary to award grants or cooperative agreements to eligible entities to develop strategies for addressing suicide among the elderly.<br/>Revises provisions requiring centers to provide appropriate information, training, and technical assistance on youth suicide to require such information, training, and assistance on suicide among all ages, particularly for groups that are at a high risk for suicide. Authorizes additional appropriations to carry out such changes.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
