<bill session="110" type="h" number="4914" updated="2009-01-09T03:09:16-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"/></status>

	<introduced date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Global HIV/AIDS Food Security and Nutrition Support Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the United States Leadership Against HIV/AIDS, Tuberculosis, and Malaria Act of 2003 to provide for the integration of food security and nutrition activities into prevention, care, treatment, and support activities.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400312"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400280" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400423" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400259" joined="2008-01-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2007-12-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	12/19/2007--Introduced.<br/>Global HIV/AIDS Food Security and Nutrition Support Act of 2007 - Amends the United States Leadership Against HIV/AIDS, Tuberculosis, and Malaria Act of 2003 to direct the Global AIDS Coordinator to: (1) ensure that an assessment of the food security and nutritional status of each patient enrolled in anti-retroviral medication treatment program is carried out; (2) provide food and nutrition support to each HIV-infected individual and his or her household for at least 180 days; (3) coordinate activities with the United States Agency for International Development (USAID), the Secretary of Agriculture, and other relevant U.S. government departments and agencies; (4) develop indicators to measure the effectiveness of nutrition and food security interventions; and (5) support linkages between U.S. colleges and universities with colleges and universities in focus countries in order to provide training and build indigenous capacity to respond to HIV/AIDS and to improve capacity to address nutrition and livelihood needs of HIV/AIDS-affected and impoverished communities.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
