<bill session="110" type="h" number="4910" updated="2009-01-09T03:08:49-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"/></status>

	<introduced date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Citizenship Processing Backlog Reduction Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide that the Secretary of Homeland Security may waive certain retirement provisions for reemployed annuitants in the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400245"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400102" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400355" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400617" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400651" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400025" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400163" joined="2007-12-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"><text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"><text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text></action>
		<action date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1201755600" datetime="2008-01-31"><committee name="House Homeland Security"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Management, Investigations, and Oversight.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	12/19/2007--Introduced.<br/>Citizenship Processing Backlog Reduction Act of 2007 - Authorizes the Secretary of Homeland Security to waive the application of provisions relating to annuities and pay on reemployment or any similar legal provision under a government retirement system on a case-by-case basis with respect to any annuitant who is reemployed on a temporary basis to: (1) process applications for naturalization filed from January 31-September 30, 2007; or (2) otherwise help the Secretary to reduce or eliminate the existing backlog of applications for naturalization.<br/>Provides that: (1) an annuitant as to whom such a waiver is in effect shall not be considered an employee for purposes of any government retirement system; and (2) no waiver under this Act may be granted after December 31, 2008, or remain in effect after December 31, 2009.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
