<bill session="110" type="h" number="492" updated="2009-01-08T17:48:14-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1168923600" datetime="2007-01-16"/></status>

	<introduced date="1168923600" datetime="2007-01-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">District of Columbia Voting Rights Restoration Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To restore the Federal electoral rights of the residents of the District of Columbia, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400343"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1168923600" datetime="2007-01-16"><text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1168923600" datetime="2007-01-16"><text>Referred to House House Administration</text></action>
		<action date="1168923600" datetime="2007-01-16"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1168923600" datetime="2007-01-16"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1174276800" datetime="2007-03-19"><committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/16/2007--Introduced.<br/>District of Columbia Voting Rights Restoration Act of 2007 - Restores the right of District of Columbia residents to participate as Maryland residents in congressional elections and presidential elections. Repeals provisions of: (1) the District of Columbia Delegate Act that establishes the office of District of Columbia Delegate to the House of Representatives; and (2) the District of Columbia Statehood Constitution Convention Initiative of 1979 that provides for electing a Senator and Representative for the District.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
