<bill session="110" type="h" number="4936" updated="2009-01-09T03:11:56-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1200373200" datetime="2008-01-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1200373200" datetime="2008-01-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Antifreeze Bittering Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Hazardous Substances Act to require engine coolant and antifreeze to contain a bittering agent so as to render it unpalatable.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400003"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400080" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400282" joined="2008-01-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400430" joined="2008-01-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="412210" joined="2008-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400049" joined="2008-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="2008-06-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400103" joined="2008-01-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400087" joined="2008-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400346" joined="2008-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400070" joined="2008-01-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="412204" joined="2008-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400251" joined="2008-01-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400415" joined="2008-01-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2008-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="2008-01-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400024" joined="2008-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400025" joined="2008-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400100" joined="2008-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400435" joined="2008-01-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1200373200" datetime="2008-01-15"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1200459600" datetime="2008-01-16"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/15/2008--Introduced.<br/>Antifreeze Bittering Act of 2007 [sic] - Requires engine coolant or antifreeze that is manufactured six months after the enactment of this Act, and that contains more than 10% ethylene glycol, to include denatonium benzoate at a minimum of 30 parts per million and a maximum of 50 parts per million as a bittering agent so as to render the coolant or antifreeze unpalatable. Requires a coolant or antifreeze manufacturer to maintain records of compliance with this Act. Limits the liability of manufacturers, distributors, recyclers, or sellers of engine coolant or antifreeze who are in compliance with the requirements of this Act for personal and property loss or damage to the environment that results from the inclusion of denatonium benzoate in any coolant or antifreeze. Declares this Act inapplicable to: (1) the sale of a motor vehicle that contains engine coolant or antifreeze; or (2) wholesale containers of engine coolant or antifreeze containing 55 gallons or more of engine coolant or antifreeze.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
