<bill session="110" type="h" number="495" updated="2009-01-08T17:48:54-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1185248160" datetime="2007-07-23T12:36:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1168923600" datetime="2007-01-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Oregon Water Resources Management Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Oregon Water Resources Management Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">North Unit Irrigation District Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To update the management of Oregon water resources, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400419"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1168923600" datetime="2007-01-16"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text></action>
		<action date="1185248040" datetime="2007-07-23T12:34:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Grijalva moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text></action>
		<action date="1185248040" datetime="2007-07-23T12:34:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8197-8199"/></action>
		<action date="1185248040" datetime="2007-07-23T12:34:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 495.</text></action>
		<vote date="1185248160" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-07-23T12:36:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text as passed in House" ref="CR H8197-8198"/></vote>
		<action date="1185249600" datetime="2007-07-24"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/23/2007--Passed House without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)<br/>Oregon Water Resources Management Act of 2007 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Oregon Resource Conservation Act of 1996 to: (1) replace references to the Deschutes River Basin Working Group with the Deschutes River Conservancy Working Group; (2) require the two representatives of private interests from irrigated agriculture on the Working Group to actively farm more than 100 acres of irrigated land and not be irrigation district managers; (3) direct the Bureau of Reclamation to pay up to a specified amount of the cost of performing projects proposed by the Working Group and approved by the Secretary of the Interior for FY2007-FY2016; and (4) authorize appropriations for Deschutes Basin ecosystem restoration projects for FY2007-FY2016. (Sec. 3) Authorizes the Secretary, acting through the Commissioner of Reclamation, to provide grants to, or enter into agreements with, tribal, state, and local governmental entities and the Associated Ditch Companies, Incorporated (ADC) to plan, design, and construct facilities needed to implement the Wallowa Lake Dam Rehabilitation Program as long as the Secretary ensures that: (1) the Program and activities meet the standards of Oregon's dam safety program; (2) ADC agrees to assume liability for any work performed or supervised with federal funds; and (3) the United States is not liable for damages arising out of any act, omission, or occurrence relating to a facility rehabilitated or constructed with federal funds. Limits the federal share of the costs of activities authorized to 50%. Prohibits crediting against the federal share any expenditure made by the Bonneville Power Administration in the Wallowa River watershed or by individual agricultural producers in any federal commodity or conservation program. Requires the Secretary to comply with applicable Oregon water law. Prohibits the federal government from holding title to any facility rehabilitated or constructed or from being responsible for operation and maintenance of any such facility. Provides that activities funded in this section shall not be considered a supplemental or additional benefit under federal reclamation law. Authorizes appropriations. Terminates the Secretary's authority to carry out this section 10 years after the date of enactment.<br/>(Sec. 4) Authorizes the Secretary, through the Bureau, to participate in the Water for Irrigation, Streams and the Economy Project water management feasibility study and environmental impact statement in accordance with the Memorandum of Agreement Between City of Medford and Bureau of Reclamation for the Water for Irrigation, Streams, and the Economy Project. Authorizes appropriations. Sets the non-federal share at 50% of the Bureau's total costs in carrying out the study and environmental impact statement. Allows the non-federal share to be in the form of in-kind services. Terminates the Secretary's authority to carry out this section 10 years after the date of enactment.<br/>North Unit Irrigation District Act of 2007 - (Sec. 5) Modifies a repayment contract between the Secretary and the North Unit Irrigation District, Oregon, to permit the District to engage in, or take advantage of, conserved water projects authorized by Oregon law. Permits the Secretary, acting through the Commissioner, to renegotiate in the future with the District such contractual terms as the District directors deem necessary only upon their written request and the Commissioner's consent.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
