<bill session="110" type="h" number="4960" updated="2009-01-09T03:14:43-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1200373200" datetime="2008-01-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1200373200" datetime="2008-01-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Immigration Law Corrections Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To repeal various provisions of the Consolidated Appropriations Act of 2008, relating to immigration and border security fencing.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400254"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1200373200" datetime="2008-01-15"><text>Referred to the Committee on Appropriations, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1200373200" datetime="2008-01-15"><text>Referred to House Appropriations</text></action>
		<action date="1200373200" datetime="2008-01-15"><text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text></action>
		<action date="1201755600" datetime="2008-01-31"><committee name="House Homeland Security"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border, Maritime, and Global Counterterrorism.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/15/2008--Introduced.<br/>Immigration Law Corrections Act of 2008 - Rescinds specified funds made available under the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2008 for: (1) the Executive Office for Immigration Review's legal orientation programs; and (2) defender services in immigration enforcement proceedings. Amends the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996, as amended by the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2008, to eliminate the Secretary of Homeland Security's discretionary authority to not install security fencing and related security resources at locations along the southwest border.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
