<bill session="110" type="h" number="498" updated="2009-01-08T17:49:15-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1168923600" datetime="2007-01-16"/></status>

	<introduced date="1168923600" datetime="2007-01-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Energy Policy Reinvestment Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to repeal the oil and gas tax subsidies enacted in the Energy Policy Act of 2005, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400438"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1168923600" datetime="2007-01-16"><text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Science and Technology, Oversight and Government Reform, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1168923600" datetime="2007-01-16"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1168923600" datetime="2007-01-16"><text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text></action>
		<action date="1168923600" datetime="2007-01-16"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1168923600" datetime="2007-01-16"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"><committee name="House Science and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text></action>
		<action date="1170392400" datetime="2007-02-02"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text></action>
		<action date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"><committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Organization, and Procurement.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/16/2007--Introduced.<br/>Energy Policy Reinvestment Act of 2007 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to repeal: (1) the expensing allowance for liquid fuel refineries; (2) accelerated depreciation for natural gas distribution and gathering lines; (3) expanded eligibility of small petroleum refiners for the exception to limitations on the oil and gas depletion allowance; and (4) accelerated amortization of geological and geophysical expenditures. Directs that any revenues resulting from these repeals be made available for certain hydrogen and fuel cell technology programs.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
