<bill session="110" type="h" number="505" updated="2009-01-08T17:50:07-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1193249040" datetime="2007-10-24T15:04:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="1000"/></status>

	<introduced date="1169010000" datetime="2007-01-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Native Hawaiian Government Reorganization Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Native Hawaiian Government Reorganization Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Native Hawaiian Government Reorganization Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To express the policy of the United States regarding the United States relationship with Native Hawaiians and to provide a process for the recognition by the United States of the Native Hawaiian governing entity.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400001"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400041" joined="2007-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400128" joined="2007-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400077" joined="2007-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="412200" joined="2007-01-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400440" joined="2007-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="2007-02-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1169010000" datetime="2007-01-17"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E133)</text></action>
		<action date="1169010000" datetime="2007-01-17"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1178078400" datetime="2007-05-02"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1178078400" datetime="2007-05-02" ><text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1192733400" datetime="2007-10-18T15:50:00-04:00"><text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-389.</text></action>
		<calendar number="243" date="1192733400" datetime="2007-10-18T15:50:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 243.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1193090520" datetime="2007-10-22T19:02:00-04:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 764 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 505 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. A specified amendment is in order.</text></action>
		<action date="1193242260" datetime="2007-10-24T13:11:00-04:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 764 passed House.</text></action>
		<action date="1193242260" datetime="2007-10-24T13:11:00-04:00"><text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 764.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H11974-11989"/></action>
		<action date="1193242260" datetime="2007-10-24T13:11:00-04:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 505 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. A specified amendment is in order.</text></action>
		<action date="1193242320" datetime="2007-10-24T13:12:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 505.</text></action>
		<action date="1193245980" datetime="2007-10-24T14:13:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H11986"/></action>
		<action date="1193245980" datetime="2007-10-24T14:13:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Flake moved to recommit with instructions to Natural Resources.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H11986-11988"/><reference label="text" ref="CR H11986"/></action>
		<action date="1193245980" datetime="2007-10-24T14:13:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Flake motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to report the bill back to the House with an amendment to make applicable the United States Constitution's Bill of Rights, the Federal Civil Rights laws, and burden or immunities clauses to the bill.</text></action>
		<action date="1193246580" datetime="2007-10-24T14:23:00-04:00"><text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H11987"/></action>
		<action date="1193248140" datetime="2007-10-24T14:49:00-04:00"><text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 178 - 235 (Roll no. 999).</text></action>
		<vote date="1193249040" how="roll" roll="1000" datetime="2007-10-24T15:04:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 261 - 153 (Roll no. 1000).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H11974-11978"/></vote>
		<action date="1193284800" datetime="2007-10-25"><text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="449" date="1193371200" datetime="2007-10-26" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 449.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/24/2007--Passed House without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)<br/>Native Hawaiian Government Reorganization Act of 2007 - (Sec. 4) Reaffirms that: (1) the United States has a special political and legal relationship with Native Hawaiians; and (2) Native Hawaiians have the right to autonomy in their internal affairs, to self-determination and self-governance, to reorganize a Native Hawaiian governing entity, and to become economically self-sufficient.<br/>(Sec. 5) Establishes the U.S. Office for Native Hawaiian Relations within the Office of the Secretary of the Interior.<br/>(Sec. 6) Establishes the Native Hawaiian Interagency Coordinating Group to: (1) coordinate federal programs and policies that affect Native Hawaiians or federal actions that may significantly or uniquely affect their resources, rights, or lands; (2) consult with the Native Hawaiian governing entity; and (3) ensure the participation of each federal agency in the development of the Group's annual report to Congress.<br/>(Sec. 7) Recognizes the right of the Native Hawaiian people to reorganize the single Native Hawaiian governing entity to provide for their common welfare and to adopt appropriate organic governing documents. Establishes a commission to: (1) prepare and maintain a roll of the adult members of the Native Hawaiian community who elect to participate in such reorganization; and (2) certify that the members proposed for inclusion on the roll meet the definition of Native Hawaiian. Requires the Secretary to dissolve the Commission upon reaffirmation of the special political and legal relationship between the governing entity and the United States.<br/>Outlines the process for such reorganization. Authorizes formation of a Native Hawaiian Interim Governing Council, which may conduct a referendum among the Native Hawaiians listed on the roll to determine the proposed elements of the governing documents.<br/>Reaffirms the special political and legal relationship between the United States and the governing entity upon the Secretary's certification of the governing documents and the election of the entity's officers. Extends federal recognition to the entity as the representative governing body of the Native Hawaiian people. (Sec. 8) Reaffirms the delegation of authority to the state of Hawaii to address the conditions of Native Hawaiians.<br/>Authorizes the United States, upon the reaffirmation of such political and legal relationship, together with the state, to enter into negotiations with the governing entity to lead to an agreement addressing such matters as: (1) the transfer of lands, natural resources, and other assets and the protection of existing rights related to such lands or resources; (2) the exercise of governmental authority over any such land and assets; (3) the exercise of civil and criminal jurisdiction; (4) the delegation of governmental powers and authorities to the governing entity by the United States and the state; (5) any residual responsibilities of the United States and the state; and (6) grievances regarding assertions of historical wrongs committed against Native Hawaiians by the United States or the state.<br/>Authorizes the parties to the negotiations, upon agreement on matters negotiated with the United States, to submit proposed amendments to federal or state law.<br/>Requires any governmental authority or power to be exercised by the governing entity that is currently exercised by the state or federal governments to be exercised by the governing entity only as agreed to in negotiations and beginning on the date on which legislation to implement such agreement has been enacted by Congress or Hawaii. Declares that this Act does not establish authority for the recognition of Native Hawaiian groups other than the governing entity.<br/>(Sec. 9) Prohibits the governing entity and Native Hawaiians from conducting gaming activities as a matter of claimed inherent authority or under the authority of federal law.<br/>Prohibits the Secretary from taking land into trust on behalf of individuals or groups claiming to be Native Hawaiian or on behalf of the governing entity.<br/>Provides that this Act will result in the recognition of the single Native Hawaiian governing entity.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
