<bill session="110" type="h" number="5069" updated="2009-01-09T03:27:03-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1200546000" datetime="2008-01-17"/></status>

	<introduced date="1200546000" datetime="2008-01-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Food and Product Responsibility Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require manufacturers to demonstrate sufficient means to cover, for certain products distributed in commerce, costs of potential recalls, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400417"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400177" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400274" joined="2008-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400355" joined="2008-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400007" joined="2008-01-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412227" joined="2008-01-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400103" joined="2008-01-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="412204" joined="2008-01-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400281" joined="2008-01-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400211" joined="2008-01-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2008-01-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400310" joined="2008-01-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400286" joined="2008-01-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1200546000" datetime="2008-01-17"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1200546000" datetime="2008-01-17"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1200546000" datetime="2008-01-17"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action date="1200632400" datetime="2008-01-18"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1200632400" datetime="2008-01-18"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text></action>
		<action date="1209096000" datetime="2008-04-25"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry.</text></action>
		<action date="1209096000" datetime="2008-04-25"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Specialty Crops, Rural Development, and Foreign Agriculture.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/17/2008--Introduced.<br/>Food and Product Responsibility Act of 2008 - Applies this Act to replacement equipment, food, drugs, devices, cosmetics, biological products, consumer products, meat or meat food product, poultry or poultry products, and eggs or egg products (covered products).<br/>Prohibits a manufacturer from distributing a covered product unless the manufacturer holds a certification from the U.S. Customs and Border Protection that the manufacturer possesses sufficient means (through insurance or otherwise) to cover the entire cost of a recall of the product, including administrative costs, compensatory damages, and costs of any product liability or other lawsuit relating to that product.<br/>Amends the Federal Meat Inspection Act (regarding meat and meat food products), the Poultry Products Inspection Act (regarding poultry and poultry products), the Egg Products Inspection Act (regarding eggs and egg products), and the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (FDCA) (regarding food) to provide for voluntary and mandatory recalls of adulterated or misbranded articles, notice to consumers and health officials, and related procedures.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
