<bill session="110" type="h" number="5090" updated="2009-01-09T03:29:24-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1200978000" datetime="2008-01-22"/></status>

	<introduced date="1200978000" datetime="2008-01-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 to permit a family member of a wounded veteran to take leave under such Act after a lesser period of service with an employer.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400628"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1200978000" datetime="2008-01-22"><text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, and House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1200978000" datetime="2008-01-22"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1200978000" datetime="2008-01-22"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1200978000" datetime="2008-01-22"><text>Referred to House House Administration</text></action>
		<action date="1204174800" datetime="2008-02-28"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/22/2008--Introduced.<br/>Amends the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 with respect to hours-of-service requirements a spouse, parent, son, or daughter of a covered servicemember must meet to qualify for leave under such Act. Entitles such individual to take such leave in order to care for the covered servicemember if he or she has been employed for at least 625 hours of service with an employer. Defines &quot;covered servicemember&quot; as a member of the Armed Forces, including a member of the National Guard or a Reserve, who is undergoing medical treatment, recuperation, or therapy, is otherwise in medical hold or medical holdover status, or is otherwise on the temporary disability retired list, for a serious injury or illness.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
