<bill session="110" type="h" number="5128" updated="2009-01-09T03:34:04-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1201064400" datetime="2008-01-23"/></status>

	<introduced date="1201064400" datetime="2008-01-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Disapproving of any formal agreement emerging from the &quot;Declaration of Principles for a Long-Term Relationship of Cooperation and Friendship Between the Republic of Iraq and the United States of America&quot; unless the agreement is approved through an Act of Congress.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400237"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400073" joined="2008-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400227" joined="2008-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400080" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400129" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2008-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400184" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="2008-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400001" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2008-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400422" joined="2008-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2008-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400042" joined="2008-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400240" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400301" joined="2008-04-30"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1201064400" datetime="2008-01-23"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1201064400" datetime="2008-01-23"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1201064400" datetime="2008-01-23"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1202878800" datetime="2008-02-13"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H926)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/23/2008--Introduced.<br/>States that any formal agreement emerging from the &quot;Declaration of Principles for a Long-term Relationship of Cooperation and Friendship Between the Republic of Iraq and the United States of America&quot; shall not have the effect of force of law unless the agreement is approved by Congress after the date of enactment of this Act. Expresses the sense of Congress that any formal agreement emerging from such Declaration must be approved by the Iraqi legislature. Prohibits funds appropriated or otherwise made available to the Department of Defense (DOD) or any other U.S. department or agency from being used to enforce or implement any formal agreement emerging from such Declaration unless the agreement is approved by Congress. 
	</summary>
</bill>
