<bill session="110" type="h" number="5137" updated="2009-01-09T03:35:12-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1204655160" datetime="2008-03-04T14:26:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1201496400" datetime="2008-01-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure that hunting remains a purpose of the New River Gorge National River.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400331"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1201496400" datetime="2008-01-28"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1201755600" datetime="2008-01-31"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action date="1204654920" datetime="2008-03-04T14:22:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Rahall moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text></action>
		<action date="1204654980" datetime="2008-03-04T14:23:00-05:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H1195"/></action>
		<action date="1204654980" datetime="2008-03-04T14:23:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5137.</text></action>
		<vote date="1204655160" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-03-04T14:26:00-05:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H1195"/></vote>
		<action date="1204693200" datetime="2008-03-05"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1217390400" datetime="2008-07-30"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="1026" date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1026.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/16/2008--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Amends the National Parks and Recreation Act of 1978 to require (current law authorizes) the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) permit hunting and fishing on lands and waters within the boundaries of the New River Gorge National River; and (2) designate zones where, and establish periods when, no hunting or fishing shall be permitted.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
