<bill session="110" type="h" number="5132" updated="2009-01-09T03:34:37-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1201064400" datetime="2008-01-23"/></status>

	<introduced date="1201064400" datetime="2008-01-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Environmental Justice Renewal Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to establish an Interagency Working Group on Environmental Justice to provide guidance to Federal agencies on the development of criteria for identifying disproportionately high and adverse human health or environmental effects on minority populations and low-income populations, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400384"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="2008-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="2008-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="412232" joined="2008-06-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="2008-02-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1201064400" datetime="2008-01-23"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1201064400" datetime="2008-01-23"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1201064400" datetime="2008-01-23"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
		<action date="1201064400" datetime="2008-01-23"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/23/2008--Introduced.<br/>Environmental Justice Renewal Act - Defines &quot;environmental justice&quot; as the fair treatment and meaningful involvement of all individuals regardless or race, color, national origin, educational level, or income in the process of developing environmental laws and regulations. Defines &quot;environmental justice community&quot; as a community with a significant representation of racial, ethnic, or low-income populations vulnerable to environmental or human health risks.<br/>Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish the Interagency Working Group on Environmental Justice to provide guidance to federal agencies in identifying disproportionately high and adverse human health or environmental effects on minority and low-income populations and to assist such agencies in developing environmental justice strategies. Requires the Working Group to develop and promulgate a coordinated interagency federal environmental justice strategy.<br/>Requires the Administrator to: (1) establish in the EPA the position of Environmental Justice Ombudsman to monitor complaints relating to environmental justice programs; (2) provide training in environmental justice to EPA employees; (3) establish grant programs to address local environmental justice concerns; (4) establish a basic training program to assist residents of environmental justice communities in identifying human health and environmental risks; (5) establish a National Environmental Justice Advisory Council to provide independent advice and recommendations to the Administrator on environmental justice issues; and (6) establish an Environmental Justice Clearinghouse to provide information on EPA activities relating to environmental justice. Requires the Comptroller General to report to Congress on the effectiveness of this Act. 
	</summary>
</bill>
