<bill session="110" type="h" number="5151" updated="2009-01-09T03:36:58-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1208902260" datetime="2008-04-22T19:11:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="206"/></status>

	<introduced date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Wild Monongahela Act: A National Legacy for West Virginia's Special Places</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Wild Monongahela Act: A National Legacy for West Virginia's Special Places</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Wild Monongahela Act: A National Legacy for West Virginia's Special Places</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Wild Monongahela Act: A National Legacy for West Virginia's Special Places</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To designate as wilderness additional National Forest System lands in the Monongahela National Forest in the State of West Virginia, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400331"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400061" joined="2008-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400281" joined="2008-01-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E99-100)</text></action>
		<action date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29"><text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action date="1201755600" datetime="2008-01-31"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action date="1204002000" datetime="2008-02-26"><committee name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1207108800" datetime="2008-04-02"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands Discharged.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1207108800" datetime="2008-04-02" ><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1208883600" datetime="2008-04-22T14:00:00-04:00"><text>Committee on Agriculture discharged.</text></action>
		<action date="1208883600" datetime="2008-04-22T14:00:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-598, Part I.</text></action>
		<calendar number="371" date="1208883660" datetime="2008-04-22T14:01:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 371.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1208884680" datetime="2008-04-22T14:18:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Rahall moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1208884740" datetime="2008-04-22T14:19:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2497-2499"/></action>
		<action date="1208884740" datetime="2008-04-22T14:19:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5151.</text></action>
		<action date="1208885220" datetime="2008-04-22T14:27:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1208901840" datetime="2008-04-22T19:04:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2531"/></action>
		<vote date="1208902260" how="roll" roll="206" datetime="2008-04-22T19:11:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" suspension="1" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 368 - 17 (Roll no. 206).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H2497-2498"/></vote>
		<action date="1208923200" datetime="2008-04-23"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1210132800" datetime="2008-05-07" ><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1213588800" datetime="2008-06-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with amendments. With written report No. 110-391.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="823" date="1213588800" datetime="2008-06-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 823.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/16/2008--Reported to Senate amended. Wild Monongahela Act: A National Legacy for West Virginia's Special Places - Designates specified federal lands in the Monongahela National Forest, West Virginia, as wilderness and as either a new component, or as an addition to an existing component, of the National Wilderness Preservation System. Allows the Secretary of Agriculture to continue to authorize the competitive running event permitted from 2003 through 2007 in the vicinity of the boundaries of the Dolly Sods Wilderness addition and the Roaring Plains West Wilderness Area in a manner compatible with the preservation of such areas as wilderness. Prohibits anything in this Act from affecting the jurisdiction or responsibility of the state of West Virginia respecting wildlife and fish.<br/>Modifies the boundary of the Laurel Fork South Wilderness designated by P.L. 97- 466 (relating to the designation of certain lands in the Monongahela National Forest as wilderness) to exclude two specified parcels of land. States that the boundary of the Monongahela National Forest is confirmed to include specified tracts of land. Provides that, for the purposes relating to the allocation of moneys from the Land and Water Conservation Fund for the acquisition of land, waters, or interests in land or waters in the National Park System, the National Forest System, or the National Wildlife Refuge System, the boundaries of the Monongahela National Forest, as confirmed by this Act, shall be considered to be the boundaries of the Forest as of January 1, 1965. Requires the Secretary to: (1) develop a plan to provide for enhanced nonmotorized recreation trail opportunities on lands not designated as wilderness within the Monongahela National Forest; and (2) submit to Congress a report on the implementation of the plan, including the identification of priority trails for development. Provides for the consideration of conversion of forest roads within Monongahela National Forest to nonmotorized uses to enhance recreational opportunities within the Forest. 
	</summary>
</bill>
