<bill session="110" type="h" number="515" updated="2009-01-08T17:51:30-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1169010000" datetime="2007-01-17"/></status>

	<introduced date="1169010000" datetime="2007-01-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Corporate Entitlement Reform Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a commission on corporate entitlement reform.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400081"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1169010000" datetime="2007-01-17"><text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1169010000" datetime="2007-01-17"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1169010000" datetime="2007-01-17"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1169010000" datetime="2007-01-17"><text>Referred to House Rules</text></action>
		<action date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"><committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Organization, and Procurement.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/17/2007--Introduced.<br/>Corporate Entitlement Reform Act of 2007 - Establishes the Corporate Entitlement Reform Commission to: (1) examine and identify federal programs and tax laws that provide corporate entitlements (federally-funded payments to profitmaking enterprises provided without a reasonable expectation that activities performed in return for such payments would result in benefits to the public at least as great as the payments); (2) review such entitlements; (3) recommend $50 billion in federal savings on corporate entitlements for the period beginning October 1, 2007, and ending September 30, 2017; and (4) report to Congress on its findings and recommendations. Sets forth procedures for congressional consideration and implementation of the Commission's recommendations.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
