<bill session="110" type="h" number="5161" updated="2009-01-09T03:38:09-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1204088400" datetime="2008-02-27" /></status>

	<introduced date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Green Transportation Infrastructure Research and Technology Transfer Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Green Transportation Infrastructure Research and Technology Transfer Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the establishment of Green Transportation Infrastructure Research and Technology Transfer Centers, and for other purpose.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400437"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400041" joined="2008-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400155" joined="2008-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400151" joined="2008-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400630" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400662" joined="2008-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="412189" joined="2008-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400396" joined="2008-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412253" joined="2008-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400663" joined="2008-02-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="2008-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400017" joined="2008-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400082" joined="2008-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400442" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400259" joined="2008-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2008-07-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412240" joined="2008-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2008-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2008-09-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400255" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400638" joined="2008-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="412200" joined="2008-07-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400193" joined="2008-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2008-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412186" joined="2008-07-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400119" joined="2008-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2008-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400204" joined="2008-03-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2008-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400240" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400011" joined="2008-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400186" joined="2008-02-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29"><text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Science and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29"><text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text></action>
		<action date="1201669200" datetime="2008-01-30"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text></action>
		<action date="1201669200" datetime="2008-01-30"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text></action>
		<action date="1201842000" datetime="2008-02-01"><committee name="House Science and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology and Innovation.</text></action>
		<action date="1201842000" datetime="2008-02-01"><committee name="House Science and Technology" subcommittee="Technology and Innovation"/><text>Hearing Held by Subcommittee on Technology and Innovation Prior to Introduction and Referral (05/10/2007).</text></action>
		<action date="1202360400" datetime="2008-02-07"><committee name="House Science and Technology" subcommittee="Technology and Innovation"/><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1202360400" datetime="2008-02-07"><committee name="House Science and Technology" subcommittee="Technology and Innovation"/><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text></action>
		<action date="1204088400" datetime="2008-02-27"><committee name="House Science and Technology"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1204088400" datetime="2008-02-27" ><committee name="House Science and Technology"/><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1207852800" datetime="2008-04-10T15:40:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science and Technology. H. Rept. 110-576, Part I.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/10/2008--Reported to House amended, Part I. Green Transportation Infrastructure Research and Technology Transfer Act - (Sec. 3) Amends federal transportation law to direct the Secretary of Transportation to make grants to existing university transportation centers, or to consortia consisting of such a center and one or more institutions of higher education, to carry out green transportation infrastructure research and development and technology transfer activities. Defines &quot;green transportation infrastructure&quot; as infrastructure that: (1) preserves and restores natural processes, landforms (such as floodplains), natural vegetated stream side buffers, wetlands, or other topographical features that can slow, filter, and naturally store stormwater runoff and floodwaters for future water supply and recharge of natural aquifers; (2) uses natural design techniques to manage stormwater; and (3) minimizes lifecycle energy consumption and air pollution. Requires grant recipients to be selected on a merit-reviewed competitive basis according to specified criteria, including demonstrated expertise in transportation and green infrastructure research and technology transfer resources. Authorizes appropriations for FY2009-FY2010. (Sec. 4) Directs the National Highway Institute of the Federal Highway Administration to continually develop courses relating to the application of emerging technologies for the use of green transportation infrastructure for environmental protection and mitigating environmental impacts of transportation construction. Adds green transportation infrastructure options as a road and transportation area for which the Secretary may make local technical assistance program grants to assist rural, local transportation agencies and tribal governments to develop and expand their expertise.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
