<bill session="110" type="h" number="517" updated="2009-01-08T17:51:45-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1169010000" datetime="2007-01-17"/></status>

	<introduced date="1169010000" datetime="2007-01-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Independence from Oil with Agriculture Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to make permanent certain tax incentives for alternative energy, to amend the Clean Air Act to accelerate the use of renewable fuels, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400095"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1169010000" datetime="2007-01-17"><text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1169010000" datetime="2007-01-17"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1169010000" datetime="2007-01-17"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1170392400" datetime="2007-02-02"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/17/2007--Introduced.<br/>Independence from Oil with Agriculture Act of 2007 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to delete provisions that terminate tax credits after a certain time (thus extending such credits) for: (1) alcohol fuels; (2) biodiesel fuels; (3) alcohol fuel mixtures; (4) biodiesel mixtures; (5) electricity produced from wind and open-loop or close-loop biomass facilities; and (6) alternative fuel vehicle refueling property.<br/>Amends the Clean Air Act to: (1) increase the applicable volume of renewable fuel for calendar years 2008-2012 that must be part of gasoline in the United States (except in noncontiguous states or territories); and (2) increase the number of gallons of renewable fuel in the calculation used to determine the required volume of renewable fuel in gasoline for calendar years 2013 and thereafter.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
