<bill session="110" type="h" number="5178" updated="2009-01-09T03:40:08-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29"/></status>

	<introduced date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Youth Reentry Improvement Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance public safety by improving the reintegration of youth offenders into the families and communities to which they are returning.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400162"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400041" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2008-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400364" joined="2008-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412221" joined="2008-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400355" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2008-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2008-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2008-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400204" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400090" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400240" joined="2008-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400024" joined="2008-02-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29"><text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Education and Labor, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1202101200" datetime="2008-02-04"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text></action>
		<action date="1208404800" datetime="2008-04-17"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Healthy Families and Communities.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/29/2008--Introduced.<br/>Youth Reentry Improvement Act of 2008 - Amends the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 to require: (1) information on the number of juveniles released from prison and their living arrangements upon release in the annual report of the Administrator of the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Office; (2) states seeking juvenile justice grants to adopt procedures to assure the availability of post-release programs and services for juvenile offenders; and (3) research and evaluation on outcomes for juvenile offenders who have been released from custody and reintegrated into communities. Directs the Attorney General to: (1) award grants to states to establish programs to identify juveniles likely to be released before attaining age 25 and to help such juveniles attain self-sufficiency; (2) develop outcome measures to assess the performance of states in operating juvenile offender reentry programs and track services provided to such offenders; and (3) conduct evaluations of state juvenile offender reentry programs. Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to continue health care benefits for juvenile offenders after release from incarceration. 
	</summary>
</bill>
