<bill session="110" type="h" number="5171" updated="2009-01-09T03:39:19-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29"/></status>

	<introduced date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Geologic Mapping Reauthorization Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To reauthorize and amend the National Geologic Mapping Act of 1992.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400618"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400412" joined="2008-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400331" joined="2008-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2008-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400193" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="2008-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2008-02-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E110)</text></action>
		<action date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1201842000" datetime="2008-02-01"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/29/2008--Introduced.<br/>National Geologic Mapping Reauthorization Act of 2008 - Amends the National Geologic Mapping Act of 1992 to extend deadlines for development of a five-year strategic plan for the geologic mapping program and for appointment of the advisory committee. Removes from program objectives the development of a geophysical- and geochemical- map database. Directs that mapping priorities be based in part on the needs of the Department of the Interior land management agencies.<br/>Modifies the composition of the advisory committee and increases the number of members on such committee. Requires the advisory committee, at the request of the President, the President's designee, the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives, or the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate, to provide an overview report on the quality, utility, and appropriateness of geologic maps (including maps of geologic hazards) used or disseminated by federal agencies for regulation or land-use planning. Directs that the national geologic map database include all maps developed with funding provided by the National Cooperative Geologic Mapping Program, including under the federal, state, and education components.<br/>Authorizes appropriations for each of FY2008 through FY2017. Increases the percentages allocated for the state and education components. 
	</summary>
</bill>
