<bill session="110" type="h" number="5192" updated="2009-01-09T03:41:44-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29"/></status>

	<introduced date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Children's Compassionate Care Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the palliative and end-of-life care provided to children with life-threatening conditions, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400327"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400414" joined="2008-06-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400286" joined="2008-01-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1203310800" datetime="2008-02-18"><committee name="House Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/29/2008--Introduced.<br/>Children's Compassionate Care Act of 2007 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to allow the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA), to award grants to: (1) provide training in pediatric palliative care and related services for children with life-threatening conditions; and (2) implement or expand pediatric palliative care programs for such children. Authorizes the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to award training grants to expand the number of physicians, nurses, mental health professionals, and appropriate allied health professionals and specialists with interdisciplinary pediatric palliative clinical training and research experience. Allows the Secretary to award grants to enhance pediatric palliative care and care for children with life-threatening conditions in general pediatric or family practice residency training programs and general or pediatric nursing education programs through the development of model interdisciplinary programs that partner with other health professional schools. Requires the Director to provide grants to fund interdisciplinary research in pediatric pain and symptom management that will utilize existing NIH facilities.<br/>Requires the Secretary to: (1) establish Medicare and private sector pediatric palliative care demonstration projects; and (2) convene a Symposium on Pediatric Palliative Care.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
