<bill session="110" type="h" number="5218" updated="2009-01-09T03:44:37-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29"/></status>

	<introduced date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Fire-Safe Communities Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To promote fire-safe communities, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400412"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2008-01-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E96-98)</text></action>
		<action date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29"><text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, Natural Resources, and Science and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29"><text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text></action>
		<action date="1201669200" datetime="2008-01-30"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text></action>
		<action date="1201842000" datetime="2008-02-01"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action date="1203570000" datetime="2008-02-21"><committee name="House Science and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology and Innovation.</text></action>
		<action date="1209096000" datetime="2008-04-25"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/29/2008--Introduced.<br/>Fire-Safe Communities Act - Requires the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) to publish a federal model ordinance for municipalities at risk (subdivisions located in a fire hazard area) that includes specified elements regarding fire prevention and management, such as: (1) specifications for construction materials and techniques for use in such communities; and (2) standards for roads, culverts, and bridges. Authorizes the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to modify, for a municipality at risk, the requirements of the Fire Management Assistance Grant Program related to the provision of a non-federal share of funds, so that if such a municipality has adopted an applicable model ordinance and is making significant progress toward implementing it, the Administrator may reduce the required non-federal share to 10% of the grant amount. Directs the Administrator to provide grants to: (1) municipalities at risk to encourage responsible development in state-identified fire-prone regions and to mitigate the catastrophic effects of fires; and (2) states to create or update fire-hazard assessment maps. Amends the Cooperative Forestry Assistance Act of 1978 to: (1) include as a purpose of the Community and Private Land Fire Assistance Program to enhance the capacity of local governments to integrate fire-resistant community and home design into local planning, zoning, building code, and brush clearing ordinances; and (2) authorize a pilot program to assess the feasibility and advisability of providing assistance to fire-safe communities located near federal land.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
