<bill session="110" type="h" number="5232" updated="2009-01-09T03:46:14-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1202274000" datetime="2008-02-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1202274000" datetime="2008-02-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide that no Federal or State requirement to increase energy efficient lighting in public buildings shall require a hospital, school, day care center, mental health facility, or nursing home to install or utilize such energy efficient lighting if the lighting contains mercury.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400052"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400089" joined="2008-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400018" joined="2008-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400365" joined="2008-03-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400658" joined="2008-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400643" joined="2008-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400032" joined="2008-02-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1202274000" datetime="2008-02-06"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1202274000" datetime="2008-02-06"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1202274000" datetime="2008-02-06"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text></action>
		<action date="1202274000" datetime="2008-02-06"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1202360400" datetime="2008-02-07"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/6/2008--Introduced.<br/>Amends the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 to prohibit any federal or state requirement to increase energy efficient lighting in public buildings from requiring a hospital, school, day care center, mental health facility, or nursing home to install or utilize energy efficient lighting that contains mercury.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
