<bill session="110" type="h" number="523" updated="2009-01-08T17:52:40-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1193090700" datetime="2007-10-22T19:05:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="984"/></status>

	<introduced date="1169010000" datetime="2007-01-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Douglas County, Washington, PUD Conveyance Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Douglas County, Washington, PUD Conveyance Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Douglas County, Washington, PUD Conveyance Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Douglas County, Washington, PUD Conveyance Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain public land located wholly or partially within the boundaries of the Wells Hydroelectric Project of Public Utility District No. 1 of Douglas County, Washington, to the utility district.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400171"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1169010000" datetime="2007-01-17"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action date="1178769600" datetime="2007-05-10"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1191988800" datetime="2007-10-10"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1191988800" datetime="2007-10-10"><text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands Discharged.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1191988800" datetime="2007-10-10" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1193070840" datetime="2007-10-22T13:34:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-398.</text></action>
		<calendar number="252" date="1193070840" datetime="2007-10-22T13:34:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 252.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1193075580" datetime="2007-10-22T14:53:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Grijalva moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1193075580" datetime="2007-10-22T14:53:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H11789-11790"/></action>
		<action date="1193075580" datetime="2007-10-22T14:53:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 523.</text></action>
		<action date="1193075820" datetime="2007-10-22T14:57:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1193090220" datetime="2007-10-22T18:57:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H11818-11819"/></action>
		<vote date="1193090700" how="roll" roll="984" datetime="2007-10-22T19:05:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" suspension="1" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 377 - 0 (Roll no. 984).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H11789"/></vote>
		<action date="1193112000" datetime="2007-10-23"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1204088400" datetime="2008-02-27"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1210132800" datetime="2008-05-07" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1213588800" datetime="2008-06-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. With written report No. 110-378.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="810" date="1213588800" datetime="2008-06-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 810.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/16/2008--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the House on October 22, 2007. The summary of that version is repeated here.)<br/>Douglas County, Washington, PUD Conveyance Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior, if the Public Utility District No. 1 of Douglas County, Washington (PUD), submits to the Secretary an offer to acquire certain public land managed by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) for the appraised value, to convey to the PUD all interest of the United States in and to the public land. Requires: (1) the PUD to pay to the Secretary an amount equal to the appraised value of the public land, as determined according to this Act; and (2) any costs related to such conveyance to be paid by the PUD. Requires the deposit of the proceeds from such land sale in the Federal Land Disposal Account established pursuant to the Federal Land Transaction Facilitation Act, which shall be spent for improving access to public lands administered by the BLM in the state of Washington. Withdraws the public land from: (1) all forms of entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patenting under the mining laws; and (3) operation of the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws. Terminates such requirement for withdrawal of the public land two years after enactment of this Act or upon the completion of the conveyance under this Act. Instructs the Secretary to retain the authority to place conditions on the license granted to the Secretary under the Federal Power Act to insure adequate protection and utilization of the public land until the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) has issued a new license for the Wells Hydroelectric Project to replace the original license expiring on May 31, 2012. 
	</summary>
</bill>
