<bill session="110" type="h" number="53" updated="2009-01-08T16:48:40-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1193076180" datetime="2007-10-22T15:03:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Virgin Islands National Park School Lease Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Virgin Islands National Park School Lease Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to enter into a long-term lease with the Government of the United States Virgin Islands to provide land on the island of Saint John, Virgin Islands, for the establishment of a school, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400073"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insular Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1183953600" datetime="2007-07-09"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1190260800" datetime="2007-09-20"><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1190260800" datetime="2007-09-20"><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text></action>
		<action date="1191988800" datetime="2007-10-10"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1191988800" datetime="2007-10-10" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1193070900" datetime="2007-10-22T13:35:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-399.</text></action>
		<calendar number="253" date="1193070960" datetime="2007-10-22T13:36:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 253.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1193075880" datetime="2007-10-22T14:58:00-04:00"><text>Mrs. Christensen moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1193075880" datetime="2007-10-22T14:58:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H11790-11791"/></action>
		<action date="1193075880" datetime="2007-10-22T14:58:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 53.</text></action>
		<vote date="1193076180" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-10-22T15:03:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H11790-11791"/></vote>
		<action date="1193112000" datetime="2007-10-23"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1208923200" datetime="2008-04-23"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/22/2007--Passed House amended. Virgin Islands National Park School Lease Act of 2007 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to lease certain Virgin Islands National Park land on the island of Saint John, U.S. Virgin Islands, to the Government of the U.S. Virgin Islands for the purpose of establishing a school on such island. Limits the lease authorized by this Act to a 99-year term. Allows the Secretary to require such additional terms and conditions in connection with the lease as the Secretary considers appropriate to protect U.S. interests. 
	</summary>
</bill>
