<bill session="110" type="h" number="5311" updated="2009-01-09T03:55:25-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1202360400" datetime="2008-02-07"/></status>

	<introduced date="1202360400" datetime="2008-02-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 10, United States Code, to provide for the transfer certain receipts derived from leases involving Oil Shale Reserves Numbered 1 and 3 to the State of Colorado, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400620"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1202360400" datetime="2008-02-07"><text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1202360400" datetime="2008-02-07"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1202360400" datetime="2008-02-07"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1202446800" datetime="2008-02-08"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text></action>
		<action date="1202446800" datetime="2008-02-08"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text></action>
		<action date="1202878800" datetime="2008-02-13"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/7/2008--Introduced.<br/>Provides for the transfer from the Secretary of the Treasury to the state of Colorado of certain amounts derived from oil and gas development leases involving Oil Shale Reserves Numbered 1 and 3, to be used by Colorado for: (1) conservation, restoration, and protection of land, water, and wildlife resources affected by oil or gas development; (2) repair, maintenance, and construction of state and county roads in development-affected areas; and (3) capital improvement projects to address impacts of such development.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
