<bill session="110" type="h" number="5348" updated="2009-01-09T03:59:32-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1202792400" datetime="2008-02-12"/></status>

	<introduced date="1202792400" datetime="2008-02-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">American Health Benefits Program Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Social Security Act and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to assure comprehensive, affordable health insurance coverage for all Americans through an American Health Benefits Program.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400230"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="2008-02-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1202792400" datetime="2008-02-12"><text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1202792400" datetime="2008-02-12"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1202792400" datetime="2008-02-12"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1202792400" datetime="2008-02-12"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1203310800" datetime="2008-02-18"><committee name="House Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/12/2008--Introduced.<br/>American Health Benefits Program Act of 2008 - Amends the Social Security Act (SSA) to establish under a new title XXII (American Health Benefits Program) a program to provide comprehensive health insurance coverage to all Americans who are: (1) not covered under certain federal health insurance programs; and (2) not eligible for employer-provided insurance coverage. Requires provision of such coverage in a manner similar to that in which coverage has been provided to Members of Congress, federal government employees, retirees, and their dependents under the Federal Employees Health Benefits Program. Requires federal government contributions towards the coverage of eligible individuals. Establishes in the Treasury an American Health Benefits Program Trust Fund. Directs the Commissioner of Health Benefits to establish a schedule of cost-sharing subsidies for lower-income individuals. Establishes an independent Health Benefits Administration, headed by the Commissioner. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) impose a premium on individuals enrolled in a qualified health plan under SSA title XXII, which shall be reduced by the amount of government contribution; (2) allow a tax credit to covered individuals equal to the sum of the aggregate amount of premiums paid (other than government contributions) with respect to the individual's coverage, and the applicable premium subsidy; (3) impose on every employer an excise tax equal to the applicable percentage of the wages paid employees; (4) allow a tax credit against such excise tax for periods during which an employee is covered by qualified employer-provided coverage; and (5) impose a tax on hospital revenues. Makes related amendments to SSA titles XIX (Medicaid) and XXI (SCHIP). Directs the Commissioner of Health Benefits to establish new guidelines that promote the proper use and understanding of health information technologies. Establishes the Health Benefits Commission to examine and make recommendations regarding the major issues and cost drivers affecting the delivery of healthcare services as it pertains to the American Health Benefits Program.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
