<bill session="110" type="h" number="534" updated="2009-01-08T17:54:16-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1169010000" datetime="2007-01-17"/></status>

	<introduced date="1169010000" datetime="2007-01-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Rail Transit Security and Safety Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the security and safety of rail and rail transit transportation systems, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400249"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1169010000" datetime="2007-01-17"><text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1169010000" datetime="2007-01-17"><text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text></action>
		<action date="1169010000" datetime="2007-01-17"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1169096400" datetime="2007-01-18"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text></action>
		<action date="1169096400" datetime="2007-01-18"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
		<action date="1170046800" datetime="2007-01-29"><committee name="House Homeland Security"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation Security and Infrastructure Protection.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/17/2007--Introduced.<br/>Rail Transit Security and Safety Act of 2007 - Directs the Under Secretary for Border and Transportation Security to complete a vulnerability assessment of freight and passenger rail transportation, and develop specific prioritized recommendations for improving rail security. Directs the Under Secretary to establish the position of Federal Rail Security Manager. Authorizes the Secretary of Transportation to make grants to Amtrak for certain fire and life-safety improvements and infrastructure upgrades to tunnels on the Northeast Corridor. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to award grants directly to public transportation agencies for allowable capital and operational security improvements based on the prioritized rail security recommendations. Sets forth certain whistleblower protections for rail employees or other persons who have provided information or otherwise assisted in any investigation regarding certain conduct, or who have refused to violate or assist in the violation of any regulation related to public transportation security. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to make grants to railroad carriers for costs incurred in instituting a rail worker emergency training program. 
	</summary>
</bill>
