<bill session="110" type="h" number="535" updated="2009-01-08T17:54:23-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1169010000" datetime="2007-01-17"/></status>

	<introduced date="1169010000" datetime="2007-01-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Rail Worker Emergency Training Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for a rail worker emergency training program.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400249"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2007-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400402" joined="2007-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400251" joined="2007-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400641" joined="2007-05-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1169010000" datetime="2007-01-17"><text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1169010000" datetime="2007-01-17"><text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text></action>
		<action date="1169010000" datetime="2007-01-17"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1169096400" datetime="2007-01-18"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
		<action date="1169528400" datetime="2007-01-23"><committee name="House Homeland Security"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation Security and Infrastructure Protection.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/17/2007--Introduced.<br/>Rail Worker Emergency Training Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security, in coordination with the Secretary of Transportation, to make grants to railroad carriers for costs incurred in instituting a rail worker emergency training program. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to issue detailed guidelines for a rail worker emergency training program to enhance rail worker training in preparation for and response to potential or actual terrorist attacks, natural disasters, and other emergencies. Authorizes the Secretary of Homeland Security to issue a letter of noncompliance to rail carriers that fail to comply with the requirements of this Act.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
