<bill session="110" type="h" number="5352" updated="2009-01-09T04:00:01-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1222207080" datetime="2008-09-23T18:58:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="626"/></status>

	<introduced date="1202792400" datetime="2008-02-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Elder Abuse Victims Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Elder Abuse Victims Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Elder Abuse Victims Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To protect seniors in the United States from elder abuse by establishing specialized elder abuse prosecution and research programs and activities to aid victims of elder abuse, to provide training to prosecutors and other law enforcement related to elder abuse prevention and protection, and for other purposes.</title>
		<title type="official" as="amended by house">A bill to protect seniors in the United States from elder abuse by establishing specialized elder abuse prosecution and research programs and activities to aid victims of elder abuse, to provide training to prosecutors and other law enforcement related to elder abuse prevention and protection, to establish programs that provide for emergency crisis response teams to combat elder abuse, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412232"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400219" joined="2008-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400364" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400080" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400120" joined="2008-05-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1202792400" datetime="2008-02-12"><text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1202792400" datetime="2008-02-12"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1202792400" datetime="2008-02-12"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1203310800" datetime="2008-02-18"><committee name="House Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Income Security and Family Support.</text></action>
		<action date="1203915600" datetime="2008-02-25"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text></action>
		<action date="1208404800" datetime="2008-04-17"><committee name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security"/><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1210046400" datetime="2008-05-06"><committee name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security"/><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1210651200" datetime="2008-05-13"><committee name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security"/><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1210651200" datetime="2008-05-13"><committee name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security"/><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text></action>
		<action date="1210737600" datetime="2008-05-14"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1213156800" datetime="2008-06-11"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1213156800" datetime="2008-06-11" ><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1222107300" datetime="2008-09-22T15:15:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 110-864, Part I.</text></action>
		<action date="1222107300" datetime="2008-09-22T15:15:00-04:00"><text>Committee on Ways and Means discharged.</text></action>
		<calendar number="561" date="1222107300" datetime="2008-09-22T15:15:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 561.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1222107780" datetime="2008-09-22T15:23:00-04:00"><text>Ms. Sutton moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1222107780" datetime="2008-09-22T15:23:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8519-8522"/></action>
		<action date="1222107780" datetime="2008-09-22T15:23:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5352.</text></action>
		<action date="1222108260" datetime="2008-09-22T15:31:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1222206600" datetime="2008-09-23T18:50:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8658"/></action>
		<vote date="1222207080" how="roll" roll="626" datetime="2008-09-23T18:58:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" suspension="1" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 387 - 28 (Roll no. 626). (text: CR H 9/22/2008 H8658)</text></vote>
		<action date="1222207080" datetime="2008-09-23T18:58:00-04:00"><text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action date="1222228800" datetime="2008-09-24"><text>Received in the Senate.</text></action>
		<action date="1222920000" datetime="2008-10-02"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/23/2008--Passed House amended. Elder Abuse Victims Act of 2008 - Title I: Elder Abuse Victims - (Sec. 101) Directs the Attorney General to: (1) study and report to Congress on state laws and practices relating to elder abuse, neglect, and exploitation; and (2) develop objectives, priorities, policies, and a long-term plan for elder justice programs and activities. Directs the Comptroller General to report to Congress any recommendations with respect to any federal legislation, regulations, or programs determined necessary to improve elder justice in the United States. Authorizes appropriations for FY2009-FY2015. (Sec. 102) Authorizes the Attorney General to award victim advocacy grants for study of the special needs of victims of elder abuse, neglect, and exploitation, including related pilot programs. Authorizes appropriations for FY2009-FY2015. (Sec. 103) Directs the Attorney General to award grants to eligible entities to provide training, technical assistance, policy development, multidisciplinary coordination, and other types of support to local prosecutors and courts handling elder justice-related cases, funding in particular: (1) specially designated elder justice positions or units in local prosecutors' offices and local courts; and (2) the creation of a Center for the Prosecution of Elder Abuse, Neglect, and Exploitation to advise and support local prosecutors and courts nationwide in the pursuit of such cases. Authorizes appropriations for FY2009-FY2015. (Sec. 104) Directs the Attorney General to award similar grants to eligible entities to provide support to state prosecutors and courts, employees of state Attorneys General, and Medicaid Fraud Control Units handling elder justice-related matters. Authorizes use of such grants to: (1) establish specially designated elder justice positions or units in state prosecutors' offices and state courts; and (2) create a position to coordinate elder justice-related cases, training, technical assistance, and policy development for state prosecutors and courts. Authorizes appropriations for FY2009-FY2015. (Sec. 105) Directs the Attorney General to award similar grants to eligible entities to provide support to police, sheriffs, detectives, public safety officers, corrections personnel, and other first responders who handle elder justice-related matters to fund specially designated elder justice positions or units designed to support first responders in elder justice matters. Authorizes appropriations for FY2009-FY2015. (Sec. 106) Directs the Attorney General to: (1) require each recipient to use a portion of grant funds to conduct a validated evaluation of the effectiveness of the activities carried out through the grant; or (2) use a portion of funds under this title to assist an eligible entity to conduct such an evaluation. Prescribes general requirements for grant applications and their review and selection. Authorizes appropriations for FY2009-FY2015. (Sec. 107) Defines eligible entity as a state or local government agency, Indian tribe or tribal organization, or any other public or nonprofit private entity that is engaged in and has expertise in issues relating to elder justice or a field necessary to promote elder justice efforts. Title II: Elder Serve Victim Grant Programs - (Sec. 201) Directs the Attorney General, acting through the Director of the Office of Victims of Crime of the Department of Justice, to carry out a three-year Elder Serve Victim program to provide grants to eligible entities (crime victim assistance programs receiving grants under the Victims of Crime Act of 1984) to establish programs to facilitate and coordinate programs for victims of elder abuse. Requires a recipient to use its grant to establish an Emergency Crisis Response Team program, which shall: (1) include immediate, short-term emergency services, including shelter, care services, food, clothing, transportation to medical or legal appointments; and (2) provide other appropriate services to victims of elder abuse. Limits short-term housing for such victims to 30 days. Requires a grant recipient also to establish counseling, mental health screening, emergency legal advocacy, job placement assistance, bereavement counseling, and other appropriate service programs. Authorizes appropriations for FY2009-FY2011.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
