<bill session="110" type="h" number="54" updated="2009-01-08T16:48:52-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/></status>

	<introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Teacher Recruitment Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To expand the eligibility of individuals to qualify for loan forgiveness for teachers in order to provide additional incentives for teachers currently employed or seeking employment in economically depressed rural areas, Territories, and Indian Reservations.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400073"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400041" joined="2007-01-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1178683200" datetime="2007-05-09"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/4/2007--Introduced.<br/>Teacher Recruitment Act of 2007 - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 (HEA) to establish new programs for teacher student loan forgiveness under the guaranteed loan program and the direct loan program. Makes eligible for such student loan forgiveness any new borrower on or after October 1, 1998, who is: (1) employed as a full-time teacher in a public elementary or secondary school in an economically disadvantaged or depressed and underserved rural area; (2) state-certified or state-licensed to teach, and in compliance with state or local accountability standards; and (3) not in default on the loan. Directs the Secretary to establish a formula that ensures fairness and equality for applicants in the selection of borrowers for such loan repayment under this section, based on the amount available. Limits the portion of the outstanding loan obligation which the Secretary may repay to 15% for the first or second year of such service, 20% for the third or fourth year, and 30% for the fifth year.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
