<bill session="110" type="h" number="5401" updated="2009-01-09T04:05:52-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1202792400" datetime="2008-02-12"/></status>

	<introduced date="1202792400" datetime="2008-02-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Grants for Renewable and Energy Efficiency Needs School Improvement Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">GREEN School Improvement Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of Education to make grants for energy efficiency improvements and renewable energy improvements at public school facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412209"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400184" joined="2008-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2008-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412198" joined="2008-03-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2008-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="412240" joined="2008-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412204" joined="2008-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400638" joined="2008-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400193" joined="2008-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400415" joined="2008-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2008-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2008-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400042" joined="2008-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400639" joined="2008-05-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400186" joined="2008-02-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1202792400" datetime="2008-02-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/12/2008--Introduced.<br/>Grants for Renewable and Energy Efficiency Needs School Improvement Act or the GREEN School Improvement Act - Requires the Secretary of Education to allocate funds to states to provide competitive grants to local educational agencies and eligible entities to make energy improvements to schools that result in a direct reduction in school energy costs, an improvement in teacher and student health, or the installation of renewable energy technologies. Requires a priority to be given to high-need local agencies and local agencies designated with a specified metrocentric locale codes.<br/>Sets forth grant application requirements, including a needs assessment for the schools involved and a description of the benefits and costs of the energy improvements to be made. Authorizes a state agency to require matching funds.<br/>Requires the Secretary of Education to make competitive grants to states to develop guidelines and standards for energy improvements and new facility construction.<br/>Requires recipients of grants under this Act to report on their use of funds. Requires the Secretary to use report results to publish best practices: (1) for school energy improvement activities; and (2) to further the goal of developing nationwide and regional guidelines and standards for improvements, modernizations, renovations, and new construction.<br/>Directs the Comptroller General to carry out a study on: (1) the costs of repair, renovation, and construction for public elementary schools and secondary schools; (2) federal, state, local, and private expenditures for such costs; and (3) the potential of federal funding to address the repair, renovation, and construction needs of such schools with energy improvements.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
