<bill session="110" type="h" number="5434" updated="2009-01-09T04:09:38-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1202878800" datetime="2008-02-13"/></status>

	<introduced date="1202878800" datetime="2008-02-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Americans from Violent Crime Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To protect innocent Americans from violent crime in national parks.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400175"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400279" joined="2008-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412252" joined="2008-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400209" joined="2008-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400317" joined="2008-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400176" joined="2008-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400652" joined="2008-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400206" joined="2008-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400287" joined="2008-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400440" joined="2008-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400141" joined="2008-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400088" joined="2008-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412191" joined="2008-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412255" joined="2008-03-11"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1202878800" datetime="2008-02-13"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1203397200" datetime="2008-02-19"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, and Oceans.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/13/2008--Introduced.<br/>Protecting Americans from Violent Crime Act of 2008 - Bars, except as provided under current federal criminal law regarding the possession or the causing to be present of firearms and other dangerous weapons in federal facilities (other than federal court facilities), the promulgation or enforcement of any regulation that prohibits an individual from possessing, transporting, or carrying a firearm, including an assembled or functional firearm, in any unit of the National Park System or the National Wildlife Refuge System if: (1) the individual is not otherwise prohibited by law from possessing, transporting, or carrying the firearm; and (2) the possession, transportation, or carrying of the firearm is in compliance with the law governing possession, transportation, or carrying of firearms in parks of the state in which the unit is located. 
	</summary>
</bill>
