<bill session="110" type="h" number="5448" updated="2009-01-09T04:11:20-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1202965200" datetime="2008-02-14"/></status>

	<introduced date="1202965200" datetime="2008-02-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Full Faith in Veterans Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the disability compensation evaluation procedure of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for veterans with post-traumatic stress disorder, to improve the diagnosis and treatment of post-traumatic stress disorder by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400007"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400123" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400290" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400661" joined="2008-09-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400041" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400177" joined="2008-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2008-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400282" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2008-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412210" joined="2008-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400274" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412189" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400052" joined="2008-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400396" joined="2008-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400412" joined="2008-04-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="412197" joined="2008-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400030" joined="2008-03-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400316" joined="2008-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400245" joined="2008-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400082" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400356" joined="2008-10-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400172" joined="2008-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="412240" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400400" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400251" joined="2008-03-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412200" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2008-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400240" joined="2008-03-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412233" joined="2008-04-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1202965200" datetime="2008-02-14"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1203051600" datetime="2008-02-15"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1213243200" datetime="2008-06-12"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/14/2008--Introduced.<br/>Full Faith in Veterans Act of 2008 - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to accept as sufficient proof of service-connection of post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) alleged to have been incurred in or aggravated by active military service a diagnosis of PTSD by a mental health professional, together with a written determination that such disorder is related to the veteran's service, if consistent with the circumstances, conditions, or hardships of such service, notwithstanding that there is no official record of such incurrence or aggravation during such service. Requires the Secretary to resolve every reasonable doubt in favor of the veteran. Allows PTSD service-connection to be rebutted by clear and convincing evidence. Directs the Secretary to require Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) employees responsible for rating disabilities, evaluating claims for disability compensation for PTSD, or adjudicating disability compensation ratings to complete a certification program established by the Secretary. Requires the Secretary to: (1) conduct audits of examinations of veterans who submit claims for disability compensation for PTSD; (2) update the schedule for rating disabilities with respect to PTSD, traumatic brain injury, and other mental disorders; (3) implement new PTSD criteria; (4) implement a holistic treatment approach for veterans with PTSD; and (5) require VA employees responsible for adjudicating disability compensation ratings to take into consideration veterans' treatment records from readjustment counseling centers and written opinions of mental health professionals.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
