<bill session="110" type="h" number="5452" updated="2009-01-09T04:11:48-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1202965200" datetime="2008-02-14"/></status>

	<introduced date="1202965200" datetime="2008-02-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Coastal State Renewable Energy Promotion Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 to authorize grants to coastal States to support State efforts to initiate and complete surveys of coastal State waters and Federal waters adjacent to a State's coastal zone to identify potential areas suitable or unsuitable for the exploration, development, and production of renewable energy, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400062"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400041" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400128" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400149" joined="2008-02-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400102" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400129" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400663" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400193" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400425" joined="2008-02-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1202965200" datetime="2008-02-14"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1203397200" datetime="2008-02-19"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, and Oceans.</text></action>
		<action date="1204174800" datetime="2008-02-28"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/14/2008--Introduced.<br/>Coastal State Renewable Energy Promotion Act of 2008 - Amends the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 to authorize grants to eligible coastal states to support voluntary state efforts to initiate and complete surveys of portions of coastal state waters and federal waters adjacent to a state's coastal zone to identify potential areas suitable or unsuitable for the exploration, development, and production of renewable (wind, wave, current, tidal, or ocean thermal) energy that are consistent with the enforceable policies of coastal management plans. Requires suitable areas to be given priority consideration by federal agencies for the siting, licensing, leasing, or permitting of renewable energy facilities and requires unsuitable areas to be avoided by federal agencies to the maximum extent practicable.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
