<bill session="110" type="h" number="5466" updated="2009-01-09T04:13:30-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1202965200" datetime="2008-02-14"/></status>

	<introduced date="1202965200" datetime="2008-02-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Invest in KIDS Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Investment in Kids' Instruction, Development and Support Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To improve outcomes for vulnerable children by investing in families, improving accountability in the child welfare system, and finding safe, stable, and permanent homes for foster children.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400262"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400160" joined="2008-04-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400092" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400080" joined="2008-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400065" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400198" joined="2008-07-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400229" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400101" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400412" joined="2008-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400130" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400008" joined="2008-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400308" joined="2008-06-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400001" joined="2008-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400103" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2008-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400653" joined="2008-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412200" joined="2008-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400081" joined="2008-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400415" joined="2008-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2008-04-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="412228" joined="2008-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400043" joined="2008-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400208" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400240" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400024" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400179" joined="2008-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="2008-03-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1202965200" datetime="2008-02-14"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action date="1203310800" datetime="2008-02-18"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Income Security and Family Support.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/14/2008--Introduced.<br/>Investment in Kids' Instruction, Development and Support Act, or the Invest in KIDS Act - Amends part B of title IV of the Social Security Act to revise requirements for foster care and adoption assistance and for child welfare services. Authorizes a state foster care and adoption assistance plan, at state option, to include a child and family services component. Eliminates certain income eligibility requirements for foster care and adoption assistance. Authorizes: (1) Indian tribes to receive federal funds for such assistance; and (2) separate standards for foster family homes in which a foster parent is a relative of the foster child that protect the child's safety and provide for criminal records checks. Requires application to all children in state custody of state plan standards for foster family homes and child care institutions. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administration of Children and Families, to make child welfare service quality improvement grants to states. Provides for an increased payment rate to states for short-term training of certain child welfare agency staff and court personnel. Allows state coverage of children in foster care after age 18 and up to age 21. Provides for state-optional kinship guardianship assistance payments for children. Authorizes the Secretary to make family connection grants to states. Extends the adoption incentives program for five years, and increases incentives payments for special needs adoptions and older child adoptions. Requires state plans to provide for siblings removed from their homes to be placed in the same foster care placement, unless contrary to their safety or well-being. Requires a state child welfare services plan to provide for development of a plan for the ongoing oversight and coordination of health care services for any child in a foster care placement. Requires case plans to include a plan for ensuring the educational stability of the child in foster care. 
	</summary>
</bill>
