<bill session="110" type="h" number="5460" updated="2009-01-09T04:12:43-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1202965200" datetime="2008-02-14"/></status>

	<introduced date="1202965200" datetime="2008-02-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Detainee Treatment Act of 2005 and title 18, United States Code, to include waterboarding in the definition of cruel, inhuman, or degrading treatment or punishment and in the definition of torture, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400124"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400403" joined="2008-02-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1202965200" datetime="2008-02-14"><text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Intelligence (Permanent Select), and Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1202965200" datetime="2008-02-14"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1202965200" datetime="2008-02-14"><text>Referred to House Intelligence (Permanent Select)</text></action>
		<action date="1202965200" datetime="2008-02-14"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1205726400" datetime="2008-03-17"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/14/2008--Introduced.<br/>Amends the Detainee Treatment Act of 2005 and the federal criminal code to include waterboarding (simulated drowning) within the definitions of cruel, inhuman, or degrading treatment or punishment, and torture. Includes individuals under the custody or physical control of the Central Intelligence Agency (CIA) within the protection against cruel, inhuman, or degrading treatment or punishment by the government.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
