<bill session="110" type="h" number="5471" updated="2009-01-09T04:14:06-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1202965200" datetime="2008-02-14"/></status>

	<introduced date="1202965200" datetime="2008-02-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Consumer Product Safety Commission to prescribe rules requiring distinctive markings on toy and look-alike firearms.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400409"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400032" joined="2008-02-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1202965200" datetime="2008-02-14"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1202965200" datetime="2008-02-14"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/14/2008--Introduced.<br/>Requires the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) to promulgate a final consumer product safety rule providing for a distinctive marking or device for any toy, look-alike, or imitation firearm to distinguish the look-alike firearm from a firearm. Includes in the term &quot;look-alike firearm&quot; any imitation of any original firearm manufactured, designed, and produced since 1898, including toy guns, water guns, replica nonguns, and air-soft guns firing nonmetallic projectiles. Excludes any nonfiring replica of a firearm developed before 1898, or traditional BB, paint-ball, or pellet-firing air guns that expel a projectile through the force of air pressure. Declares that this Act supersedes any state or local law relating to markings, identification, or sale of toy, look-alike, and imitation firearms. Prohibits any state or political subdivision from prohibiting the sale or manufacturer of any look-alike, nonfiring to or collector replica of an antique firearm developed prior to 1898 or prohibiting the sale (other than prohibiting the sale to minors) of traditional BB, paint ball, or pellet-firing air guns. Declares that this paragraph does not apply to any provision of state or local law enacted before January 30, 1955, that prohibits the sale of any toy or imitation firearm unless its exterior surface is brightly colored.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
