<bill session="110" type="h" number="5480" updated="2009-01-09T04:15:09-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1203915600" datetime="2008-02-25"/></status>

	<introduced date="1203915600" datetime="2008-02-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Funding Warning Response Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Help Efficient, Accessible, Low-cost, Timely Healthcare (HEALTH) Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To respond to a Medicare funding warning.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400189"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400036" joined="2008-02-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1203915600" datetime="2008-02-25"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E228)</text></action>
		<action date="1203915600" datetime="2008-02-25"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1203915600" datetime="2008-02-25"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1203915600" datetime="2008-02-25"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1203915600" datetime="2008-02-25"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1203915600" datetime="2008-02-25"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1204261200" datetime="2008-02-29"><committee name="House Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/25/2008--Introduced.<br/>Medicare Funding Warning Response Act of 2008 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) develop and implement a system for encouraging nationwide adoption and use of interoperable electronic health records and to make available personal health records for Medicare beneficiaries; (2) develop and implement a plan for ensuring that, by the year 2013, quality measures are available and reported with respect to at least 50% of the care provided under the Medicare program; (3) design and implement a system under which a portion of Medicare payments that would otherwise be made to some or all classes of individuals and entities furnishing items or services to beneficiaries would be based on the quality and efficiency of their performance; (4) implement incentives for Medicare beneficiaries to use more efficient providers and preventive services known to reduce costs; and (5) use and release Medicare data for quality improvement, performance measurement, public reporting, and treatment-related purposes. Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to authorize the public release of physician performance measurements. Help Efficient, Accessible, Low-cost, Timely Healthcare (HEALTH) Act of 2008 - Sets conditions for health care lawsuits to: (1) require commencement of such lawsuits within three years after manifestation or one year after discovery of injury; (2) limit noneconomic damages and attorneys' contingent fees; (3) prescribe requirements for determining punitive damages; (4) deny punitive damages in the case of products approved, cleared, or licensed by the Food and Drug Administration (FDA), or otherwise considered in compliance with FDA standards; and (4) authorize periodic payment of future damages. Amends SSA title XVIII part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program) to require high income-related reductions in the part D premium subsidy.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
