<bill session="110" type="h" number="5507" updated="2009-01-09T04:18:15-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1204088400" datetime="2008-02-27"/></status>

	<introduced date="1204088400" datetime="2008-02-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Fully-Funded United States Military Redeployment and Sovereignty of Iraq Restoration Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require the safe, complete, and fully-funded redeployment of United States Armed Forces and contractor security forces from Iraq and to prohibit the establishment of any enduring or permanent United States military bases in Iraq, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400436"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2008-06-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="412221" joined="2008-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400333" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400424" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400063" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-06-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2008-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400013" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400422" joined="2008-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400217" joined="2008-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400074" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2008-04-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400090" joined="2008-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400301" joined="2008-04-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1204088400" datetime="2008-02-27"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1204088400" datetime="2008-02-27"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1204088400" datetime="2008-02-27"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/27/2008--Introduced.<br/>Fully-Funded United States Military Redeployment and Sovereignty of Iraq Restoration Act of 2008 - States that it is the policy of the United States to: (1) commence the safe and orderly redeployment of U.S. troops and military contractors from Iraq; (2) pursue security and stability in Iraq through diplomacy; (3) help preserve the territorial integrity of Iraq and establish a democratic central government there; (4) account for missing U.S. personnel and citizens in Iraq; and (5) turn over all internal security activities and military operations in Iraq to its elected government within one year after the enactment of this Act. Repeals the Authorization for Use of Military Force Against Iraq Resolution of 2002. Requires the withdrawal of U.S. Armed Forces and contractor security forces from Iraq within one year. Prohibits the further use of any funds to continue such deployments. Prohibits the construction of permanent or long-term military installations in Iraq unless explicitly approved by Congress. Authorizes the President to deploy an international stabilization force to Iraq. Requires the closure of U.S. detention centers in Iraq. Permits actions for damages by a citizen or national of Iraq (or of any other foreign country who was imprisoned or detained in Iraq) against the United States for certain acts committed by specified U.S. personnel against prisoners or detainees in Iraq. Limits the total number of U.S. government personnel at the United States Embassy in Iraq. Prohibits U.S. production-sharing agreements for Iraqi petroleum resources. Establishes an Iraqi-American Interparliamentary Group. Authorizes the President of the United States Institute for Peace to provide political reconciliation assistance to Iraq. States that it is the policy of the United States to work with Iraq and the international community to provide for the reconstruction of Iraq. Directs the President to: (1) establish and implement a plan to initiate a diplomatic surge to bring an end to the occupation of Iraq; and (2) deploy U.S. Armed Forces outside the United States to target global terrorism. Establishes the Commission on Funding the Reconstruction of Iraq.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
