<bill session="110" type="h" number="5511" updated="2009-01-09T04:18:43-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1213930800" datetime="2008-06-19T12:00:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1204174800" datetime="2008-02-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Leadville Mine Drainage Tunnel Remediation Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Leadville Mine Drainage Tunnel Remediation Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Leadville Mine Drainage Tunnel Remediation Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Reclamation, to remedy problems caused by a collapsed drainage tunnel in Leadville, Colorado, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412191"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400620" joined="2008-03-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400412" joined="2008-02-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400287" joined="2008-03-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1204174800" datetime="2008-02-28"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1204606800" datetime="2008-03-04"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text></action>
		<action date="1210219200" datetime="2008-05-08"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1213156800" datetime="2008-06-11"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1213156800" datetime="2008-06-11" ><text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1213723920" datetime="2008-06-17T14:32:00-04:00"><text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-715.</text></action>
		<calendar number="456" date="1213723920" datetime="2008-06-17T14:32:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 456.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1213728480" datetime="2008-06-17T15:48:00-04:00"><text>Ms. Bordallo moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1213728480" datetime="2008-06-17T15:48:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H5430-5431"/></action>
		<action date="1213728480" datetime="2008-06-17T15:48:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5511.</text></action>
		<action date="1213728660" datetime="2008-06-17T15:51:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Ms. Bordallo objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text></action>
		<action date="1213887540" datetime="2008-06-19T11:59:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H5595"/></action>
		<vote date="1213930800" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-06-19T12:00:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote. (text: CR 6/17/2008 H5430)</text></vote>
		<action date="1213934400" datetime="2008-06-20"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/19/2008--Passed House amended. Leadville Mine Drainage Tunnel Remediation Act of 2008 - Amends the Reclamation Projects Authorization and Adjustment Act of 1992 to repeal a provision requiring construction of a water treatment plant to treat effluent discharged from the Leadville Mine Drainage Tunnel, Colorado. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to participate in the implementation of the operable unit 6 remedy for the California Gulch Superfund Site, as defined in the Environmental Protection Agency's (EPA) 2003 Record of Decision for such unit, by: (1) treating water behind any blockage or bulkhead in the Tunnel; and (2) managing and maintaining the mine pool behind such blockage or bulkhead at a level that precludes surface runoff and releases and minimizes the potential for Tunnel failure due to excessive water pressure.<br/>Requires the Secretary to take necessary steps to repair or maintain the Tunnel's structural integrity to prevent Tunnel failure and to preclude uncontrolled release of water from the Tunnel.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
