<bill session="110" type="h" number="5518" updated="2009-01-09T04:19:33-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1204174800" datetime="2008-02-28"/></status>

	<introduced date="1204174800" datetime="2008-02-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Unsafe Meat and Poultry Recall Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Meat Inspection Act and the Poultry Products Inspection Act to authorize the Secretary of Agriculture to order the recall of meat and poultry that is adulterated, misbranded, or otherwise unsafe.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400413"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1204174800" datetime="2008-02-28"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E272-273)</text></action>
		<action date="1204174800" datetime="2008-02-28"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text></action>
		<action date="1227070800" datetime="2008-11-19"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/28/2008--Introduced.<br/>Unsafe Meat and Poultry Recall Act - Amends the Federal Meat Inspection Act and the Poultry Products Inspection Act to: (1) direct a person (other than a household consumer or other exempted person) who believes a meat or poultry product that such person handled is adulterated or misbranded to notify the Secretary of Agriculture; (2) direct the Secretary, upon a determination of a public health risk from such adulteration or misbranding, to permit the person to voluntarily provide handler notification, cease distribution, recall such product, and provide consumer notice; and (3) authorize the Secretary, in the case of noncompliance, to require that the person take such actions (other than consumer notice which shall be provided by the Secretary). Defines &quot;person.&quot; 
	</summary>
</bill>
