<bill session="110" type="h" number="5548" updated="2009-01-09T04:23:00-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1204779600" datetime="2008-03-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1204779600" datetime="2008-03-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Postal Service Access Assurance Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the continued availability of automated stamp vending machines at facilities of the United States Postal Service serving underserved communities, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412236"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412221" joined="2008-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2008-06-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1204779600" datetime="2008-03-06"><text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1204779600" datetime="2008-03-06"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1204779600" datetime="2008-03-06"><text>Referred to House Financial Services</text></action>
		<action date="1207800000" datetime="2008-04-10"><committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/6/2008--Introduced.<br/>Postal Service Access Assurance Act of 2008 - Requires the U.S. Postal Service to ensure that, to the maximum extent practicable, automated stamp vending machines are provided at all facilities which are owned by or under the control of the Postal Service and provide retail services to the public. Exempts automated stamp vending machines in such locations from requirements that business operations conducted by the Postal Service and certain other entities be fully capable of accepting $1 coins.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
