<bill session="110" type="h" number="556" updated="2009-01-08T17:57:31-05:00">
	<status><enacted date="1185422400" datetime="2007-07-26" /></status>

	<introduced date="1169096400" datetime="2007-01-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Security Foreign Investment Reform and Strengthened Transparency Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">National Security Foreign Investment Reform and Strengthened Transparency Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">National Security Foreign Investment Reform and Strengthened Transparency Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">Foreign Investment and National Security Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="enacted">Foreign Investment and National Security Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure national security while promoting foreign investment and the creation and maintenance of jobs, to reform the process by which such investments are examined for any effect they may have on national security, to establish the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400251"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400123" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400661" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400061" joined="2007-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400327" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400034" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400219" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400280" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400659" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400257" joined="2007-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400381" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400027" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400660" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400282" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400271" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400424" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400344" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400379" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400018" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400003" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400423" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="2007-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400288" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400249" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="412198" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400010" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400402" joined="2007-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400235" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400230" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400277" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400311" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400051" joined="2007-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="412193" joined="2007-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400631" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400087" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400166" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400653" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400195" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400255" joined="2007-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400338" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400074" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="412196" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400171" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400012" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400145" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400109" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400139" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400090" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400182" joined="2007-01-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400150" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400363" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400163" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400179" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400639" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400309" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400252" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400186" joined="2007-01-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1169096400" datetime="2007-01-18"><text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1169096400" datetime="2007-01-18"><text>Referred to House Financial Services</text></action>
		<action date="1169096400" datetime="2007-01-18"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1169096400" datetime="2007-01-18"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1170392400" datetime="2007-02-02"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text></action>
		<action date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"><committee name="House Financial Services"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13" ><committee name="House Financial Services"/><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1171429200" datetime="2007-02-14"><committee name="House Financial Services"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1171429200" datetime="2007-02-14" ><committee name="House Financial Services"/><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1171653900" datetime="2007-02-16T15:25:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Frank (MA) asked unanimous consent that the Committee on Financial Services have until midnight on Feb. 23 to file a report on H.R. 556. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action date="1172268180" datetime="2007-02-23T18:03:00-05:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 110-24, Part I.</text></action>
		<action date="1172268180" datetime="2007-02-23T18:03:00-05:00"><text>Committee on Energy and Commerce discharged.</text></action>
		<action date="1172268240" datetime="2007-02-23T18:04:00-05:00"><text>Committee on Foreign Affairs discharged.</text></action>
		<calendar number="9" date="1172268240" datetime="2007-02-23T18:04:00-05:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 9.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1172619360" datetime="2007-02-27T19:36:00-05:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 195 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 556 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Financial Services now printed in the bill.</text></action>
		<action date="1172675280" datetime="2007-02-28T11:08:00-05:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 195 passed House.</text></action>
		<action date="1172675340" datetime="2007-02-28T11:09:00-05:00"><text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 195.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H1987-2010"/><reference label="text of measure as reported in House" ref="CR H1994-1997"/></action>
		<action date="1172675340" datetime="2007-02-28T11:09:00-05:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 556 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be read by section. Bill is open to amendments. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Financial Services now printed in the bill.</text></action>
		<action date="1172675400" datetime="2007-02-28T11:10:00-05:00"><text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 195 and Rule XVIII.</text></action>
		<action date="1172675400" datetime="2007-02-28T11:10:00-05:00"><text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Ed Pastor to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text></action>
		<action date="1172675400" datetime="2007-02-28T11:10:00-05:00"><text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 556.</text></action>
		<action date="1172677320" datetime="2007-02-28T11:42:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Frank (MA) amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action date="1172677620" datetime="2007-02-28T11:47:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the King (IA) amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action date="1172721780" datetime="2007-02-28T12:03:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Barrow amendment numbered 12 under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action date="1172721960" datetime="2007-02-28T12:06:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committtee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the McCaul amendment numbered 5 under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action date="1172722260" datetime="2007-02-28T12:11:00-05:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of the debate on the McCaul amendment numbered 5, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes prevailed. Mr. McCaul demanded a recorded vote and the Chair announced further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until late in the legislative day.</text></action>
		<action date="1172722380" datetime="2007-02-28T12:13:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the McCaul amendment numbered 6 under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action date="1172722740" datetime="2007-02-28T12:19:00-05:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of the debate on the McCaul amendment numbered 6, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes prevailed. Mr. McCaul demanded a recorded vote and the Chair announced further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until late in the legislative day.</text></action>
		<action date="1172722800" datetime="2007-02-28T12:20:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the McCaul amendment numbered 7 under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action date="1172724240" datetime="2007-02-28T12:44:00-05:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of the debate on the McCaul amendment numbered 7, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes prevailed. Mr. McCaul demanded a recorded vote and the Chair announced further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until late in the legislative day.</text></action>
		<action date="1172724360" datetime="2007-02-28T12:46:00-05:00"><text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1172683980" datetime="2007-02-28T13:33:00-05:00"><text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 556.</text></action>
		<action date="1172683980" datetime="2007-02-28T13:33:00-05:00"><text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2007"/></action>
		<action date="1172684040" datetime="2007-02-28T13:34:00-05:00"><text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text></action>
		<action date="1172684040" datetime="2007-02-28T13:34:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Neugebauer moved to recommit with instructions to Financial Services.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2007-2009"/><reference label="text" ref="CR H2007-2008"/></action>
		<action date="1172684100" datetime="2007-02-28T13:35:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Neugebauer motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with amendments that require the President to include in the annual report a detailed discussion of factors, including the deleterious effect of burdensome regulations.</text></action>
		<action date="1172684640" datetime="2007-02-28T13:44:00-05:00"><text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2008"/></action>
		<action date="1172685780" datetime="2007-02-28T14:03:00-05:00"><text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 193 - 229 (Roll no. 109).</text></action>
		<vote date="1172686380" how="roll" roll="110" datetime="2007-02-28T14:13:00-05:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 423 - 0 (Roll no. 110).</text></vote>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1183089600" datetime="2007-06-29"><text>Senate Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text></action>
		<action date="1183089600" datetime="2007-06-29"><text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S8755"/></action>
		<action date="1183089600" datetime="2007-06-29"><text>Senate struck all after the Enacting Clause and substituted the language of S. 1610 amended.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S8755"/></action>
		<vote date="1183089600" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2007-06-29" where="s" type="vote2" result="pass" ><text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text></vote>
		<action date="1183089600" datetime="2007-06-29"><text>See also S. 1610.</text></action>
		<action date="1183089600" datetime="2007-06-29"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<action date="1184092080" datetime="2007-07-10T15:28:00-04:00"><text>Mrs. Maloney (NY) moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment.</text></action>
		<action date="1184092140" datetime="2007-07-10T15:29:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on the motion to suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment to H.R. 556.</text></action>
		<action date="1184092740" datetime="2007-07-10T15:39:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1184181000" datetime="2007-07-11T16:10:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 370 - 45 (Roll no. 614).</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H7558-7559"/><reference label="text as House agreed to Senate amendment" ref="CR H7452-7455"/></action>
		<topresident date="1184126400" datetime="2007-07-11" ><text>Cleared for White House.</text></topresident>
		<topresident date="1184731200" datetime="2007-07-18" ><text>Presented to President.</text></topresident>
		<signed date="1185422400" datetime="2007-07-26" ><text>Signed by President.</text></signed>
		<enacted number="110-49" date="1185422400" datetime="2007-07-26" type="public" ><text>Became Public Law No: 110-49.</text></enacted>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/26/2007--Public Law. (This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the Senate on June 29, 2007. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Foreign Investment and National Security Act of 2007 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Defense Production Act of 1950 to revise provisions concerning presidential authority to review certain mergers, acquisitions, and takeovers to direct the President, acting through the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States (CFIUS), and upon receiving written notification from any parties to a possible merger, acquisition or takeover proposed or pending after August 23, 1988, which could result in foreign control of any person engaged in interstate commerce (covered transaction), to review such covered transaction to determine its effects on national security. Requires CFIUS to investigate a covered transaction which it determines is a foreign government-controlled transaction. Permits any party to a covered transaction to initiate a review by submitting a written notice of the transaction to CFIUS. Authorizes the President or CFIUS to initiate a review of: (1) any covered transaction; (2) any covered transaction that has been previously reviewed or investigated, if any party submitted false or misleading material information; or (3) any covered transaction that has been previously reviewed or investigated, if any party intentionally materially breaches a mitigation agreement or condition imposed on the transaction. Requires CFIUS to immediately conduct an investigation of the effects of certain covered transactions on national security and to take necessary actions to protect the national security, if a review results in a determination that: (1) the transaction threatens to impair national security and that threat has not been mitigated, or the transaction is a foreign government-controlled transaction; (2) the transaction would result in control of any U.S. critical infrastructure by a foreign person, if CFIUS determines that the transaction could impair national security and that impairment has not been properly mitigated; or (3) the lead agency for each covered transaction recommends, and CFIUS concurs, that an investigation be undertaken. Requires such investigations to be completed within 45 days. Provides that an investigation of a foreign government-controlled transaction or one involving a critical infrastructure will not be required if the Secretary of the Treasury and the head of the lead agency jointly determine that the transaction will not impair national security. Requires the chairperson of CFIUS: (1) to publish in the Federal Register guidance on the types of transactions that CFIUS has reviewed and that have presented national security considerations; and (2) and head of the lead agency to transmit to specified Members of Congress a certified notice and written report concerning each investigation of a covered transaction. Requires the Director of National Intelligence to conduct an analysis of any threat to national security posed by a covered transaction. (Sec. 3) Establishes: (1) CFIUS as a multi-agency statutory committee and revises its membership; and (2) an additional Assistant Secretary of the Treasury to perform CFIUS-related duties. Requires the Secretary to designate a CFIUS member(s) to act as the lead agency or agencies with respect to a covered transaction. (Sec. 4) Adds several factors to be considered by the President in evaluating a covered transaction, including whether the proposed transaction: (1) has national security-related effects on U.S. critical technologies; and (2) is a foreign government-controlled transaction. (Sec. 5) Authorizes CFIUS or a lead agency to enter into agreements with parties to a covered transaction to mitigate any threat to national security. Requires the lead agency to negotiate, modify, monitor, and enforce such agreements. Requires designated agencies to provide periodic reports to CFIUS on the implementation of any agreements or conditions. (Sec. 6) Authorizes the President to suspend or prohibit any covered transaction that threatens to impair national security. (Current law authorizes the President to suspend or prohibit a transaction by or with foreign persons so that their control will not threaten to impair national security.) Requires (under current law, authorizes) the President to consider specified factors (including those added in this Act) when determining whether to suspend or prohibit a covered transaction. (Sec. 7) Requires: (1) upon request, CFIUS to brief certain Members of Congress of covered transactions for which action has concluded; and (2) CFIUS annual reports to Congress after completed investigations. Requires specific report information with respect to possible foreign acquisition of U.S. companies involved in the research, development, or production of critical technologies, as well as possible industrial espionage activities. Requires the Secretary to: (1) annually study foreign direct investments in the United States, especially investments in critical infrastructure and industries affecting national security by foreign governments (or their agents) which comply with any boycott of Israel or do not ban terrorist organizations; and (2) report each study's results to Congress. Directs the Inspector General of the Treasury to: (1) conduct an investigation of each failure of the Department of the Treasury to make any report required by CFIUS; and (2) report to the appropriate congressional committees on investigation results. (Sec. 8) Requires the certification of information submitted by a party to a covered transaction.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
