<bill session="110" type="h" number="5570" updated="2009-01-09T04:25:31-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1208278680" datetime="2008-04-15T13:58:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1205121600" datetime="2008-03-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Religious Worker Visa Extension Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Religious Worker Visa Extension Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Religious Worker Visa Extension Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to eliminate the sunset in the special immigrant nonminister religious worker visa program.</title>
		<title type="official" as="amended by house">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act with respect to the special immigrant nonminister religious worker program, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400245"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1205121600" datetime="2008-03-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1205208000" datetime="2008-03-11"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text></action>
		<action date="1205294400" datetime="2008-03-12"><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1205294400" datetime="2008-03-12"><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by the Yeas and Nays: 8 - 1 .</text></action>
		<action date="1207108800" datetime="2008-04-02"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1207108800" datetime="2008-04-02" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1208212920" datetime="2008-04-14T19:42:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 110-589.</text></action>
		<calendar number="364" date="1208212920" datetime="2008-04-14T19:42:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 364.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1208276340" datetime="2008-04-15T13:19:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Conyers moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1208276400" datetime="2008-04-15T13:20:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2284-2289"/></action>
		<action date="1208276400" datetime="2008-04-15T13:20:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5570.</text></action>
		<vote date="1208278680" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-04-15T13:58:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2284-2285"/></vote>
		<action date="1208278680" datetime="2008-04-15T13:58:00-04:00"><text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action date="1208318400" datetime="2008-04-16"><text>Received in the Senate.</text></action>
		<action date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/15/2008--Passed House amended. Religious Worker Visa Extension Act of 2008 - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to issue final regulations to eliminate or reduce fraud in the special immigrant non-minister religious worker program by December 31, 2008. Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to: (1) extend the special immigrant program for non-minister religious workers until January 1, 2010; and (2) extend the program until January 1, 2016, (to be effective March 1, 2009) if the Secretary issues such final regulations by December 31, 2008. Directs the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security to report to Congress on such regulations' effectiveness by September 30, 2010. Requires that such report shall include an analysis of a random sample of non-minister special immigrant religious workers, before their second anniversary of being admitted, to determine whether they are still employed by the religious organization that petitioned for them, and if not, the reasons for their departure from such employment. 
	</summary>
</bill>
