<bill session="110" type="h" number="5608" updated="2009-01-09T04:29:56-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"/></status>

	<introduced date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Consultation and Coordination With Indian Tribal Governments Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish regular and meaningful consultation and collaboration with tribal officials in the development of Federal policies that have tribal implications, to strengthen the United States government-to-government relationships with Indian tribes, and to reduce the imposition of unfunded mandates upon Indian tribes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400331"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400216" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412253" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400645" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400391" joined="2008-07-31"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E383-384)</text></action>
		<action date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1207713600" datetime="2008-04-09"><text>Committee Hearings Held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/13/2008--Introduced.<br/>Consultation and Coordination with Indian Tribal Governments Act - Requires the Department of the Interior, the Indian Health Service, and the National Indian Gaming Commission, when formulating, amending, implementing, or rescinding policies that have tribal implications, to adhere to certain fundamental principles and policymaking criteria, including that the United States: (1) has a unique legal and political relationship with Indian tribal governments; (2) recognizes the right of Indian tribes to self government; and (3) shall encourage Indian tribes to develop their own policies to meet program objectives. Prohibits such entities from formulating, amending, or implementing policies that impose substantial direct compliance costs on Indian tribal governments and are not required by federal law, unless: (1) funds necessary to pay such costs are provided by the federal government; or (2) the entities consulted with tribal officials early in the process of developing the proposed policy and provided a tribal summary impact statement to specified congressional committees and affected tribes. Requires such entities to have accountable consultation processes and to explore and use consensual mechanisms for developing policies on issues relating to tribal self-government, tribal trust resources, or Indian tribal treaty and other rights. Prohibits such entities from implementing policies that have tribal implications and that preempt tribal law unless the entities: (1) consulted with tribal officials in the policy's development; and (2) provided to specified congressional committees and affected Indian tribes a tribal summary impact statement.<br/>Sets forth provisions concerning the process for Indian tribes applying for waivers from requirements.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
