<bill session="110" type="h" number="5600" updated="2009-01-09T04:28:59-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1205294400" datetime="2008-03-12"/></status>

	<introduced date="1205294400" datetime="2008-03-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">District of Columbia Court, Offender Supervision, Parole, and Public Defender Employees Equity Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To permit nonjudicial employees of the District of Columbia courts, employees transferred to the Pretrial Services, Parole, Adult Probation, and Offender Supervision Trustee, and employees of the District of Columbia Public Defender Service to have periods of service performed prior to the enactment of the Balanced Budget Act of 1997 included as part of the years of service used to determine the time at which such employees are eligible to retire under chapter 84 of title 5, United States Code, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400295"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400098" joined="2008-03-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1205294400" datetime="2008-03-12"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E375)</text></action>
		<action date="1205294400" datetime="2008-03-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text></action>
		<action date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/12/2008--Introduced.<br/>District of Columbia Court, Offender Supervision, Parole, and Public Defender Employees Equity Act of 2008 - Entitles any individual serving as a federal or congressional employee or a Member of Congress who performed qualifying District of Columbia (D.C.) service to have such service included in calculating such individual's creditable service under the Federal Employees' Retirement System (FERS), but only for purposes of specified sections of FERS. Defines &quot;qualifying D.C. service&quot; to mean certain service performed by an individual as: (1) a D.C. court nonjudicial employee; (2) an employee of an entity of the D.C. government whose functions were transferred to the Pretrial Services, Parole, Adult Supervision, and Offender Supervision Trustee under the Balanced Budget Act of 1997; (3) an employee of the D.C. Public Defender Service; and (4) an employee of the D.C. Department of Corrections that was appointed to a position in the federal government under the priority consideration program established by the Bureau of Prisons.<br/>Requires the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to accept the certification of the appropriate personnel official of the D.C. government concerning qualifying service.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
