<bill session="110" type="h" number="5610" updated="2009-01-09T04:30:12-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"/></status>

	<introduced date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting America's Wild Places Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">California Desert and Mountain Heritage Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Copper Salmon Wilderness Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Sabinoso Wilderness Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Sequoia-Kings Canyon National Park Wilderness Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Tumacacori Highlands Wilderness Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Wild Monongahela Act: A National Legacy for West Virginia's Special Places</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To designate as wilderness additional National Forest System lands, Bureau of Land Management Lands, and National Parks Service lands in the States of West Virginia, Arizona, New Mexico, Oregon, and California, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400162"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400413" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400618" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="2008-04-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400331" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400100" joined="2008-03-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"><text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action date="1205726400" datetime="2008-03-17"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action date="1209096000" datetime="2008-04-25"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/13/2008--Introduced.<br/>Protecting America's Wild Places Act of 2008 - Designates specified National Forest System, Bureau of Land Management, and National Park Service lands in West Virginia, Arizona, New Mexico, Oregon, and California as wilderness and as a component, or as an addition to an existing component, of the National Wilderness Preservation System. Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate specified segments of rivers in Oregon and California as wild, scenic, or recreational rivers. Amends the Santa Rosa and San Jacinto Mountains National Monument Act of 2000 to include additional lands within the boundaries of the Santa Rosa and San Jacinto Mountains National Monument. 
	</summary>
</bill>
