<bill session="110" type="h" number="5616" updated="2009-01-09T04:30:57-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"/></status>

	<introduced date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Light Bulb Freedom of Choice Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the repeal of the phase out of incandescent light bulbs unless the Comptroller General makes certain specific findings.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412216"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412252" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400089" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400113" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412217" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400365" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400652" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400055" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400427" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400658" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400311" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412235" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400131" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400655" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400368" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400153" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400005" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412213" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400032" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400182" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400141" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400088" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400394" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412191" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400656" joined="2008-04-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1205467200" datetime="2008-03-14"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/13/2008--Introduced.<br/>Light Bulb Freedom of Choice Act - Amends the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 to repeal provisions concerning energy efficiency standards for general service incandescent lamps, rough service lamps, other designated lamps, and incandescent reflector lamps unless the Comptroller General has transmitted to Congress within six months after this Act's enactment a report that finds that: (1) consumers will obtain a net savings, in terms of dollars spent on monthly electric bills and expenses for new light fixtures to accommodate the use of the light bulbs required by such provisions, compared to dollars spent before their enactment; (2) the phase-out of incandescent light bulbs required by such provisions will reduce overall carbon dioxide emissions by 20% in the United States by 2025; and (3) such phase-out will not pose any health risks, including risks associated with mercury containment in certain light bulbs, to consumers or the general public, including health risks with respect to hospitals, schools, day care centers, mental health facilities, and nursing homes.<br/>Requires the report to include monthly and yearly projections of expenses for electric bills and new light fixtures for January 1, 2012, through December 31, 2017.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
