<bill session="110" type="h" number="5617" updated="2009-01-09T04:31:05-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"/></status>

	<introduced date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Political Intelligence Disclosure Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 to require the disclosure of political intelligence activities.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400011"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400378" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400100" joined="2008-05-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1208145600" datetime="2008-04-14"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/13/2008--Introduced.<br/>Political Intelligence Disclosure Act - Amends the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (LDA) to require the disclosure of political intelligence activities. Requires political intelligence consultants to register with the Secretary of the Senate and the Clerk of the House of Representatives, and make quarterly reports on political intelligence activities. Requires any person or entity that makes an oral political intelligence contact with a covered legislative branch or executive branch official on the official's request to: (1) state whether such person or entity is registered under this Act; (2) identify the client on behalf of whom the contact is made; and (3) state whether such client is a foreign entity, and make any related disclosures. Requires any person making a written political intelligence contact with a covered legislative branch or executive branch official to make similar disclosures, especially about clients considered foreign entities. 
	</summary>
</bill>
