<bill session="110" type="h" number="5626" updated="2009-01-09T04:32:05-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"/></status>

	<introduced date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Protect Our Troops and Our Constitution Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To reassert the constitutional role of Congress in making long-term security commitments, to defer significant long-term security commitments to Iraq to the next Administration and Congress, and to maintain international legal authority and immunity for United States Armed Forces in Iraq by promoting the extension of the United Nations mandate.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400102"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2008-04-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400129" joined="2008-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2008-04-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400130" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400437" joined="2008-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="412199" joined="2008-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400103" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400166" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="2008-04-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2008-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2008-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412200" joined="2008-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400201" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2008-09-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/13/2008--Introduced.<br/>Protect Our Troops and Our Constitution Act of 2008 - Prohibits funds from being used to: (1) establish or maintain any permanent or long-term U.S. military base or facility in Iraq; or (2) implement any agreement that is consistent with U.S. security commitments to Iraq under the Declaration of Principles or any agreement that provides &quot;authority to fight&quot; for U.S. Armed Forces engaged in combat operations other than for self-defense purposes, unless the agreement is an Article II treaty with respect to which the Senate has given its advice and consent to ratification or the agreement is approved by an Act of Congress enacted after the date of the enactment of this Act. Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) long-term U.S.-Iraq relations should be determined by the U.S. Administration taking office on January 20, 2009; (2) in determining its policy toward Iraq such Administration should consult with Congress, the government of Iraq, Coalition partners, and Iraq's neighbors; and (3) to maintain international legal authority as well as immunity from Iraqi prosecution for U.S. Armed Forces and other Coalition forces operating in Iraq while such Administration determines policy toward Iraq the current U.S. Administration should encourage the government of Iraq to request renewal of the U.N. mandate for Iraq beyond December 31, 2008.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
