<bill session="110" type="h" number="562" updated="2009-01-08T17:58:15-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1169096400" datetime="2007-01-18"/></status>

	<introduced date="1169096400" datetime="2007-01-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Long-Term Care Hospital Improvement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to ensure and foster continued patient quality of care by establishing facility and patient criteria for long-term care hospitals and related improvements under the Medicare Program.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400123"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400155" joined="2007-05-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400635" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400443" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400077" joined="2007-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400323" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400406" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400241" joined="2007-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400216" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400634" joined="2007-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400352" joined="2007-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400206" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400006" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412227" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400400" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412213" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400012" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400046" joined="2007-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400636" joined="2007-05-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1169096400" datetime="2007-01-18"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action date="1169614800" datetime="2007-01-24"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/18/2007--Introduced.<br/>Medicare Long-Term Care Hospital Improvement Act of 2007 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to prescribe requirements for a long-term care hospital (LTCH) and patient criteria for prospective payment to an LTCH. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) determine the LTCH diagnosis related groups (LTCH-DRGs) associated with a high severity of illness for specified medical conditions; and (2) study and report to Congress on appropriate quality measures for Medicare patients receiving care in LTCHs.<br/>Directs the Secretary to choose three quality measures from the study for LTCHs to report.<br/>Amends the Medicare, Medicaid, and SCHIP Benefits Improvement and Protection Act of 2000 to require annual updates of LTCH base rates and wage indices and the reweighting of LTCH-DRGs. Prohibits the Secretary from extending application of the 25% (or applicable percentage) patient threshold payment adjustment to freestanding LTCHs.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
