<bill session="110" type="h" number="5624" updated="2009-01-09T04:31:52-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"/></status>

	<introduced date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Radiological Materials Security Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to secure domestic sources of radiological materials that could be used to make a radiological dispersion device against access by terrorists, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412221"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400246" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400184" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400402" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400230" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400166" joined="2008-03-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text></action>
		<action date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"><text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text></action>
		<action date="1207108800" datetime="2008-04-02"><committee name="House Homeland Security"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emerging Threats, Cybersecurity, and Science and Technology.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/13/2008--Introduced.<br/>Radiological Materials Security Act - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to enhance domestic preparedness for and collective response to terrorism by conducting a risk assessment regarding the threat of, vulnerability to, and consequences of theft or other procurement of radiological materials that could be used by a terrorist in a radiological dispersion device.<br/>Requires the Secretary to: (1) disseminate the findings of, and specific risk information developed in, the assessment to participants in the radiological sources security system; (2) develop a classification system for information regarding radiological materials and classify the assessment under such system; (3) share the assessment with participants with appropriate clearances; (4) develop a terrorism risk self-assessment tool for facilities to ascertain risk and provide it to the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC), which shall disseminate it to system facilities; (5) issue recommended practices for securing high-risk radiological materials; and (6) make available infrastructure protection grants to owners and operators of facilities with approved facility security plans.<br/>Directs the NRC to: (1) update, promulgate, and enforce regulations for the security of radiological materials; (2) maintain and update a nuclear materials events database and a database to track regulated radiological materials and orphaned, lost, or stolen radiological materials; and (3) issue regulations requiring the owner or operator of a facility containing high-risk radiological material to create, submit to the NRC and certain states, and implement facility security plans to address vulnerabilities.<br/>Directs the Secretary of Energy to provide technical assistance for securing high-risk radiological materials to the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), the NRC, state and local authorities, and participating facilities.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
