<bill session="110" type="h" number="5647" updated="2009-01-09T04:34:33-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1205467200" datetime="2008-03-14"/></status>

	<introduced date="1205467200" datetime="2008-03-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Fair Share Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Pell Grants for Kids Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide public charter school options for those students that attend schools that are in need of improvement and have been identified for restructuring and those schools with a graduation rate of less than 60 percent, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400120"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400006" joined="2008-05-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1205467200" datetime="2008-03-14"><text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1205467200" datetime="2008-03-14"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1205467200" datetime="2008-03-14"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/14/2008--Introduced.<br/>Pell Grants for Kids Act of 2008 - Directs the Secretary, subject to advance appropriations, to award competitive grants to states, public chartering agencies, local educational agencies, or tax-exempt organizations to enhance the capacity of public charter schools to serve additional students, particularly those transferring from schools identified as needing restructuring under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 for failing to make adequate yearly progress (AYP) pursuant to state academic performance standards for five consecutive school years. Limits grant use to providing subgrants to public charter schools, covering the administrative expenses of grantees and subgrantees, and enhancing the availability of credit for such schools. Fair Share Act of 2008 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code and title II (Old Age, Survivors, and Disability Insurance Benefits) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act to treat certain foreign subsidiaries of U.S. companies performing services under a contract with the U.S. government as U.S. employers for purposes of Social Security and Medicare employment taxes.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
