<bill session="110" type="h" number="5669" updated="2009-01-09T04:37:05-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1212608640" datetime="2008-06-04T16:44:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="373"/></status>

	<introduced date="1207022400" datetime="2008-04-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Poison Center Support, Enhancement, and Awareness Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Poison Center Support, Enhancement, and Awareness Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to reauthorize the poison center national toll-free number, national media campaign, and grant program to provide assistance for poison prevention, sustain the funding of poison centers, and enhance the public health of people of the United States.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400409"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400289" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400623" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400430" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412195" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400344" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400063" joined="2008-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400261" joined="2008-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400152" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400030" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2008-06-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400640" joined="2008-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400331" joined="2008-05-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400082" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400048" joined="2008-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400442" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400172" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400631" joined="2008-05-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412211" joined="2008-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400400" joined="2008-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400439" joined="2008-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400350" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400107" joined="2008-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400120" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2008-06-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400090" joined="2008-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400240" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400334" joined="2008-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400025" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400425" joined="2008-04-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1207022400" datetime="2008-04-01"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1207108800" datetime="2008-04-02"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1207108800" datetime="2008-04-02"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H1943)</text></action>
		<action date="1208923200" datetime="2008-04-23"><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1208923200" datetime="2008-04-23"><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text></action>
		<action date="1210132800" datetime="2008-05-07"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1210132800" datetime="2008-05-07" ><text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1212590100" datetime="2008-06-04T11:35:00-04:00"><text>Reported by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 110-681.</text></action>
		<calendar number="426" date="1212590160" datetime="2008-06-04T11:36:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 426.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1212591420" datetime="2008-06-04T11:57:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Green, Gene moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text></action>
		<action date="1212591480" datetime="2008-06-04T11:58:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H4896-4899"/></action>
		<action date="1212591480" datetime="2008-06-04T11:58:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5669.</text></action>
		<action date="1212635160" datetime="2008-06-04T12:06:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1212608100" datetime="2008-06-04T16:35:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H4936-4937"/></action>
		<vote date="1212608640" how="roll" roll="373" datetime="2008-06-04T16:44:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" suspension="1" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 405 - 10 (Roll no. 373).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H4896-4897"/></vote>
		<action date="1212638400" datetime="2008-06-05"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/4/2008--Passed House without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)<br/>Poison Center Support, Enhancement, and Awareness Act of 2008 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to provide coordination and assistance for the maintenance of the nationwide toll-free phone number to access poison centers. Changes the name of poison control centers to poison centers.<br/>Requires the Secretary to carry out and expand upon a national media campaign to educate the public and health care providers about poison prevention and the availability of poison center resources in local communities. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into contracts with a nationally recognized organization for the development and implementation of a nationwide poison prevention and poison center awareness campaign.<br/>Expands the poison center grant program to allow the Secretary to award grants for poison centers to comply with the operational requirements needed to sustain certification. Adds as the purposes for which such grants may be used: (1) to establish and evaluate best practices in the United States for poison prevention, poison center outreach, and emergency and preparedness programs; (2) to develop and implement standard patient management guidelines for commonly encountered toxic exposures; (3) to improve national toxic exposure surveillance; (4) to develop, support, and enhance technology and capabilities of professional organizations in the field of poison control to collect national poisoning, toxic occurrence, and related public health data; and (5) to develop initiatives to foster the enhanced public health utilization of national poison data. Eliminates matching requirements for such grants. Authorizes appropriations for FY2010-FY2014.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
