<bill session="110" type="h" number="5665" updated="2009-01-09T04:36:38-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1206936000" datetime="2008-03-31"/></status>

	<introduced date="1206936000" datetime="2008-03-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Reciprocity and Fairness in Foreign Investment Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To impose limitations on investment and certain operations by foreign entities in the United States.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400411"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1206936000" datetime="2008-03-31"><text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Foreign Affairs, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1206936000" datetime="2008-03-31"><text>Referred to House Financial Services</text></action>
		<action date="1206936000" datetime="2008-03-31"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1206936000" datetime="2008-03-31"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1207022400" datetime="2008-04-01"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/31/2008--Introduced.<br/>Reciprocity and Fairness in Foreign Investment Act - Permits a foreign person owned, in whole or in part, or controlled by a foreign government to acquire ownership in either a business, or in real property in the United States, but only to the same extent as that foreign government allows U.S. persons to acquire ownership in comparable enterprises organized under the laws of that foreign country. Subjects investment and operation of critical infrastructure in the United States by such a foreign person to the same reciprocity requirements. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to issue implementing regulations. Establishes civil penalties for violations of this Act. 
	</summary>
</bill>
