<bill session="110" type="h" number="569" updated="2009-01-08T17:59:54-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1173302400" datetime="2007-03-07T17:20:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="125"/></status>

	<introduced date="1169096400" datetime="2007-01-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Water Quality Investment Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Water Quality Investment Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Water Quality Investment Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to authorize appropriations for sewer overflow control grants.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400309"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400295" joined="2007-01-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400058" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400063" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400276" joined="2007-01-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2007-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400274" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400396" joined="2007-01-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400249" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400359" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400663" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400308" joined="2007-01-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="412240" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412204" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400217" joined="2007-01-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412186" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400119" joined="2007-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400641" joined="2007-01-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="412219" joined="2007-02-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1169096400" datetime="2007-01-18"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text></action>
		<action date="1169182800" datetime="2007-01-19"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text></action>
		<action date="1169442000" datetime="2007-01-22"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E167)</text></action>
		<action date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text></action>
		<action date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07" ><text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1171657020" datetime="2007-02-16T16:17:00-05:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation. H. Rept. 110-16.</text></action>
		<calendar number="7" date="1171657080" datetime="2007-02-16T16:18:00-05:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 7.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1173215640" datetime="2007-03-06T17:14:00-05:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 214 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 569 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure now printed in the bill.</text></action>
		<action date="1173329520" datetime="2007-03-07T12:52:00-05:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 214 passed House.</text></action>
		<action date="1173329700" datetime="2007-03-07T12:55:00-05:00"><text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 214.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2252-2265"/></action>
		<action date="1173329700" datetime="2007-03-07T12:55:00-05:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 569 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is open to amendments. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure now printed in the bill.</text></action>
		<action date="1173329700" datetime="2007-03-07T12:55:00-05:00"><text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 214 and Rule XVIII.</text></action>
		<action date="1173329700" datetime="2007-03-07T12:55:00-05:00"><text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Adam B. Schiff to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text></action>
		<action date="1173329700" datetime="2007-03-07T12:55:00-05:00"><text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 569.</text></action>
		<action date="1173289140" datetime="2007-03-07T13:39:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the King (IA) amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action date="1173289500" datetime="2007-03-07T13:45:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Price(GA) amendment under the five-minute rule.</text></action>
		<action date="1173290520" datetime="2007-03-07T14:02:00-05:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Price(GA) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes prevailed. Mr. Price(GA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text></action>
		<action date="1173290580" datetime="2007-03-07T14:03:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Rohrabacher amendment under the five-minute rule, pending reservation of a point of order.</text></action>
		<action date="1173290760" datetime="2007-03-07T14:06:00-05:00"><text>Ms. Johnson, E. B. moved that the Committee rise.</text></action>
		<action date="1173290820" datetime="2007-03-07T14:07:00-05:00"><text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text></action>
		<action date="1173290820" datetime="2007-03-07T14:07:00-05:00"><text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 569 as unfinished business.</text></action>
		<action date="1173298020" datetime="2007-03-07T16:07:00-05:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2262-2264"/></action>
		<action date="1173298080" datetime="2007-03-07T16:08:00-05:00"><text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text></action>
		<action date="1173298080" datetime="2007-03-07T16:08:00-05:00"><text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of an amendment which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1173299700" datetime="2007-03-07T16:35:00-05:00"><text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 569.</text></action>
		<action date="1173299760" datetime="2007-03-07T16:36:00-05:00"><text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text></action>
		<action date="1173299820" datetime="2007-03-07T16:37:00-05:00"><text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text></action>
		<action date="1173299880" datetime="2007-03-07T16:38:00-05:00"><text>Mr. McHenry moved to recommit with instructions to Transportation.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2263"/><reference label="text" ref="CR H2263"/></action>
		<action date="1173299940" datetime="2007-03-07T16:39:00-05:00"><text>Floor summary: DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the McHenry motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment inserting at the end of the bill a new section on limitation on the use of funds.</text></action>
		<action date="1173300480" datetime="2007-03-07T16:48:00-05:00"><text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2263-2264"/></action>
		<action date="1173301860" datetime="2007-03-07T17:11:00-05:00"><text>On motion to recommit with instructions Agreed to by recorded vote: 425 - 0 (Roll no. 124).</text></action>
		<vote date="1173302400" how="roll" roll="125" datetime="2007-03-07T17:20:00-05:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 367 - 58 (Roll no. 125).</text></vote>
		<action date="1173330000" datetime="2007-03-08"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/7/2007--Passed House amended. Water Quality Investment Act of 2007 - Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to require projects receiving sewer overflow control grant assistance to be carried out subject to the requirements applicable to projects receiving assistance from state water pollution control revolving funds, except to the extent that the governor of the state in which the project is located determines that a revolving fund requirement is inconsistent with the purposes of the sewer overflow control grant program. Authorizes appropriations for sewer overflow control grants through FY2012. Modifies grant funding allocation provisions to reflect new dates of authorization and reauthorized amounts. Eliminates the set-aside for the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to make direct grants to municipalities and municipal entities during the second year of authorization. Establishes a December 31, 2010, deadline for the Administrator's report to Congress on recommended funding levels for sewer overflow control grants. Prohibits the funds authorized by this Act from being used to lobby governmental entities or officers or to pay for expenses related to memberships in organizations or associations.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
