<bill session="110" type="h" number="5702" updated="2009-01-09T04:41:01-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1207195200" datetime="2008-04-03"/></status>

	<introduced date="1207195200" datetime="2008-04-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Advance Directive Promotion Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend titles XVIII and XIX of the Social Security Act to promote the use of advance directives, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400238"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400257" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400282" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400623" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400129" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400216" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400437" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400103" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400070" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400378" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400641" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400090" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400218" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400240" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400186" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="2008-04-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1207195200" datetime="2008-04-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1207281600" datetime="2008-04-04"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/3/2008--Introduced.<br/>Advance Directive Promotion Act of 2008 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) and XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to require a service provider, Medicare+Choice organization, or prepaid or eligible organization to include the content of an advanced directive in a prominent part of an individual's current medical record. Requires a service provider to give effect to a valid advance directive executed outside the state in which such directive is presented to the same extent as such provider would give effect to a valid advance directive executed under the law of the state in which it is presented. Requires an initial preventative physical examination to include an end-of-life planning consultation. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services, to operate a clearinghouse and a 24-hour toll free telephone hotline in order to provide consumer information about advance directives, end-of-life decisionmaking, and available end-of-life and hospice care services. Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary, directly or through grants to public or nonprofit private entities, to conduct a national public education campaign to increase awareness of advance directive planning.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
