<bill session="110" type="h" number="5718" updated="2009-01-09T04:42:56-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1207627200" datetime="2008-04-08"/></status>

	<introduced date="1207627200" datetime="2008-04-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Employees Paid Parental Leave Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide that 8 of the 12 weeks of parental leave made available to a Federal employee shall be paid leave, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400251"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400227" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400130" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400098" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412223" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400103" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400259" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400653" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400366" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400189" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400415" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412212" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400090" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400240" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400025" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="2008-04-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1207627200" datetime="2008-04-08"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E541)</text></action>
		<action date="1207627200" datetime="2008-04-08"><text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committees on House Administration, and Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1207627200" datetime="2008-04-08"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1207627200" datetime="2008-04-08"><text>Referred to House House Administration</text></action>
		<action date="1207627200" datetime="2008-04-08"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1207800000" datetime="2008-04-10"><committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/8/2008--Introduced.<br/>Federal Employees Paid Parental Leave Act of 2008 - Allows federal employees to substitute any available paid leave for any leave without pay available for either the: (1) birth of a child; or (2) placement of a child with the employee for either adoption or foster care. Makes available for any of the 12 weeks of leave an employee is entitled to for such purposes: (1) eight administrative weeks of paid parental leave in connection with the birth or placement involved; and (2) any accumulated annual or sick leave.<br/>Amends the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 to allow the same substitution for covered congressional employees.<br/>Amends the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 to allow the same substitution for Government Accountability Office (GAO) and Library of Congress employees.<br/>Requires GAO to study and report on the feasibility and desirability of providing an insurance benefit to federal employees which affords partial or total wage replacement with respect to periods of qualified leave. Defines &quot;qualified leave&quot; as leave that: (1) is available by reason of the need to care for the spouse, child, or parent of the employee having a serious health condition or by reason of a serious health condition affecting the employee that renders such employee unable to perform the functions of his or her position; and (2) would otherwise be leave without pay.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
