<bill session="110" type="h" number="5722" updated="2009-01-09T04:43:24-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1207627200" datetime="2008-04-08"/></status>

	<introduced date="1207627200" datetime="2008-04-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">International Megan's Law of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To mandate reporting requirements for convicted sex traffickers and other sex offenders intending to engage in international travel, to provide advance notice of convicted sex offenders who intend to travel outside the United States to the government of the country of destination, to prevent entry into the United States by any foreign sex offender, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400380"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400327" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400128" joined="2008-05-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400344" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400423" joined="2008-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400071" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400040" joined="2008-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400433" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400055" joined="2008-05-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400658" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400640" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400320" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400244" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400435" joined="2008-04-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1207627200" datetime="2008-04-08"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1207627200" datetime="2008-04-08"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1207627200" datetime="2008-04-08"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1209355200" datetime="2008-04-28"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text></action>
		<action date="1209355200" datetime="2008-04-28"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/8/2008--Introduced.<br/>International Megan's Law of 2008 - Requires registered sex offenders to report their departure to or arrival from a foreign place not later than 21 days before such departure or arrival. Imposes a fine and/or prison term of up to 10 years for failure to report such travel. Requires the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish a system of notice to foreign countries about travel outside of the United States by registered sex offenders. Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to make convicted sex offenders inadmissible to the United States. Amends the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 to include in the annual report of the Secretary of State on the status of severe forms of human trafficking efforts of foreign countries to identify and provide notice of international travel by sex offenders.<br/>Encourages the President to use authorities under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to assist foreign countries in identifying and providing notice of sex offenders traveling to the United States and other countries.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
