<bill session="110" type="h" number="574" updated="2009-01-08T18:00:50-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1169096400" datetime="2007-01-18"/></status>

	<introduced date="1169096400" datetime="2007-01-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Lake Barkley Water Level Improvement Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure the safety of residents and visitors to Lake Barkley, Kentucky, and to improve recreation, navigation, and the economic vitality of the lake's region, the Army Corps of Engineers, together with any other Federal agency that has the authority to change the pool elevation of such lake, shall establish a pilot program to maintain the pool elevation of such lake at 359 feet until after the first Monday in September.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400431"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1169096400" datetime="2007-01-18"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text></action>
		<action date="1169182800" datetime="2007-01-19"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/18/2007--Introduced.<br/>Lake Barkley Water Level Improvement Act - Directs the Army Corps of Engineers, together with any other federal agency that has the authority to change the pool elevation of Lake Barkley, Kentucky, to conduct a two-year pilot program to extend, under normal weather conditions, the summer pool elevation of 359 feet on such lake from the current draw down date of July 1 until after the first Monday in September. Requires: (1) the Chief of Engineers to evaluate the effectiveness of such extension and report to Congress; and (2) the Corps, if it determines that the pilot program is effective, to continue the summer elevation of 359 feet on that lake through the first Monday in September each year. 
	</summary>
</bill>
