<bill session="110" type="h" number="5751" updated="2009-01-09T04:46:47-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1216180800" datetime="2008-07-16" /></status>

	<introduced date="1207713600" datetime="2008-04-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Walnut Canyon Study Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Walnut Canyon Study Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture to jointly conduct a study of certain land adjacent to the Walnut Canyon National Monument in the State of Arizona, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400310"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-04-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1207713600" datetime="2008-04-09"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1208145600" datetime="2008-04-14"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action date="1215662400" datetime="2008-07-10"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1216180800" datetime="2008-07-16"><text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands Discharged.</text></action>
		<action date="1216180800" datetime="2008-07-16"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1216180800" datetime="2008-07-16" ><text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1217372340" datetime="2008-07-29T19:59:00-04:00"><text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-799.</text></action>
		<calendar number="517" date="1217372340" datetime="2008-07-29T19:59:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 517.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/29/2008--Reported to House without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)<br/>Walnut Canyon Study Act of 2008 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture to conduct a study of an area identified as the Walnut Canyon Proposed Study Area (the study area) to assess: (1) the suitability and feasibility of designating all or part of the study area as an addition to Walnut Canyon National Monument in Arizona; and (2) continued management of the study area by the Forest Service, or any other designation or management option that would provide for protection of resources within the study area and continued access to, and use of, the study area by the public. Requires the Secretaries to provide for public comment in the preparation of the study, including with appropriate federal, state, and local governmental entities. 
	</summary>
</bill>
