<bill session="110" type="h" number="5761" updated="2009-01-09T04:48:02-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1207800000" datetime="2008-04-10"/></status>

	<introduced date="1207800000" datetime="2008-04-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To withhold Federal financial assistance from each country that denies or unreasonably delays the acceptance of nationals of such country who have been ordered removed from the United States and to prohibit the issuance of visas to nationals of such country.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400070"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400123" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400385" joined="2008-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400288" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400658" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400144" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400648" joined="2008-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400570" joined="2008-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400320" joined="2008-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400266" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400032" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400435" joined="2008-05-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1207800000" datetime="2008-04-10"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1207800000" datetime="2008-04-10"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1207800000" datetime="2008-04-10"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1207800000" datetime="2008-04-10"><text>Referred to House Rules</text></action>
		<action date="1209355200" datetime="2008-04-28"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/10/2008--Introduced.<br/>Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to prohibit funds from being dispersed to a country that denies or unreasonably delays the acceptance of its citizens, nationals, or residents who have been ordered removed under the Immigration and Nationality Act (INA) from the United States. Amends INA to prohibit visa issuance to citizens, nationals, or residents of such country unless: (1) the country is in full compliance with travel document requirements under this Act; or (2) Congress waives such prohibition. Requires the Secretary of Homeland Security to report to Congress every three months listing countries that deny or delay such repatriation. Imposes assistance and visa prohibitions on a listed country that does not issue appropriate travel documents for such aliens. Authorizes presidential waiver of such assistance and visa prohibitions.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
