<bill session="110" type="h" number="5775" updated="2009-01-09T04:49:39-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1207800000" datetime="2008-04-10"/></status>

	<introduced date="1207800000" datetime="2008-04-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Labor Management Reporting and Disclosure Enforcement Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Labor-Management Reporting and Disclosure Act to provide for specified civil penalties for violations of that Act, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400367"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400627" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="412252" joined="2008-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400134" joined="2008-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400113" joined="2008-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400385" joined="2008-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400267" joined="2008-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="412230" joined="2008-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400388" joined="2008-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400196" joined="2008-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400077" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400433" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400288" joined="2008-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400224" joined="2008-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400017" joined="2008-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400287" joined="2008-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400220" joined="2008-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400655" joined="2008-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400320" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400175" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400368" joined="2008-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400644" joined="2008-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400221" joined="2008-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400636" joined="2008-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="412011" joined="2008-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="412191" joined="2008-04-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1207800000" datetime="2008-04-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/10/2008--Introduced.<br/>Labor Management Reporting and Disclosure Enforcement Act of 2008 - Amends the Labor-Management Reporting and Disclosure Act of 1959 (Landrum-Griffin Act) to make a labor organization liable to any of its members for a civil money penalty of up to $250 for each day that it fails to provide such member information regarding the organization's constitution, bylaws, organization report, and annual financial report, including any books, records, and accounts necessary to verify such reports. Authorizes the Secretary of Labor to bring an action in U.S. district court for injunctive relief and enforcement of administrative penalties against any person who has violated or is about to violate any reporting requirements of such Act, including those applying to a labor organization which has or assumes trusteeship over any subordinate labor organization. Requires a district court, upon a complaint by the Secretary that demonstrates failure to file timely and complete reports, to enjoin continued violation of the related reporting requirements. Authorizes the Secretary, upon finding a violation of specified reporting and disclosure requirements, to impose an administrative money penalty of up to $250 a day, or $10,000 in aggregate, adjusted for inflation, against the person, labor organization, or employer responsible for such violation. 
	</summary>
</bill>
