<bill session="110" type="h" number="5808" updated="2009-01-09T04:53:33-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1208232000" datetime="2008-04-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1208232000" datetime="2008-04-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Women's Environmental Health and Disease Prevention Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize the National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences to develop multidisciplinary research centers regarding women's health and disease prevention, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400378"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2008-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2008-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400080" joined="2008-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2008-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400268" joined="2008-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400384" joined="2008-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2008-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400259" joined="2008-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2008-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400415" joined="2008-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2008-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="2008-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2008-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400062" joined="2008-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400425" joined="2008-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="2008-04-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1208232000" datetime="2008-04-15"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E615)</text></action>
		<action date="1208232000" datetime="2008-04-15"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1208318400" datetime="2008-04-16"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/15/2008--Introduced.<br/>Women's Environmental Health and Disease Prevention Act of 2008 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Director of the National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences to make grants for the development and operation of centers to conduct multidisciplinary research on environmental factors that may be related to the development of women's health conditions. Requires each such center to: (1) conduct basic or clinical research; (2) develop protocols and conduct training programs for physicians, scientists, nurses, and other health and allied health professionals; (3) disseminate information to such professionals and the public; and (4) emphasize activities that are directed toward preventing the development in women of the diseases and conditions involved. Allows a center to use funds to provide stipends for health and allied health professionals enrolled in training programs.<br/>Requires each center to establish and maintain ongoing collaborations with community organizations in the geographic area served by the center, including organizations that represent women or children with disorders that appear to stem from environmental factors.<br/>Requires the Director to provide for the coordination of information among centers and ensure regular communication between them.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
