<bill session="110" type="h" number="5805" updated="2009-01-09T04:53:13-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1208232000" datetime="2008-04-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1208232000" datetime="2008-04-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Zeroing In American Energy Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a new solar energy future for America through public-private partnership and energy leasing for reliable and affordable energy for the American people, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400313"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412218" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400659" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400134" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400336" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400029" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400287" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400220" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400368" joined="2008-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="412201" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400440" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="412255" joined="2008-05-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1208232000" datetime="2008-04-15"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1208750400" datetime="2008-04-21"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/15/2008--Introduced.<br/>Zeroing In American Energy Act of 2008 - Requires the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a program for the leasing of federal lands for the advancement, development, assessment, installation, and operation of commercial photovoltaic and concentrating solar power energy systems.<br/>Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) and in consultation with the Secretary of Energy, to: (1) identify lease sites comprising 6.4 million acres of federal lands under BLM jurisdiction in Arizona, California, New Mexico, Nevada, and Utah that are suitable and feasible for the installation and operation of such energy systems; and (2) incorporate solar energy development into the relevant agency land use and resource management plans or equivalent plans for such identified sites.<br/>Sets forth provisions concerning: (1) the size of such sites; (2) annual milestones for the number of acres of sites to be leased by each of the years 2010-2019; and (3) the collection and payment of royalties from projects under such program.<br/>Prohibits the following federal lands from being included within such program: (1) Components of the National Landscape Conservation System; (2) Wilderness and Wilderness Study Areas; (3) Wild and Scenic Rivers; (4) National Scenic and Historic Trails; (5) Monuments; and (6) Resource Natural Areas.<br/>Requires the Secretary to complete: (1) a programmatic environmental impact statement for such program prior to implementing it; and (2) a study of federal lands available for a compressed air energy storage system, barriers to access to federal lands for transmission of energy produced under the program, and the need for energy transmission corridors on public lands.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
