<bill session="110" type="h" number="5834" updated="2009-01-09T04:56:39-05:00">
	<status><enacted date="1223352000" datetime="2008-10-07" /></status>

	<introduced date="1208404800" datetime="2008-04-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">North Korean Human Rights Reauthorization Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">North Korean Human Rights Reauthorization Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">North Korean Human Rights Reauthorization Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">North Korean Human Rights Reauthorization Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="enacted">North Korean Human Rights Reauthorization Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the North Korean Human Rights Act of 2004 to promote respect for the fundamental human rights of the people of North Korea, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400344"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400380" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400003" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400071" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400662" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400055" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400649" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400371" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400025" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400252" joined="2008-04-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1208404800" datetime="2008-04-17"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1210702740" datetime="2008-05-13T15:19:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Foreign Affairs. H. Rept. 110-628.</text></action>
		<calendar number="392" date="1210702740" datetime="2008-05-13T15:19:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 392.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1210712820" datetime="2008-05-13T18:07:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Berman moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1210712820" datetime="2008-05-13T18:07:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3747-3750"/></action>
		<action date="1210712820" datetime="2008-05-13T18:07:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5834.</text></action>
		<action date="1210713840" datetime="2008-05-13T18:24:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Simpson objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text></action>
		<action date="1210877280" datetime="2008-05-15T15:48:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H4047"/></action>
		<vote date="1210877340" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-05-15T15:49:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote. (text: CR 5/13/2008 H3747-3748)</text></vote>
		<action date="1211169600" datetime="2008-05-19"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
		<action date="1222056000" datetime="2008-09-22"><text>Senate Committee on Foreign Relations discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text></action>
		<action date="1222056000" datetime="2008-09-22"><text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S9218-9219"/></action>
		<vote date="1222056000" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2008-09-22" where="s" type="vote2" result="pass" ><text>Passed Senate with amendments by Unanimous Consent.</text></vote>
		<action date="1222142400" datetime="2008-09-23"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<action date="1222207620" datetime="2008-09-23T19:07:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Scott (GA) moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendments.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8659-8661"/></action>
		<action date="1222207680" datetime="2008-09-23T19:08:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate H.R. 5834.</text></action>
		<action date="1222208580" datetime="2008-09-23T19:23:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendments Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text as House agreed to Senate amendments" ref="CR H8659"/></action>
		<topresident date="1222142400" datetime="2008-09-23" ><text>Cleared for White House.</text></topresident>
		<topresident date="1222401600" datetime="2008-09-26" ><text>Presented to President.</text></topresident>
		<signed date="1223352000" datetime="2008-10-07" ><text>Signed by President.</text></signed>
		<enacted number="110-346" date="1223352000" datetime="2008-10-07" type="public" ><text>Became Public Law No: 110-346.</text></enacted>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/7/2008--Public Law. (This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the Senate on September 22, 2008. The summary of that version is repeated here.) North Korean Human Rights Reauthorization Act of 2008 - Expresses the sense of Congress with respect to the resettlement of North Korean refugees. Amends the North Korean Human Rights Act of 2004 to authorize appropriations through FY2012 for: (1) activities to support human rights and democracy and freedom of information (by increasing the availability of non-government controlled sources) in North Korea; and (2) assistance to North Koreans who are outside North Korea. Directs the Broadcasting Board of Governors to report respecting U.S. broadcasting to North Korea and the extent to which the Board has achieved the goal of 12-hour-per-day broadcasting to North Korea. States that the Special Envoy on North Korean human rights issues (as renamed by this Act) in North Korea shall have the rank of ambassador. Extends the Special Envoy's annual congressional reporting requirement through FY2012. Extends the United States Agency for International Development's (USAID) congressional reporting requirement respecting U.S. humanitarian assistance to North Koreans and efforts to improve transparency and monitoring in the provision of such assistance inside North Korea through 2012. Sets forth specified reporting provisions.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
