<bill session="110" type="h" number="5846" updated="2009-01-09T04:58:02-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1208404800" datetime="2008-04-17"/></status>

	<introduced date="1208404800" datetime="2008-04-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Wireless Internet Nationwide for Families Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Federal Communications Commission to auction spectrum for a free and open access broadband service.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400124"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400253" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400059" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400424" joined="2008-09-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400198" joined="2008-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400384" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400245" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400402" joined="2008-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400068" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400048" joined="2008-06-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2008-06-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400074" joined="2008-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2008-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2008-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400114" joined="2008-04-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1208404800" datetime="2008-04-17"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E651)</text></action>
		<action date="1208404800" datetime="2008-04-17"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1208404800" datetime="2008-04-17"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and the Internet.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/17/2008--Introduced.<br/>Wireless Internet Nationwide for Families Act of 2008 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to require the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to promote nationwide broadband competition through the use of wireless services by issuing nationwide licenses, for a term of at least 15 years, for two bands of frequencies, each composed of 20 megahertz of unpaired contiguous spectrum, one band under 3 gigahertz and not part of the recovered analog spectrum and the other band between 2155 and 2180 megahertz. Requires licensees, among other things, to offer to consumers and authorized public safety users, without subscription, airtime, usage, or other charges, a data service that is faster than 200 kilobits per second and that has technology that protects underage users from accessing obscene or indecent material. Requires a separate rule-making or other procedures for licensing through auction additional unpaired contiguous spectrum of 20 megahertz below 3 gigahertz, but states that the auction shall be conducted without the conditions specified in the immediately preceding paragraph unless the Commission finds it is in the public interest.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
