<bill session="110" type="h" number="5856" updated="2009-01-09T04:59:11-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1211407800" datetime="2008-05-21T19:10:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="349"/></status>

	<introduced date="1208836800" datetime="2008-04-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Facility Authorization and Lease Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Facility Authorization and Lease Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Facility Authorization and Lease Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize major medical facility projects and major medical facility leases for the Department of Veterans Affairs for fiscal year 2009, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400274"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1208836800" datetime="2008-04-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1208836800" datetime="2008-04-22"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1208923200" datetime="2008-04-23"><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1208923200" datetime="2008-04-23"><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text></action>
		<action date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30" ><text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1210882140" datetime="2008-05-15T17:09:00-04:00"><text>Reported by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 110-648.</text></action>
		<calendar number="409" date="1210882140" datetime="2008-05-15T17:09:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 409.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1211304900" datetime="2008-05-20T14:35:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Filner moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text></action>
		<action date="1211304900" datetime="2008-05-20T14:35:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H4199-4202"/></action>
		<action date="1211304900" datetime="2008-05-20T14:35:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5856.</text></action>
		<action date="1211305980" datetime="2008-05-20T14:53:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1211404980" datetime="2008-05-21T18:23:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H4415-4416"/></action>
		<vote date="1211407800" how="roll" roll="349" datetime="2008-05-21T19:10:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" suspension="1" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 416 - 0 (Roll no. 349). (text: CR 5/20/2008 H4199-4200)</text></vote>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/21/2008--Passed House without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Facility Authorization and Lease Act of 2008 - Authorizes the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out major medical facility projects (projects) in FY2009 in: (1) Palo Alto, California; (2) San Antonio, Texas; and (3) San Juan, Puerto Rico. Amends the Veterans Benefits, Health Care, and Information Technology Act of 2006 to increase the amount authorized under such Act for: (1) all projects; and (2) specified projects in Florida, Nevada, and Pennsylvania in connection with the Capital Asset Realignment Initiative. Authorizes the Secretary to carry out specified major medical facility leases (leases) in FY2009 in Arizona, California, Colorado, Florida, Georgia, Ohio, Oregon, Puerto Rico, South Carolina, and Wisconsin. Authorizes the Secretary to carry out a project in Okaloosa County, Florida. Authorizes appropriations for projects and leases authorized or increased under this Act. Directs the Secretary to submit to the congressional veterans' committees: (1) a report updating progress made in complying with provisions requiring the establishment of, and responsibilities for, a Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) Director of Construction and Facilities Management; and (2) an annual report on VA community-based outpatient clinics and other outpatient clinics.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
