<bill session="110" type="h" number="5867" updated="2009-01-09T05:00:26-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1208836800" datetime="2008-04-22"/></status>

	<introduced date="1208836800" datetime="2008-04-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Energy Conservation Through Trees Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a grant program to assist retail power providers with the establishment and operation of energy conservation programs using targeted residential tree-planting, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400663"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400049" joined="2008-09-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="2008-06-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400437" joined="2008-07-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2008-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400238" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400025" joined="2008-05-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1208836800" datetime="2008-04-22"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E670-671)</text></action>
		<action date="1208836800" datetime="2008-04-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1208836800" datetime="2008-04-22"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/22/2008--Introduced.<br/>Energy Conservation Through Trees Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Energy to provide financial, technical, and related assistance to retail power providers to assist with the establishment of new, or continued operation of existing, targeted residential tree-planting programs. Requires the Secretary to create a national public recognition initiative to encourage participation in tree-planting programs by such providers.<br/>Limits assistance provided under this Act to programs that utilize targeted, strategic tree-siting guidelines to plant trees in relation to residence location, sunlight, and prevailing wind direction. Sets forth requirements that must be met for tree-planting programs to qualify for assistance.<br/>Authorizes the Secretary to award grants only to providers that have entered into binding legal agreements with nonprofit tree-planting organizations.<br/>Requires providers, in order to qualify for assistance, to establish and consult with a local technical advisory committee, which shall provide advice and consultation to the program, and which may: (1) design and adopt an approved plant list that emphasizes the use of hardy, noninvasive tree species, native or low water-use shade trees, or both; (2) design and adopt planting, installation, and maintenance specifications and create a process for inspection and quality control; (3) ensure that tree recipients are educated to care for and maintain their trees over the long term; (4) help the public become more engaged and educated in the planting and care of shade trees; (5) prioritize which sites receive trees, giving preference to locations with the most potential for energy conservation and secondary preference to areas where the average annual income is below the regional median; and (6) assist with monitoring and collection of data on tree health, tree survival, and energy conservation benefits generated under this Act.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
