<bill session="110" type="h" number="5876" updated="2009-01-09T05:01:34-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1210737600" datetime="2008-05-14" /></status>

	<introduced date="1208923200" datetime="2008-04-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Child Abuse in Residential Programs for Teens Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Stop Child Abuse in Residential Programs for Teens Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require certain standards and enforcement provisions to prevent child abuse and neglect in residential programs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400278"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400227" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400364" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400257" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400184" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400216" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400103" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412211" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="412204" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="412232" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412200" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400240" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400179" joined="2008-04-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1208923200" datetime="2008-04-23"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1210737600" datetime="2008-05-14"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1210737600" datetime="2008-05-14" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 27 - 16.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1211494140" datetime="2008-05-22T19:09:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Education and Labor. H. Rept. 110-669.</text></action>
		<calendar number="421" date="1211494200" datetime="2008-05-22T19:10:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 421.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1213738740" datetime="2008-06-17T18:39:00-04:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1276 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 5876 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. The rule waives all points of order against consideration of the bill except clauses 9 and 10 of rule XXI. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Education and Labor now printed in the bill shall be considered as an original bill for the purpose of amendment. The rule waives all points of order against the amendment in the nature of a substitute except for clause 10 of rule XXI.</text></action>
		<action date="1213969560" datetime="2008-06-20T10:46:00-04:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 1276 passed House.</text></action>
		<action date="1214333820" datetime="2008-06-24T15:57:00-04:00"><text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 1276.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H5949-5953, H5953-5962"/><reference label="text of measure as reported in House" ref="CR H5956-5958"/></action>
		<action date="1214333820" datetime="2008-06-24T15:57:00-04:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 5876 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. The rule waives all points of order against consideration of the bill except clauses 9 and 10 of rule XXI. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Education and Labor now printed in the bill shall be considered as an original bill for the purpose of amendment. The rule waives all points of order against the amendment in the nature of a substitute except for clause 10 of rule XXI.</text></action>
		<action date="1214333820" datetime="2008-06-24T15:57:00-04:00"><text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 1276 and Rule XVIII.</text></action>
		<action date="1214333820" datetime="2008-06-24T15:57:00-04:00"><text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Betty McCollum to act as Chairwoman of the Committee.</text></action>
		<action date="1214333820" datetime="2008-06-24T15:57:00-04:00"><text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 5876.</text></action>
		<action date="1214336640" datetime="2008-06-24T16:44:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1276, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with twenty minutes of debate on the George Miller (CA) amendment.</text></action>
		<action date="1214337180" datetime="2008-06-24T16:53:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the George Miller (CA) amendment the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. George Miller (CA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text></action>
		<action date="1214338800" datetime="2008-06-24T17:20:00-04:00"><text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 5876.</text></action>
		<action date="1214338860" datetime="2008-06-24T17:21:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H5961"/></action>
		<action date="1214338980" datetime="2008-06-24T17:23:00-04:00"><text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H5956-5958"/></action>
		<action date="1214339040" datetime="2008-06-24T17:24:00-04:00"><text>Mrs. Bachmann moved to recommit with instructions to Education and Labor.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H5961-5962"/><reference label="text" ref="CR H5961"/></action>
		<action date="1214339160" datetime="2008-06-24T17:26:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Bachmann motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to add an amendment requiring parents or legal guardians to give consent before prescription medication is administered to children. During the course of debate, further proceedings on H.R. 5876 were postponed until a time to be announced.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/22/2008--Reported to House amended. Stop Child Abuse in Residential Programs for Teens Act of 2008 - (Sec. 3) Directs the Assistant Secretary for Children and Families of the Department of Health and Human Services to require each location of a covered program to meet specified minimum standards if individually or together with other locations it has an effect on interstate commerce. Defines &quot;covered program&quot; as one not operated by a governmental entity that for children unrelated to the program owner or operator: (1) provides a residential environment; and (2) operates with a focus on serving children with emotional, behavioral, or mental health problems or disorders, or problems with alcohol or substance abuse. Directs the Assistant Secretary to require each location of a covered program that, individually or together with other locations, has an effect on interstate commerce, to meet certain minimum health and safety standards. Directs the Assistant Secretary also to: (1) establish a process for conducting unannounced site inspections of each covered program location to determine compliance with such standards; (2) implement an ongoing review process for investigating and evaluating reports of child abuse and neglect; (3) establish civil penalties for violations of standards; (4) establish public websites with information about each covered program, as well as a national toll-free telephone hotline to receive complaints; and (5) establish a process to ensure that complaints received by the hotline are promptly reviewed by persons with appropriate expertise. (Sec. 4) Requires the Assistant Secretary to refer any violation of such standards to the Attorney General for appropriate action. Authorizes the Attorney General to file such a complaint on his or her own initiative regardless of whether such a referral has been made. (Sec. 5) Authorizes a private right of action in a U.S. district court for harm caused by a violation of minimum standards. (Sec. 7) Authorizes appropriations for FY2009-FY2013. (Sec. 8) Amends the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act to establish additional eligibility requirements for grants to states to prevent child abuse and neglect at residential programs. Requires such states to develop policies and procedures to prevent child abuse and neglect at covered programs consistent with the standards specified by this Act. Authorizes appropriations for FY2009-FY2013. 
	</summary>
</bill>
