<bill session="110" type="h" number="5873" updated="2009-01-09T05:01:11-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1208836800" datetime="2008-04-22"/></status>

	<introduced date="1208836800" datetime="2008-04-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Family Leave Insurance Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for a paid family and medical leave insurance program, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400387"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400031" joined="2008-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400289" joined="2008-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2008-04-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-04-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="2008-04-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400384" joined="2008-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400152" joined="2008-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400048" joined="2008-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400103" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2008-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400013" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400653" joined="2008-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400251" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2008-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412232" joined="2008-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2008-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400366" joined="2008-09-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2008-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400240" joined="2008-04-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400024" joined="2008-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="2008-04-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1208836800" datetime="2008-04-22"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E678)</text></action>
		<action date="1208836800" datetime="2008-04-22"><text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1208836800" datetime="2008-04-22"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1208836800" datetime="2008-04-22"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1208836800" datetime="2008-04-22"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1210564800" datetime="2008-05-12"><committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/22/2008--Introduced.<br/>Family Leave Insurance Act of 2008 - Directs the Secretary of Labor to establish a Family and Medical Leave Insurance Program, mandatory for certain covered employers.. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) contract for a state to provide benefits in that state through the Program, including expansion of a pre-existing state program; or (2) at a governor's request enter an interagency agreement with the Commissioner of the Social Security Administration to establish and provide Program benefits directly through a state Family and Medical Insurance Program. Entitles eligible employees to Program benefits that include specified percentages of their daily earnings for 12 workweeks of leave under the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 during any 12-month period. Authorizes any employer, with the Secretary's approval, to establish a voluntary plan meeting specified criteria. Specifies prohibited acts by an employer, and penalties for violations. Requires the Director of the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to establish a Civil Service Family and Medical Leave Insurance Program with the same Program benefits for certain federal agency employees. Establishes the Family and Medical Leave Insurance Fund in the Treasury. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose a family and medical leave premium on every individual and every employer to finance a Family and Medical Leave Trust Fund in the Treasury for Program benefits. Exempts from such premium: (1) employers or self-employers with voluntary plans approved by the Secretary as equivalent or better than the Program; and (2) small employers who have elected not to participate in it. 
	</summary>
</bill>
