<bill session="110" type="h" number="5904" updated="2009-01-09T05:05:19-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1209009600" datetime="2008-04-24"/></status>

	<introduced date="1209009600" datetime="2008-04-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Safe FEAST Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Safe Food Enforcement, Assessment, Standards and Targeting Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to establish new procedures and requirements to improve the safety of food, whether produced and distributed domestically or imported into the United States, by providing for improved information technology to identify high-risk imports and for enhanced capacity in the United States and in foreign governments to identify and address food safety issues on a scientific basis, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400618"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400330" joined="2008-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400129" joined="2008-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400065" joined="2008-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400297" joined="2008-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400158" joined="2008-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400400" joined="2008-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400320" joined="2008-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400234" joined="2008-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400328" joined="2008-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400334" joined="2008-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400321" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412255" joined="2008-09-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1209009600" datetime="2008-04-24"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1209096000" datetime="2008-04-25"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/24/2008--Introduced.<br/>Safe Food Enforcement, Assessment, Standards and Targeting Act of 2008 or Safe FEAST Act of 2008 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to grant the Secretary of Health and Human Services access to certain records relating to an article of food during a food-related emergency. Requires: (1) owners and operators of facilities engaged in manufacturing, processing, packing, or holding food for consumption in the United States (with specified exceptions) to take specified steps regarding hazard evaluation, implementation of risk-based preventive controls, monitoring and verification of control performance, corrective actions, recordkeeping, and facility inspection; and (2) the Secretary to establish minimum standards for implementation of those requirements. Prohibits operation of a facility that processes or packs food for sale in the United States if the operator has not conducted the required hazard analysis or implemented reasonably appropriate science-based preventive controls or has failed to conduct a required reanalysis or to have a plan documenting compliance with such requirements.<br/>Requires each U.S. importer to adopt and document a foreign supplier safety assurance program to assure that imported food is in compliance, is not adulterated, and does not pose a threat of serious adverse health consequences or death.<br/>Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) certification of imports by a competent authority of an exporting country; (2) establishment of a voluntary qualified importer program; (3) recognition of qualified laboratories for analyses of imported foods; (4) establishment of regulations for the safe production, harvesting, and packaging of fruits and vegetables; and (5) recognition of third party certification programs.<br/>Grants the Secretary mandatory recall authority of food that will cause serious adverse health consequences.<br/>Directs the Secretary to develop a comprehensive plan to expand the technical, scientific, and regulatory capacity of foreign governments and food industries from which foods are exported to the United States.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
