<bill session="110" type="h" number="5917" updated="2009-01-09T05:06:55-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1209441600" datetime="2008-04-29"/></status>

	<introduced date="1209441600" datetime="2008-04-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">New Bridging Industry and Government Through Hi-Tech Research on Energy Efficiency Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the coordination of efforts in the development of viable efficient alternative fuel technologies.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400225"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400414" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400385" joined="2008-05-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400342" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400276" joined="2008-04-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400288" joined="2008-05-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400400" joined="2008-05-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1209441600" datetime="2008-04-29"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E763-764)</text></action>
		<action date="1209441600" datetime="2008-04-29"><text>Referred to the Committee on Science and Technology, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, Oversight and Government Reform, Energy and Commerce, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1209441600" datetime="2008-04-29"><text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text></action>
		<action date="1209441600" datetime="2008-04-29"><committee name="House Science and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text></action>
		<action date="1209441600" datetime="2008-04-29"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1209441600" datetime="2008-04-29"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1209441600" datetime="2008-04-29"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1209441600" datetime="2008-04-29"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text></action>
		<action date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/29/2008--Introduced.<br/>New Bridging Industry and Government Through Hi-Tech Research on Energy Efficiency Act of 2008 - Requires the Secretary of Energy to establish a program for making grants to National Laboratories and institutions of higher education for research, development, and demonstration of high-efficiency advanced battery technologies. Allows such grants to be used for: (1) exploratory research; (2) battery system development; (3) vehicle technology demonstration and validation; and (4) U.S. advanced battery production capability development.<br/>Defines &quot;battery&quot; to mean an electrochemical energy storage system powered directly by electrical current.<br/>Requires the Secretary to give priority consideration to National Laboratories and institutions of higher education that partner with original equipment manufacturers of vehicles that will use the technologies.<br/>Amends the Internal Revenue Code to extend and revise the credit for increasing research activities. Establishes an Interagency Working Group on Corporate Average Fuel Economy Standards to ensure that federal agencies' work to research and develop advanced fuel technology is coordinated and concerted in order to increase vehicle fuel efficiency and reduce emissions.<br/>Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to work with national and international standard setting organizations to harmonize standards for the production of biofuels from a variety of feedstocks and the blending of such fuels with petroleum-based fuels at various concentrations.<br/>Requires the Secretary of Transportation to establish a program for making grants with the goal of establishing at least 100 publicly available hydrogen fueling pumps at retail gas stations by 2013 in at least two selected regions.<br/>Authorizes funds to be appropriated to the Administrator of the General Services Administration (GSA) for the acquisition of hydrogen fuel cell vehicles for use by federal agencies for each of FY2012-FY2014. 
	</summary>
</bill>
