<bill session="110" type="h" number="5913" updated="2009-01-09T05:06:21-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1209441600" datetime="2008-04-29"/></status>

	<introduced date="1209441600" datetime="2008-04-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Americans from Unsafe Foreign Products Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 28, United States Code, to provide for service of process over foreign nationals in cases involving defective products causing injury in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400355"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400364" joined="2008-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400080" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412225" joined="2008-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400424" joined="2008-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400630" joined="2008-07-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400245" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412199" joined="2008-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="2008-06-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412228" joined="2008-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400310" joined="2008-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400100" joined="2008-06-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1209441600" datetime="2008-04-29"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E755)</text></action>
		<action date="1209441600" datetime="2008-04-29"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1209441600" datetime="2008-04-29"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, the Internet, and Intellectual Property.</text></action>
		<action date="1209441600" datetime="2008-04-29"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text></action>
		<action date="1209614400" datetime="2008-05-01"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/29/2008--Introduced.<br/>Protecting Americans from Unsafe Foreign Products Act - Amends the federal judicial code to provide for service of process on foreign citizens or subjects (nationals), or their agents, in cases involving defective products causing injury in the United States which were manufactured by the foreign national outside the United States. Conditions jursidiction for service of process on the fact that the foreign national: (1) knew or reasonably should have known that the product or component would be imported for sale or use in the United States; or (2) had contacts with the United States, whether or not such contacts occurred in the place where the injury occurred. 
	</summary>
</bill>
