<bill session="110" type="h" number="5915" updated="2009-01-09T05:06:37-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1209441600" datetime="2008-04-29"/></status>

	<introduced date="1209441600" datetime="2008-04-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">SAFE Truckers Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Screening Applied Fairly and Equitably to Truckers Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require motor vehicle operators transporting security sensitive material in commerce to obtain a transportation security card from the Secretary of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400617"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400356" joined="2008-09-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1209441600" datetime="2008-04-29"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text></action>
		<action date="1212379200" datetime="2008-06-02"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation Security and Infrastructure Protection.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/29/2008--Introduced.<br/>Screening Applied Fairly and Equitably to Truckers Act of 2008, or the SAFE Truckers Act of 2008 - Amends the Homeland Security Act 2002 to require the Secretary of Homeland Security to: (1) designate security sensitive material; and (2) prohibit an individual from operating a motor vehicle in commerce while transporting such material, unless the operator of the motor vehicle holds a transportation security card issued by the Secretary. Directs the Secretary to prohibit a person (shipper) from offering a security sensitive material for transportation by motor vehicle, or causing the transportation of such material by motor vehicle, unless the operator of the motor vehicle holds a transportation security card. Sets forth both civil and criminal penalties for persons who violate the requirements of this Act. Prohibits a motor vehicle registered in Mexico or Canada from transporting security sensitive material in U.S. commerce until the operator of the motor vehicle has undergone a background records check similar to that required for U.S. commercial motor vehicle operators licensed to transport security sensitive materials in U.S. commerce. Requires the Secretary to conduct periodically a named-based background check against the U.S. integrated terrorism watch list of all individuals licensed to operate a motor vehicle to transport a hazardous material in commerce. Establishes task forces on: (1) highway security; and (2) crimes disqualifying individuals from certain transportation-related employment. 
	</summary>
</bill>
