<bill session="110" type="h" number="5927" updated="2009-01-09T05:08:12-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30"/></status>

	<introduced date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">International Violence Against Women Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To combat international violence against women and girls.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400025"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400253" joined="2008-12-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400222" joined="2008-09-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-12-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400282" joined="2008-12-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400333" joined="2008-12-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2008-12-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400198" joined="2008-12-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400063" joined="2008-12-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400361" joined="2008-12-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400274" joined="2008-12-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400254" joined="2008-04-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="2008-12-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="2008-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400652" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="2008-12-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400030" joined="2008-12-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="412188" joined="2008-12-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400245" joined="2008-12-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="2008-12-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="412223" joined="2008-12-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400103" joined="2008-04-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400259" joined="2008-12-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400383" joined="2008-12-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400251" joined="2008-12-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2008-12-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400074" joined="2008-12-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400125" joined="2008-12-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="412186" joined="2008-12-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400326" joined="2008-12-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400371" joined="2008-12-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/30/2008--Introduced.<br/>International Violence Against Women Act of 2008 - Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to establish in the Department of State the Office of Women's Global Initiatives (which shall replace the Office of International Women's Issues) to coordinate U.S. government efforts respecting international women's issues. Establishes within the Department an Advisory Commission on International Violence Against Women. Directs the President to develop a comprehensive strategy to prevent violence against women and girls. Directs the Coordinator of the Women's Global Initiatives to ensure that foreign assistance programs incorporate measures to prevent and respond to violence against women and girls. Provides that U.S. training of foreign military and police forces incorporates training on prevention of violence against women and girls. Directs the Department and the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) to assist programs that prevent and respond to violence against women and girls in all humanitarian relief, conflict, and post-conflict operations. Directs the Secretary of State to: (1) encourage U.N. member states to expand the number of female members of U.N. peacekeeping missions; and (2) take emergency measures to respond to violence against women and girls during conflict or post-conflict operations. Expresses the sense of Congress that the United Nations should strengthen its ability to prevent violence against women and girls by U.N. military and civilian personnel. Provides that Foreign Service training include instruction on prevention of violence against women and girls. Authorizes appropriations to support the United Nations Development Fund for Women Trust Fund in Support of Actions to Eliminate Violence Against Women.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
