<bill session="110" type="h" number="5923" updated="2009-01-09T05:07:44-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1209441600" datetime="2008-04-29"/></status>

	<introduced date="1209441600" datetime="2008-04-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Patients' Health Care Reform Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Access and Choice for Entrepreneurs Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow individuals a refundable and advancable credit against income tax for health insurance costs, to allow employees who elect not to participate in employer subsidized health plans an exclusion from gross income for employer payments in lieu of such participations, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400368"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400151" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400385" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400196" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400116" joined="2008-09-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400049" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400662" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400433" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400017" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412235" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400287" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400131" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400320" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400421" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400005" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400221" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400016" joined="2008-09-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400315" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400141" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412011" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400656" joined="2008-04-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1209441600" datetime="2008-04-29"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1209441600" datetime="2008-04-29"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1209441600" datetime="2008-04-29"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1209441600" datetime="2008-04-29"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1210132800" datetime="2008-05-07"><committee name="House Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/29/2008--Introduced.<br/>Patients' Health Care Reform Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to provide for the establishment and governance of : (1) HealthMarts, which are nonprofit organizations that offer health benefits coverage to employers, employees, and individuals through contracts with health insurance issuers; and (2) individual membership associations (IMAs), which are organizations that offer health benefits coverage to members through health insurance issuer contracts. Requires the Secretary of Heath and Human Services to pay 50% of a state's costs to provide health benefits coverage under a high-risk pool, a reinsurance pool, or other risk-adjustment mechanisms used to subsidize the purchase of private health insurance.<br/>Small Business Access and Choice for Entrepreneurs Act of 2007 [sic]- Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to provide for establishment and governance of association health plans, which are group health plans whose sponsors are trade, industry, professional, chamber of commerce, or similar business associations and which meet certain ERISA certification requirements.<br/>Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide individuals with a tax credit for payments for qualified health insurance and allows the Secretary of the Treasury to make advance payments of the credit to providers. Excludes from gross income any compensating coverage payment made by an employer to an employee who elects not to participate in the employer's subsidized health plan.<br/>Requires health insurance issuers offering coverage in connection with a group health plan to provide certain information to the administrator of the plan, including information regarding: (1) plan benefits and exclusions; (2) a participant's financial responsibilities; and (3) legal recourse options for participants and beneficiaries.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
