<bill session="110" type="h" number="5929" updated="2009-01-09T05:08:25-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30"/></status>

	<introduced date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Nuclear Terrorism Deterrence and Detection Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the Nation's nuclear forensics capability to help deter and respond to nuclear terrorism.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412257"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30"><text>Referred to the Committee on Science and Technology, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, Foreign Affairs, Homeland Security, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30"><text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text></action>
		<action date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30"><text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text></action>
		<action date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1209614400" datetime="2008-05-01"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text></action>
		<action date="1212379200" datetime="2008-06-02"><committee name="House Homeland Security"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emerging Threats, Cybersecurity, and Science and Technology.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/30/2008--Introduced.<br/>Nuclear Terrorism Deterrence and Detection Act - Declares that it is the sense of Congress that the Administrator for Nuclear Security should, with specified minimum levels of funding, establish a graduate fellowship program in nuclear chemistry and carry out research and development to improve the speed and accuracy of nuclear forensics radiation-measurement equipment. Amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008 to require a report to Congress on any legislative, regulatory, or treaty actions necessary to facilitate international cooperation in enhancement of international nuclear-material databases and the linking of those databases to enable prompt data access. Directs the Secretaries of Defense, Energy, and Homeland Security to establish a joint independent Nuclear Forensics Advisory Panel of experts not directly associated with federal laboratories to provide independent validation of any federal nuclear forensics analysis. Directs the President to report to specified congressional committees on the involvement of Cabinet-level leadership in planned nuclear terrorism preparedness exercises that include nuclear forensics analysis.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
