<bill session="110" type="h" number="5931" updated="2009-01-09T05:08:39-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30"/></status>

	<introduced date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Joint Guam Projects Oversight Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure appropriate implementation and oversight of the realignment of military installations and the relocation of military personnel on Guam, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400041"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400001" joined="2008-04-30"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30"><text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30"><text>Referred to House Small Business</text></action>
		<action date="1210132800" datetime="2008-05-07"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E852-853)</text></action>
		<action date="1211515200" datetime="2008-05-23"><committee name="House Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/30/2008--Introduced.<br/>Joint Guam Projects Oversight Act - Establishes the Guam Defense Policy Review Initiative Account to carry out transactions in connection with the realignment and relocation of military personnel on Guam. Expresses the sense of Congress with respect to: (1) the use of special purpose entities for military housing related to such realignment and relocation; and (2) federal assistance to Guam for infrastructure development and other needs in connection with the realignment and relocation. Requires a report from the: (1) Comptroller General concerning interagency requirements related to such realignment and relocation; and (2) Department of Defense (DOD) Inspector General addressing potential waste and fraud associated with the realignment of military forces on Guam. Outlines energy and environmental design requirements related to such realignment and relocation. Makes the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands eligible for DOD military base reuse studies and community planning assistance. Requires the Secretary of Defense to: (1) develop and support programs for training the local workforce on Guam for employment opportunities arising from realignment and relocation; and (2) enter into a cooperative agreement for establishing a Procurement Technical Assistance Center on Guam. Requires construction contractors operating for DOD in connection with military personnel realignment or relocation on Guam to follow certain procedures to demonstrate compliance with Guam tax, employment, and licensing laws.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
