<bill session="110" type="h" number="5942" updated="2009-01-09T05:09:54-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1209614400" datetime="2008-05-01"/></status>

	<introduced date="1209614400" datetime="2008-05-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Trauma Center Stabilization Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure the continued and future availability of lifesaving trauma health care in the United States and to prevent further trauma center closures and downgrades by assisting trauma centers with uncompensated care costs, core mission services, emergency needs, and information technology.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400409"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400620" joined="2008-07-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400280" joined="2008-09-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400337" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400413" joined="2008-09-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400380" joined="2008-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400406" joined="2008-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400052" joined="2008-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400101" joined="2008-06-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400412" joined="2008-07-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400437" joined="2008-07-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400352" joined="2008-07-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400048" joined="2008-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412235" joined="2008-06-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400044" joined="2008-06-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400399" joined="2008-07-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400251" joined="2008-06-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400118" joined="2008-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400139" joined="2008-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400032" joined="2008-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2008-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400425" joined="2008-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400186" joined="2008-07-21"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1209614400" datetime="2008-05-01"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1209960000" datetime="2008-05-05"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/1/2008--Introduced.<br/>National Trauma Center Stabilization Act of 2008 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to revise provisions governing grants to trauma centers. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish four programs to award grants to public or nonprofit trauma centers to: (1) assist in defraying substantial uncompensated care costs; (2) further a center's core mission; (3) provide emergency relief to ensure continued and future availability of trauma service; and (4) support the development and maintenance of innovative information technology systems. Sets forth: (1) minimum qualifications of eligible centers, including requirements for levels of uncompensated care provided; and (2) preferences for awarding grants among level I, II, III, and IV trauma centers and among centers based on the changing availability of or demand for trauma care in the area served and financial need. Requires grantees to submit a long-term plan for providing trauma care.<br/>Requires the Secretary to: (1) annually determine and notify centers of their eligibility to receive a grant; and (2) periodically report on the status of such grants, the financial stability of the centers, the populations using the centers, and the effectiveness and efficiency of center activities.<br/>Authorizes appropriations for such grants for FY2009-FY2014 and specifies percentages to be reserved for the different types of grants.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
