<bill session="110" type="h" number="5944" updated="2009-01-09T05:10:08-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1209614400" datetime="2008-05-01"/></status>

	<introduced date="1209614400" datetime="2008-05-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Enhancement of Recruitment, Retention, and Readjustment Through Education Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend titles 10 and 38, United States Code, to improve educational assistance for members of the Armed Forces and veterans in order to enhance recruitment and retention for the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400328"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400123" joined="2008-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400142" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400385" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400342" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400267" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400154" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400239" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400052" joined="2008-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400433" joined="2008-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400658" joined="2008-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400642" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400224" joined="2008-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400212" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400147" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400287" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412216" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400400" joined="2008-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400404" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400107" joined="2008-05-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400171" joined="2008-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400005" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400221" joined="2008-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400108" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400157" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412191" joined="2008-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400252" joined="2008-05-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1209614400" datetime="2008-05-01"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E865)</text></action>
		<action date="1209614400" datetime="2008-05-01"><text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1209614400" datetime="2008-05-01"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1209614400" datetime="2008-05-01"><text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1211515200" datetime="2008-05-23"><committee name="House Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/1/2008--Introduced.<br/>Enhancement of Recruitment, Retention, and Readjustment Through Education Act of 2008 - Directs the Secretary of Defense to develop a plan on the coordination of current Department of Defense (DOD) educational assistance programs and the development of additional programs to enable members of the Armed Forces (members) to attain a bachelor's degree while pursuing a military career. Increases rates of educational assistance: (1) under the Montgomery GI Bill; (2) for members of the Selected Reserve; and (3) for Selected Reserve members with extended (more than 12 years) service who provide support for contingency operations and other operations. Provides an annual stipend for individuals receiving basic educational assistance and pursuing a program of education at an approved institution of higher education. Allows a member who has completed six years of service (current law allows only members who have completed six years of service and have a military skill designated as critical) to transfer to one or more dependents any unused portion of the member's educational assistance entitlement. Provides similar authority for members of the Selected Reserve. Authorizes a member on active duty and entitled to basic educational assistance to use all or a portion thereof to repay any outstanding federal student loan. Makes eligible for educational assistance an individual who, after September 30, 2009, receives a commission upon graduation of a service academy or completion of Senior Reserve Officers' Training, and completes at least five years of continuous active duty. Makes eligible for enrollment under the Montgomery GI Bill certain retired personnel originally enrolled in the veterans' educational assistance program. Requires the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a supplemental educational grant program under which a participating institution of higher education provides certain veterans with the non-federal share of a percentage of such veteran's unmet educational financial need.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
