<bill session="110" type="h" number="5973" updated="2009-01-09T05:13:30-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1210046400" datetime="2008-05-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1210046400" datetime="2008-05-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Transparency and Accountability in Intelligence Contracting Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance transparency and accountability within the intelligence community for activities performed under Federal contracts, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400326"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412222" joined="2008-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2008-05-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1210046400" datetime="2008-05-06"><text>Referred to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1210046400" datetime="2008-05-06"><text>Referred to House Intelligence (Permanent Select)</text></action>
		<action date="1210046400" datetime="2008-05-06"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1210046400" datetime="2008-05-06"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/6/2008--Introduced.<br/>Transparency and Accountability in Intelligence Contracting Act of 2008 - Amends the National Security Act of 1947 to require the Director of National Intelligence (DNI) to prepare an annual assessment for such element of the intelligence community (IC) that assesses such element's use of private contractors and private contractor personnel. Requires each assessment to be submitted to the congressional intelligence committees. Directs that each contract, subcontract, or task or delivery order entered into with an IC element shall require the contractor to provide to the IC element contracting officer certain information on the personnel performing contracting activities, including their training, the process used to hire the individuals, and the number of foreign nationals employed. Prohibits the use of private contractors for the arrest, interrogation, detention, or transportation or transfer of persons under government custody or control. Requires a report from the DNI to Congress describing the personal services activities performed by contractors across the IC, the impact of such contractors on the IC workforce, plans for conversion of contractor employment into government employment, and accountability mechanisms governing the performance of such contractors.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
