<bill session="110" type="h" number="5977" updated="2009-01-09T05:13:58-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1210046400" datetime="2008-05-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1210046400" datetime="2008-05-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">TRUCC Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Trust in Reliable Understanding of Consumer Costs Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, to require a motor carrier, broker, or freight forwarder that collects a fuel surcharge to disclose and pay the fuel surcharge to the person responsible for bearing the cost of the fuel, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400100"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2008-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400209" joined="2008-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400183" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400635" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400191" joined="2008-09-08" withdrawn="2008-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400063" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="412210" joined="2008-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400355" joined="2008-07-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412208" joined="2008-07-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400638" joined="2008-09-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400009" joined="2008-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400318" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400310" joined="2008-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400042" joined="2008-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="412206" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400011" joined="2008-08-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1210046400" datetime="2008-05-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text></action>
		<action date="1210046400" datetime="2008-05-06"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/6/2008--Introduced.<br/>Trust in Reliable Understanding of Consumer Costs Act, or the TRUCC Act - Amends federal transportation law to require certain fuel costs disclosures and fuel costs reimbursements by a motor carrier, broker, or freight forwarder providing or arranging transportation or service using fuel for which it does not bear the cost. Requires such a motor carrier, broker, or freight forwarder to: (1) reimburse persons (truckers) that do bear fuel costs for any such costs they have paid; and (2) give such persons a written list that identifies any freight charge, brokerage fee or commission, fuel surcharge or adjustment, and any other charges. Prohibits any person from causing a motor carrier, broker, or freight forwarder to present false or misleading information on a document or in an oral representation about the actual rate, charge, or allowance to any party to the transaction or transportation.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
