<bill session="110" type="h" number="5979" updated="2009-01-09T05:14:11-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1210046400" datetime="2008-05-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1210046400" datetime="2008-05-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Stillbirth Awareness and Research Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for the national collection of data on stillbirths in a standardized manner, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400219"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400420" joined="2008-07-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2008-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400160" joined="2008-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2008-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400080" joined="2008-07-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400660" joined="2008-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400101" joined="2008-07-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400152" joined="2008-06-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400346" joined="2008-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400195" joined="2008-07-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2008-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400234" joined="2008-06-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400645" joined="2008-09-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2008-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="412213" joined="2008-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400654" joined="2008-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400321" joined="2008-06-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1210046400" datetime="2008-05-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1210132800" datetime="2008-05-07"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/6/2008--Introduced.<br/>Stillbirth Awareness and Research Act of 2008 - Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) more states should enact legislation that allows the issuance of a Certificate of Birth Resulting in Stillbirth; and (2) the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) should increase the allocation of funds and other resources for stillbirth research.<br/>Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to establish and maintain a scientific registry of stillbirths in the United States, which shall include for each stillbirth information on the stillborn fetus and the mother's health and pregnancy as collected and submitted by states on the U.S. Standard Report of Fetal Death. Requires the Secretary to: (1) provide for the development of a standard definition of stillbirth and a standard protocol for stillbirth data collection and surveillance; and (2) carry out a national campaign to increase public and state awareness of such definition and protocol and public awareness and knowledge of stillbirths.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
