<bill session="110" type="h" number="5981" updated="2009-01-09T05:14:25-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1210046400" datetime="2008-05-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1210046400" datetime="2008-05-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">DNA Expansion and Improvement Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To reauthorize certain DNA-related grant programs under the Justice For All Act of 2004, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400426"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1210046400" datetime="2008-05-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1212465600" datetime="2008-06-03"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/6/2008--Introduced.<br/>DNA Expansion and Improvement Act of 2008 - Directs the Attorney General to make grants to states and local governments to purchase or improve forensic DNA technology. Amends the DNA Analysis Backlog Elimination Act of 2000 to: (1) require grants under the DNA identification program to pay the salaries of employees of DNA criminal laboratories; (2) require grant applications under such program to provide assurances that states and local governments will implement a process for the collection of DNA samples from convicted felons in their prisons; (3) increase and extend through FY2014 the authorization of appropriations for the DNA identification program; and (4) require the Attorney General to give priority to grant applications that will use funds for crime laboratories with demonstrated training and personnel needs.<br/>Amends the Justice For All Act of 2004 to extend through FY2014 grants for: (1) DNA training and education for law enforcement and correctional personnel, forensic science professionals, and court officers; (2) sexual assault DNA identification; (3) research and development for DNA forensic technology; (4) the Kirk Bloodsworth Post-Conviction DNA Testing Grant Program; and (5) DNA identification of missing persons and unidentified human remains.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
