<bill session="110" type="h" number="5990" updated="2009-01-09T05:15:40-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1210132800" datetime="2008-05-07"/></status>

	<introduced date="1210132800" datetime="2008-05-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Video Games Ratings Enforcement Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require ratings label on video games and to prohibit the sales and rentals of adult-rated video games to minors.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400255"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400379" joined="2008-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400355" joined="2008-07-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400030" joined="2008-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400400" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400266" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400345" joined="2008-06-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1210132800" datetime="2008-05-07"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1210219200" datetime="2008-05-08"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/7/2008--Introduced.<br/>Video Games Ratings Enforcement Act - Prohibits shipping or distributing in interstate commerce, selling, or renting a video game the outside packaging of which does not display a label containing an age-based content rating determined by the Entertainment Software Ratings Board (ESRB). Directs the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to require all retail establishments that sell video games to display information about the ESRB content rating system. Prohibits any person from selling or renting video games containing the ESRB content rating of : (1) &quot;adults only&quot; to any person under the age of 18; or (2) &quot;mature&quot; to any person under the age of 17. Treats violations of such requirements and prohibitions as an unfair or deceptive act or practice subject to a civil penalty of not more than $5,000 per violation.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
