<bill session="110" type="h" number="6001" updated="2009-01-09T05:16:55-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1210219200" datetime="2008-05-08"/></status>

	<introduced date="1210219200" datetime="2008-05-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Main Street U.S.A. Energy Security Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Deep Ocean Energy Resources Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Energy Natural Resources Enhancement Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Geo Fund Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Refinery Permit Process Schedule Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Renewable Energy and Energy Conservation Tax Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Rigs to Reefs Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To rebalance the United States energy portfolio, to increase and utilize the Nation's domestic energy resources and supply, to strengthen energy security and independence, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400056"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400099" joined="2008-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400385" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400077" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="409888" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400288" joined="2008-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400055" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400373" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400224" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400172" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400158" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400368" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412201" joined="2008-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400644" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400319" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400421" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400440" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400016" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400032" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400315" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400182" joined="2008-05-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1210219200" datetime="2008-05-08"><text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, Ways and Means, Armed Services, and Science and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1210219200" datetime="2008-05-08"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1210219200" datetime="2008-05-08"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1210219200" datetime="2008-05-08"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1210219200" datetime="2008-05-08"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1210219200" datetime="2008-05-08"><text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text></action>
		<action date="1210219200" datetime="2008-05-08"><committee name="House Science and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text></action>
		<action date="1210564800" datetime="2008-05-12"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text></action>
		<action date="1210824000" datetime="2008-05-15"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1211515200" datetime="2008-05-23"><committee name="House Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/8/2008--Introduced.<br/>Main Street U.S.A. Energy Security Act of 2008 - Refinery Permit Process Schedule Act - Authorizes the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), upon request of a state governor, to provide financial assistance to hire additional personnel with expertise in federal refinery authorizations. Directs the President to: (1) appoint a federal coordinator to implement a federal refinery authorization; and (2) designate certain closed military installations as potentially suitable refinery construction sites. Sets forth an oil and gas leasing program on the Coastal Plain of Alaska. Deep Ocean Energy Resources Act of 2008 - Amends the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (OCSLA) to revise the outer Continental Shelf leasing program. Federal Energy Natural Resources Enhancement Act of 2008 - Authorizes appropriations for a natural resources enhancement program for management of fish, wildlife, and natural resources. Rigs to Reefs Act of 2008 - Authorizes the Secretary to use decommissioned offshore oil and gas platforms for artificial reef and scientific research. Redesignates as the Energy and Mineral Schools Reinvestment Act specified law governing mining and petroleum schools. Revises requirements for the funding of certain state-chartered petroleum or mining schools. National Geo Fund Act of 2008 - Instructs the Secretary to establish: (1) a fuel production program using strategic unconventional resources and CO2 enhanced recovery; and (3) a grant program to produce geothermal and geopressure oil and gas.<br/>Grants the lessee of an existing oil and gas lease located completely within 100 miles of the coastline of California or Florida Adjacent Zones the option, without compensation, of exchanging such lease for a new oil and gas lease having a primary term of five years. Amends OCSLA to: (1) repeal the coastal impact assistance program; and (2) provide conditional funds for the Secure Rural Schools and Community Self-Determination Act of 2000. Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to: (1) revise incentives for innovative technologies; (2) authorize construction of nuclear power plants by 2010 (Nuclear Power 2010 Program); and (3) instruct the Secretary of Labor to promulgate implementing regulations for a nuclear energy workforce program. Creates an interagency working group to recommend coordinated federal promotion of increased domestic nuclear manufacturing capacity and export of domestic nuclear energy products and services. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a qualifying nuclear power manufacturing tax credit. Directs: (1) the Secretary of Energy to establish a National Nuclear Energy Council; and (2) the President to establish a High Level Waste Authority with jurisdiction over nuclear waste contracts.<br/>Sets forth a program to develop coal-to-liquid manufacturing on federal land. Renewable Energy and Energy Conservation Tax Act of 2008 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to extend and modify tax credits for: (1) renewable energy; (2) electricity produced from marine and hydrokinetic renewable energy; (3) electricity produced from the production of substitute natural gas from refined coal or petcoke; (4) new clean renewable energy bonds; (5) residential energy efficient property; (6) plug-in hybrid vehicles; (7) production of cellulosic ethanol; and (8) alternative fuels and vehicles. Instructs the Secretary of Energy to: (1) implement a research and development program for blending transportation fuels derived from coal-to-liquids with transportation fuels derived from renewable sources; and (2) maintain four Bioenergy Research Centers.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
