<bill session="110" type="h" number="6007" updated="2009-01-09T05:17:36-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1210219200" datetime="2008-05-08"/></status>

	<introduced date="1210219200" datetime="2008-05-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of Transportation to establish a Port of Guam Improvement Enterprise Program, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400041"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1210219200" datetime="2008-05-08"><text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1210219200" datetime="2008-05-08"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1210219200" datetime="2008-05-08"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1210305600" datetime="2008-05-09"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text></action>
		<action date="1211515200" datetime="2008-05-23"><committee name="House Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/8/2008--Introduced.<br/>Authorizes the Secretary of Transportation, acting through the Administrator of the Maritime Administration, to establish a Port of Guam Improvement Enterprise Program for the planning, design, and construction of projects for the Port of Guam to improve port facilities, relieve congestion, increase port security, and provide greater access to port facilities. Expands intermodal surface freight transfer facility project eligibility for federal loans, loan guarantees, and lines of credit to include an intermodal or marine facility project under the Program. Establishes the Port of Guam Improvement Enterprise Fund.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
