<bill session="110" type="h" number="6017" updated="2009-01-09T05:18:51-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1210219200" datetime="2008-05-08"/></status>

	<introduced date="1210219200" datetime="2008-05-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To ameliorate the effects of harmful algal blooms in the Great Lakes by reducing phosphorus inputs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400391"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400276" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400238" joined="2008-06-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1210219200" datetime="2008-05-08"><text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1210219200" datetime="2008-05-08"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1210219200" datetime="2008-05-08"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1210219200" datetime="2008-05-08"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1210305600" datetime="2008-05-09"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text></action>
		<action date="1210564800" datetime="2008-05-12"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text></action>
		<action date="1211256000" datetime="2008-05-20"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, and Oceans.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/8/2008--Introduced.<br/>Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to develop and submit to Congress a regional response plan to address and mitigate harmful algal blooms in the Great Lakes that includes: (1) an analysis of the scientific data about the causes of such blooms; (2) proposed solutions to address and mitigate such blooms, an analysis of the technological and economic feasibility of such solutions, and an estimate of the cost of implementing them; (3) an analysis of the ability of secondary treatment by wastewater treatment facilities to reduce the amount of phosphorus and nitrogen being discharged into the Great Lakes; (4) an evaluation of the relevant water quality standards promulgated by each of the Great Lakes states; and (5) suggested revisions to such standards if they are not adequate to reduce the incidence and severity of such blooms. Requires the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) to declare as a banned hazardous substance under the Federal Hazardous Substances Act any cleaning product that contains greater than 0.5% phosphorus by volume and is intended for use in individual households.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
