<bill session="110" type="h" number="6019" updated="2009-01-09T05:19:06-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1210219200" datetime="2008-05-08"/></status>

	<introduced date="1210219200" datetime="2008-05-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Ray Ruiz Special Exposure Cohort Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Energy Employees Occupational Illness Compensation Program Act of 2000 to grant Special Exposure Cohort designation to a specific group of individuals from a Department of Energy facility in Los Alamos, New Mexico.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400413"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1210219200" datetime="2008-05-08"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E861-862)</text></action>
		<action date="1210219200" datetime="2008-05-08"><text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1210219200" datetime="2008-05-08"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1210219200" datetime="2008-05-08"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1212465600" datetime="2008-06-03"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/8/2008--Introduced.<br/>Ray Ruiz Special Exposure Cohort Act - Amends the Energy Employees Occupational Illness Compensation Program Act of 2000 to include an employee of the Department of Energy (DOE) or its contractors or subcontractors who worked for at least 250 work days at the Los Alamos site in New Mexico within the meaning of the term &quot;member of the Special Exposure Cohort&quot; for purposes of occupational illness compensation.<br/>Provides that a claim that an individual qualifies for compensation or benefits under such Act shall be considered notwithstanding any denial of any other claim for compensation with respect to such individual.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
