<bill session="110" type="h" number="6015" updated="2009-01-09T05:18:37-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1210219200" datetime="2008-05-08"/></status>

	<introduced date="1210219200" datetime="2008-05-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Hospital and ASC Price Disclosure and Litigation Protection Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require hospitals and ambulatory surgical centers to disclose charge-related information and to provide price protection for treatments not covered by insurance as conditions for receiving protection from charge-related legal actions.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400367"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400131" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400032" joined="2008-05-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1210219200" datetime="2008-05-08"><text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1210219200" datetime="2008-05-08"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1210219200" datetime="2008-05-08"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1210564800" datetime="2008-05-12"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/8/2008--Introduced.<br/>Hospital and ASC Price Disclosure and Litigation Protection Act of 2008 - Prohibits a charge-related legal action from being brought by an individual against a hospital or ambulatory surgical center if the hospital or center: (1) has met the requirements under this Act; (2) has entered into an agreement with the uninsured individual before treatment that sets the maximum price that will be charged for such treatment; and (3) has met the terms of such agreement.<br/>Sets forth disclosures that a hospital or center must provide to an individual who is scheduled to receive treatment and include in any itemized bill, including: (1) the estimated price or the price charged for the treatment; (2) the payment rate for the treatment negotiated with the network plan or managed care plan that has the largest number of enrollees; and (3) the Medicare payment rate for the treatment. Excludes from such requirements a treatment for which there exists a third-party price arrangement unless the individual involved requests such information.<br/>Requires a hospital or ambulatory surgical center to report data to the Secretary of Health and Human Services regarding: (1) the frequency of performing certain services and administering certain drugs; (2) the charge by the hospital or center for such services or drugs; (3) the negotiated rate of payment for the treatment by the plan with the largest number of enrollees; and (4) the Medicare payment rate for the treatment.<br/>Requires the Secretary to: (1) publicly post such information on the Internet in a manner that promotes charge comparisons among hospitals and centers; and (2) select which services or drugs are to be reported based on the frequency with which the services are performed or the drugs are administered.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
