<bill session="110" type="h" number="6033" updated="2009-01-09T05:20:46-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1210651200" datetime="2008-05-13"/></status>

	<introduced date="1210651200" datetime="2008-05-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Home-Based Health Services Job Training and Caregiving Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To promote training and employment for public housing residents in home-based health services so such residents can provide Medicaid covered home-based health services to elderly and disabled persons receiving public housing assistance from the Department of Housing and Urban Development.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400416"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1210651200" datetime="2008-05-13"><text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1210651200" datetime="2008-05-13"><text>Referred to House Financial Services</text></action>
		<action date="1210651200" datetime="2008-05-13"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1210651200" datetime="2008-05-13"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1210737600" datetime="2008-05-14"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text></action>
		<action date="1210737600" datetime="2008-05-14"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1211169600" datetime="2008-05-19"><committee name="House Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/13/2008--Introduced.<br/>Home-Based Health Services Job Training and Caregiving Act of 2008 - Amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 to require the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to establish a pilot program to make grants to eligible entities to promote the training and employment of public housing residents as home health aides and providers of home-based health services, in order for such residents to provide Medicaid-covered home-based health services to either elderly or disabled public housing residents, or both. Qualifies as an eligible entity any public housing agency, state or local government (or agency), community health center, home care provider organization, faith-based organization, labor organization, or other organization meeting specified criteria. Amends the Housing and Urban Development Act of 1968 to require the Secretary to: (1) ensure low- and very low-income persons, residing within a home-based health services public housing project, opportunities for training and employment arising in connection with such project; and (2) award contracts to businesses that provide such training and employment opportunities. 
	</summary>
</bill>
