<bill session="110" type="h" number="6037" updated="2009-01-09T05:21:13-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1210651200" datetime="2008-05-13"/></status>

	<introduced date="1210651200" datetime="2008-05-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Security Culture and Language Training Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend titles 10 and 37, United States Code, to create the position of Assistant Secretary of Defense for Irregular Warfare, Cultural Training, and Social Science Initiatives and to authorize a new skill incentive pay and proficiency bonus to encourage members of the Armed Forces to train in critical foreign languages and foreign cultural studies.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412188"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412199" joined="2008-05-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412219" joined="2008-05-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1210651200" datetime="2008-05-13"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
		<action date="1211515200" datetime="2008-05-23"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Terrorism, Unconventional Threats and Capabilities.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/13/2008--Introduced.<br/>National Security Culture and Language Training Act - Establishes an: (1) Assistant Secretary of Defense for Irregular Warfare, Cultural Training, and Social Sciences Initiatives; and (2) Office of Irregular Warfare, Cultural Training, and Social Sciences Initiatives. Requires the Office to, among other things: (1) devise and implement a training doctrine that includes the development of cultural, sociological, and psychological knowledge and skills for members of the Armed Forces; and (2) use existing military cultural training programs to expand training efforts for all military personnel. Authorizes the Secretary of the military department concerned (Secretary concerned) to pay: (1) a skill proficiency bonus to a regular or reserve member in training to acquire proficiency in a foreign language or expertise in foreign cultural studies or a related skill designated as critical by the Secretary concerned; and (2) incentive pay to a person enrolled in an officer training program to also participate in an education or training program to acquire such proficiency. Directs the Secretary of Defense to conduct a pilot program to provide a skill proficiency bonus to a member of the reserves receiving compensation for inactive-duty training while participating in an education or training program to acquire such proficiency.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
