<bill session="110" type="h" number="605" updated="2009-01-08T18:04:58-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1169442000" datetime="2007-01-22"/></status>

	<introduced date="1169442000" datetime="2007-01-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Seniors Taking on Phony Marketers Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, to provide an increased maximum penalty for telemarketing fraud targeting seniors, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400172"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1169442000" datetime="2007-01-22"><text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1169442000" datetime="2007-01-22"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1169442000" datetime="2007-01-22"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1169442000" datetime="2007-01-22"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1170392400" datetime="2007-02-02"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text></action>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text></action>
		<action date="1174622400" datetime="2007-03-23"><committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/22/2007--Introduced.<br/>Seniors Taking on Phony Marketers Act of 2007 - Amends the federal criminal code to increase from 10 to 15 years the additional term of imprisonment for telemarketing fraud aimed at individuals over the age of 55. Authorizes appropriations for FY2008 for: (1) 50 new postal inspectors to investigate telemarketing fraud; (2) 30 new assistant U.S. attorneys to prosecute telemarketing fraud cases; and (3) public awareness and prevention initiatives to educate senior citizens about telemarketing fraud.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
