<bill session="110" type="h" number="6064" updated="2009-01-09T05:24:31-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1221688920" datetime="2008-09-17T19:02:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1210824000" datetime="2008-05-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Silver Alert Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Kristen's Act Reauthorization of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">National Silver Alert Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Kristen's Act Reauthorization of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">National Silver Alert Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To encourage, enhance, and integrate Silver Alert plans throughout the United States.</title>
		<title type="official" as="amended by house">To encourage, enhance, and integrate Silver Alert plans throughout the United States, to authorize grants for the assistance of organizations to find missing adults, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400111"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400290" joined="2008-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400253" joined="2008-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400061" joined="2008-07-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400280" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400337" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400227" joined="2008-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400289" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400160" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400407" joined="2008-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400657" joined="2008-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="412221" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400102" joined="2008-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400302" joined="2008-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400380" joined="2008-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400403" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400623" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400129" joined="2008-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412195" joined="2008-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400647" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412230" joined="2008-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400276" joined="2008-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400077" joined="2008-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400323" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400423" joined="2008-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="412231" joined="2008-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="412189" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400101" joined="2008-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="412250" joined="2008-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400152" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400355" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412198" joined="2008-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="412188" joined="2008-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400339" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400230" joined="2008-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400048" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412199" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400087" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2008-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400383" joined="2008-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400422" joined="2008-07-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400653" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400251" joined="2008-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400021" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400638" joined="2008-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400193" joined="2008-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400415" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412254" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412186" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400326" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400201" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400391" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400204" joined="2008-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2008-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400208" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400218" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400240" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400024" joined="2008-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400425" joined="2008-07-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400233" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400179" joined="2008-05-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1210824000" datetime="2008-05-15"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1216008000" datetime="2008-07-14"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text></action>
		<action date="1216094400" datetime="2008-07-15"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1217217600" datetime="2008-07-28"><text>Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security Discharged.</text></action>
		<action date="1217390400" datetime="2008-07-30"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1217390400" datetime="2008-07-30" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1220902260" datetime="2008-09-08T16:31:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 110-825.</text></action>
		<calendar number="531" date="1220902260" datetime="2008-09-08T16:31:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 531.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1221508140" datetime="2008-09-15T16:49:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Scott (VA) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1221508140" datetime="2008-09-15T16:49:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8078-8083"/></action>
		<action date="1221508140" datetime="2008-09-15T16:49:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 6064.</text></action>
		<action date="1221509040" datetime="2008-09-15T17:04:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Issa objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text></action>
		<action date="1221688920" datetime="2008-09-17T19:02:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8368-8369"/></action>
		<vote date="1221688920" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-09-17T19:02:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote. (text CR 9/15/2008 H8078-8080)</text></vote>
		<action date="1221688920" datetime="2008-09-17T19:02:00-04:00"><text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action date="1221624000" datetime="2008-09-17"><text>Received in the Senate.</text></action>
		<action date="1222920000" datetime="2008-10-02"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/17/2008--Passed House amended. (This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on September 8, 2008. The summary of that version is repeated here.)<br/>Title I: Silver Alert Communications Network - National Silver Alert Act - (Sec. 102) Defines &quot;missing senior&quot; as any individual who is reported to, or identified by, a law enforcement agency as a missing person and who meets state requirements for designation as a missing senior.<br/>(Sec. 103) Directs the Attorney General to establish a national Silver Alert Communications Network within the Department of Justice (DOJ) to assist regional and local search efforts for missing seniors.<br/>(Sec. 104) Directs the Attorney General to designate in DOJ a national Silver Alert Communications Network Coordinator. Requires the Coordinator to: (1) work with states to encourage the development of additional Silver Alert plans in the network; (2) establish voluntary guidelines for states to use in developing Silver Alert plans; (3) develop proposed protocols for efforts to recover missing seniors and reduce the number of seniors who are reported missing; (4) establish an advisory group to assist states, local governments, law enforcement agencies, and other entities in the communications network; and (5) act as the nationwide point of contact for the development of the network and regional coordination of alerts for missing seniors. Requires the Coordinator to submit annual reports to Congress on the Coordinator's activities and the effectiveness and status of the Silver Alert plans of each state. Requires such report to include a list of states that have established Silver Alert plans and statistics about the recovery of missing persons. (Sec. 105) Requires the Coordinator to: (1) establish minimum standards for the issuance and dissemination of alerts through the Silver Alert Communications Network; (2) make available to states, local governments, and law enforcement agencies training and education programs and informational materials related to the communications network; and (3) coordinate with the Assistant Secretary for Aging of the Department of Health and Human Services and the head of the Missing Alzheimer's Disease Patient Alert Program within DOJ in developing training and educational programs.<br/>Authorizes appropriations to carry out the Silver Alert Communications Network.<br/>(Sec. 108) Directs the Attorney General to make grants to states on an equitable basis throughout the United States for the development and enhancement of programs for the support of Silver Alert plans and the Silver Alert Communications Network. Authorizes appropriations for FY2009-FY2013.<br/>(Sec. 109) Authorizes the Attorney General to award grants to states and local governments to carry out a program to provide voluntary electronic monitoring services to elderly individuals to assist in the location of such individuals if reported missing. Authorizes appropriations for FY2009-FY2014. Designates such grant program as the Sammy Kirk Voluntary Electronic Monitoring Program.<br/>Title II: Kristen's Act Reauthorization - Kristen's Act Reauthorization of 2008 - (Sec. 203) - Directs the Attorney General to make competitive grants to public agencies and/or nonprofit private organizations to: (1) maintain a national resource center and information clearinghouse for missing and unidentified adults; (2) maintain a national, interconnected database for tracking missing adults who are determined by law enforcement to be endangered due to age, diminished mental capacity, or the circumstances of disappearance when foul play is suspected or circumstances are unknown; (3) coordinate public and private programs that locate or recover missing adults or reunite missing adults with their families; (4) provide assistance and training to law enforcement agencies, state and local governments, elements of the criminal justice system, nonprofit organizations, and individuals in the prevention, investigation, prosecution, and treatment of cases involving missing adults; (5) provide assistance to families in locating and recovering missing adults; and (6) assist in public notification and victim advocacy related to missing adults.<br/>Directs the Attorney General to: (1) coordinate programs relating to missing adults that are funded by the federal government; and (2) encourage coordination between state and local law enforcement and public agencies and nonprofit organizations receiving a grant under this title.<br/>(Sec. 204) Authorizes appropriations for FY2009-FY2019.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
