<bill session="110" type="h" number="6065" updated="2009-01-09T05:24:39-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1210824000" datetime="2008-05-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1210824000" datetime="2008-05-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Green Schools Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To promote green schools.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400222"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400253" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400041" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400027" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412234" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412232" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400255" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400638" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400240" joined="2008-05-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1210824000" datetime="2008-05-15"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E933)</text></action>
		<action date="1210824000" datetime="2008-05-15"><text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1210824000" datetime="2008-05-15"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1210824000" datetime="2008-05-15"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/15/2008--Introduced.<br/>Green Schools Act - Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish a program awarding matching grants to local educational agencies for green school construction and improvement projects that create healthy learning environments while saving natural resources and money. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to extend, through 2012, the Qualified Zone Academy Bond program (which provides tax credits to the holders of such bonds, which in turn finance low or no interest loans for the improvement of public schools serving low-income areas). Requires public school rehabilitation, repair, or equipment financed through such bonds to serve the green goals of creating healthy learning environments while saving natural resources and money.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
