<bill session="110" type="h" number="6072" updated="2009-01-09T05:25:28-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1210824000" datetime="2008-05-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1210824000" datetime="2008-05-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Interagency Cooperation Commission Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a Commission to examine the long-term global challenges facing the United States and develop legislative and administrative proposals to improve interagency cooperation.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400137"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400230" joined="2008-09-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1210824000" datetime="2008-05-15"><text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1210824000" datetime="2008-05-15"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1210824000" datetime="2008-05-15"><text>Referred to House Rules</text></action>
		<action date="1213156800" datetime="2008-06-11"><committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Organization, and Procurement.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/15/2008--Introduced.<br/>Interagency Cooperation Commission Act - Establishes the Interagency Cooperation Commission to examine the long-term global challenges facing the United States and develop legislative and administrative proposals to improve interagency cooperation.<br/>Requires the Commission to: (1) address the role and impact in facilitating or impeding interagency cooperation of a variety of budgetary, planning, and operational factors; and (2) examine interdepartmental cooperation within the Department of Defense (DOD), including the common organizational structures, reference materials, and budget processes, and examine the value of such structures as models for broader government commonality.<br/>Lists as the subjects of required assessments: (1) past examples of successful and unsuccessful interagency cooperation; (2) the impact of the Goldwater-Nichols Act within DOD; (3) the effectiveness of current interagency structures and processes to engage in strategic planning and oversee and implement long-term United States policy in global affairs; (4) simulation-based assessments of global scenarios the United States may face in the long-term; and (5) the legal decision-making authority and resources needed in each department and at the highest levels of government to execute reforms proposed by the Commission.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
