<bill session="110" type="h" number="6088" updated="2009-01-09T05:27:23-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1211256000" datetime="2008-05-20"/></status>

	<introduced date="1211256000" datetime="2008-05-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Domestic Violence Volunteer Attorney Network Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a domestic violence volunteer attorney network to represent domestic violence victims.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400080"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400623" joined="2008-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400652" joined="2008-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400259" joined="2008-09-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1211256000" datetime="2008-05-20"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E976)</text></action>
		<action date="1211256000" datetime="2008-05-20"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1217217600" datetime="2008-07-28"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text></action>
		<action date="1217217600" datetime="2008-07-28"><text>Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security Discharged.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/20/2008--Introduced.<br/>National Domestic Violence Volunteer Attorney Network Act - Authorizes the Attorney General to award grants to the American Bar Association Commission on Domestic Violence to work in collaboration with the American Bar Association Committee on Pro Bono and Public Service and other organizations to create, recruit lawyers for, and provide training, mentoring, and technical assistance for a National Domestic Violence Volunteer Attorney Network.<br/>Requires the Office on Violence Against Women of the Department of Justice to designate five states in which to implement the pilot program of a National Domestic Violence Volunteer Attorney Referral Project and distribute funds under this Act.<br/>Requires the Attorney General to award grants to national domestic violence legal technical assistance providers to expand their services to provide training and ongoing technical assistance to volunteer attorneys in the National Domestic Violence Volunteer Network, statewide legal coordinators, the National Domestic Violence Hotline, and Internet-based legal referral organizations.<br/>Authorizes the Attorney General to: (1) award grants to the National Domestic Violence Hotline to provide information about statewide legal coordinators and legal services; and (2) award grants to Internet-based non-profit organizations with a demonstrated expertise on domestic violence to provide state-specific information about statewide legal coordinators and legal services through the Internet. Directs the National Institute of Justice to study and report to Congress on the scope and quality of legal representation and advocacy for victims of domestic violence, dating violence, and stalking, including the provision of culturally and linguistically appropriate services.<br/>Directs the Attorney General to establish the Domestic Violence Legal Advisory Task Force.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
