<bill session="110" type="h" number="608" updated="2009-01-08T18:05:19-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1169442000" datetime="2007-01-22"/></status>

	<introduced date="1169442000" datetime="2007-01-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Digital Television Consumer Education Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To further inform consumers about the transition to digital television.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400018"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400279" joined="2007-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400414" joined="2007-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400330" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400419" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400342" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400388" joined="2007-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400132" joined="2007-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400373" joined="2007-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400039" joined="2007-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400169" joined="2007-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400400" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400056" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400319" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400139" joined="2007-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400032" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400150" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400088" joined="2007-02-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1169442000" datetime="2007-01-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1170392400" datetime="2007-02-02"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and the Internet.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/22/2007--Introduced.<br/>Digital Television Consumer Education Act of 2007 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to require through December 1, 2009: (1) retail distributors that sell or rent televisions with analog receivers, including distributors that sell by direct mail or electronic means, to prominently display a specified consumer alert respecting digital television transition information; (2) multichannel video programming distributors to include specified transition information in consumer bills; and (3) full-power commercial television broadcast licensees or permittees to report at least quarterly to the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) respecting transition education efforts to consumers. Authorizes the FCC to issue civil forfeitures for violations of such requirements. Requires the FCC to establish: (1) a digital television public outreach program, including FCC website information; and (2) the DTV Working Group to consult with state and local governments, providers of low-income assistance programs, educational institutions, community groups, and the National Telecommunications and Information Administration to promote consumer outreach regarding such transition and the converter-box program. Amends the Digital Television Transition and Public Safety Act of 2005 to require the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information to establish energy consumption standards applicable to digital-to-analog converter boxes in order for such boxes to qualify for certain coupon purchases. States that such standards shall be the exclusive energy consumption standards for converter boxes manufactured or imported for use in the United States on and after the effective date established by the Assistant Secretary and until January 1, 2010.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
