<bill session="110" type="h" number="6087" updated="2009-01-09T05:27:17-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1211256000" datetime="2008-05-20"/></status>

	<introduced date="1211256000" datetime="2008-05-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To sunset the Federal recognition and acknowledgment process within the Bureau of Indian Affairs of the Department of the Interior, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412011"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412252" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400400" joined="2008-06-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1211256000" datetime="2008-05-20"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/20/2008--Introduced.<br/>Bars an American Indian Group seeking federal tribal acknowledgment that does not submit a letter of intent to the Secretary of the Interior within 180 days after receiving notice under this Act from petitioning for or receiving status as a federally recognized Indian tribe through any administrative process.<br/>Requires the Secretary to publish in the Federal Register the need of any group to submit such a letter and to notify each group with a pending petition for federal tribal acknowledgment by first class mail. Directs the Secretary, when multiple petitions are submitted by groups claiming the same name, to inform each group that all such petitions shall receive no consideration and such petitions shall not be considered.<br/>Authorizes: (1) the Office of Federal Acknowledgment (OFA) to expedite a finding declining to acknowledge a group if it determines that the group clearly did not demonstrate in the application that it meets at least three of seven required criteria; and (2) a group that has an application denied to appeal to the Board of Indian Appeals.<br/>Sets deadlines for the submission of applications and for the consideration of petitions. Terminates the Federal Recognition and Acknowledgment Process by the earlier of three years after enactment of this Act or upon completion of all final decisions by OFA. Provides that no groups shall thereafter be acknowledged as federally recognized Indian tribes through an administrative process. 
	</summary>
</bill>
