<bill session="110" type="h" number="6100" updated="2009-01-09T05:28:45-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1211256000" datetime="2008-05-20"/></status>

	<introduced date="1211256000" datetime="2008-05-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Kid-Safe Chemicals Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Toxic Substances Control Act to reduce the exposure of children, workers, and consumers to toxic chemical substances.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400384"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2008-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-09-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400346" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2008-06-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2008-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="412232" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2008-09-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400366" joined="2008-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400062" joined="2008-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400425" joined="2008-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="2008-06-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1211256000" datetime="2008-05-20"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1211342400" datetime="2008-05-21"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/20/2008--Introduced.<br/>Kid-Safe Chemicals Act of 2008 - Amends the Toxic Substances Control Act to require each manufacturer of a chemical substance distributed in commerce to submit to the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA): (1) a statement certifying that the substance meets required safety standards or that there is insufficient data to make such determination; and (2) all reasonably available information concerning the substance not previously submitted. Requires manufacturers to update such information at least every three years or at any time new information becomes available on a substance's toxicity. Requires manufacturers to provide chemical safety information upon the Administrator's request.<br/>Prohibits the manufacture, importation, or distribution in commerce of a chemical substance if the Administrator determines that the manufacturer has failed to comply with this Act or that the substance does not meet applicable safety standards. Authorizes the Administrator to prohibit a specified use of a chemical substance in consumer products if the use of the product in the home results in human exposure that does not meet the safety standard.<br/>Requires the Administrator to: (1) publish a priority list that categorizes all chemical substances distributed in commerce; (2) develop a priority list for making safety determinations of at least 300 chemical substances; (3) determine whether a manufacturer has established that its priority-list substances meet applicable safety standards; (4) arrange for the Director of the National Center for Environmental Health at the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to conduct a biomonitoring study to determine the presence of a chemical substance in human cord blood if the Administrator determines that it may be present in human blood, fluids, or tissue; (5) implement animal testing alternatives; (6) create market incentives for the development of safer alternatives to existing chemical substances; (7) establish an Interagency Science Advisory Board on Children's Health and Toxic Substances; (8) cooperate with international efforts to monitor chemical substances; and (9) create a database to share information on the toxicity and use of, and exposure to, chemical substances and provide public access to such data.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
