<bill session="110" type="h" number="6119" updated="2009-01-09T05:30:59-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1211342400" datetime="2008-05-21"/></status>

	<introduced date="1211342400" datetime="2008-05-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend part B of title XVIII of the Social Security Act to make a technical correction to ensure that all physicians, as defined for purposes of the Medicare Program, are permitted to perform required face-to-face examinations and prescribe Medicare covered durable medical equipment, prosthetics, orthotics, and supplies.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400345"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400415" joined="2008-05-21"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1211342400" datetime="2008-05-21"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1211342400" datetime="2008-05-21"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1211342400" datetime="2008-05-21"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1212465600" datetime="2008-06-03"><committee name="House Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/21/2008--Introduced.<br/>Amends part B (Supplemental Medical Insurance) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to ensure that all physicians, as defined for Medicare purposes (including doctors of dental surgery or of dental medicine, of podiatric medicine, or of optometry, and chiropractors), are permitted to perform required face-to-face examinations and prescribe Medicare-covered durable medical equipment (DME), prosthetics, orthotics, and supplies (including motorized or power wheelchairs).<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
