<bill session="110" type="h" number="6125" updated="2009-01-09T05:31:40-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"/></status>

	<introduced date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide a mechanism for the construction of petroleum refineries on military installations to provide a reliable source of petroleum products for use by the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400052"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400385" joined="2008-08-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1214193600" datetime="2008-06-23"><committee name="House Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/22/2008--Introduced.<br/>Authorizes the President to authorize the design and construction of a petroleum refinery for each of the Army, Navy, Air Force, and Marine Corps that will be located on a military installation and reserved for the exclusive purpose of manufacturing petroleum products designated for consumption by units and elements of that branch of the Armed Forces.<br/>Directs the President to solicit proposals for the design and construction of a refinery under this Act. Amends the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 to repeal the reduced lifecycle greenhouse gas emissions requirement relating to federal agency procurement and acquisition of alternative fuels. 
	</summary>
</bill>
