<bill session="110" type="h" number="6130" updated="2009-01-09T05:32:15-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"/></status>

	<introduced date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for a study of the effects of speculation in the futures markets for natural gas, crude oil, and gasoline on cash market and retail prices for the commodities and on the choice of trading venue, and to require the Commodity Futures Trading Commission to issue a notice of proposed rulemaking regarding comparability of foreign regulation of futures and derivatives trading.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400018"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400414" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400099" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400330" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400342" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400313" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400388" joined="2008-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400196" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400261" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400052" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400288" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400642" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400235" joined="2008-06-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400144" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400206" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400039" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412216" joined="2008-06-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400400" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400368" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400404" joined="2008-06-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400056" joined="2008-06-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400319" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400431" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400046" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400654" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400321" joined="2008-06-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/22/2008--Introduced.<br/>Requires the Federal Trade Commission (FTC), the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, and the Energy Information Agency to conduct a joint study and report to specified congressional committees on the effects of speculation in the domestic and foreign futures markets for natural gas, crude oil, and gasoline on cash market and retail prices for the commodities. Requires the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC) to: (1) issue a notice of proposed rulemaking regarding how the CFTC determines whether regulation of futures contracts and derivatives by a foreign country is comparable to regulation of such under the Commodity Exchange Act; (2) evaluate any comments submitted; and (3) determine whether the CFTC should issue a proposed rule regarding the matter.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
