<bill session="110" type="h" number="6155" updated="2009-01-09T05:35:04-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"/></status>

	<introduced date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Renewable Investment and Consumer Protection Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish and fund a Clean Energy Fund, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400253"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, Science and Technology, and Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text></action>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1211515200" datetime="2008-05-23"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1088-1089)</text></action>
		<action date="1212465600" datetime="2008-06-03"><committee name="House Science and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/22/2008--Introduced.<br/>Renewable Investment and Consumer Protection Act - Establishes in the Treasury a Clean Energy Fund, to which shall be appropriated an amount equivalent to the increase in revenues resulting from a tax imposed on each repurchase of outstanding shares of stock by a major integrated oil company pursuant to a stock buyback program.<br/>Appropriates amounts in the fund as follows: (1) 60% to offset the cost of subsequent legislation to accelerate the use of clean domestic renewable energy resources and alternative fuels, promote energy efficiency and conservation, and increase research, development, and deployment of clean renewable energy and energy efficiency technologies; and (2) 40% for carrying out the Low-Income Home Energy Assistance program.<br/>Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose the oil company stock repurchase transaction tax.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
