<bill session="110" type="h" number="6151" updated="2009-01-09T05:34:38-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"/></status>

	<introduced date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Responsibility in Drug and Device Advertising Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act with respect to drug and device advertising, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400103"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2008-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400073" joined="2008-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400630" joined="2008-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400121" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400259" joined="2008-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2008-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400111" joined="2008-06-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400100" joined="2008-06-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/22/2008--Introduced.<br/>Responsibility in Drug and Device Advertising Act of 2008 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to prohibit direct-to-consumer advertising in the first three years after approval of a new drug or device. Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) waive such prohibition if such advertising would have an affirmative value to public health; and (2) continue such prohibition in subsequent years if the drug or device has significant adverse health effects.<br/>Requires any direct-to-consumer advertisement to include a fair balance of the benefits and risks associated with the drug or device.<br/>Deems a drug to be misbranded if a direct-to-consumer television advertisement for such drug does not prominently display a statement encouraging individuals to report negative side effects of prescription drugs to the Food and Drug Administration (FDA). Requires the Secretary to discontinue the study designed to determine if such a statement is appropriate for television advertisements.<br/>Deems a device to be misbranded if a direct-to-consumer television advertisement for such device does not include a statement encouraging individuals to report negative side effects of medical devices to the FDA.<br/>Sets forth civil monetary penalties for violations relating to the advertising and promotion of a drug or device. Allows the Secretary to order the distribution of materials to notify the public and the medical community of such a violation and to provide corrective information.<br/>Requires the Secretary to conduct an education campaign to increase public awareness of risks that, for some patients, may outweigh the benefits of using a particular drug or device.<br/>Authorizes additional appropriations to regulate direct-to-consumer drug and device advertisements.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
