<bill session="110" type="h" number="6152" updated="2009-01-09T05:34:44-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"/></status>

	<introduced date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Family Relief and Economic Stimulus Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To stimulate the economy of the United States and provide financial relief to low-income families in the United States.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400123"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400147" joined="2008-05-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Referred to House Financial Services</text></action>
		<action date="1212379200" datetime="2008-06-02"><committee name="House Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Income Security and Family Support.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/22/2008--Introduced.<br/>Family Relief and Economic Stimulus Act - Allows federal-state agreements for payment of emergency unemployment compensation to individuals who have exhausted their rights to such compensation.<br/>Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) allow individuals who are facing foreclosure to make penalty-free withdrawals from tax-exempt retirement plans; (2) extend through 2008 the tax deduction for dividends received from controlled foreign corporations; (3) suspend the excise tax on gasoline, diesel fuel, and kerosene for a specified period in 2008; and (4) adjust the basis of certain capital assets for inflation for purposes of determining gain or loss for income tax purposes. Provides additional funding to state and local governments for the redevelopment of abandoned and foreclosed upon residences and for the weatherization of homes of low-income families.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
