<bill session="110" type="h" number="6163" updated="2009-01-09T05:36:01-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"/></status>

	<introduced date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Telehealth Enhancement Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the provision of telehealth services under the Medicare Program, to provide grants for the development of telehealth networks, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400403"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400123" joined="2008-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400620" joined="2008-09-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2008-07-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400124" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400030" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400663" joined="2008-09-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400400" joined="2008-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2008-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412239" joined="2008-06-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400326" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400391" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412219" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400190" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412255" joined="2008-07-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1212379200" datetime="2008-06-02"><committee name="House Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/22/2008--Introduced.<br/>Medicare Telehealth Enhancement Act of 2008 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act regarding telehealth services (furnished via a telecommunication system by a physician to an enrolled individual). Removes current geographic restrictions on the provision of such services. Adds to the types of facilities authorized to participate in the telehealth program. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to encourage and facilitate the adoption of state reciprocity agreements for practitioner licensure in order to expedite the provision of telehealth services across state lines. Directs the Secretary to include as a home health visit for Medicare purposes telehealth services furnished an individual by a home health agency. Provides for coverage of remote patient management services, including home health remote patient management services, for certain chronic health conditions. Directs the Secretary to establish a demonstration project to evaluate the impact and benefits of covering remote patient management services for certain chronic health conditions. Directs the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Office for the Advancement of Telehealth (of the Health Resources and Services Administration), to make grants to expand access via telehealth to health care services for individuals in medically underserved rural, frontier, and urban areas. Amends the Public Health Service Act to reauthorize telehealth network and telehealth resource centers grant programs.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
