<bill session="110" type="h" number="6165" updated="2009-01-09T05:36:15-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"/></status>

	<introduced date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">End the Pain at the Pump Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Deep Ocean Energy Resources Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Energy Natural Resources Enhancement Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Refinery Permit Process Schedule Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Rigs to Reefs Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to assist individuals confronting high gasoline and diesel fuel costs in commuting to work by allowing a refundable credit against income tax based on the business standard mileage rate for commuting miles, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400431"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400219" joined="2008-06-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Natural Resources, Oversight and Government Reform, Armed Services, and Science and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text></action>
		<action date="1212465600" datetime="2008-06-03"><committee name="House Science and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text></action>
		<action date="1212638400" datetime="2008-06-05"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1214193600" datetime="2008-06-23"><committee name="House Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/22/2008--Introduced.<br/>End the Pain at the Pump Act of 2008 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) allow an excise tax credit between June 1, 2008, and May 30, 2011, for individuals commuting to work in a vehicle fueled primarily by gasoline or diesel fuel; (2) treat the income of partners performing investment management services as ordinary income and set forth tax rules for the treatment of partnership acquisition indebtedness and other partnership interests; and (3) require the inclusion in gross income for income tax purposes of employee compensation deferred under a nonqualified deferred compensation plan of a nonqualified entity when there is no substantial risk of forfeiture of the rights to such compensation.<br/>Refinery Permit Process Schedule Act - Authorizes the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), upon request of a state governor, to provide financial assistance to hire additional personnel with expertise in federal refinery authorizations.<br/>Directs the President to: (1) appoint a federal coordinator to implement federal refinery authorizations; and (2) designate certain closed military installations as potentially suitable refinery construction sites.<br/>Directs the Secretary of the Interior to establish and implement a competitive oil and gas leasing program in the Coastal Plain of Alaska.<br/>Repeals the prohibition against producing oil and gas from the Arctic National Wildlife Refuge.<br/>Sets forth requirements for the sale of oil and natural gas leases in the Coastal Plain, environmental protection, and transportation easements. Establishes the Coastal Plain Local Government Impact Aid Assistance Fund to provide financial assistance to specified jurisdictions in Alaska.<br/>Deep Ocean Energy Resources Act of 2008 - Amends the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (OCSLA) to revise the outer Continental Shelf leasing program.<br/>Federal Energy Natural Resources Enhancement Act of 2008 - Authorizes appropriations for a natural resources enhancement program for the management of fish, wildlife, and natural resources.<br/>Terminates existing federal laws prohibiting the spending of appropriated funds to conduct oil and natural gas leasing or the issuance of a lease to any individual for any area of the outer Continental Shelf.<br/>Rigs to Reefs Act of 2008 - Amends the OCSLA to authorize the Secretary to use decommissioned offshore oil and gas platforms for artificial reef and scientific research.<br/>Allows the cancellation and exchange of certain oil and gas leases within 100 miles of the coastline within the California or Florida Adjacent Zones.<br/>Repeals: (1) the requirement to conduct a comprehensive inventory of outer Continental Shelf oil and natural gas resources; (2) the coastal impact assistance program; and (3) the Oil Shale, Tar Sands, and Other Strategic Unconventional Fuels Act of 2005.<br/>Amends the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 to repeal emission requirements with respect to the procurement and acquisition of alternative fuels.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
