<bill session="110" type="h" number="617" updated="2009-01-08T18:06:20-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1169442000" datetime="2007-01-22"/></status>

	<introduced date="1169442000" datetime="2007-01-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Restoring the Everglades, an American Legacy Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize ecosystem restoration projects for the Indian River Lagoon-South and the Picayune Strand, Collier County, in the State of Florida.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400170"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400623" joined="2007-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400430" joined="2007-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412195" joined="2007-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412197" joined="2007-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412198" joined="2007-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400048" joined="2007-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400044" joined="2007-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400270" joined="2007-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400107" joined="2007-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400108" joined="2007-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400622" joined="2007-02-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1169442000" datetime="2007-01-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text></action>
		<action date="1169528400" datetime="2007-01-23"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/22/2007--Introduced.<br/>Restoring the Everglades, an American Legacy Act of 2007 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Army to carry out the project for ecosystem restoration, water supply, flood control, and protection of water quality, Indian River Lagoon, South Florida, at a specified total cost, in accordance with the recommendations of the report of the Chief of Engineers, dated August 6, 2004. Deauthorizes certain projects authorized under the Water Resources Development Act of 2000 and the Flood Control Act of 1968. Authorizes the Secretary of the Army to carry out the project for ecosystem restoration, Picayune Strand, Collier County, Florida, at a specified total cost in accordance with section 601 of Water Resources Development Act of 2000 (relating to the Comprehensive Everglades Restoration Plan) and the report of the Chief of Engineers, September 15, 2006. 
	</summary>
</bill>
