<bill session="110" type="h" number="6171" updated="2009-01-09T05:36:55-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1212465600" datetime="2008-06-03"/></status>

	<introduced date="1212465600" datetime="2008-06-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Capital Region Leadership in Environmental and Energy Stewardship Commission Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the establishment of a commission and a national competition to significantly improve the energy efficiency of and reduce emissions from Federal buildings in the National Capital Region.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400617"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400618" joined="2008-06-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400063" joined="2008-06-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2008-06-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1212465600" datetime="2008-06-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/3/2008--Introduced.<br/>National Capital Region Leadership in Environmental and Energy Stewardship Commission Act - Establishes the National Capital Region Leadership in Environmental and Energy Stewardship Commission, requiring it to: (1) analyze the overall facility environmental and energy footprint and impact of the federal government in the National Capital Region; (2) hold a nationwide competition for a cash prize to find innovative solutions to significantly eliminate such emissions and reduce dependence on the national power grid by making local combustion facilities climate neutral or implementing other technologies to achieve the same goals; (3) analyze existing and upcoming technologies which the government can implement to eliminate facility pollution and reduce dependence on the national power grid; and (4) recommend appropriate ways for the government to significantly eliminate facility pollution emissions, including greenhouse gases, and reduce its dependence on the national electrical grid.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
