<bill session="110" type="h" number="6177" updated="2009-01-09T05:37:36-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1216785600" datetime="2008-07-23" /></status>

	<introduced date="1212552000" datetime="2008-06-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Rio Grande Wild and Scenic River Extension Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Rio Grande Wild and Scenic River Extension Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to modify the boundary of the Rio Grande Wild and Scenic River.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400339"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1212552000" datetime="2008-06-04"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1213070400" datetime="2008-06-10"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action date="1215662400" datetime="2008-07-10"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1216785600" datetime="2008-07-23"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1216785600" datetime="2008-07-23" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1216785600" datetime="2008-07-23"><text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands Discharged.</text></action>
		<action date="1221191820" datetime="2008-09-11T12:57:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-838.</text></action>
		<calendar number="538" date="1221191820" datetime="2008-09-11T12:57:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 538.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/11/2008--Reported to House amended. Rio Grande Wild and Scenic River Extension Act of 2008 - Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to modify the boundary of the Rio Grande Wild and Scenic River. Prohibits anything in this Act from: (1) being construed to conflict with specified treaties between the United States and Mexico; and (2) preventing or obstructing the planning, construction, operation, or maintenance of a border fence in the area or affecting the operations or duties in such area of the Department of Homeland Security, including the Border Patrol, or of state or local law enforcement agencies. 
	</summary>
</bill>
