<bill session="110" type="h" number="6249" updated="2009-01-09T05:46:01-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1213243200" datetime="2008-06-12"/></status>

	<introduced date="1213243200" datetime="2008-06-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">H-HOMERUN Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Helping Home Owners Make Energy-Efficiency Residential Upgrades Now Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a direct loan program for providing energy efficiency improvements for single family housing, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400642"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1213243200" datetime="2008-06-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/12/2008--Introduced.<br/>Helping Home Owners Make Energy-Efficiency Residential Upgrades Now Act of 2008 or the H-HOMERUN Act of 2008 - Requires the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to establish a program to make direct loans for energy efficiency improvements for single family housing. Sets forth loan requirements.<br/>Directs the Secretary to require that the total present value cost of such improvement is less than the total present value of the energy saved over the useful life of the improvement. Requires such cost and savings to be determined pursuant to a home energy rating report based upon a physical inspection of the property by a home energy rating system, or energy consultant, approved by the Secretary. Requires the aggregate outstanding principal balance of direct loans to not at any time exceed $100 billion.<br/>Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 to prohibit the Secretary from establishing a maximum limitation on the cost of the cost-effective energy efficiency improvements to be financed by an energy efficient mortgage provided under the Energy Efficient Mortgages Program. Requires a mortgagor to pay on account of the cost-effective energy efficiency improvements for which the mortgage is made at least 5% of the Secretary's estimate of the cost of acquisition and/or installation.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
