<bill session="110" type="h" number="6283" updated="2009-01-09T05:50:05-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1213675200" datetime="2008-06-17"/></status>

	<introduced date="1213675200" datetime="2008-06-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Reimbursing Our American Drivers (ROAD) Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To increase the standard mileage rate for use of an automobile for business, medical, and moving deduction purposes for 2008 and permanently increase such rate for charitable deduction purposes under the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and to temporarily increase the reimbursement rate for use of an automobile by Federal employees.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400240"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2008-07-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400311" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400111" joined="2008-07-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400043" joined="2008-09-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="2008-07-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1213675200" datetime="2008-06-17"><text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1213675200" datetime="2008-06-17"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1213675200" datetime="2008-06-17"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/17/2008--Introduced.<br/>Reimbursing Our American Drivers (ROAD) Act of 2008 - Increases to 70 cents per mile, for the period after December 31, 2007, and before January 1, 2009: (1) the standard mileage rate for calculating the tax deduction for business, medical, and moving use of an automobile; and (2) the standard mileage rate for reimbursement of federal employee automobile expenses. Increases from 14 to 40 cents per mile the standard mileage rate for purposes of computing the tax deduction for the use of a passenger automobile for charitable purposes.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
