<bill session="110" type="h" number="6297" updated="2009-01-09T05:51:40-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1213761600" datetime="2008-06-18"/></status>

	<introduced date="1213761600" datetime="2008-06-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Climate Change Drinking Water Adaptation Research Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance the ability of drinking water utilities in the United States to develop and implement climate change adaptation programs and policies, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400101"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400290" joined="2008-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400663" joined="2008-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2008-09-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400024" joined="2008-07-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1213761600" datetime="2008-06-18"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Science and Technology.</text></action>
		<action date="1216008000" datetime="2008-07-14"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/18/2008--Introduced.<br/>Climate Change Drinking Water Adaptation Research Act - Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish and provide funding for a program of directed and applied research, to be conducted through a nonprofit water research foundation and sponsored by drinking water utilities, to assist suppliers of drinking water in adapting to the effects of climate change.<br/>Requires research areas to include: (1) water quality and quantity impacts and solutions; (2) impacts on groundwater supplies from carbon sequestration; (3) infrastructure impacts and solutions; (4) desalination, water reuse, and alternative supply technologies; (5) energy efficiency and greenhouse gas minimization; (6) regional and hydrological basin cooperative water management solutions; (7) utilities management, decision support systems, and water management models; (8) greenhouse gas emissions reduction and energy demand management; (9) water conservation and demand management; and (10) communications, education, and public acceptance.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
