<bill session="110" type="h" number="6300" updated="2009-01-09T05:52:00-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1213761600" datetime="2008-06-18"/></status>

	<introduced date="1213761600" datetime="2008-06-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Dona Ana County Planned Growth, Open Space, and Rangeland Preservation Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish special preservation areas and rangeland preservation areas in Dona Ana County, New Mexico, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400313"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1213761600" datetime="2008-06-18"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/18/2008--Introduced.<br/>Dona Ana County Planned Growth, Open Space, and Rangeland Preservation Act of 2008 - Designates special preservation and rangeland preservation areas in Dona Ana County, New Mexico, and directs the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Land Management, to manage such areas to promote conservation of grazing land, wildlife habitats, and open spaces. Allows the Secretary to acquire non-federal land in such areas from a state, local government, or non-profit organization through purchase, exchange, or donation. Requires the Secretary to develop a comprehensive plan for the long-range protection and management of rangeland preservation areas.<br/>Authorizes an exchange of land between the United States and New Mexico State University.<br/>Requires the Secretary to: (1) conduct a sale of specified federal lands in Dona Ana County; and (2) use the proceeds of such sale for certain purposes, including payments to the County and for the acquisition of environmentally sensitive land, the development of parks, trails, and natural areas, and for rangeleand improvements.<br/>Establishes the Dona Ana County Land Disposal Advisory Board to advise the Secretary on the disposal of federal lands.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
