<bill session="110" type="h" number="6311" updated="2009-01-09T05:53:15-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1213848000" datetime="2008-06-19"/></status>

	<introduced date="1213848000" datetime="2008-06-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Nonnative Wildlife Invasion Prevention Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To prevent the introduction and establishment of nonnative wildlife species that negatively impact the economy, environment, or human or animal species' health, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400041"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400290" joined="2008-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="2008-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400216" joined="2008-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="412198" joined="2008-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400001" joined="2008-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400259" joined="2008-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400218" joined="2008-06-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1213848000" datetime="2008-06-19"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1288-1289)</text></action>
		<action date="1213848000" datetime="2008-06-19"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1214193600" datetime="2008-06-23"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, and Oceans.</text></action>
		<action date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/19/2008--Introduced.<br/>Nonnative Wildlife Invasion Prevention Act - Requires the Secretary of the Interior to promulgate regulations establishing a process for assessing the risk of all nonnative wildlife species proposed for importation into the United States, other than those included in a list of approved species issued under this Act. Sets forth factors that must be considered at minimum, including the identity of the organism to the species level, the geographic source, and the likelihood of spread and harm to groups of species or habitats.<br/>Provides procedures for issuance and expansion of the approved-for-importation list.<br/>Establishes prohibitions on: (1) importation of nonnative species or viable eggs; (2) permit violation; and (3) knowing possession, purchase, sale, barter, release, or breeding (including of prohibited species previously imported legally).<br/>Allows the imposition of fees to recover the costs of assessing risks of nonnative wildlife species. Establishes a Nonnative Wildlife Invasion Prevention Fund into which such fees will be deposited.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
