<bill session="110" type="h" number="6322" updated="2009-01-09T05:54:30-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1216180800" datetime="2008-07-16" /></status>

	<introduced date="1213848000" datetime="2008-06-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Public Charter Schools Home Rule Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Public Charter Schools Home Rule Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the District of Columbia School Reform Act of 1995 to permit the District of Columbia government to exercise authority over the Public Charter School Board in the same manner as the District government may exercise authority over other entities of the District government.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400295"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1213848000" datetime="2008-06-19"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1284)</text></action>
		<action date="1213848000" datetime="2008-06-19"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text></action>
		<action date="1216008000" datetime="2008-07-14"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia.</text></action>
		<action date="1216094400" datetime="2008-07-15"><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1216094400" datetime="2008-07-15"><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee .</text></action>
		<action date="1216180800" datetime="2008-07-16"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1216180800" datetime="2008-07-16" ><text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1217255760" datetime="2008-07-28T11:36:00-04:00"><text>Reported by the Committee on Oversight and Government. H. Rept. 110-782.</text></action>
		<calendar number="501" date="1217255760" datetime="2008-07-28T11:36:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 501.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1220979120" datetime="2008-09-09T13:52:00-04:00"><text>FILING AUTHORITY - Mr. Davis (IL) asked unanimous consent that the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform be permitted to file a supplemental report on H.R. 6322. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action date="1220980140" datetime="2008-09-09T14:09:00-04:00"><text>Supplemental report filed by the Committee on Oversight and Government, H. Rept. 110-782, Part II.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/28/2008--Reported to House without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Public Charter Schools Home Rule Act of 2008 - Amends the District of Columbia School Reform Act of 1995 to grant authority to the District of Columbia government to regulate the Public Charter School Board with respect to its membership and the process by which Board members are appointed. Allows the current process to remain in effect until the District enacts a law that establishes such membership and process. Repeals: (1) certain requirements for annual reporting to the federal government by eligible chartering authorities and the State Education Office; and (2) the requirement that the District's Board of Education provide the federal government with access to its fiscal and staffing data.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
