<bill session="110" type="h" number="6345" updated="2009-01-09T05:57:20-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1214193600" datetime="2008-06-23"/></status>

	<introduced date="1214193600" datetime="2008-06-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Patient-Controlled Health IT Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a demonstration program to provide financial incentives to encourage the adoption and use of interactive personal health records and to encourage health information exchange networks to link clinical data to such personal health records.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400636"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1214193600" datetime="2008-06-23"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1214193600" datetime="2008-06-23"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1214193600" datetime="2008-06-23"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1214798400" datetime="2008-06-30"><committee name="House Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/23/2008--Introduced.<br/>Patient-Controlled Health IT Act - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a demonstration program to provide financial incentives to providers and health information exchange networks for the use of qualifying personal health records (QPHRs). Requires the Secretary to provide for activities to educate qualifying providers about the patient, provider, and overall health care benefits of using QPHRs and participating in electronic health information exchange networks.<br/>Requires access to the record to be controlled solely by the patient. Authorizes the patient to add personal health information to the record, but not alter information entered by any qualifying provider.<br/>Limits access to the record to only: (1) a health care provider who is authorized by the patient to access the record; and (2) the minimum data set specified by the patient.<br/>Deems the patient to have provided authorization for health care providers to access a limited information set concerning the patient for emergency response purposes, unless the patient specifies that such information may not be so accessed.<br/>Provides for: (1) the use of de-identified data for public health analysis, postmarket safety surveillance of prescription drugs, and research purposes; and (2) a messaging system to send messages to patients, including education messages, reminders, and messages concerning health care or benefits from federal agencies.<br/>Sets forth security and privacy standards, policies, and practices for the demonstration program.<br/>Requires the Secretary to establish a PHR Incentive Fund to receive contributions from Fund partners, such as health care payers, drug and device manufacturers, and government agencies, including the Medicare program.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
