<bill session="110" type="h" number="6351" updated="2009-01-09T05:58:15-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1214193600" datetime="2008-06-23"/></status>

	<introduced date="1214193600" datetime="2008-06-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">21st Century Rural Health Care Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to reauthorize the National Health Service Corps Program, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412229"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412262" joined="2008-06-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1214193600" datetime="2008-06-23"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1214193600" datetime="2008-06-23"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1214193600" datetime="2008-06-23"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1214798400" datetime="2008-06-30"><committee name="House Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/23/2008--Introduced.<br/>21st Century Rural Health Care Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to reauthorize appropriations for the National Health Service Corps for FY2009-FY2013.<br/>Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to define &quot;accredited training program with an integrated rural track&quot; to mean an accredited medical residency training program that is located in an urban area which offers a curriculum for family practice for all residents in the program and that meets certain requirements, including: (1) four month-long rotations in rural public health and community health settings; and (2) specified minimum training in obstetrics, pediatrics, and emergency medicine.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
