<bill session="110" type="h" number="6364" updated="2009-01-09T05:59:48-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1214366400" datetime="2008-06-25"/></status>

	<introduced date="1214366400" datetime="2008-06-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Puget Sound Recovery Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to provide assistance for programs and activities to protect the water quality of Puget Sound, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400109"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400660" joined="2008-06-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400379" joined="2008-06-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="2008-06-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400232" joined="2008-06-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400193" joined="2008-06-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400011" joined="2008-06-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1214366400" datetime="2008-06-25"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1348-1349)</text></action>
		<action date="1214366400" datetime="2008-06-25"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text></action>
		<action date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/25/2008--Introduced.<br/>Puget Sound Recovery Act of 2008 - Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) to direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish a Puget Sound Program Office, to be located in the state of Washington and headed by a Director who shall assist the management conference convened for Puget Sound in carrying out its goals.<br/>Requires the Director to: (1) assist and support the implementation of the comprehensive conservation and management plan developed by the conference (&quot;Comprehensive Plan&quot;); (2) coordinate the major functions of the federal government related to the implementation of the Comprehensive Plan; (3) carry out studies and research necessary for strengthened implementation of the Comprehensive Plan; (4) coordinate and manage environmental data related to Puget Sound; (5) coordinate the grant, research, and planning programs authorized under this Act; (6) coordinate activities for the protection of Puget Sound and the Georgia Straits with Canadian authorities and responsibilities, including under species recovery plans, through cooperation with other federal agencies that have jurisdiction in the Puget Sound watershed; and (7) collect and make available to the public information relating to the environmental quality of Puget Sound.<br/>Requires a biennial report to Congress on the implementation of the Comprehensive Plan.<br/>Allows the Administrator to make grants for projects and studies that will help implement the Comprehensive Plan and for projects to address sewage and stormwater discharges into the Puget Sound watershed.<br/>Requires the President, as part of the annual budget, to submit information regarding expenditures and roles of each federal agency involved in Puget Sound protection and restoration.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
