<bill session="110" type="h" number="6375" updated="2009-01-09T06:01:05-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1214366400" datetime="2008-06-25"/></status>

	<introduced date="1214366400" datetime="2008-06-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Healthy Transition Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide assistance to adolescents and young adults with serious mental health disorders as they transition to adulthood.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400387"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400058" joined="2008-07-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400065" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400268" joined="2008-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400254" joined="2008-07-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="2008-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400384" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="2008-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400245" joined="2008-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400082" joined="2008-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400039" joined="2008-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2008-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400013" joined="2008-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2008-09-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400218" joined="2008-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400025" joined="2008-09-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400425" joined="2008-07-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400309" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="2008-06-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1214366400" datetime="2008-06-25"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1353-1354)</text></action>
		<action date="1214366400" datetime="2008-06-25"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/25/2008--Introduced.<br/>Healthy Transition Act of 2008 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to award grants or cooperative agreements to states: (1) to develop plans for the statewide coordination of services to assist adolescents and young adults with a serious mental health disorder in acquiring the skills, knowledge, and resources necessary to ensure their healthy transition to successful adult roles and responsibilities; and (2) for the coordination of such services.<br/>Requires the Secretary to designate a federal entity, or establish a Committee of Federal Partners, to coordinate programs providing such services. Directs such entity or committee to: (1) review how federal programs and efforts that address issues related to the transition of adolescents and young adults with serious mental health disorders may be coordinated to ensure the maximum benefit for the individuals being served; and (2) provide technical assistance to the states who are planning or implementing programs under this Act.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
