<bill session="110" type="h" number="6383" updated="2009-01-09T06:02:05-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"/></status>

	<introduced date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Alternative Energy Advancement Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To make available for research and development of alternative energy certain revenue received by the United States for all future oil and gas leases.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400172"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"><text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Science and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"><text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text></action>
		<action date="1214884800" datetime="2008-07-01"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1216008000" datetime="2008-07-14"><committee name="House Science and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/26/2008--Introduced.<br/>Alternative Energy Advancement Act - Establishes in the Treasury a Trust Fund for deposit of all amounts received by the United States as bonus bids, rents, royalties under leases for exploration, development, and production of oil and gas awarded after enactment of this Act for any area of federal lands or of federal submerged lands of the outer Continental Shelf that, on the enactment of this Act, are withdrawn from such leasing or for which the expenditure of federal funds for such leasing is prohibited.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
