<bill session="110" type="h" number="6393" updated="2009-01-09T06:03:22-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"/></status>

	<introduced date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Quit Smoking for Life Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend titles V, XVIII, and XIX of the Social Security Act to promote tobacco use cessation under the Medicare Program, the Medicaid Program, and the maternal and child health program.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400101"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400166" joined="2008-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400321" joined="2008-06-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1215576000" datetime="2008-07-09"><committee name="House Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/26/2008--Introduced.<br/>Quit Smoking for Life Act of 2008 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to cover diagnostic, therapy, and counseling services, furnished by or under a physician's supervision, for cessation of tobacco use. Provides for payment of 80% of the lesser of the actual charge or the fee schedule amount. Eliminates the deductible. Includes tobacco cessation agents as covered drugs under Medicare part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program).<br/>Amends SSA titles V (Maternal and Child Health Services) and XIX (Medicaid) also to cover counseling and medication for cessation of tobacco use. Requires inclusion of anti-tobacco messages in health promotion counseling as part of quality maternal and child health services.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
