<bill session="110" type="h" number="6406" updated="2009-01-09T06:04:52-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1222288740" datetime="2008-09-24T17:39:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To elevate the Inspector General of the Commodity Futures Trading Commission to an Inspector General appointed pursuant to section 3 of the Inspector General Act of 1978.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400233"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412219" joined="2008-07-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text></action>
		<action date="1217217600" datetime="2008-07-28"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Organization, and Procurement.</text></action>
		<action date="1222287960" datetime="2008-09-24T17:26:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Towns moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1222288020" datetime="2008-09-24T17:27:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H9321-9323"/></action>
		<action date="1222288020" datetime="2008-09-24T17:27:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 6406.</text></action>
		<vote date="1222288740" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-09-24T17:39:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H9321-9322"/></vote>
		<action date="1222315200" datetime="2008-09-25"><text>Received in the Senate.</text></action>
		<action date="1222920000" datetime="2008-10-02"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/26/2008--Introduced.<br/>Amends the Inspector General Act of 1878 to require presidential appointment of the Inspector General of the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC), by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, without regard to political affiliation and solely on the basis of integrity and demonstrated ability in accounting, auditing, financial analysis, law, management analysis, public administration, or investigations. 
	</summary>
</bill>
