<bill session="110" type="h" number="6410" updated="2009-01-09T06:05:20-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"/></status>

	<introduced date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Legislative Automatic Spending Hikes (SLASH) Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the elimination of agencies and programs which receive ineffective ratings or three consecutive adequate ratings under the Government Performance and Results Act of 1993 and to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to rebate the savings from such eliminations to the taxpayers.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400260"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400659" joined="2008-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400311" joined="2008-07-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"><text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1217217600" datetime="2008-07-28"><committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Organization, and Procurement.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/26/2008--Introduced.<br/>Stop Legislative Automatic Spending Hikes (SLASH) Act of 2008 - Requires: (1) the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to report to Congress on all agencies and programs that received ineffective ratings or three consecutive annual adequate ratings under the Government Performance and Results Act of 1993; (2) the termination of such agencies and programs unless continued by statute; (3) the transfer of the functions of such terminated agencies and programs to other appropriate agencies; and (4) an annual OMB estimate of the savings under this Act.<br/>Amends the Internal Revenue Code to grant tax rebates to individual taxpayers from the amounts saved by the termination of ineffective agencies and programs under this Act.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
