<bill session="110" type="h" number="6415" updated="2009-01-09T06:05:54-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"/></status>

	<introduced date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide that goods that are manufactured in a foreign trade zone and comply with the rules of origin under a trade agreement to which the United States is a party may enter the customs territory of the United States at the rate of duty applicable under that agreement.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400309"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400092" joined="2008-07-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400087" joined="2008-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400649" joined="2008-09-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action date="1215576000" datetime="2008-07-09"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/26/2008--Introduced.<br/>Amends the Foreign Trade Zones Act to provide that goods that are manufactured in a foreign trade zone and comply with the rules of origin under a trade agreement to which the United States is a party may enter the U.S. customs territory at the rate of duty applicable under such agreement. Amends the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) Implementation Act to repeal certain rules of origin requirements with respect to goods made of nonoriginating material that are produced in a foreign-trade zone or subzone that enter a U.S. customs territory. Adds a rule with respect to goods produced entirely in the territory of one or more NAFTA countries, but where any nonoriginating materials, provided for as parts and used in a good's production, do not undergo a change in tariff classification. Requires, in such an instance, that a good be treated as originating in a NAFTA country if: (1) the regional value-content of the good is at least 60% where the transaction value method is used, or at least 50% where the net cost method is used; and (2) the good satisfies all other applicable requirements.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
