<bill session="110" type="h" number="6416" updated="2009-01-09T06:06:01-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"/></status>

	<introduced date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Just and Lasting Peace in Sudan Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To codify existing sanctions against the Government of Sudan until the Government of Sudan meets certain conditions relating to a just and lasting peace in Sudan.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400312"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2008-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2008-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400333" joined="2008-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="2008-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400198" joined="2008-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400063" joined="2008-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400130" joined="2008-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400030" joined="2008-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400048" joined="2008-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2008-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400422" joined="2008-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400350" joined="2008-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400415" joined="2008-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400201" joined="2008-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400204" joined="2008-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400090" joined="2008-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400394" joined="2008-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400435" joined="2008-06-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/26/2008--Introduced.<br/>Just and Lasting Peace in Sudan Act of 2008 - Prohibits sanctions imposed against the government of Sudan from being lifted until the President certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that the following conditions have been met for at least one year: (1) the government of Sudan (government) implements the Comprehensive Peace Agreement and the Darfur Peace Agreement; (2) the Abyei Boundary Commission recommendations are implemented and oil revenue shares are paid retroactively; (3) the government hands over to the International Criminal Court (ICC) all indicted individuals; (4) the government ends its atrocities against innocent civilians in Darfur and other parts of Sudan; (5) the government allows the deployment of United Nations African Union Mission in Darfur forces and allows unhindered access to humanitarian workers; (6) the government ends its terrorist ties; and (7) senior government officials are held accountable for crimes committed in the Nuba, South Sudan, Southern Blue Nile, and Eastern Sudan, and for their support for Osama bin Laden and other terrorist groups. Expresses the sense of Congress that the U.S. government should not normalize relations with Sudan until such conditions have been implemented for at least one year.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
