<bill session="110" type="h" number="6429" updated="2009-01-09T06:07:50-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1215489600" datetime="2008-07-08"/></status>

	<introduced date="1215489600" datetime="2008-07-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Energy Emergency Relief Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a small business energy emergency disaster loan program.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400274"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400102" joined="2008-07-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="412220" joined="2008-07-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1215489600" datetime="2008-07-08"><text>Referred to the Committee on Small Business, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1215489600" datetime="2008-07-08"><text>Referred to House Small Business</text></action>
		<action date="1215489600" datetime="2008-07-08"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action date="1223006400" datetime="2008-10-03"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Specialty Crops, Rural Development, and Foreign Agriculture.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/8/2008--Introduced.<br/>Small Business Energy Emergency Relief Act of 2008 - Amends the Small Business Act to authorize the Small Business Administration to make disaster loans to assist small businesses that have suffered or are likely to suffer substantial economic injury as the result of a significant increase in the price of heating fuel occurring on or after October 1, 2007. Prohibits such loan from being made if the total amount outstanding and committed to the borrower would exceed $1.5 million, unless the borrower is a major source of employment in its surrounding area. Amends the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to authorize the Secretary of Agriculture to make loans to farm operations that qualify as a small business and that have or are likely to suffer substantial economic injury on or after October 1, 2007, as the result of a significant increase in energy costs in connection with an energy emergency declared by the President or the Secretary.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
