<bill session="110" type="h" number="6421" updated="2009-01-09T06:06:35-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"/></status>

	<introduced date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Energy Independence Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">American Energy Independence and Price Reduction Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Deep Ocean Energy Resources Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Energy Natural Resources Enhancement Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Rigs to Reefs Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to establish and implement a competitive oil and gas leasing program for the Coastal Plain of Alaska, to provide for expanded leasing of the oil and gas resources of the outer Continental Shelf for exploration, to eliminate certain impediments to the development of nuclear energy sources, to promote coal-to-liquid fuel activities, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="409888"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"><text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, Energy and Commerce, Science and Technology, Transportation and Infrastructure, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text></action>
		<action date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
		<action date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"><text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text></action>
		<action date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"><text>Referred to House Rules</text></action>
		<action date="1214539200" datetime="2008-06-27"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text></action>
		<action date="1214539200" datetime="2008-06-27"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
		<action date="1214539200" datetime="2008-06-27"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text></action>
		<action date="1214539200" datetime="2008-06-27"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text></action>
		<action date="1215662400" datetime="2008-07-10"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1216008000" datetime="2008-07-14"><committee name="House Science and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/26/2008--Introduced.<br/>Energy Independence Act - American Energy Independence and Price Reduction Act - Sets forth an oil and gas leasing program for lands within the Coastal Plain of Alaska. Establishes the Coastal Plain Local Government Impact Aid Assistance Fund, to provide financial assistance to entities directly impacted by oil and gas exploration and development, and the ANWR Alternative Energy Trust Fund. Deep Ocean Energy Resources Act of 2008 - Amends the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (OCSLA) regarding: (1) Adjacent Zones and Planning Areas in the outer Continental Shelf (OCS) subsoil and seabed; (2) oil and gas lease administration; and (3) lease grants. Federal Energy Natural Resources Enhancement Act of 2008- Establishes the Federal Energy Natural Resources Enhancement Program. Redesignates the Minerals Management Service as the National Ocean Resources and Royalty Service. Rigs to Reefs Act of 2008- Amends the OCSLA to prescribe requirements for the use of decommissioned offshore oil and gas platforms for artificial reefs. Prescribes conditions for authorizing leases for areas located within 100 miles of California or Florida.<br/>Repeals the coastal impact assistance program under OCSLA. Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to modify terms and conditions governing: (1) federal authority to enter into contracts with sponsors of certain advanced nuclear facilities; and (2) the Nuclear Power 2010 Program. Establishes the Interagency Working Group to promote increasing domestic manufacturing capacity and export of domestic nuclear energy products and services. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to establish: (1) a nuclear power manufacturing and facility construction credit; (2) a qualifying coal-to-liquid fuels project credit; (4) an election to expense certain coal-to-liquid fuels facilities; and (5) an extension of the alternative fuel credit for fuel derived from coal through the Fischer-Tropsch process or the Schobert process. Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to direct the Secretary of Labor to promulgate regulations for a workforce training program for workers skilled in the nuclear utility and nuclear energy products and services. Amends the Atomic Energy Act to modify licensing procedures for new nuclear power plants.<br/>Instructs the Secretary of Energy to establish a National Nuclear Energy Council.<br/>Prescribes procedures for: (1) such Secretary to initiate and implement temporary nuclear fuel storage agreements; and (2) expedited congressional review of temporary spent nuclear fuel storage agreements.<br/>Amends the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 to revise contracting procedures for certain civilian nuclear power reactors.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
