<bill session="110" type="h" number="6433" updated="2009-01-09T06:08:19-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1216180800" datetime="2008-07-16" /></status>

	<introduced date="1215489600" datetime="2008-07-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Animal Generic Drug User Fee Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Animal Generic Drug User Fee Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to establish a program of fees relating to generic new animal drugs.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400308"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400099" joined="2008-07-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400018" joined="2008-07-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="2008-07-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400101" joined="2008-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400110" joined="2008-07-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1215489600" datetime="2008-07-08"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1215489600" datetime="2008-07-08"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1215576000" datetime="2008-07-09"><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1215576000" datetime="2008-07-09"><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text></action>
		<action date="1216180800" datetime="2008-07-16"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1216180800" datetime="2008-07-16" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1217436540" datetime="2008-07-30T13:49:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 110-805.</text></action>
		<calendar number="521" date="1217436540" datetime="2008-07-30T13:49:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 521.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/30/2008--Reported to House amended. Animal Generic Drug User Fee Act of 2008 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to assess and collect fees for an abbreviated application for a generic new animal drug, including application fees, product fees, and sponsor fees.<br/>Sets forth total revenue to be collected for each type of fee for FY2009-FY2013.<br/>Provides for fee adjustments. Requires the Secretary to establish such fees each fiscal year.<br/>Provides for fee waivers where the Secretary finds that the generic new animal drug is intended solely to provide for a minor use or minor species indication.<br/>Authorizes appropriations for FY2009-FY2013.<br/>Requires the Secretary to report to Congress and make publicly available information on: (1) progress toward the goal of expediting the generic new animal drug development process and the review of abbreviated applications for such drugs; and (2) the implementation of the authority for and use of generic new animal drug fees.<br/>Sets forth the process for developing recommendations to present to Congress for the review of abbreviated applications for generic new animal drugs after FY2013.<br/>Terminates the authority to assess and use generic new animal drug fees on October 1, 2013. Terminates reporting requirements on January 31, 2014. 
	</summary>
</bill>
