<bill session="110" type="h" number="6450" updated="2009-01-09T06:10:18-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1215576000" datetime="2008-07-09"/></status>

	<introduced date="1215576000" datetime="2008-07-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">ECO Fund Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Energy Conservation Opportunity Fund Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a revolving loan fund to provide loans to States and Indian tribes to provide incentives to undertake activities to provide renewable energy sources for housing and other structures.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412220"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412192" joined="2008-07-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1215576000" datetime="2008-07-09"><text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1215576000" datetime="2008-07-09"><text>Referred to House Financial Services</text></action>
		<action date="1215576000" datetime="2008-07-09"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1215576000" datetime="2008-07-09"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/9/2008--Introduced.<br/>Energy Conservation Opportunity Fund Act of 2008 or the ECO Fund Act of 2008 - Establishes in the Treasury an Alternative Energy Sources State Revolving Fund.<br/>Directs the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to use amounts in the Fund to provide loans to states and Indian tribes to provide incentives to owners of single family and multifamily housing, commercial properties, and public buildings to provide: (1) renewable energy sources, such as wind, wave, solar, biomass, or geothermal energy, for such structures; (2) energy efficiency and energy conserving improvements and features for such structures; or (3) infrastructure related to the delivery of electricity and hot water for structures lacking such amenities.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
