<bill session="110" type="h" number="6454" updated="2009-01-09T06:10:46-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1215662400" datetime="2008-07-10"/></status>

	<introduced date="1215662400" datetime="2008-07-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">E-Verify Extension and Expansion Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To extend and expand the E-verify program for employment eligibility confirmation, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400059"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1215662400" datetime="2008-07-10"><text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Education and Labor, Science and Technology, and Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1215662400" datetime="2008-07-10"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1215662400" datetime="2008-07-10"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1215662400" datetime="2008-07-10"><text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text></action>
		<action date="1215662400" datetime="2008-07-10"><text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text></action>
		<action date="1216008000" datetime="2008-07-14"><committee name="House Science and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology and Innovation.</text></action>
		<action date="1222660800" datetime="2008-09-29"><committee name="House Homeland Security"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border, Maritime, and Global Counterterrorism.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/10/2008--Introduced.<br/>E-Verify Extension and Expansion Act of 2008 - Amends the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 to replace the current three employment eligibility confirmation pilot programs with two pilot programs: (1) the revised E-Verify program in all 50 states; and (2) the secure electronic employment verification system (SEEVS) in all 50 states by December 1, 2009. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish such programs. Terminates such pilot programs not later than December 31, 2013. States that the E-Verify program shall be voluntary except for: (1) the federal government; and (2) employers who have violated certain employment provisions.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
