<bill session="110" type="h" number="6461" updated="2009-01-09T06:11:39-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1215662400" datetime="2008-07-10"/></status>

	<introduced date="1215662400" datetime="2008-07-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Supporting America's Volunteer Emergency Services Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To assist volunteer fire companies in coping with the precipitous rise in fuel prices.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412231"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400227" joined="2008-09-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400257" joined="2008-09-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400080" joined="2008-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400183" joined="2008-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="412210" joined="2008-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412214" joined="2008-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400264" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400184" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400285" joined="2008-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412188" joined="2008-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400642" joined="2008-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400352" joined="2008-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400195" joined="2008-09-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400286" joined="2008-09-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400321" joined="2008-07-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1215662400" datetime="2008-07-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text></action>
		<action date="1215748800" datetime="2008-07-11"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/10/2008--Introduced.<br/>Supporting America's Volunteer Emergency Services Act of 2008 - Directs the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to determine the average annual price per gallon for gasoline and diesel fuel for each of the five Petroleum Administration for Defense Districts for 2007. Requires: (1) the average annual price per gallon to be based solely on data reported by the Energy Information Administration; and (2) that price to serve as the baseline fuel cost for each District.<br/>Requires FEMA to reimburse a qualified volunteer fire department for 75% of the difference between: (1) the actual expenditures of the department for gasoline and diesel fuel for a year; and (2) the amount that such expenditures would have been using the baseline fuel costs. Directs each qualified volunteer fire department seeking reimbursement to submit to the FEMA at the end of each year: (1) all of its receipts and bills of sales documenting the amounts of gasoline and diesel fuel purchased during that year; and (2) a sum total of the aggregate number of gallons and the costs of gasoline and diesel fuel purchased.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
