<bill session="110" type="h" number="6472" updated="2009-01-09T06:12:59-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1215662400" datetime="2008-07-10"/></status>

	<introduced date="1215662400" datetime="2008-07-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Resist Offsetting with Additional Debt Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">ROAD Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To rescind certain earmark projects under SAFETEA-LU for the purpose of eliminating the shortfall in the Highway Trust Fund, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400134"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1215662400" datetime="2008-07-10"><text>Referred to the Committee on Appropriations, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1215662400" datetime="2008-07-10"><text>Referred to House Appropriations</text></action>
		<action date="1215662400" datetime="2008-07-10"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1215748800" datetime="2008-07-11"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/10/2008--Introduced.<br/>Resist Offsetting with Additional Debt Act or the ROAD Act - Rescinds unobligated balances of certain earmark surface transportation projects under the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users (SAFETEA-LU) (in order to eliminate the shortfall in the Highway Trust Fund (HTF)). Prohibits the transfer of funds from the General Fund of the Treasury to the HTF. Expresses the sense of Congress that state transportation departments should consider implementing certain projects under the highway bridge program and the surface transportation program that improve transportation safety.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
