<bill session="110" type="h" number="6483" updated="2009-01-09T06:14:13-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1216008000" datetime="2008-07-14"/></status>

	<introduced date="1216008000" datetime="2008-07-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Recreational Performance Outerwear Apparel Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for duty free treatment of certain recreational performance outerwear, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400033"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400255" joined="2008-07-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1216008000" datetime="2008-07-14"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1451)</text></action>
		<action date="1216008000" datetime="2008-07-14"><text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Science and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1216008000" datetime="2008-07-14"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1216008000" datetime="2008-07-14"><text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text></action>
		<action date="1216008000" datetime="2008-07-14"><committee name="House Science and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology and Innovation.</text></action>
		<action date="1216872000" datetime="2008-07-24"><committee name="House Science and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/14/2008--Introduced.<br/>Recreational Performance Outerwear Apparel Act of 2008 - Amends the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States to provide for the duty-free treatment of certain recreational performance outerwear. Establishes the Sustainable Textile and Apparel Research Fund (STAR Fund). Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to: (1) impose and collect, with specified exceptions, a fee of 1.5% of the appraised value of imported recreational performance outerwear and to deposit amounts collected into the STAR Fund; and (2) make quarterly distributions from the STAR Fund to one or more appropriate organizations to conduct applied research, development, and education activities to enhance the competitiveness of U.S. businesses in clean, eco-friendly apparel, other textile and apparel products, and sewn-product design and manufacturing.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
