<bill session="110" type="h" number="6506" updated="2009-01-09T06:16:53-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1216180800" datetime="2008-07-16"/></status>

	<introduced date="1216180800" datetime="2008-07-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Children's Doctor Access Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XXI of the Social Security Act to require SCHIP annual reports to include information on the HEDIS measure relating to access to primary care practitioners by individuals eligible for child health assistance under such plans and on State efforts to avoid certain displacement of private health coverage, and to express the sense of Congress that such States should utilize Consumer Assessment of Healthcare Providers and Systems consumer satisfaction surveys to measure access by such individuals to physicians.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400636"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1216180800" datetime="2008-07-16"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1216180800" datetime="2008-07-16"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/16/2008--Introduced.<br/>Improving Children's Doctor Access Act of 2008 - Amends title XXI (State Children's Health Insurance) (SCHIP) of the Social Security Act to require annual state SCHIP reports to include information on: (1) the HEDIS (Health Plan Employer Data and Information Set) measure relating to access to primary care practitioners by individuals eligible for child health assistance; and (2) efforts to avoid displacement of private health coverage. Expresses the sense of Congress that states with a state child health plan should utilize consumer satisfaction surveys developed by the Consumer Assessment of Healthcare Providers and Systems (CAHPS) administered by the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality, specifically the Getting Needed Care and Getting Care Quickly question components of the CAHPS 4.0H Child Survey, to measure the extent to which individuals eligible for child health assistance under the state plan have access to physicians.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
