<bill session="110" type="h" number="6539" updated="2009-01-09T06:20:58-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1216267200" datetime="2008-07-17"/></status>

	<introduced date="1216267200" datetime="2008-07-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Tracking Registered And Convicted Known (TRACK) Sex Offenders Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the use of information in the National Directory of New Hires in enforcing sex offender registration laws.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412216"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400004" joined="2008-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400380" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400652" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400570" joined="2008-07-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1216267200" datetime="2008-07-17"><text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1216267200" datetime="2008-07-17"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1216267200" datetime="2008-07-17"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/17/2008--Introduced.<br/>Tracking Registered And Convicted Known (TRACK) Sex Offenders Act - Amends title IV (Grants to States for Aid and Services to Needy Families with Children and for Child-Welfare Services) of the Social Security Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to disclose to the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) information in the National Directory of New Hires to assist in the enforcement of a federal or state law requiring the registration of sex offenders. Authorizes the FBI to disclose such information to state or local law enforcement agencies for purposes of enforcing sex offender registration laws. 
	</summary>
</bill>
