<bill session="110" type="h" number="6552" updated="2009-01-09T06:22:28-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1216267200" datetime="2008-07-17"/></status>

	<introduced date="1216267200" datetime="2008-07-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Incentivizing Renewable Energy Production Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide incentives for the reduction of green house gases.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400400"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1216267200" datetime="2008-07-17"><text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, Rules, Energy and Commerce, and Science and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1216267200" datetime="2008-07-17"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1216267200" datetime="2008-07-17"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1216267200" datetime="2008-07-17"><text>Referred to House Rules</text></action>
		<action date="1216267200" datetime="2008-07-17"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1216267200" datetime="2008-07-17"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text></action>
		<action date="1216267200" datetime="2008-07-17"><text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text></action>
		<action date="1216267200" datetime="2008-07-17"><committee name="House Science and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/17/2008--Introduced.<br/>Incentivizing Renewable Energy Production Act of 2008 - Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to allow loan guarantees for closed-loop ethanol plants. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) allow a tax credit for the production of livestock-derived renewable energy; (2) allow an increased tax credit for research expenses relating to any clean-burning fuel and closed-loop system (including any anaerobic digester); (3) allow a tax credit for the production of biomaterials from certain renewable resources; and (4) increase the tax credit for alternative fuel vehicle refueling property expenditures.<br/>Amends the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 to: (1) require the Secretary of Energy to establish a program to support development in biofuel technologies; and (2) authorize appropriations through FY2019 for the grant program for the production of advanced biofuels.<br/>Directs the Secretary of Commerce to make publicly available at least 100 hydrogen fueling pumps at retail gas stations by 2014 in specified regions of the United States. Authorizes appropriations for the purchase of fuel cell vehicles by the federal government in FY2012-FY2014.<br/>Amends the Rules of the House of Representatives to require committee reports to include a domestic energy impact statement prepared by the Comptroller General. 
	</summary>
</bill>
