<bill session="110" type="h" number="6563" updated="2009-01-09T06:23:44-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1216699200" datetime="2008-07-22"/></status>

	<introduced date="1216699200" datetime="2008-07-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Financial Disclosure Integrity Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 to require information on the value of any personal residence and on the balance, interest rate, and remaining number of years of any mortgage secured by real property to be included in the annual financial disclosure reports required to be filed under such Act.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400385"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2008-07-31"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1216699200" datetime="2008-07-22"><text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committees on House Administration, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1216699200" datetime="2008-07-22"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1216699200" datetime="2008-07-22"><text>Referred to House House Administration</text></action>
		<action date="1216699200" datetime="2008-07-22"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/22/2008--Introduced.<br/>Financial Disclosure Integrity Act - Amends the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 to require the annual financial disclosure reports of certain federal officers and employees to include mortgages secured by real properties which are the personal residences of the reporting individuals or their spouses. Requires the reporting of any liability consisting of such a mortgage to include applicable interest rate payments during the preceding calendar year and the number of years (or portions) remaining on the mortgage. Requires in the financial report a brief description, the date, and category of value of any purchase, sale, or exchange of such a property during a preceding calendar year.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
