<bill session="110" type="h" number="6567" updated="2009-01-09T06:24:18-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1216699200" datetime="2008-07-22"/></status>

	<introduced date="1216699200" datetime="2008-07-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Pulmonary Fibrosis Research Enhancement Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To expand the research, prevention, and awareness activities of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and the National Institutes of Health with respect to pulmonary fibrosis, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400011"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400222" joined="2008-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400099" joined="2008-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400155" joined="2008-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400407" joined="2008-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400430" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400065" joined="2008-09-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412259" joined="2008-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400154" joined="2008-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400254" joined="2008-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="2008-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400101" joined="2008-09-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400029" joined="2008-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400007" joined="2008-09-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400245" joined="2008-09-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400235" joined="2008-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400147" joined="2008-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400166" joined="2008-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400070" joined="2008-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400439" joined="2008-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400234" joined="2008-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412239" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400153" joined="2008-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400211" joined="2008-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400326" joined="2008-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412212" joined="2008-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2008-09-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400425" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400321" joined="2008-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400435" joined="2008-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400309" joined="2008-10-02"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1216699200" datetime="2008-07-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1216699200" datetime="2008-07-22"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/22/2008--Introduced.<br/>Pulmonary Fibrosis Research Enhancement Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to: (1) develop a system to collect data on pulmonary fibrosis and other interstitial lung diseases; (2) establish the National PF Registry; and (3) establish the National Pulmonary Fibrosis Advisory Board.<br/>Allows the Secretary, acting through the Director of the CDC, to provide for the collection, analysis, and reporting of data on pulmonary fibrosis and other interstitial lung diseases that can be confused with, misdiagnosed as, and progress to pulmonary fibrosis.<br/>Requires the Secretary, in developing the Registry, to: (1) expand and coordinate existing data and surveillance systems, surveys, registries, and other federal public health and environmental infrastructure; and (2) provide for research access to pulmonary fibrosis data.<br/>Directs the Secretary to ensure that epidemiological and other types of information are made available to the National Institutes of Health (NIH) and the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA).<br/>Requires the Director of the National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute to expand, intensify, and coordinate Institute pulmonary fibrosis research activities.<br/>Requires the Director of CDC to prepare the National Pulmonary Fibrosis Action Plan.<br/>Requires the Secretary to: (1) convene a summit of individuals with expertise in research and care of pulmonary fibrosis to provide a detailed overview of NIH research activities and discuss potential collaborations between NIH and other federal health agencies; and (2) make information about NIH activities relating to pulmonary fibrosis publicly available.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
