<bill session="110" type="h" number="6595" updated="2009-01-09T06:27:35-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1216872000" datetime="2008-07-24"/></status>

	<introduced date="1216872000" datetime="2008-07-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Middle Class Tax Fairness Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide middle class tax relief while closing tax loopholes, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412214"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400177" joined="2008-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412224" joined="2008-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2008-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412208" joined="2008-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400120" joined="2008-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2008-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="412228" joined="2008-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="412257" joined="2008-09-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1216872000" datetime="2008-07-24"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H7063)</text></action>
		<action date="1216872000" datetime="2008-07-24"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action date="1217390400" datetime="2008-07-30"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1624)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/24/2008--Introduced.<br/>Middle Class Tax Fairness Act of 2008 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow in 2008 and 2009: (1) an increase in the basic standard tax deduction; (2) a tax deduction for real property taxes for taxpayers who do not itemize their deductions; and (3) a reduction in the earned income threshold amount for determining the refundable portion of the child tax credit.<br/>Provides for certain revenue-raising provisions, including: (1) treatment of net income and loss from an investment services partnership as ordinary income and loss; (2) denial of tax benefits for major integrated oil companies; (3) imposing a limit on tax deductions and exemptions for individuals with adjusted gross incomes in excess of $250,000 ($500,000 in the case of a joint tax return); (4) the inclusion in gross income of certain deferred compensation from foreign entities; (5) new reporting requirements for payment settlement entities and securities brokers; (6) repeal of tax rules for the worldwide allocation of interest for purposes of computing the limitation on the foreign tax credit; (7) new rules for the application of the economic substance doctrine to transactions affecting tax liability; and (8) penalties for underpayment of tax due to transactions lacking economic substance.<br/>Requires any increase in tax receipts resulting from this Act to be used for deficit reduction purposes. 
	</summary>
</bill>
