<bill session="110" type="h" number="6592" updated="2009-01-09T06:27:15-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1216785600" datetime="2008-07-23"/></status>

	<introduced date="1216785600" datetime="2008-07-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Lovelace Respiratory Research Institute Land Conveyance Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the conveyance of certain public land in the State of New Mexico owned or leased by the Department of Energy, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400434"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400313" joined="2008-07-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1216785600" datetime="2008-07-23"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Natural Resources, and Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1216785600" datetime="2008-07-23"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1216785600" datetime="2008-07-23"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1216785600" datetime="2008-07-23"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1217217600" datetime="2008-07-28"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action date="1220500800" datetime="2008-09-04"><committee name="House Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/23/2008--Introduced.<br/>Lovelace Respiratory Research Institute Land Conveyance Act - Directs the Secretary of Energy to convey specified land identified as Parcel A (including any improvements) to the Lovelace Respiratory Research Institute in New Mexico only for research, scientific, or educational use. Requires the Secretaries of the Interior and Air Force to complete any real property actions, including the revocation of any federal withdrawals of Parcels A and B, that are necessary to allow the Secretary to convey Parcel A or to transfer administrative jurisdiction over Parcel B to the Secretary of the Air Force.<br/>Authorizes the Secretary of the Air Force to retain ownership and control of: (1) portions of the utility system and infrastructure on Parcel A; and (2) rights of access determined to be necessary to operate and maintain the utilities on such parcel. Requires the Institute to pay or reimburse costs incurred in the conveyance of Parcel A, including related survey costs. Instructs the Institute to take fee title to Parcel A and any improvements, as contaminated. Makes the Institute responsible for completing all environmental remediation required with respect to such parcel for all environmental conditions related to or arising from contamination.<br/>Directs the Secretary of the Air Force to provide the Institute with: (1) access for employees and invitees of the Institute across Kirtland Air Force Base to Parcel A; and (2) access to utility services for such parcel.<br/>Requires the Secretary of Energy to arrange and pay for the removal of any improvements made to Parcel B. 
	</summary>
</bill>
