<bill session="110" type="h" number="6599" updated="2009-01-09T06:28:04-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1217598720" datetime="2008-08-01T10:52:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="563"/></status>

	<introduced date="1216872000" datetime="2008-07-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Military Construction and Veterans Affairs Appropriations Act, 2009</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Military Construction and Veterans Affairs Appropriations Act, 2009</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Military Construction and Veterans Affairs Appropriations Act, 2009</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Making appropriations for military construction, the Department of Veterans Affairs, and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2009, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400118"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1216935120" datetime="2008-07-24T18:32:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-775, by Mr. Edwards (TX).</text></action>
		<calendar date="1216935180" datetime="2008-07-24T18:33:00-04:00" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 494.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1217372580" datetime="2008-07-29T20:03:00-04:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1384 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 6599 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be read by paragraph. Bill is open to amendments. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. Notwithstanding clause 11 of rule XVIII, no amendment to the bill shall be in order except those printed in the portion of the Congressional Record designated for that purpose in clause 8 of rule XVIII in a daily issue dated July 30, 2008, or earlier and except pro forma amendments for the purpose of debate.</text></action>
		<action date="1217531340" datetime="2008-07-31T16:09:00-04:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 1384 passed House.</text></action>
		<action date="1217545080" datetime="2008-07-31T19:58:00-04:00"><text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 1384. (consideration: CR 8/1/2008 H7709-7775; text of Title I as introduced in House: CR 8/1/2008 H7722, H7744, H7745, H7745-7748; text of Title II as introduced in House: CR 8/1/2008 H7748-7749, H7749, H7750-7751, H7754-7754; text of Title III as introduced in House: CR 8/1/2008 H7761; text of Title IV as introduced in House: CR 8/1/2008 H7761, H7799)</text></action>
		<action date="1217545080" datetime="2008-07-31T19:58:00-04:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 6599 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be read by paragraph. Bill is open to amendments. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. Notwithstanding clause 11 of rule XVIII, no amendment to the bill shall be in order except those printed in the portion of the Congressional Record designated for that purpose in clause 8 of rule XVIII in a daily issue dated July 30, 2008, or earlier and except pro forma amendments for the purpose of debate.</text></action>
		<action date="1217545080" datetime="2008-07-31T19:58:00-04:00"><text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 1384 and Rule XVIII.</text></action>
		<action date="1217545080" datetime="2008-07-31T19:58:00-04:00"><text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Earl Pomeroy to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text></action>
		<action date="1217545080" datetime="2008-07-31T19:58:00-04:00"><text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 6599.</text></action>
		<action date="1217546160" datetime="2008-07-31T20:16:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Edwards (TX) moved that the committee rise.</text></action>
		<action date="1217546220" datetime="2008-07-31T20:17:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the committee rise. Agreed to by voice vote.</text></action>
		<action date="1217546280" datetime="2008-07-31T20:18:00-04:00"><text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text></action>
		<action date="1217546340" datetime="2008-07-31T20:19:00-04:00"><text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole resumed debate on H.R. 6599.</text></action>
		<action date="1217549400" datetime="2008-07-31T21:10:00-04:00"><text>The Committee of the Whole rose informally.</text></action>
		<action date="1217549460" datetime="2008-07-31T21:11:00-04:00"><text>The Committee of the Whole resumed its sitting.</text></action>
		<action date="1217549820" datetime="2008-07-31T21:17:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Bishop (UT) amendment pending reservation of a point of order.</text></action>
		<action date="1217550960" datetime="2008-07-31T21:36:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Burgess amendment pending reservation of a point of order.</text></action>
		<action date="1217552340" datetime="2008-07-31T21:59:00-04:00"><text>The Committee of the Whole rose informally.</text></action>
		<action date="1217552400" datetime="2008-07-31T22:00:00-04:00"><text>The Committee of the Whole resumed its sitting.</text></action>
		<action date="1217552460" datetime="2008-07-31T22:01:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Garrett (NJ) amendment.</text></action>
		<action date="1217553000" datetime="2008-07-31T22:10:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Garrett (NJ) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Garrett (NJ) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action date="1217553060" datetime="2008-07-31T22:11:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Buyer amendment.</text></action>
		<action date="1217553900" datetime="2008-07-31T22:25:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Buyer amendment pending reservation of a point of order.</text></action>
		<action date="1217555040" datetime="2008-07-31T22:44:00-04:00"><text>The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Jackson-Lee (TX) amendment pending reservation of a point of order.</text></action>
		<action date="1217555460" datetime="2008-07-31T22:51:00-04:00"><text>EN BLOC CONSIDERATION OF AMENDMENTS - Mr. Filner asked unanimous consent that the amendments numbered 18 and 19 printed in the Congressional Record be considered en bloc. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action date="1217555520" datetime="2008-07-31T22:52:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Filner amendments en bloc pending reservation of a point of order.</text></action>
		<action date="1217555760" datetime="2008-07-31T22:56:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Filner amendment pending reservation of a point of order.</text></action>
		<action date="1217557620" datetime="2008-07-31T23:27:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Terry amendment pending reservation of a point of order.</text></action>
		<action date="1217557980" datetime="2008-07-31T23:33:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Hensarling amendment.</text></action>
		<action date="1217558400" datetime="2008-07-31T23:40:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Taylor amendment.</text></action>
		<action date="1217558580" datetime="2008-07-31T23:43:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Commitee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the McCaul (TX) amendment.</text></action>
		<action date="1217558760" datetime="2008-07-31T23:46:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the McCaul (TX) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. McCaul (TX) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action date="1217558820" datetime="2008-07-31T23:47:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Stupak amendment.</text></action>
		<action date="1217559180" datetime="2008-07-31T23:53:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Wamp amendment.</text></action>
		<action date="1217559360" datetime="2008-07-31T23:56:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Murphy (CT) amendment.</text></action>
		<action date="1217602860" datetime="2008-08-01T00:01:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Flake amendment.</text></action>
		<action date="1217605500" datetime="2008-08-01T00:45:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Flake amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Flake demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action date="1217605560" datetime="2008-08-01T00:46:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Gingrey amendment.</text></action>
		<action date="1217605920" datetime="2008-08-01T00:52:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the King (IA) amendment.</text></action>
		<action date="1217563380" datetime="2008-08-01T01:03:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the King (IA) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. King (IA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text></action>
		<action date="1217563500" datetime="2008-08-01T01:05:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Edwards (TX) moved that the Committee rise.</text></action>
		<action date="1217563500" datetime="2008-08-01T01:05:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text></action>
		<action date="1217563560" datetime="2008-08-01T01:06:00-04:00"><text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 6599 as unfinished business.</text></action>
		<action date="1217593200" datetime="2008-08-01T09:20:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H7793-7802"/></action>
		<action date="1217593260" datetime="2008-08-01T09:21:00-04:00"><text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text></action>
		<action date="1217596380" datetime="2008-08-01T10:13:00-04:00"><text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 6599.</text></action>
		<action date="1217596440" datetime="2008-08-01T10:14:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H7799"/></action>
		<action date="1217596440" datetime="2008-08-01T10:14:00-04:00"><text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text></action>
		<action date="1217596500" datetime="2008-08-01T10:15:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Lewis (CA) moved to recommit with instructions to Appropriations.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H7799-7800"/><reference label="text" ref="CR H7799"/></action>
		<action date="1217596560" datetime="2008-08-01T10:16:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the Lewis (CA) motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require to bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment inserting a section enacting H.R. 6566, the American Energy Act.</text></action>
		<action date="1217596980" datetime="2008-08-01T10:23:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Edwards (TX) raised a point of order against the motion to recommit with instructions. The provisions of the motion to recommit constitute legislation in an appropriations bill. Sustained by the Chair.</text></action>
		<action date="1217596980" datetime="2008-08-01T10:23:00-04:00"><text>Point of order sustained against the motion to recommit with instructions.</text></action>
		<action date="1217597340" datetime="2008-08-01T10:29:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Peterson (PA) appealed the ruling of the chair. The question was then put on sustaining the ruling of the chair.</text></action>
		<action date="1217597340" datetime="2008-08-01T10:29:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Edwards (TX) moved to table the motion to appeal the ruling of the chair</text></action>
		<action date="1217598300" datetime="2008-08-01T10:45:00-04:00"><text>On motion to table the motion to appeal the ruling of the chair Agreed to by recorded vote: 230 - 184 (Roll no. 562).</text></action>
		<vote date="1217598720" how="roll" roll="563" datetime="2008-08-01T10:52:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 409 - 4 (Roll no. 563).</text></vote>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="945" date="1220846400" datetime="2008-09-08" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 945.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/1/2008--Passed House amended. Military Construction and Veterans Affairs Appropriations Act, 2009 - Title I: Department of Defense - Appropriates funds for FY2009 for the Department of Defense (DOD) for: (1) military construction for the Army, Navy and Marine Corps, and Air Force (military departments), DOD, the Army and Air National Guard, and the Army, Navy, and Air Force reserves; (2) the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) Security Investment Program; (3) family housing construction and related operation and maintenance for the military departments and DOD; (4) the Department of Defense Family Housing Improvement Fund; (5) the Homeowners Assistance Fund; (6) chemical demilitarization construction; and (7) the Department of Defense Base Closure Accounts of 1990 and 2005. Specifies restrictions and authorizations regarding the use of funds appropriated in this title and in other military construction appropriations Acts. (Sec. 113) Directs the Secretary of Defense to notify the appropriate congressional committees 30 days in advance of the plans and scope of any proposed military exercise involving U.S. personnel if construction costs are anticipated to exceed $100,000. (Sec. 118) Directs the Secretary to report to the appropriations committees on actions proposed by DOD to encourage other members of NATO, Japan, South Korea, and U.S. allies bordering the Arabian Sea to assume a greater share of the common defense burden of such nations and the United States. (Sec. 121) Requires the Secretary of the military department concerned, at least 60 days prior to issuing any solicitation for a contract with the private sector for military family housing, to notify the appropriations committees of any guarantees (including the making of mortgage or rental payments) proposed to be made to the private party in the event of: (1) the closure or realignment of the installation for which the housing is provided; (2) a reduction in force of units stationed at such installation; or (3) the extended deployment overseas of units stationed at such installation. (Sec. 122) Authorizes the transfer of DOD funds for expenses associated with the Homeowners Assistance Program under the Metropolitan Demonstration Cities and Metropolitan Development Act of 1966. (Sec. 125) Places specified restrictions and limitations on the obligation or expenditure of funds made available in this title or in any other military construction appropriations Act to carry out a military construction, land acquisition, or family housing project at or for a military installation approved for closure, or for supporting a function that has been approved for realignment to another installation, in 2005 under the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Act of 1990. (Sec. 126) Provides for the transfer of lapsed unobligated military construction and family housing funds into the Foreign Currency Fluctuations, Defense account. (Sec. 127) Prohibits this Act's funds from being used for any action that relates to or promotes the expansion of the boundaries or size of the Pinon Canyon Maneuver Site, Colorado. Title II: Department of Veterans Affairs - Authorizes appropriations for the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) for: (1) the Veterans Benefits Administration; (2) readjustment benefits; (3) veterans insurance and indemnities; (4) the Veterans Housing Benefit Program Fund; (5) the Vocational Rehabilitation Loans Program; (6) the Native American Veteran Housing Loan Program; (7) guaranteed transitional housing loans for homeless veterans; (8) the Veterans Health Administration (including for medical and prosthetic research and information technology systems); (9) the National Cemetery Administration; (10) the Office of the Inspector General; (11) construction for major and minor projects; and (12) grants for the construction of state extended care facilities and veterans cemeteries. Specifies restrictions and authorizations regarding the use of funds appropriated in this title. (Sec. 210) Makes funds from this title available to reimburse expenses of the Office of Resolution Management and the Office of Employment Discrimination Complaint Adjudication, within specified limits. (Sec. 216) Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to allow veterans eligible under existing VA medical care requirements and who reside in Alaska to obtain medical services from facilities supported by the Indian Health Service or tribal organizations. (Sec. 218) Prohibits the VA from using funds available in this or any other Act to replace the current system by which the Veterans Integrated Service Networks select and contract for diabetes monitoring supplies and equipment. (Sec. 220) Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to report quarterly to the appropriations committees on the financial status of the Veterans Health Administration. (Sec. 224) Extends through FY2009: (1) certain daily copayment limits for veterans receiving hospital or nursing home care; and (2) VA authority to recover from third party insurers the cost of care provided to a veteran for a non-service-connected disability. Title III: Related Agencies - Appropriates funds for: (1) the American Battle Monuments Commission; (2) the U.S. Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims; (3) cemeterial expenses; and (4) the Armed Forces Retirement Home. Title IV: General Provisions - Specifies restrictions and authorizations regarding the use of funds appropriated in this Act, including prohibitions on the use of funds: (1) to enforce a provision of a VHA policy directive concerning voter registration at patient facilities; (2) to take private property for public use without just compensation; or (3) for a project or program named for an individual serving as a Member, Delegate, Resident Commissioner, or Senator of the U.S. Congress.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
