<bill session="110" type="h" number="6610" updated="2009-01-09T06:29:23-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1216872000" datetime="2008-07-24"/></status>

	<introduced date="1216872000" datetime="2008-07-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Rules of Evidence to address the waiver of the attorney-client privilege and the work product doctrine.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400199"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1216872000" datetime="2008-07-24"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/24/2008--Introduced.<br/>Amends the Federal Rules of Evidence with respect to the disclosure of a communication or information covered by the attorney-client privilege and work product protection. Provides that, when such a disclosure is made in a federal proceeding or to a federal office or agency, and waives the attorney-client privilege or work-product protection, the waiver extends to an undisclosed communication or information in a federal or state proceeding only if: (1) the waiver is intentional; (2) the disclosed and undisclosed communications or information concern the same subject matter; and (3) they ought in fairness to be considered together. States that, when the disclosure is made in a federal proceeding or to a federal office or agency, it does not operate as a waiver in a federal or state proceeding if: (1) the disclosure is inadvertent; (2) the holder of the privilege or protection took reasonable steps to prevent disclosure; and (3) the holder promptly took reasonable steps to rectify the error. Declares that, when the disclosure is made in a state proceeding and is not the subject of a state-court order concerning waiver, it does not operate as a waiver in a federal proceeding if the disclosure: (1) would not be a waiver under this rule if it had been made in a federal proceeding; or (2) is not waived under law of the state where the disclosure occurred.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
