<bill session="110" type="h" number="6616" updated="2009-01-09T06:30:04-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1216872000" datetime="2008-07-24"/></status>

	<introduced date="1216872000" datetime="2008-07-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Colonel Charles Young Home National Historical Site Study Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a study of the Colonel Charles Young Home in Xenia, Ohio, and other associated locations to determine if those locations should be included as a unit of the National Park System, to include those locations if the Secretary concludes that they meet the criteria for inclusion, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400180"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400327" joined="2008-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412229" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400406" joined="2008-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400411" joined="2008-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400211" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="412010" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="412228" joined="2008-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400208" joined="2008-07-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1216872000" datetime="2008-07-24"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1217217600" datetime="2008-07-28"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/24/2008--Introduced.<br/>Colonel Charles Young Home National Historical Site Study Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with the Secretary of the Army, to conduct a study of the Colonel Charles Young Home, a National Historic Landmark in Xenia, Ohio, and associated locations and museums (the study area) to assess its national significance and the suitability and feasibility of including it as a unit of the National Park System. Requires the Secretary, if the study area meets the criteria for inclusion, to include it as a unit of the System. Provides for: (1) the consideration of an affiliation of the study area with the National Museum of the United States Army, the Buffalo Soldiers National Museum, or other entities associated with Colonel Charles Young in order to focus on his life and the African-American military experience; and (2) an investigation of the historical relationship of the Colonel Charles Young Home with the Underground Railroad. 
	</summary>
</bill>
