<bill session="110" type="h" number="6623" updated="2009-01-09T06:30:52-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1216872000" datetime="2008-07-24"/></status>

	<introduced date="1216872000" datetime="2008-07-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To waive sovereign immunity and extend the otherwise applicable statute of limitations for certain actions under the USEC Privatization Act.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400431"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1216872000" datetime="2008-07-24"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1216872000" datetime="2008-07-24"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1216872000" datetime="2008-07-24"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text></action>
		<action date="1216872000" datetime="2008-07-24"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/24/2008--Introduced.<br/>Amends the USEC Privatization Act with respect to certain actions in U.S. district court related to accrued, vested pension benefits of employees of an operating contractor of the United States Enrichment Corporation (USEC) at one or both of the two USEC gaseous diffusion plants following: (1) termination of or a change in contractor; and (2) consequent transfer of pension plan assets and liabilities. Authorizes specified active or retired participants (or beneficiaries) under the contractor's pension plan to bring an action against the Department of Energy in U.S. district court for relief, in the form of a one-time lump sum payment, in connection with such a transfer of plan assets and liabilities. Authorizes commencement of such an action on or before June 30, 2011. Waives U.S. sovereign immunity to any such an action.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
