<bill session="110" type="h" number="664" updated="2009-01-08T18:12:23-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1191988800" datetime="2007-10-10" /></status>

	<introduced date="1169614800" datetime="2007-01-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Dana Point Desalination Project Authorization Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Dana Point Desalination Project Authorization Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Water Desalination Act of 1996 to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to assist in research and development, environmental and feasibility studies, and preliminary engineering for the Municipal Water District of Orange County, California, Dana Point Desalination Project located at Dana Point, California.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412011"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400348" joined="2007-03-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400277" joined="2007-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400057" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400343" joined="2007-02-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1169614800" datetime="2007-01-24"><text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Science and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1169614800" datetime="2007-01-24"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1169614800" datetime="2007-01-24"><text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text></action>
		<action date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"><committee name="House Science and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text></action>
		<action date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text></action>
		<action date="1191988800" datetime="2007-10-10"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1191988800" datetime="2007-10-10"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Subcommittee on Water and Power Discharged.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1191988800" datetime="2007-10-10" ><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1200595320" datetime="2008-01-17T14:42:00-05:00"><text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-511, Part I.</text></action>
		<action date="1200595320" datetime="2008-01-17T14:42:00-05:00"><text>Committee on Science and Technology discharged.</text></action>
		<calendar number="312" date="1200595320" datetime="2008-01-17T14:42:00-05:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 312.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/17/2008--Reported to House without amendment, Part I. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Dana Point Desalination Project Authorization Act - Amends the Water Desalination Act of 1996 to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to assist in research and development, environmental and feasibility studies, and preliminary engineering for the Municipal Water District of Orange County, California, Dana Point Desalination Project. Limits the federal share to 25% of the total cost of the project. Terminates the Secretary's authority to carry out this Act 10 years after its enactment.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
