<bill session="110" type="h" number="6670" updated="2009-01-09T06:36:16-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1217390400" datetime="2008-07-30"/></status>

	<introduced date="1217390400" datetime="2008-07-30"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">LEASE Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Long-Term Energy Assurance and Security Enhancement Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Consumer Energy Supply Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Energy Markets Emergency Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To open areas of the Outer Continental Shelf to oil and gas leasing, to direct the Commodity Futures Trading Commission to utilize its authority to curb immediately the role of excessive speculation in energy markets, to require sales of light grade petroleum from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve and acquisitions of equivalent volumes of heavy grade petroleum, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400160"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412260" joined="2008-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400618" joined="2008-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400092" joined="2008-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400657" joined="2008-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400302" joined="2008-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400635" joined="2008-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400229" joined="2008-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400084" joined="2008-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400152" joined="2008-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400339" joined="2008-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400001" joined="2008-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="412262" joined="2008-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400645" joined="2008-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="412257" joined="2008-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400345" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400179" joined="2008-07-30"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1217390400" datetime="2008-07-30"><text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, Science and Technology, Transportation and Infrastructure, Education and Labor, and Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1217390400" datetime="2008-07-30"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1217390400" datetime="2008-07-30"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1217390400" datetime="2008-07-30"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text></action>
		<action date="1217390400" datetime="2008-07-30"><text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text></action>
		<action date="1217390400" datetime="2008-07-30"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1217390400" datetime="2008-07-30"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1217390400" datetime="2008-07-30"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text></action>
		<action date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text></action>
		<action date="1217908800" datetime="2008-08-05"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1221624000" datetime="2008-09-17"><committee name="House Science and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text></action>
		<action date="1223006400" datetime="2008-10-03"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text></action>
		<action date="1223006400" datetime="2008-10-03"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on General Farm Commodities and Risk Management.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/30/2008--Introduced.<br/>Long-Term Energy Assurance and Security Enhancement Act of 2008 or the LEASE Act of 2008 - Instructs the Secretary of the Interior to open certain areas in the Eastern Gulf of Mexico to oil and gas leasing. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to distribute certain Outer Continental Shelf (OCS) revenues to: (1) the general fund of the Treasury; (2) the Energy Independence and Security Fund (established by this Act); (3) Gulf producing states; and (4) financial assistance to states. Allocates funds among Gulf producing states and coastal political subdivisions.<br/>Instructs the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) protect the environment and the conservation of the natural resources of the OCS; and (2) establish lateral boundaries between coastal states in areas of the OCS that are outside the Gulf of Mexico and under exclusive federal jurisdiction in order to lease areas for oil and natural gas exploration and production. Authorizes the governor of a coastal state to request Secretary of the Interior to assess OCS oil and gas resources. Terminates federal prohibitions against the expenditure of appropriated funds to conduct oil and natural gas leasing and preleasing in specified areas of the OCS. Establishes the Energy Independence and Security Fund, whose amounts shall be distributed to designated research and development programs, including: (1) assessments of oil and gas resources; (2) wind energy research; (3) solar energy; (4) marine and hydrokinetic renewable electric energy; and (5) the Weatherization Assistance Program. Energy Markets Emergency Act of 2008 - Directs the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC) to: (1) curb immediately the role of excessive speculation in any contract market within its jurisdiction and control that trades energy futures or swaps; and (2) eliminate unlawful activity causing major market disturbances that prevent the market from accurately reflecting the forces of supply and demand for energy commodities. Consumer Energy Supply Act of 2008 - Instructs the Secretary of Energy to: (1) sell light grade petroleum from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve (SPR) and acquire an equivalent volume of heavy grade petroleum; and (2) deposit the cash proceeds into the SPR Petroleum Account.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
