<bill session="110" type="h" number="6686" updated="2009-01-09T06:38:06-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"/></status>

	<introduced date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">COMBAT Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Combat Operations and Medical Benefit Authorization for our Troops Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 37, United States Code, to increase the maximum monthly rate for the military special pay known as hostile fire pay, imminent danger pay, or hazardous duty pay, to increase the maximum monthly rate for the family separation allowance paid to deployed members of the Armed Forces, and to increase other special and incentive pays to recognize the service of members of the Armed Forces and encourage recruitment and retention.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412189"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400031" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2008-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400246" joined="2008-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="412222" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2008-07-31"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
		<action date="1220500800" datetime="2008-09-04"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/31/2008--Introduced.<br/>Combat Operations and Medical Benefit Authorization for Our Troops Act of 2008 or COMBAT Act - Increases the maximum monthly rates of: (1) hazardous duty pay; (2) hostile fire or imminent danger pay; (3) special pay for service as a member of a Weapons of Mass Destruction Civil Support Team; (4) special pay for members extending duty at designated overseas locations; (5) combat-related injury rehabilitation pay; and (6) the family separation allowance. Increases the maximum annual rates of special pay for: (1) officers serving as psychologists and nonphysician health care providers; and (2) special warfare officers extending their active-duty period.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
