<bill session="110" type="h" number="6695" updated="2009-01-09T06:39:09-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"/></status>

	<introduced date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to conform the mileage reimbursement rates used under the beneficiary travel program administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to the mileage reimbursement rates for Government employees on official business who use privately owned vehicles, to eliminate all deductibles under the beneficiary travel program, to ensure that all veterans can participate in the beneficiary travel program, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412214"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400041" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="412229" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400177" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400018" joined="2008-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400316" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400642" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400339" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400224" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="412193" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400172" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="412240" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="412222" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400638" joined="2008-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400244" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="412228" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="412194" joined="2008-09-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H7635)</text></action>
		<action date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/31/2008--Introduced.<br/>Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in determining the amount of any allowance or reimbursement to be paid under the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) veterans beneficiary travel program, to use the mileage reimbursement rates for the use of privately owned vehicles by government employees traveling on official business. Authorizes the Secretary to use a rate in excess of such rate. Prohibits the Secretary from making payments for travel performed by a special mode unless it is: (1) medically required and previously authorized; or (2) in connection with a medical emergency of such a nature that delay would have been hazardous to the person's life or health. Eliminates required deductions in connection with travel under the program. Allows such payments in connection with all veterans and family members eligible for examination, treatment, care, rehabilitation, or counseling through the VA. 
	</summary>
</bill>
