<bill session="110" type="h" number="6697" updated="2009-01-09T06:39:23-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"/></status>

	<introduced date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Marginal Well Production Preservation and Enhancement Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for marginal well production preservation and enhancement.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400645"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400655" joined="2008-07-31"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"><text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text></action>
		<action date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/31/2008--Introduced.<br/>Marginal Well Production Preservation and Enhancement Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) increase to 27.5% the percentage depletion allowance for domestic crude oil and natural gas production from marginal properties; (2) extend through 2008 the temporary suspension of the taxable income limit with respect to marginal production of crude oil and natural gas; and (3) accelerate to three years the recovery period of qualified tertiary injectant property for depreciation purposes.<br/>Amends the Clean Air Act with respect to emissions from small oil and gas exploration and production-related equipment. Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to: (1) amend the definition of &quot;wastewater treatment facility&quot; to include produced water from an oil production facility; and (2) require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish cost-effective minimal requirements for the prevention of oil and hazardous substance discharges for small facilities with oil storage capacities of less than 50,000 gallons at which no single tank exceeds a nominal capacity of 21,000 gallons. 
	</summary>
</bill>
