<bill session="110" type="h" number="6703" updated="2009-01-09T06:40:08-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"/></status>

	<introduced date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Museum of Industrial History Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To assist in the establishment of an interpretive center and museum in Bethlehem, Pennsylvania, to protect and interpret the history of the industrialization of the United States.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400648"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1217908800" datetime="2008-08-05"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/31/2008--Introduced.<br/>National Museum of Industrial History Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to seek to enter into an agreement with an appropriate entity to provide federal assistance for the development and operation of an interpretive center and museum on the former Bethlehem Steel Plant Site in Bethlehem, Pennsylvania, to preserve, display, and interpret historical resources related to industrialization in the United States and to promote other historical and cultural resources in the region through activities conducted at the interpretive center and museum. Sets forth covered and prohibited uses of such financial assistance, including prohibiting the use of assistance for the acquisition of items for the museum's collection. Provides for a non-federal match from the other parties to the agreement. Requires the Secretary to submit annual reports to Congress which describe: (1) the current status of the development of the interpretive center and museum; (2) the projects and activities funded; and (3) the balance of unexpended appropriated funds available to carry out this Act. 
	</summary>
</bill>
