<bill session="110" type="h" number="6717" updated="2009-01-09T06:41:48-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"/></status>

	<introduced date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Emergency Energy Cut the Red Tape Now Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To terminate or provide for suspension of the application of Federal laws that restrict exploration, development, or production of oil, gas, or oil shale, to facilitate the construction of new crude oil refineries, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412216"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400627" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="412252" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400113" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="412256" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400055" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400373" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400277" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400287" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400320" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="412010" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400644" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400005" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400221" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400141" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="412191" joined="2008-07-31"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H7634)</text></action>
		<action date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"><text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text></action>
		<action date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action date="1217908800" datetime="2008-08-05"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1223006400" datetime="2008-10-03"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/31/2008--Introduced.<br/>Emergency Energy Cut the Red Tape Now Act of 2008 - Declares without force or effect all: (1) federal prohibitions against the leasing of federal Outer Continental Shelf, Bureau of Land Management, or National Forest lands or federal submerged lands for exploration, development, or production of oil, gas, or oil shale; (2) federal withdrawals of such lands from such leasing; or (3) federal prohibitions against the expenditure of federal funds for such leasing. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to waive the application of any federal law that requires a permit to engage in drilling for oil or gas under a lease of federal lands or federal submerged lands during any period in which the most recent spot market price for West Texas Intermediate crude oil at the domestic spot market at Cushing, Oklahoma, is less than $100 per barrel. Requires such a waiver during any period in which the most recent spot price is greater than $100 per barrel. Requires the Department of Energy to act as the lead agency to coordinate all applicable federal refinery authorizations and related environmental reviews with respect to a designated refinery. Requires each federal and state agency or official required to provide a federal refinery authorization to cooperate with the Secretary of Energy and comply with deadlines the Secretary establishes. Requires the Secretary to establish a schedule for all federal refinery authorizations with respect to a designated refinery. Requires the Secretary to approve an application for a federal refinery authorization within 30 days after any failure of a federal or state administrative agency or official to complete an approval proceeding in accordance with the schedule established by the Secretary. 
	</summary>
</bill>
