<bill session="110" type="h" number="672" updated="2009-01-08T18:13:19-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1169614800" datetime="2007-01-24"/></status>

	<introduced date="1169614800" datetime="2007-01-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Puerto Rico Karst Conservation Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To protect the critical aquifers and watersheds that serve as a principal water source for the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, to protect the tropical forests of the Karst Region of the Commonwealth, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400662"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1169614800" datetime="2007-01-24"><text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1169614800" datetime="2007-01-24"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1169614800" datetime="2007-01-24"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/24/2007--Introduced.<br/>Puerto Rico Karst Conservation Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture to make grants, enter contracts, and exercise specified authorities to acquire, protect, and manage land and forest resources in and adjacent to the Karst Region of Puerto Rico for the purpose of protecting and conserving the water quality and aquifers and the geological, ecological, fish and wildlife, and other natural values of the Region. Establishes the Puerto Rico Karst Conservation Fund which shall be available to the Secretary for purposes of this Act. Makes all lands in the Region eligible for inclusion in the Forest Legacy Program.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
