<bill session="110" type="h" number="6728" updated="2009-01-09T06:43:03-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"/></status>

	<introduced date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Everglades National Park Land Exchange Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the resolution of several land ownership and related issues with respect to parcels of land located within the Everglades National Park.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400108"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400273" joined="2008-09-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="2008-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400048" joined="2008-09-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400270" joined="2008-09-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400107" joined="2008-09-11"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1217995200" datetime="2008-08-06"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/31/2008--Introduced.<br/>Everglades National Park Land Exchange Act of 2008 - Requires the Secretary of the Interior, if the state of Florida offers to convey non-federal land within Florida, and the offer is acceptable, to accept the offer and convey specified federal land within Everglades National Park to the state. Requires the land acquired by the Secretary through the exchange to become part of the Park. Ratifies a specified agreement between the United States and Florida Power &amp;amp; Light Company for the exchange and relocation of the Company's property in or adjacent to the Everglades National Park Expansion Area. Authorizes the Secretary to prepare an environmental assessment regarding such land exchange that identifies any immediate and proximate effect that may arise from the exchange and any potential mitigation measure for each such effect identified. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into an agreement with the Osceola family of Roy Cypress that: (1) allows the family to perpetually occupy and use a parcel of land commonly known as the William McKinley Osceola Hammock as a domestic residence; and (2) ensures that the occupancy and use of the Hammock by such family does not prevent the Secretary from constructing necessary improvements allowing for the completion of the Central and Southern Florida Project (for the improvement of water deliveries to the Park). Bars the area of the Hammock, subject to the written approval of the Secretary, from being enlarged through the addition of fill or by any other means.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
