<bill session="110" type="h" number="6724" updated="2009-01-09T06:42:36-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"/></status>

	<introduced date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Drill Offshore to Pay Less Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To terminate prohibitions on expenditures for, and withdrawals from, offshore oil and gas leasing off the coast of Virginia, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400060"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400658" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="412255" joined="2008-07-31"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"><text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1218081600" datetime="2008-08-07"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/31/2008--Introduced.<br/>Drill Offshore to Pay Less Act - Declares without force or effect for any area of the Outer Continental Shelf (OCS) more than 50 miles off the Virginia coast all federal prohibitions against the expenditure of appropriated funds to conduct oil and natural gas leasing and preleasing activities. Revokes all withdrawls from leasing of federal OCS submerged lands more than 50 miles off the Virginia coast. Prohibits the availability of any area of the OCS off the Virginia coast for leasing for exploration for, or the development or production of, oil or natural gas unless the Governor of Virginia, with the concurrence of the Virginia legislature, has requested the Secretary of the Interior to make such area available. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to take necessary action to ensure that oil and gas exploration, development, and production activities under federal leases of areas off the Virginia coast will result in no significant adverse effect on fish and wildlife, their habitat, subsistence resources, and the environment. Provides for allocation of oil and gas lease revenues under this Act. Prohibits any person from engaging in any exploration, development, or production of oil or natural gas off the Virginia coast that would conflict with any military operation, as determined by the Secretary of Defense.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
