<bill session="110" type="h" number="673" updated="2009-01-08T18:13:27-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1185851520" datetime="2007-07-30T12:12:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="without objection" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1169614800" datetime="2007-01-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Cocopah Lands Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Cocopah Lands Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Cocopah Lands Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to take lands in Yuma County, Arizona, into trust as part of the reservation of the Cocopah Indian Tribe, and for other purposes.</title>
		<title type="official" as="amended by house">A bill to direct the Secretary of the Interior to take lands in Yuma County, Arizona, into trust as part of the reservation of the Cocopah Tribe of Arizona, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400162"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1169614800" datetime="2007-01-24"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1181707200" datetime="2007-06-13"><text>Committee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1184731200" datetime="2007-07-18"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1184731200" datetime="2007-07-18" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text></calendar>
		<calendar number="173" date="1185850860" datetime="2007-07-30T12:01:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 173.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1185850860" datetime="2007-07-30T12:01:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-271.</text></action>
		<action date="1185851460" datetime="2007-07-30T12:11:00-04:00"><text>Mrs. Christensen asked unanimous consent discharge the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union.</text></action>
		<action date="1185851460" datetime="2007-07-30T12:11:00-04:00"><text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8825-8826"/><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR H8825-8826"/></action>
		<vote date="1185851520" how="without objection" datetime="2007-07-30T12:12:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On passage Passed without objection.</text></vote>
		<action date="1185851520" datetime="2007-07-30T12:12:00-04:00"><text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action date="1185854400" datetime="2007-07-31"><text>Received in the Senate.</text></action>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/30/2007--Passed House amended. Cocopah Lands Act - Provides that if the Cocopah Indian Tribe of Arizona transfers title to certain described land to the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary shall take it into trust for the benefit of the Tribe, if there are no recognized environmental conditions or contamination related concerns and no adverse legal claims to it, including outstanding liens, mortgages, or taxes owed. Considers such land to be part of the Tribe's initial reservation. Designates Yuma county, Arizona, to be the Tribe's service area for the delivery of federal services to enrolled members of the Tribe. Prohibits its use for gaming under the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act. 
	</summary>
</bill>
