<bill session="110" type="h" number="6779" updated="2009-01-09T06:48:49-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"/></status>

	<introduced date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">SEA Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Security and Energy for America Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Energy Natural Resources Enhancement Fund Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Freedom Fuels Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Rigs to Reefs Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">SEACOR</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Secure Rural Schools and Counties Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">State Enhanced Authority for Coastal and Ocean Resources Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for secure rural schools and counties, and State enhanced authority for coastal and ocean resources, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400419"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412218" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400367" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400659" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400376" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400336" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400330" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400317" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400113" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400313" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400297" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412230" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400176" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400049" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400040" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400662" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400029" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400288" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400658" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400038" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400121" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400335" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412201" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400319" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400421" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400171" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400617" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400440" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400651" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400088" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400394" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400341" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412191" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400434" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412255" joined="2008-08-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"><text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, Agriculture, the Judiciary, Education and Labor, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text></action>
		<action date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1217822400" datetime="2008-08-04"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text></action>
		<action date="1217822400" datetime="2008-08-04"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text></action>
		<action date="1217822400" datetime="2008-08-04"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text></action>
		<action date="1217822400" datetime="2008-08-04"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
		<action date="1217822400" datetime="2008-08-04"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text></action>
		<action date="1218427200" datetime="2008-08-11"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action date="1218427200" datetime="2008-08-11"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1223006400" datetime="2008-10-03"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/1/2008--Introduced.<br/>Security and Energy for America Act of 2008 or the SEA Act of 2008 - Secure Rural Schools and Counties Act of 2008 - Amends federal law governing payment for certain federal lands (entitlement land) to prescribe: (1) a transitional funding schedule for payments in lieu of taxes; and (2) transitional payments to states and counties previously entitled to payments under the Secure Rural Schools and Community Self-determination Act of 2000. Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) amounts made available by a state to certain counties to support public schools should be in addition to, and not in lieu of, general state funds to support such schools; and (2) a state should not adjust education funding allocations to reflect specified receipts. State Enhanced Authority for Coastal and Ocean Resources Act of 2008 or SEACOR - Amends the Submerged Lands Act (SLA) to: (1) revise the seaward boundaries of states; and (2) except from confirmation and establishment of states' title, power, and rights any oil and gas mineral rights located within the revised seaward boundaries. Amends the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (OCSLA) regarding Adjacent Zones and Planning Areas in the Outer Continental Shelf (OCS). Sets forth procedures for the Secretary of the Interior (Secretary) to grant and administer oil and natural gas leases on the OCS. Revises provisions concerning oil and gas leases.<br/>Federal Energy Natural Resources Enhancement Fund Act of 2008 - Establishes the Federal Energy Natural Resources Enhancement Fund to monitor and manage wildlife and fish and other natural resources related to energy and minerals development on federal lands. Declares without force or effect existing federal prohibitions against spending appropriated funds to: (1) conduct oil and natural gas leasing and preleasing activities, or to issue a lease for any OCS; or (2) issue final commercial leasing regulations or any other function related to oil shale and tar sands. Prohibits a federal agency from permitting construction or operation of any facility, or from designating or maintaining a restricted transportation corridor or operating area, on either federal OCS or state waters that will be incompatible with oil, gas, or natural gas leasing, and with exploration and production of tracts that are geologically prospective for oil or natural gas. Amends the Mineral Leasing Act to revise regulations governing onshore surface-disturbing activities.<br/>Redesignates the Minerals Management Service as the National Ocean Resources and Royalty Service.<br/>Rigs to Reefs Act of 2008 - Amends OCSLA to prescribe procedures to use decommissioned offshore oil and gas platforms and other facilities for artificial reef and scientific research.<br/>Establishes the Energy and Mineral Schools Reinvestment Act Fund to enable maintenance and restoration of existing and historic petroleum and mining engineering programs. Redesignates the Mining and Mineral Resources Institutes Act as the Energy and Mineral Schools Reinvestment Act. Instructs the Secretary to establish OCS regional headquarters for the Atlantic OCS Region and the Pacific OCS Region. Freedom Fuels Act - Establishes the Freedom Fuels Fund, to be used for specified programs including: (1) geologic and geophysical programs; (2) geothermal and geopressure energy renewable resource management; (3) unconventional energy resources management; and (4) renewable energy management. Directs the Secretary to establish a program for production of: (1) liquid fuels from strategic unconventional resources; and (2) oil and gas resources using advanced CO2 enhanced recovery. Directs the Secretary to establish a grant program, among other purposes, for: (1) geothermal and geopressure oil and gas energy production; (2) FEED grants for projects for coal-to-liquids, petroleum coke-to-liquids, oil shale, tar sands, and Alaska natural gas-to-liquids and the production of low-rank coal water fuel; and (3) production of renewable energy from designated resources. Amends the OCSLA to: (1) repeal the Coastal Impact Assistance program; and (2) revise royalty-in-kind requirements. Amends the the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to: (1) prescribe default requirements if the Secretary of Energy does not issue regulations governing payments for research, development, and demonstration leases, and for commercial leases for oil shale and tar sands; (2) require the Secretary to grant royalty relief for natural gas production from gas hydrates; (3) direct the Secretary to reduce royalties for certain federal oil and gas leases; and (4) instruct the Secretary of the Interior to use specified estimates and considerations when compiling oil and gas resource assessments. Repeals the Gulf of Mexico Energy Security Act of 2006.<br/>Instructs the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) establish specified fees for conservation resources; (2) require that OCS oil and gas exploration utilize technology to minimize air emissions and discharges into the water; (3) establish Federal OCS Joint Regional Permitting Offices; and (4) develop, upon lessee request, oil spill response plans for each OCS Planning area.<br/>Exempts certain oil and gas leasing and exploration from federal agency coordination requirements of the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972. Instructs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to delegate to the Minerals Management Service permitting and enforcement authority for specified federal OCS activities.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
