<bill session="110" type="h" number="6796" updated="2009-01-09T06:50:49-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"/></status>

	<introduced date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Very Unscrupulous Loan Transfers from Underprivileged countries to Rich, Exploitive Funds Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Stop VULTURE Funds Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To prevent speculation and profiteering in the defaulted debt of certain poor countries, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400422"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400661" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400080" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400295" joined="2008-09-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400623" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2008-09-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400163" joined="2008-08-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"><text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"><text>Referred to House Financial Services</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/1/2008--Introduced.<br/>Stop Very Unscrupulous Loan Transfers from Underprivileged Countries to Rich, Exploitive Funds Act or the Stop VULTURE Funds Act - Prohibits: (1) any U.S. person from engaging in sovereign debt profiteering, or any person engaging in sovereign debt profiteering in the United States; and (2) any U.S. court from issuing a summons, subpoena, writ, judgment, attachment, or execution in aid of a claim which would further sovereign debt profiteering. Sets forth: (1) required court disclosures in actions involving collection of sovereign debt; and (2) related responsibilities of the Secretary of the Treasury.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
