<bill session="110" type="h" number="6791" updated="2009-01-09T06:50:14-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"/></status>

	<introduced date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Cancer Fund Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to increase Federal excise taxes on tobacco products and to dedicate the revenues from the increased taxes to the war on cancer.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400641"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2008-09-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400257" joined="2008-09-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400268" joined="2008-09-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="412189" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400437" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400030" joined="2008-09-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400008" joined="2008-09-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="412240" joined="2008-10-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400195" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400215" joined="2008-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400062" joined="2008-09-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"><text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/1/2008--Introduced.<br/>National Cancer Fund Act of 2008 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) establish in the Treasury the National Cancer Fund for programs to fight cancer, including for expenditures for cancer research, early detection and treatment, and tobacco cessation; (2) increase the excise tax rate on tobacco products and dedicate increased tax revenues to the Fund; and (3) impose permit, reporting, and recordkeeping requirements on manufacturers of processed tobacco.<br/>Amends the Public Health Service Act to: (1) revise the membership and duties of the President's Cancer Panel; and (2) require the Panel to study the feasibility of additional funding sources for the National Cancer Fund.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
