<bill session="110" type="h" number="6806" updated="2009-01-09T06:51:58-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"/></status>

	<introduced date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Citizenship Should Count for Something Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a Citizens Congressional Health Benefits Program, based on the Federal employees health benefits program, to provide health insurance coverage for the President, Vice President, and Members of Congress, and citizens not eligible for coverage under the Federal employees health benefits program.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400153"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, and House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"><text>Referred to House House Administration</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/1/2008--Introduced.<br/>Citizenship Should Count for Something Act - Establishes the Citizens Congressional Health Benefits Program to provide comprehensive health insurance coverage to federal elected officials and to all other citizens who are not covered under the Federal Employees Health Benefits Program (FEHBP). Requires such coverage to be provided in a manner similar to the manner in which coverage has been provided under FEHBP.<br/>Eliminates eligibility of the President, Vice-President, and members of Congress for FEHBP.<br/>Requires the Director of the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to: (1) establish a process for eligible individuals to enroll in qualified health plans; (2) provide for the dissemination of information on such plans; and (3) enter into contracts with entities to offer such plans.<br/>Requires qualified health plans to: (1) provide for the same scope and type of comprehensive benefits that have been provided under FEHBP; and (2) meet consumer and patient protections. Prohibits qualified health plans from imposing preexisting condition exclusions or otherwise discriminating against an enrollee based on health status. Requires premiums established for a qualified health plan to be community-rated and not vary based on gender, health status, or other factors.<br/>Requires the Director to: (1) establish a process for the collection of premiums owed by enrollees; (2) monitor marketing practices to assure the accuracy of information disseminated and reasonable costs for such marketing; and (3) provide for an annual contribution towards the coverage provided under this Act for eligible individuals.<br/>Authorizes the Director to establish a contingency reserve and to impose a premium surcharge to provide financing for such reserve. 
	</summary>
</bill>
