<bill session="110" type="h" number="6819" updated="2009-01-09T06:53:26-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"/></status>

	<introduced date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Medicare Improvements for Patients and Providers Act of 2008 to eliminate certain inappropriate changes in law made to the Medicare Advantage program.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412190"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400123" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400297" joined="2008-08-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"><text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/1/2008--Introduced.<br/>Amends the Medicare Improvements for Patients and Providers Act of 2008 (MIPPA) to repeal provisions relating to: (1) the requirement for certain nonemployer Medicare Advantage (MA) private fee-for-service plans to use contracts with providers; (2) the moratorium on authority to designate other plans as specialized MA plans for special needs individuals; (3) the limitation on out-of-pocket costs for dual eligibles and qualified Medicare beneficiaries enrolled in a specialized MA plan for special needs individuals; (4) access to Medicare reasonable cost reimbursement contract plans, especially the prohibition on extension of such a contract in certain circumstances; and (5) the requirement for a study and report to Congress by the Comptroller General of the reasons (if any) why reasonable cost contracts are unable to become MA plans. Restores the corresponding provisions of the Social Security Act as they were before the amendments made by MIPPA.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
