<bill session="110" type="h" number="6822" updated="2009-01-09T06:53:46-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"/></status>

	<introduced date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Legislative Branch Personnel Appeals Procedural Consolidation Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require appeals of personnel actions involving the officers and employees of the Government Accountability Office to be considered by the Office of Special Counsel and the Merit Systems Protection Board in the same manner as appeals of prohibited personnel practices involving employees of Executive agencies under title 5, United States Code, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400295"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1696)</text></action>
		<action date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/1/2008--Introduced.<br/>Legislative Branch Personnel Appeals Procedural Consolidation Act of 2008 - Transfers from the Government Accountability Office (GAO) Personnel Appeals Board to the Office of Special Counsel (OSC) authority to investigate any personnel action taken with respect to a GAO officer or employee, or an officer or employee of a participating federal office, and seek corrective and disciplinary action with respect to such personnel action, in the same manner and subject to the same terms and conditions as if such officer or employee were an executive agency employee and such action were a prohibited practice against them. Authorizes the officer or employee to seek corrective and disciplinary action with respect to such an action from the OSC and the Merit Systems Protection Board in the same manner and subject to the same terms. Excludes current appeals by GAO officers and employees from the provisions of this Act. (Thus, allows such appeals to be considered by the GAO Personnel Appeals Board.)<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
