<bill session="110" type="h" number="6827" updated="2009-01-09T06:54:20-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"/></status>

	<introduced date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Enable Divestment from Sudan and Iran Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for rollover of gain from divesting certain qualified securities of business entities engaged in Iran or Sudan discouraged activities.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400371"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400222" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400092" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400122" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400344" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412192" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400055" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400208" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400024" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400025" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412011" joined="2008-08-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/1/2008--Introduced.<br/>Enable Divestment from Sudan and Iran Act of 2008 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to promote the divestment of investments in Iran or the Sudan by pemitting the deferral of tax on any gain from the sale of securities in any business that is engaged in certain discouraged activities in Iran or the Sudan if the holder of such securities purchases replacement securities from a business not engaged in such discouraged activities. Includes as discouraged activities in Iran: (1) the sale of munitions to the Iranian government; (2) loans aggregating more than $20 million to the Iranian government; (3) investments of over $20 million in the Iranian energy sector; or (4) conducting business with or making charitable donations to any Iranian person designated as a terrorist. Defines &quot;Sudan discouraged activity&quot; as an investment in any business operation described in the Sudan Accountability and Divestment Act of 2007 (e.g., businesses engaged in power production activities, mineral extraction activities, oil-related activities, or the production of military equipment).<br/>Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to publish and update every six months a list of business entities engaging in any Sudan or Iran discouraged activities. 
	</summary>
</bill>
