<bill session="110" type="h" number="6825" updated="2009-01-09T06:54:05-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"/></status>

	<introduced date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to assess the irrigation infrastructure of the Pine River Indian Irrigation Project in the State of Colorado, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400620"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1217995200" datetime="2008-08-06"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/1/2008--Introduced.<br/>Directs the Secretary of the Interior to study the irrigation infrastructure of the Pine River Indian Irrigation Project, Colorado, and develop a list of improvements to repair, rehabilitate, or reconstruct the Project over a 10-year period.<br/>Requires the Secretary to prioritize improvements based on: (1) recommendations of the Southern Ute Indian Tribe; (2) cost-benefit analyses; (3) the ability of the Project's users to irrigate agricultural land using the Project's irrigation infrastructure; (4) the effect on water conservation; (5) the cultural benefits that the improvements would have on the Tribe; and (6) the opportunity to address water supply or environmental conflicts.<br/>Authorizes the Secretary to provide grants to, and enter into cooperative agreements with, the Tribe in order to repair, rehabilitate, reconstruct, or replace the Project's irrigation infrastructure. Prohibits such a grant or agreement from being used for the repair, rehabilitation, or reconstruction of any major impoundment structure or for on-farm improvements.<br/>Requires the Secretary, in carrying out a grant or cooperative agreement, to: (1) consult with the Tribe and the Director of the Bureau of Indian Affairs (BIA) and obtain the Tribe's approval; and (2) coordinate the project with any work being conducted under the BIA's irrigation operations and maintenance program. Authorizes the Secretary to require the Tribe to provide nonfederal funds to match not less than 25% of the total amount of a grant or agreement.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
