<bill session="110" type="h" number="6846" updated="2009-01-09T06:56:37-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1220932800" datetime="2008-09-09"/></status>

	<introduced date="1220932800" datetime="2008-09-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Iraq Security Agreement Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure that any agreement with Iraq containing a security commitment or arrangement is concluded as a treaty or is approved by Congress.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400237"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400661" joined="2008-09-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2008-09-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400257" joined="2008-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2008-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="2008-09-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2008-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400663" joined="2008-09-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-09-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2008-09-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400013" joined="2008-09-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400422" joined="2008-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2008-09-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2008-09-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1220932800" datetime="2008-09-09"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1220932800" datetime="2008-09-09"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1220932800" datetime="2008-09-09"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1220932800" datetime="2008-09-09"><text>Referred to House Rules</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/9/2008--Introduced.<br/>Iraq Security Agreement Act of 2008 - Directs the President to report annually to the appropriate congressional committees respecting U.S. security commitments to, and arrangements with, other countries. Directs the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Defense to consult with the appropriate congressional committees respecting negotiations pursuant to the Declaration of Principles between the United States and Iraq. Prohibits any agreement (or the obligation of implementing funds) containing a security commitment to, or security arrangement with, the Republic of Iraq, from entering into force except pursuant to Article II, section 2, clause 2 (relating to treaties) or Article I, section 7, clause 2 (relating to enactment of laws) of the Constitution of the United States.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
