<bill session="110" type="h" number="6852" updated="2009-01-09T06:57:19-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1220932800" datetime="2008-09-09"/></status>

	<introduced date="1220932800" datetime="2008-09-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Community Protection and Response Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to improve Federal response efforts after a terrorist strike or other major disaster affecting homeland security, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400251"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400366" joined="2008-09-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1220932800" datetime="2008-09-09"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1731)</text></action>
		<action date="1220932800" datetime="2008-09-09"><text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1220932800" datetime="2008-09-09"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1220932800" datetime="2008-09-09"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1220932800" datetime="2008-09-09"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Hazardous Materials .</text></action>
		<action date="1220932800" datetime="2008-09-09"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1220932800" datetime="2008-09-09"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1221019200" datetime="2008-09-10"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text></action>
		<action date="1221019200" datetime="2008-09-10"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text></action>
		<action date="1221019200" datetime="2008-09-10"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text></action>
		<action date="1221019200" datetime="2008-09-10"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/9/2008--Introduced.<br/>Community Protection and Response Act of 2008 - Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to include a terrorist attack, dispersion of radioactive or other contaminants, dispersion of hazardous substances, or other catastrophic event as a &quot;major disaster&quot; eligible for relief under the Act. Includes as a &quot;public facility&quot; for purposes of damages coverage in a major disaster private for-profit telecommunications, phone services, and utilities when losses occur during a homeland security event and are not covered by insurance. Authorizes the President, at the request of a state governor, to declare that a major disaster constitutes a homeland security event and is of such severity and magnitude that effective response is beyond the capacity of the affected state and local government. Provides specified federal assistance under the Act upon such a declaration, including reimbursement and grant assistance for lost compensation, sustained losses, and required repairs. Includes as critical services under the Act education systems, providers of counseling, and providers of assistance to the homeless.<br/>Removes the $5 million limit on community disaster loans provided under the Act. Requires or provides for: (1) standards for reporting information concerning disasters involving homeland security events; (2) a special commission to review air quality following a homeland security event; (3) guidelines concerning health risks associated with the release of materials following a homeland security event and associated monitoring and analysis; and (4) grants for data collection during public health emergencies, research on assisting victims, advance preparation for public health emergencies, and disaster relief for local educational agencies.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
