<bill session="110" type="h" number="6867" updated="2009-01-09T06:59:04-05:00">
	<status><enacted date="1227243600" datetime="2008-11-21" /></status>

	<introduced date="1221019200" datetime="2008-09-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Unemployment Compensation Extension Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Unemployment Compensation Extension Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">Unemployment Compensation Extension Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="enacted">Unemployment Compensation Extension Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for additional emergency unemployment compensation.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400262"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400123" joined="2008-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400227" joined="2008-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400177" joined="2008-10-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400333" joined="2008-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="412195" joined="2008-10-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2008-10-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400324" joined="2008-10-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-10-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412227" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400110" joined="2008-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412211" joined="2008-10-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412262" joined="2008-10-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412222" joined="2008-10-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412204" joined="2008-10-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412200" joined="2008-10-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412228" joined="2008-10-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412257" joined="2008-10-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400238" joined="2008-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="2008-09-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1221019200" datetime="2008-09-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action date="1223051940" datetime="2008-10-03T13:39:00-04:00"><text>ORDER OF BUSINESS - Mr. Rangel asked unanimous consent that it be in order today for the Speaker to entertain motions to suspend the rules relating to H.R. 6867. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action date="1223051940" datetime="2008-10-03T13:39:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Rangel moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1223051940" datetime="2008-10-03T13:39:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H10808-10814"/></action>
		<action date="1223051940" datetime="2008-10-03T13:39:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 6867.</text></action>
		<vote date="1223055960" how="roll" roll="683" datetime="2008-10-03T14:46:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" suspension="1" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 368 - 28 (Roll no. 683).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H10808-10809"/></vote>
		<action date="1226898000" datetime="2008-11-17"><text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text></action>
		<action date="1226984400" datetime="2008-11-18"><text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1123 under authority of the order of the Senate of 11/17/2008.</text></action>
		<action date="1227070800" datetime="2008-11-19"><text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure made in Senate.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S10627-10628"/></action>
		<action date="1227070800" datetime="2008-11-19"><text>Cloture motion on the motion to proceed to the measure presented in Senate.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S10627-10628"/><reference label="text" ref="CR S10627"/></action>
		<action date="1227157200" datetime="2008-11-20"><text>Cloture on the motion to proceed to the measure invoked in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 89 - 6. Record Vote Number: 214.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S10701-10702"/><reference label="text" ref="CR S10701"/></action>
		<action date="1227157200" datetime="2008-11-20"><text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure agreed to in Senate.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S10701-10702"/></action>
		<action date="1227157200" datetime="2008-11-20"><text>Measure laid before Senate by motion.</text></action>
		<vote date="1227157200" how="by Voice Vote" datetime="2008-11-20" where="s" type="vote2" result="pass" ><text>Passed Senate without amendment by Voice Vote.</text></vote>
		<action date="1227157200" datetime="2008-11-20"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<topresident date="1227157200" datetime="2008-11-20" ><text>Cleared for White House.</text></topresident>
		<topresident date="1227157200" datetime="2008-11-20" ><text>Presented to President.</text></topresident>
		<signed date="1227243600" datetime="2008-11-21" ><text>Signed by President.</text></signed>
		<enacted number="110-449" date="1227243600" datetime="2008-11-21" type="public" ><text>Became Public Law No: 110-449.</text></enacted>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/21/2008--Public Law. (This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the House on October 3, 2008. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Unemployment Compensation Extension Act of 2008 - Amends the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2008 to revise the formula for Tier-1 amounts a state credits to an applicant's emergency unemployment compensation account (EUCA) for a benefit year. Increases the figures in the formula (the lesser of which shall be the amount credited): (1) from 50% to 80% of the total amount of regular compensation (including dependents' allowances) payable to the individual during the benefit year; and (2) from 13 to 20 times the individual's average weekly benefit amount for the benefit year. Provides an additional Tier-2 period for deposits to an individual's EUCA, using the current formula, if, at the time that the amount established under this Act is exhausted, or at any time thereafter, the individual's state is in an extended benefit period. Prescribes a formula for determining if a state is in an extended benefit period. Allows the Tier-2 period augmentation to be applied to the individual's EUCA only once. Prohibits a Tier-2 augmentation to an individual's EUCA under this Act after March 31, 2009, if the EUCA is exhausted after such date. Extends the period of emergency unemployment compensation through August 27, 2009. Exempts weeks of unemployment between enactment of this Act and December 8, 2009, from the prohibition in the Federal-State Extended Unemployment Compensation Act of 1970 against federal matching payments to a state for the first week in an individual's eligibility period for which extended compensation or sharable regular compensation is paid if the state law of such state provides for payment (at any time or under any circumstances) of regular compensation to an individual for his first week of otherwise compensable unemployment. (Thus allows temporary federal matching for the first week of extended benefits for states with no waiting period.)<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
