<bill session="110" type="h" number="6871" updated="2009-01-09T06:59:31-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16" /></status>

	<introduced date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Expedited Funds Availability Dollar Limits Adjustment Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Expedited Funds Availability Dollar Limits Adjustment Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Expedited Funds Availability Act to provide a 1-time adjustment in certain dollar amounts to account for inflation over the 21 years since the enactment of such Act, to provide for future adjustments of such amounts on a regular basis, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400251"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="2008-09-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400371" joined="2008-09-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1772)</text></action>
		<action date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text></action>
		<action date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16" ><text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1228850640" datetime="2008-12-09T15:24:00-05:00"><text>Reported by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 110-917.</text></action>
		<calendar number="592" date="1228850940" datetime="2008-12-09T15:29:00-05:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 592.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	12/9/2008--Reported to House without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)<br/>Expedited Funds Availability Dollar Limits Adjustment Act of 2008 - Amends the Expedited Funds Availability Act to increase: (1) from $100 to $175 the amount of a federal, state, or local government check that is available for next business day withdrawal; and (2) from $400 to $700 the maximum cash amount of non-government checks available for 5 p.m. withdrawal.<br/>Directs the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System to make cost-of-living adjustments to such amounts every five years. 
	</summary>
</bill>
