<bill session="110" type="h" number="6890" updated="2009-01-09T07:01:45-05:00">
	<status><enacted date="1223438400" datetime="2008-10-08" /></status>

	<introduced date="1221451200" datetime="2008-09-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To extend the waiver authority for the Secretary of Education under section 105 of subtitle A of title IV of division B of Public Law 109-148, relating to elementary and secondary education hurricane recovery relief.</title>
		<title type="official" as="amended by house">To extend the waiver authority for the Secretary of Education under section 105 of subtitle A of title IV of division B of Public Law 109-148, relating to elementary and secondary education hurricane recovery relief, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400635"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412260" joined="2008-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400261" joined="2008-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412261" joined="2008-09-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400006" joined="2008-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400201" joined="2008-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400636" joined="2008-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="2008-09-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1221451200" datetime="2008-09-15"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1222106400" datetime="2008-09-22T15:00:00-04:00"><text>Mrs. Davis (CA) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1222106400" datetime="2008-09-22T15:00:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8525-8527"/></action>
		<action date="1222106400" datetime="2008-09-22T15:00:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 6890.</text></action>
		<vote date="1222106880" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-09-22T15:08:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H8525-8526"/></vote>
		<action date="1222106880" datetime="2008-09-22T15:08:00-04:00"><text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action date="1222056000" datetime="2008-09-22"><text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text></action>
		<vote date="1222315200" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2008-09-25" where="s" type="vote2" result="pass" ><text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S9551"/></vote>
		<topresident date="1222315200" datetime="2008-09-25" ><text>Cleared for White House.</text></topresident>
		<action date="1222401600" datetime="2008-09-26"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<topresident date="1222660800" datetime="2008-09-29" ><text>Presented to President.</text></topresident>
		<signed date="1223438400" datetime="2008-10-08" ><text>Signed by President.</text></signed>
		<enacted number="110-366" date="1223438400" datetime="2008-10-08" type="public" ><text>Became Public Law No: 110-366.</text></enacted>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/8/2008--Public Law. (This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the House of Representatives on September 22, 2008. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Amends the Hurricane Education Recovery Act, title IV of division B of the Department of Defense, Emergency Supplemental Appropriations to Address Hurricanes in the Gulf of Mexico, and Pandemic Influenza Act, 2006, with respect to elementary and secondary education hurricane recovery relief. Extends through FY2009 the authority of the Secretary of Education, in providing any grant or other assistance to an entity in a state which in 2005 suffered a major disaster related to Hurricane Katrina or Hurricane Rita, to waive or modify, in order to ease fiscal burdens, any elementary and secondary education assistance requirement relating to: (1) maintenance of effort; (2) use of federal funds to supplement, not supplant, non-federal funds; or (3) any non-federal share or capital contribution required to match federal funds. Protects local educational agencies that serve areas in which a major disaster has been declared in 2008 related to severe storms, tornadoes, or flooding in the Midwest or hurricanes in the Gulf of Mexico, from experiencing a FY2009 reduction of school improvement funds under part A of title I (Improving the Academic Achievement of the Disadvantaged) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
