<bill session="110" type="h" number="6903" updated="2009-01-09T07:03:14-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1221451200" datetime="2008-09-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1221451200" datetime="2008-09-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Bruce Vento Ban Asbestos and Prevent Mesothelioma Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Toxic Substances Control Act to reduce the health risks posed by asbestos-containing products, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400160"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400616" joined="2008-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400384" joined="2008-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400663" joined="2008-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400259" joined="2008-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400013" joined="2008-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2008-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2008-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400062" joined="2008-09-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1221451200" datetime="2008-09-15"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1809-1810)</text></action>
		<action date="1221451200" datetime="2008-09-15"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1221451200" datetime="2008-09-15"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/15/2008--Introduced.<br/>Bruce Vento Ban Asbestos and Prevent Mesothelioma Act of 2008 - Amends the Toxic Substances Control Act to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish a plan and initiate a program to: (1) increase awareness of the dangers posed by asbestos-containing products in homes and workplaces and by asbestos-related diseases; (2) provide information to, and encourage participation in research and treatment endeavors by, asbestos-related disease patients and their families and front-line health care providers; and (3) encourage health care providers and researchers to provide to patients and their families information relating to research, diagnostic, and clinical treatments relating to asbestos.<br/>Prohibits any person from importing, manufacturing, processing, or distributing asbestos-containing products, subject to limited exemption upon petition and specified exemptions sought by the Department of Defense (DOD) and the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA). Sets forth exceptions for specified levels of asbestos with respect to: (1) chlor-alkali electrolysis installations or caustic soda produced at such installations; (2) aggregate products (extracted from stone, sand, or gravel operations) that are imported, manufactured, processed, or distributed in commerce for use as an integral part of specified cemented materials; (3) calcium carbonate, olivine, talc, vermiculite, and wollastonite; and (4) taconite pellets or iron ore that will be used to produce such pellets (but the prohibition does apply to tailings, waste material, or other byproducts of iron ore extraction).<br/>Provides that such prohibitions shall apply to any asbestos-containing calcium carbonate, olivine, talc, vermiculite, and wollastonite imported, manufactured, processed, or distributed in commerce for use in or for processing: (1) food that is intended for human consumption; (2) products used by individuals for personal health or cosmetic reasons; (3) drugs for human use; (4) consumer garden products; (5) cosmetics; (6) products designed or intended primarily for use by children 12 years old or younger; or (7) other products with such asbestos-containing materials that endanger human health or the environment.<br/>Requires the disposal of asbestos-containing products within three years after enactment of this Act.<br/>Provides for: (1) criminal penalties for violations; and (2) citizen petitions to the Administrator to initiate a proceeding for the issuance, amendment, or repeal of a rule or order under such Act.<br/>Declares that nothing in this Act: (1) preempts state or federal law; (2) creates a cause of action or increases or diminishes the liability of persons under other laws; or (3) prohibits the importation, manufacture, processing, or distribution in commerce of drinking water in a manner that complies with the Safe Drinking Water Act.<br/>Revises the definition of &quot;asbestos&quot; to include winchite and richterite asbestos and asbestiform amphibole mineral.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
