<bill session="110" type="h" number="6919" updated="2009-01-09T07:05:04-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1221624000" datetime="2008-09-17"/></status>

	<introduced date="1221624000" datetime="2008-09-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the conveyance of certain property from the United States to the Maniilaq Association located in Kotzebue, Alaska.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400440"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1221624000" datetime="2008-09-17"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1818)</text></action>
		<action date="1221624000" datetime="2008-09-17"><text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1221624000" datetime="2008-09-17"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1221624000" datetime="2008-09-17"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1221624000" datetime="2008-09-17"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
		<action date="1221624000" datetime="2008-09-17"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/17/2008--Introduced.<br/>Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HSS) to convey the Maniilaq Health Center, Garage and Activity Center and specified staff quarters to the Maniilaq Association in Kotzebue, Alaska, for use in connection with health and social services programs. Shields the Maniilaq Association from liability for any soil, surface water, groundwater, or other contamination on any of the property described above. Accords the Secretary any easement or access to the conveyed property as may be reasonably necessary to satisfy any retained obligations and liability of the Secretary. 
	</summary>
</bill>
