<bill session="110" type="h" number="6941" updated="2009-01-09T07:07:37-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1221710400" datetime="2008-09-18"/></status>

	<introduced date="1221710400" datetime="2008-09-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Measuring American Poverty Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XI of the Social Security Act to provide for an improved method to measure poverty so as to enable a better assessment of the effects of programs under the Social Security Act, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400262"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400290" joined="2008-11-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400423" joined="2008-11-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="2008-11-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400251" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2008-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="412186" joined="2008-12-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1221710400" datetime="2008-09-18"><text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1221710400" datetime="2008-09-18"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1221710400" datetime="2008-09-18"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/18/2008--Introduced.<br/>Measuring American Poverty Act of 2008 - Amends part A of title XI of the Social Security Act to direct the Bureau of the Census, in collaboration with the Bureau of Labor Statistics, to calculate modern poverty thresholds and modern poverty rates for each calendar year. Declares that the modern poverty threshold for a reference family consisting of two adults and their two related children shall be an amount equal to the average of 120% of the 33rd percentile of the distribution of annual expenditures by such families on food, clothing, and shelter during each of the three most recent years for which data is available from the Consumer Expenditure Survey, a superior federal government source of data, or some combination of such sources. Prescribes requirements for determining modern poverty rates. Directs the Bureau of the Census, in collaboration with the Bureau of Labor Statistics (BLS), to contract with the National Academy of Sciences (NAS) to develop and publish methods of: (1) calculating a decent living standard threshold; and (2) measuring the extent to which the income of families in the United States is sufficient to meet it. Directs the Bureau of the Census, in collaboration with BLS, the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality, and the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services to contract with NAS to develop and publish a method of: (1) measuring the extent of medical care risk in the United States; and (2) calculating the number and percentage of individuals in the United States who lack adequate health insurance, leaving them at risk of being unable to afford needed treatment. 
	</summary>
</bill>
