<bill session="110" type="h" number="6944" updated="2009-01-09T07:07:58-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1221710400" datetime="2008-09-18"/></status>

	<introduced date="1221710400" datetime="2008-09-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Midewin National Tallgrass Prairie Expansion Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To transfer administrative jurisdiction over the Joliet Training Area in Will County, Illinois, to the Secretary of Agriculture for inclusion in the Midewin National Tallgrass Prairie, to provide for the conveyance of several parcels of the Joliet Training Area, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400429"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1221710400" datetime="2008-09-18"><text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, Transportation and Infrastructure, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1221710400" datetime="2008-09-18"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1221710400" datetime="2008-09-18"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action date="1221710400" datetime="2008-09-18"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1221710400" datetime="2008-09-18"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1221710400" datetime="2008-09-18"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
		<action date="1221796800" datetime="2008-09-19"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/18/2008--Introduced.<br/>Midewin National Tallgrass Prairie Expansion Act of 2008 - Transfers administrative jurisdiction over the Joliet Training Area (JTA) from the Secretary of the Army to the Secretary of Agriculture. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to convey a specified parcel of land to Will County, Illinois. Requires the deed for such land to contain restrictive covenants enforceable by such Secretary for the benefit of the appurtenant federal lands and the Midewin National Tallgrass Prairie. Requires the conveyed lands to only be used for: (1) parks and recreation; (2) firing ranges for small arms; (3) office and training facilities for fire fighters, police, and emergency personnel; (4) public safety facilities (but not for incarceration); and (5) offices for county and municipal governments. Prohibits the use of such lands for industrial or commercial purposes. Provides for environmental remediation of the lands conveyed to the county. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to convey to CenterPoint Properties, LLC, an easement to specified lands to permit the construction of roads and railroads for access to appurtenant properties. Provides for certain cash payments. Requires the Secretary of the Army to provide a preliminary assessment/site inspection to the Secretary of Agriculture for the lands comprising the JTA and to develop plans for remediation of the recognized environmental conditions identified by the preliminary assessment/site inspection.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
