<bill session="110" type="h" number="6955" updated="2009-01-09T07:09:16-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1221710400" datetime="2008-09-18"/></status>

	<introduced date="1221710400" datetime="2008-09-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Taxpayer Reimbursement Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To suspend contributions by the Federal National Mortgage Association and Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation to the Housing Trust Fund during any conservatorship of such enterprises and to ensure full repayment to the Federal Government for costs of any such conservatorship and costs of HOPE for Homeowners program.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400016"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400627" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400367" joined="2008-09-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412252" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400626" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400209" joined="2008-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400089" joined="2008-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400441" joined="2008-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400116" joined="2008-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2008-09-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400433" joined="2008-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400010" joined="2008-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400017" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400051" joined="2008-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400655" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400368" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400644" joined="2008-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400221" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400145" joined="2008-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400315" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400651" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400141" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="412191" joined="2008-10-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412202" joined="2008-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400252" joined="2008-09-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1221710400" datetime="2008-09-18"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/18/2008--Introduced.<br/>Taxpayer Reimbursement Act of 2008 - Amends the Federal Housing Enterprises Financial Safety and Soundness Act of 1992, as amended by the Federal Housing Finance Regulatory Reform Act of 2008, to require the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency to suspend temporarily any allocations by the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae) or the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac) upon: (1) the appointment of a conservator or receiver, and for the duration of a conservatorship or receivership; or (2) a finding that the federal government has not been fully reimbursed for the costs of such a conservatorship. Repeals the reduced percentages for calendar years 2010 and 2011 to require the use of 100% of certain Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac allocations to reimburse the Treasury for payments on bonds of the HOPE for Homeowners Program for calendar 2009-2001. Suspends the annual goals and duties established for Fannie Mae or Freddie Mac during any period it is in conservatorship or receivership. 
	</summary>
</bill>
