<bill session="110" type="h" number="6994" updated="2009-01-09T07:13:43-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1222056000" datetime="2008-09-22"/></status>

	<introduced date="1222056000" datetime="2008-09-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Tule River Tribe Water Development Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a study on the feasibility and suitability of constructing a storage reservoir, outlet works, and a delivery system for the Tule River Indian Tribe of California to provide a water supply for domestic, municipal, industrial, and agricultural purposes, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400297"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1222056000" datetime="2008-09-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1222315200" datetime="2008-09-25"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/22/2008--Introduced.<br/>Tule River Tribe Water Development Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Reclamation, to complete a feasibility study to evaluate alternatives for a domestic, commercial, municipal, industrial, and irrigation water supply for the Tule River Tribe of the Tule River Reservation.<br/>Prohibits any project constructed in relation to that study from providing water supplies for the current tribal casino, an expansion of the current tribal casino, or any other tribal casino, including any current or future lodging, dining, entertainment, meeting space, parking, or other similar facilities in support of gaming activities. Requires water supplies provided from such a project to be available to serve the domestic, municipal, and governmental (including firefighting) needs of the tribe and its members and other commercial, agricultural, and industrial needs unrelated to gaming activities.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
