<bill session="110" type="h" number="6992" updated="2009-01-09T07:13:29-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1222056000" datetime="2008-09-22"/></status>

	<introduced date="1222056000" datetime="2008-09-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Reclamation Title Transfer Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to establish a program to facilitate the transfer to non-Federal ownership of appropriate reclamation projects or facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400659"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400618" joined="2008-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412230" joined="2008-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412217" joined="2008-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400029" joined="2008-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412201" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400440" joined="2008-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412191" joined="2008-09-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1222056000" datetime="2008-09-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1222228800" datetime="2008-09-24"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text></action>
		<action date="1222315200" datetime="2008-09-25"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/22/2008--Introduced.<br/>Reclamation Title Transfer Act of 2008 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to establish a program to: (1) identify and analyze the potential for public benefits from the transfer out of federal ownership of eligible reclamation projects or facilities; and (2) facilitate such transfer to promote more efficient management of water and water-related facilities.<br/>Authorizes the Secretary to convey title in any such facility to a qualifying entity (including an agency of a state or local government or Indian tribe, a municipal corporation, or another entity such as a water district), provided that: (1) the Secretary retains any associated mineral interests; (2) water interests are conveyed by written agreement; and (3) interests in eligible facilities are conveyed by an agreement developed in consultation with the facility's existing power customers.<br/>Requires the Secretary to: (1) complete all actions required under all applicable laws (including environmental and historic preservation laws) before conveying land and facilities; and (2) establish criteria for determining whether facilities are eligible for title transfer, including requirements that a qualifying entity agrees to accept title to the property and that the proposed title transfer will not have an unmitigated significant effect on the environment.<br/>Shields the United States from liability for any act, omission, or occurrence based on its prior ownership or operation of the conveyed property. Requires a recipient entity to comply with all applicable laws and regulations in its operation of conveyed property. 
	</summary>
</bill>
