<bill session="110" type="h" number="7002" updated="2009-01-09T07:14:37-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1222142400" datetime="2008-09-23"/></status>

	<introduced date="1222142400" datetime="2008-09-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Making Opportunities Via Efficient and More Effective National Transportation Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">MOVEMENT Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Transportation to establish and collect a national container fee and to use amounts collected from the fee to make grants for infrastructure projects at United States seaports and in surrounding areas to improve the movement of goods, enhance transportation security, and mitigate environmental damage caused by the movement of goods.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412253"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1222142400" datetime="2008-09-23"><text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1222142400" datetime="2008-09-23"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1222142400" datetime="2008-09-23"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1222142400" datetime="2008-09-23"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1222228800" datetime="2008-09-24"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text></action>
		<action date="1222228800" datetime="2008-09-24"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text></action>
		<action date="1222228800" datetime="2008-09-24"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/23/2008--Introduced.<br/>Making Opportunities Via Efficient and More Effective National Transportation Act of 2008 or the MOVEMENT Act of 2008 - Directs the Secretary of Transportation to establish a national container fee to be collected on each cargo container imported into, or exported from, a covered U.S. seaport. Establishes the National Goods Movement Improvement Account in which such fees shall be deposited. Directs the Secretary to carry out a National Goods Movement Improvement Grant Program to provide grant funding for eligible projects, including goods movement improvement, homeland security, and environmental projects located at or near a covered U.S. seaport. 
	</summary>
</bill>
