<bill session="110" type="h" number="7018" updated="2009-01-09T07:16:26-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1222142400" datetime="2008-09-23"/></status>

	<introduced date="1222142400" datetime="2008-09-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">21st Century Energy Technology Deployment Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To promote development of a 21st century energy system to increase United States competitiveness in the world energy technology marketplace, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400193"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412192" joined="2008-09-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="412198" joined="2008-09-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400195" joined="2008-09-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1222142400" datetime="2008-09-23"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1222142400" datetime="2008-09-23"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1222142400" datetime="2008-09-23"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text></action>
		<action date="1222142400" datetime="2008-09-23"><text>Referred to House Financial Services</text></action>
		<action date="1222142400" datetime="2008-09-23"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/23/2008--Introduced.<br/>21st Century Energy Technology Deployment Act - Directs the Secretary of Energy, after consultation with the Energy Technology Advisory Council of the 21st Century Energy Deployment Corporation (both established by this Act), to develop and publish near-, medium-, and long-term goals for the deployment of clean energy technologies through the Corporation to establish or promote specified energy generation, transmission, and use and energy technology manufacturing capacities.<br/>Requires the Advisory Council to publish 5- and 10-year performance targets and to establish initial targets until those are published.<br/>Allows the Corporation to purchase, and make commitments to purchase, debt instruments associated with the deployment of clean energy technologies. Describes lending authorities of the Corporation. Allows the Corporation to issue securities for purchase by the Secretary of the Treasury.<br/>Requires annual reports to Congress on the technologies supported and on Corporation performance. Requires the Secretary to oversee Corporation operations and finances.<br/>Allows the Corporation to prepare a strategic plan to issue common stock to enable expansion of its operations and requires the plan to include consideration of Board restructuring alternatives.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
