<bill session="110" type="h" number="7016" updated="2009-01-09T07:16:12-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1222142400" datetime="2008-09-23"/></status>

	<introduced date="1222142400" datetime="2008-09-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Susan B. Anthony Prenatal Nondiscrimination Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit discrimination against the unborn on the basis of sex or race, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400141"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400381" joined="2008-09-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400630" joined="2008-09-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400640" joined="2008-09-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400399" joined="2008-09-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400315" joined="2008-09-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1222142400" datetime="2008-09-23"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/23/2008--Introduced.<br/>Susan B. Anthony Prenatal Nondiscrimination Act of 2008 - Imposes criminal penalties for knowingly: (1) performing an abortion knowing that the abortion is sought based on the sex, gender, color or race of the child, or the race of a parent; (2) using force or the threat of force to intentionally injure or intimidate any person for the purpose of coercing a sex-selection or race-selection abortion; or (3) soliciting or accepting funds to finance a sex-selection abortion or a race-selection abortion. Provides for injunctive relief and the loss of federal funding. Provides for a private right of action for appropriate relief: (1) for the father if he is married to the mother at the time she has such an abortion; or (2) for the maternal grandparents of the unborn child if the mother is under 18 at the time of the abortion. Declares that appropriate relief includes money damages for all injuries, whether psychological, physical, or financial, including loss of companionship and support. Requires a medical or mental health professional to report known or suspected violations to law enforcement authorities. Imposes criminal penalties for a failure to so report. Prohibits a woman having such an abortion from being prosecuted or held civilly liable. Excludes from the definition of &quot;abortion&quot; actions taken to terminate a pregnancy if the intent is to save the life or preserve the health of the unborn child, remove a dead unborn child caused by spontaneous abortion, or remove an ectopic pregnancy.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
