<bill session="110" type="h" number="7032" updated="2009-01-09T07:18:05-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1222228800" datetime="2008-09-24"/></status>

	<introduced date="1222228800" datetime="2008-09-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To improve interagency coordination and cooperation in the processing of Federal permits for production of domestic oil and gas resources.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400018"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400367" joined="2008-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400414" joined="2008-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400089" joined="2008-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400165" joined="2008-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400288" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400392" joined="2008-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400039" joined="2008-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400655" joined="2008-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400400" joined="2008-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400404" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400654" joined="2008-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400341" joined="2008-09-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1222228800" datetime="2008-09-24"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1222660800" datetime="2008-09-29"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/24/2008--Introduced.<br/>Establishes the Office of the Federal Oil and Gas Permit Coordinator, headed by a Federal Permit Coordinator, to: (1) coordinate permitting activities by federal and state agencies regarding any oil and gas project under a federal lease either onshore or on the Outer Continental Shelf (OCS), including oil shale projects; and (2) ensure the compliance of participating federal and state agencies. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to establish regional offices to coordinate review of federal permits for oil and gas projects on federal lands onshore and on the OCS. Sets forth a schedule for federal agency review of oil and gas applications for: (1) Class I permits, that require preparation of an environmental impact statement to inform the permitting decision; (2) Class II permits, for activities that would not significantly affect the quality of the human environment; and (3) Class III permits, for activities that qualify for a statutory or regulatory categorical exclusion under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969. Prescribes dispute resolution procedures governing oil and gas permit reviews. Empowers the Regional Permit Coordinator to resolve all administrative issues affecting such reviews. Directs the Regional Permit Coordinators to facilitate and coordinate concurrent state reviews of permits for oil and gas projects in the state or on an adjacent portion of the OCS. Grants the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia exclusive original jurisdiction over any civil action for the review of a permit decision. 
	</summary>
</bill>
