<bill session="110" type="h" number="7041" updated="2009-01-09T07:19:06-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1222228800" datetime="2008-09-24"/></status>

	<introduced date="1222228800" datetime="2008-09-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Laboratory Surge Capacity Preparedness Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of Homeland Security to award grants on a competitive basis to regional biocontainment laboratories for maintaining surge capacity that can be used to respond to acts of bioterrorism or outbreaks of infectious diseases, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412234"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400616" joined="2008-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400183" joined="2008-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400647" joined="2008-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412231" joined="2008-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400285" joined="2008-09-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400130" joined="2008-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2008-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400010" joined="2008-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400308" joined="2008-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400266" joined="2008-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2008-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2008-09-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400114" joined="2008-09-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1222228800" datetime="2008-09-24"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1222228800" datetime="2008-09-24"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1222228800" datetime="2008-09-24"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1222228800" datetime="2008-09-24"><text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text></action>
		<action date="1222660800" datetime="2008-09-29"><committee name="House Homeland Security"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emergency Communications, Preparedness, and Response.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/24/2008--Introduced.<br/>Laboratory Surge Capacity Preparedness Act - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to award grants to regional biocontainment laboratories for maintaining surge capacity that can be used to respond to acts of bioterrorism or outbreaks of infectious diseases. Authorizes the Secretary to award such a grant only if the laboratory agrees to allow the Secretary and other relevant federal agencies to inspect laboratory facilities.<br/>Requires the Secretary to report to Congress on: (1) activities undertaken to integrate the network of regional biocontainment laboratories with the laboratory response network of the Center for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC); and (2) the extent to which additional Biosafety Level 3 laboratories are needed to fulfill the national's laboratory surge capacity needs.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
