<bill session="110" type="h" number="7071" updated="2009-01-09T07:22:36-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1222315200" datetime="2008-09-25"/></status>

	<introduced date="1222315200" datetime="2008-09-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Agency Program Realignment and Closure Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a commission to recommend the elimination or realignment of Federal agencies that are duplicative or perform functions that would be more efficient on a non-Federal level, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400392"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412252" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400151" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="412230" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="409888" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400017" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="412201" joined="2008-10-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400005" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400221" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="412213" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400651" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400141" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="412191" joined="2008-10-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1222315200" datetime="2008-09-25"><text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1222315200" datetime="2008-09-25"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1222315200" datetime="2008-09-25"><text>Referred to House Rules</text></action>
		<action date="1222488000" datetime="2008-09-27"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2076)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/25/2008--Introduced.<br/>Federal Agency Program Realignment and Closure Act - Establishes the Federal Agency Program Realignment and Closure Commission to: (1) evaluate each executive agency and its programs; and (2) submit to the President and Congress a list of the agencies and programs it recommends eliminating or realigning.<br/>Requires the Commission to recommend that an agency or program be: (1) realigned where a function performed by two or more agencies or programs can be consolidated; (2) eliminated if it performs a function that is also provided by a state or that would be more efficient if performed at the state level; or (3) eliminated if it performs a function that can be more efficently performed by a private entity.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
