<bill session="110" type="h" number="707" updated="2009-01-08T18:17:41-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1170046800" datetime="2007-01-29"/></status>

	<introduced date="1170046800" datetime="2007-01-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Chattahoochee National Forest Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Mountaintown National Scenic Area in the Chattahoochee National Forest, Georgia, and to designate additional National Forest System land in the State of Georgia as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400099"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412252" joined="2007-09-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170046800" datetime="2007-01-29"><text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1170046800" datetime="2007-01-29"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1170046800" datetime="2007-01-29"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action date="1170738000" datetime="2007-02-06"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text></action>
		<action date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/29/2007--Introduced.<br/>Chattahoochee National Forest Act of 2007 - Establishes the Mountaintown National Scenic Area in the Chattahoochee National Forest in Georgia. Requires the Secretary of Agriculture to develop a management plan for the Scenic Area as an amendment to the land and resource management plan for the Forest. Designates specified lands in Georgia which are administered by the Secretary as part of the Chattahoochee National Forest as wilderness and incorporates such lands into the existing wilderness area to which they adjoin. 
	</summary>
</bill>
