<bill session="110" type="h" number="7081" updated="2009-01-09T07:23:43-05:00">
	<status><enacted date="1223438400" datetime="2008-10-08" /></status>

	<introduced date="1222315200" datetime="2008-09-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">United States-India Nuclear Cooperation Approval and Nonproliferation Enhancement Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">United States-India Nuclear Cooperation Approval and Nonproliferation Enhancement Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To approve the United States-India Agreement for Cooperation on Peaceful Uses of Nuclear Energy, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400025"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400128" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400122" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400430" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400348" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400344" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400003" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400229" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400087" joined="2008-09-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1222315200" datetime="2008-09-25"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1222315200" datetime="2008-09-25"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1222315200" datetime="2008-09-25"><text>Referred to House Rules</text></action>
		<action date="1222465680" datetime="2008-09-26T18:48:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Berman moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text></action>
		<action date="1222465680" datetime="2008-09-26T18:48:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H10088-10103"/></action>
		<action date="1222465680" datetime="2008-09-26T18:48:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 7081.</text></action>
		<action date="1222468800" datetime="2008-09-26T19:40:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1222544340" datetime="2008-09-27T16:39:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H10223"/></action>
		<vote date="1222544640" how="roll" roll="662" datetime="2008-09-27T16:44:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" suspension="1" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 298 - 117, 1 Present (Roll no. 662). (text: CR 9/26/2008 H10088-10090)</text></vote>
		<action date="1222660800" datetime="2008-09-29"><text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text></action>
		<action date="1222833600" datetime="2008-10-01"><text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S10191-10198, S10199-10208, S10290-10291"/></action>
		<vote date="1222833600" how="roll" roll="211" datetime="2008-10-01" where="s" type="vote2" result="pass" ><text>Passed Senate, having achieved the required 60 votes in the affirmative, pursuant to the order of September 30, 2008, without amendment by Yea-Nay Vote. 86 - 13. Record Vote Number: 211.</text></vote>
		<topresident date="1222833600" datetime="2008-10-01" ><text>Cleared for White House.</text></topresident>
		<action date="1222920000" datetime="2008-10-02"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<topresident date="1223006400" datetime="2008-10-03" ><text>Presented to President.</text></topresident>
		<signed date="1223438400" datetime="2008-10-08" ><text>Signed by President.</text></signed>
		<enacted number="110-369" date="1223438400" datetime="2008-10-08" type="public" ><text>Became Public Law No: 110-369.</text></enacted>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/25/2008--Introduced.<br/>United States-India Nuclear Cooperation Approval and Nonproliferation Enhancement Act - Approves the United States-India Agreement for Cooperation on Peaceful Uses of Nuclear Energy (Agreement), subject to the provisions of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, the Henry J. Hyde United States-India Peaceful Atomic Energy Cooperation Act of 2006, and other applicable U.S. law. Urges the government of India to sign and adhere to an Additional Protocol with the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA). States that licenses may be issued by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) for transfers pursuant to the Agreement only after the President certifies to Congress that: (1) the Agreement Between the Government of India and the International Atomic Energy Agency for the Application of Safeguards to Civilian Nuclear Facilities has entered into force; and (2) the government of India has filed a declaration of facilities that is not materially inconsistent with the facilities and schedule of the separation plan presented in the national parliament of India. Amends the Henry J. Hyde United States-India Peaceful Atomic Energy Cooperation Act of 2006 to revise related congressional reporting requirements. States that no subsequent arrangement concerning reprocessing arrangements and procedures shall take effect until: (1) the President reports to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Senate Committee on Foreign Relations (Committees) respecting the reasons for such arrangement and a certification that third-party reprocessing arrangements with India will be conducted under similar arrangements; and (2) a period of 30 days of continuous session has elapsed after such report's transmittal. Amends the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to direct the President to inform the Committees of any negotiations relating to a new or amended agreement for peaceful nuclear cooperation. Directs the President to: (1) certify to the Committees that it is U.S. policy to work with members of the Nuclear Suppliers Group (NSG) to restrict transfers of equipment and technology related to the enrichment of uranium and reprocessing of spent nuclear fuel; and (2) seek to achieve within NSG or with NSG participating governments the adoption of principles and exchanges of information to assure peaceful use and accounting of by-product material. 
	</summary>
</bill>
