<bill session="110" type="h" number="7099" updated="2009-01-09T07:25:49-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1222315200" datetime="2008-09-25"/></status>

	<introduced date="1222315200" datetime="2008-09-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Drug Trafficking Vessel Interdiction Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend titles 46 and 18, United States Code, with respect to the operation of submersible vessels and semi-submersible vessels without nationality.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400617"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400652" joined="2008-09-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1222315200" datetime="2008-09-25"><text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1222315200" datetime="2008-09-25"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1222315200" datetime="2008-09-25"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1222401600" datetime="2008-09-26"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text></action>
		<action date="1222401600" datetime="2008-09-26"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>For Further Action See S.3598.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/25/2008--Introduced.<br/>Drug Trafficking Vessel Interdiction Act of 2008 - Amends the federal criminal code to impose a fine and/or prison term of up to 15 years for knowingly operating or attempting or conspiring to operate by any means, or for embarking in, any submersible or semi-submersible vessel that is without nationality and that is navigating or has navigated into, through, or from waters beyond the outer limit of the territorial sea of a single country or a lateral limit of that country's territorial sea with an adjacent country, with the intent to avoid detection. Imposes an additional civil fine of up to $1 million for violations.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
