<bill session="110" type="h" number="7124" updated="2009-01-09T07:28:49-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1222401600" datetime="2008-09-26"/></status>

	<introduced date="1222401600" datetime="2008-09-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish procedures for causes and claims relating to the leasing of Federal lands (including submerged lands) for the exploration, development, production, processing, or transmission of oil, natural gas, or any other source or form of energy, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400368"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400279" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400059" joined="2008-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400659" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400330" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400441" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="412256" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400176" joined="2008-09-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2008-09-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400040" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400288" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400642" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400068" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400643" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400421" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400005" joined="2008-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400617" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400221" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="412213" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400016" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400315" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400182" joined="2008-09-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1222401600" datetime="2008-09-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/26/2008--Introduced.<br/>Confers exclusive jurisdiction upon the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia to hear causes and claims arising from a covered energy project, any action or decision by a federal official regarding: (1) leasing federal lands for the exploration, development, production, processing, or transmission of any source or form of energy; (2) actions and decisions regarding the selection or offering of federal lands for such leasing; or (3) any action under such a lease. Bars any cause or claim not filed within a 60-day period for filing a complaint. Prescribes a 180-day deadline for court resolution of a complaint or cause of action. Declares that such a complaint or cause of action shall take precedence over all other pending matters before the District Court. Restricts to the Supreme Court any judicial review of an interlocutory or final judgment, decree, or order of the district court. Prescribes a 180-day deadline for Supreme Court resolution of such a matter. Declares that all such proceedings shall take precedence over all other matters then before the Supreme Court.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
