<bill session="110" type="h" number="7147" updated="2009-01-09T07:31:55-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1222401600" datetime="2008-09-26"/></status>

	<introduced date="1222401600" datetime="2008-09-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to prohibit State election officials from accepting a challenge to an individual's eligibility to register to vote in an election for Federal office or to vote in an election for Federal office in a jurisdiction on the grounds that the individual resides in a household in the jurisdiction which is subject to foreclosure proceedings or that the jurisdiction was adversely affected by a hurricane or other major disaster, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400198"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400364" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400289" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400092" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400080" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400424" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400063" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400152" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400245" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400097" joined="2008-09-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1222401600" datetime="2008-09-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/26/2008--Introduced.<br/>Amends the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to prohibit a state or local election official from accepting a challenge to an individual's eligibility to register to vote in an election for federal office in a jurisdition or to vote in an election for federal office in a jurisdiction if the challenge is not based on good cause. Declares that a challenge is not based on good cause if it is based on residence in property subject to foreclosure proceedings or in an area damaged by hurricane or other major disaster.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
