<bill session="110" type="h" number="716" updated="2009-01-08T18:18:45-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1185247560" datetime="2007-07-23T12:26:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1170046800" datetime="2007-01-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Santa Rosa Urban Water Reuse Plan Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Santa Rosa Urban Water Reuse Plan Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to participate in the Santa Rosa Urban Water Reuse Plan.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400436"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170046800" datetime="2007-01-29"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text></action>
		<action date="1179374400" datetime="2007-05-17"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1181620800" datetime="2007-06-12"><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1181620800" datetime="2007-06-12"><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Unanimous Consent .</text></action>
		<calendar date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1185246000" datetime="2007-07-23T12:00:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-246.</text></action>
		<calendar number="155" date="1185246060" datetime="2007-07-23T12:01:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 155.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1185247380" datetime="2007-07-23T12:23:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Grijalva moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1185247440" datetime="2007-07-23T12:24:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8195"/></action>
		<action date="1185247440" datetime="2007-07-23T12:24:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 716.</text></action>
		<vote date="1185247560" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-07-23T12:26:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text as passed in House" ref="CR H8195"/></vote>
		<action date="1185249600" datetime="2007-07-24"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1207627200" datetime="2008-04-08"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/23/2007--Passed House amended. Santa Rosa Urban Water Reuse Plan Act - Amends the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior, in cooperation with the city of Santa Rosa, California, to participate in design, planning, and construction of projects to implement the Santa Rosa Urban Water Reuse Plan. Limits the federal share to 25% of the total project costs. Prohibits the use of: (1) federal funds for operation or maintenance of an authorized project; or (2) funds authorized by this legislation for the development of new wetland areas.<br/>Authorizes appropriations.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
