<bill session="110" type="h" number="7181" updated="2009-01-09T07:35:48-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1222488000" datetime="2008-09-27"/></status>

	<introduced date="1222488000" datetime="2008-09-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Life Sustaining Treatment Preferences Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for coverage under the Medicare Program for consultations regarding orders for life sustaining treatment and to provide grants for the development and expansion of programs for such orders.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400033"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="2008-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400130" joined="2008-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400437" joined="2008-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400218" joined="2008-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400240" joined="2008-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400186" joined="2008-09-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1222488000" datetime="2008-09-27"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1222488000" datetime="2008-09-27"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1222488000" datetime="2008-09-27"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1222488000" datetime="2008-09-27"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1222574400" datetime="2008-09-28"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2136-2137)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/27/2008--Introduced.<br/>Life Sustaining Treatment Preferences Act of 2008 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act, as amended by the Medicare Improvements for Patients and Providers Act of 2008, to extend Medicare coverage to consultations regarding an order for life sustaining treatment for qualified individuals. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to eligible entities to: (1) establish new programs for orders regarding life sustaining treatment in a state or locality; (2) expand or enhance an existing program; or (3) set up a clearinghouse of information on programs for such orders and consultative services for the development or enhancement of such programs.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
