<bill session="110" type="h" number="7195" updated="2009-01-09T07:37:24-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1222488000" datetime="2008-09-27"/></status>

	<introduced date="1222488000" datetime="2008-09-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To entitle affected participants under a pension plan referred to in the USEC Privatization Act to payment for benefit increases not received.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400431"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1222488000" datetime="2008-09-27"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1222488000" datetime="2008-09-27"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1222488000" datetime="2008-09-27"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1222488000" datetime="2008-09-27"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/27/2008--Introduced.<br/>Entitles to a one-time lump sum payment any persons (affected participants) who: (1) retired from active employment at one of the gaseous diffusion plants of the U.S. Enrichment Corporation (USEC) on or before USEC's privatization date as vested participants in a pension plan maintained either by USEC's operating contractor or by a contractor employed before July 1, 1993, by the Department of Energy to operate a gaseous diffusion plant; or (2) are employed by USEC's operating contractor on or before the privatization date, and are vested participants in such a pension plan. Prescribes a formula for determination of the payment. Allows any affected participant to treat such payment as a rollover contribution to a regular individual retirement account (IRA) or a Roth IRA. Prescribes hearing and judicial review rights for any affected participant who may have been prejudiced by any decision with regard to such a payment.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
