<bill session="110" type="h" number="7217" updated="2009-01-09T07:39:55-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1222710540" datetime="2008-09-29T14:49:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="without objection" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1222660800" datetime="2008-09-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Real Property Disposal Enhancement Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Federal Real Property Disposal Enhancement Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 40, United States Code, to enhance authorities with regard to real property that has yet to be reported excess, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400282"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400116" joined="2008-09-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1222660800" datetime="2008-09-29"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text></action>
		<action date="1222710540" datetime="2008-09-29T14:49:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Towns asked unanimous consent to discharge from committee and consider.</text></action>
		<action date="1222710540" datetime="2008-09-29T14:49:00-04:00"><text>Committee on Oversight and Government discharged.</text></action>
		<action date="1222710540" datetime="2008-09-29T14:49:00-04:00"><text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H10626-10629"/></action>
		<vote date="1222710540" how="without objection" datetime="2008-09-29T14:49:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On passage Passed without objection.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H10626-10628"/></vote>
		<action date="1222747200" datetime="2008-09-30"><text>Received in the Senate.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/29/2008--Passed House without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)<br/>Federal Real Property Disposal Enhancement Act of 2008 - Expands requirements for the identification and disposal of excess federal real property to require the Administrator of the General Services Administration (GSA) to: (1) issue guidance for the development and implementation of real property plans, including recommendations on how to identify excess properties, evaluate disposal costs and benefits, and prioritize disposal decisions based on agency missions and anticipated future needs for holdings; (2) establish and maintain a single, comprehensive, and descriptive database of all federal real property assets under the custody and control of all executive agencies, other than assets excluded for national security reasons; (3) report to the House Committees on Oversight and and Government Reform and Transportation and Infrastructure and the Senate Committees on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and Environment and Public Works annually for five years on agency efforts to reduce real property assets; and (4) assist agencies in the identification and disposal of excess real property. Includes among the amounts the Administrator is authorized to obligate from proceeds from the disposition of excess real property: (1) amounts to pay the costs related to identifying and preparing properties to be reported excess by another agency; and (2) amounts to pay the costs associated with the reversion, custody, and disposal of reverted real property.<br/>Expands requirements for the use of net proceeds from the transfer or sale of excess real property assets.<br/>Exempts in FY2009 and FY2010 certain eligible properties from requirements under the McKinney Vento Homeless Assistance Act for the use of public buildings to assist the homeless. Defines as &quot;eligible property&quot; a property (other than Department of Veteran Affairs property): (1) that is selected for demolition, located on land not determined to be excess for which there is an ongoing federal need, and not to be used in any lease, exchange, leaseback arrangement, or service agreement; and (2) that is located in an area to which the general public is denied access for national security reasons or that is uninhabitable, not a housing unit, and selected for demolition by an agency. Requires notification to Congress of properties demolished and scheduled for demolition and the publication of a list of such properties on the GSA website. 
	</summary>
</bill>
