<bill session="110" type="h" number="7230" updated="2009-01-09T07:41:26-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1222660800" datetime="2008-09-29"/></status>

	<introduced date="1222660800" datetime="2008-09-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Save America's Utility Infrastructure and Secure America Now Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Power Act to provide for enforcement, including criminal penalties, by the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission of electric reliability standards, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400199"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1222660800" datetime="2008-09-29"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1222660800" datetime="2008-09-29"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1222660800" datetime="2008-09-29"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text></action>
		<action date="1222660800" datetime="2008-09-29"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1222747200" datetime="2008-09-30"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/29/2008--Introduced.<br/>Save America's Utility Infrastructure and Secure America Now Act of 2008 - Amends the Federal Power Act to grant the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) enforcement powers with respect to electric reliability standards. (Currently such powers are exercised by an Electric Reliability Organization [ERO].) Revises penalty guidelines to subject to federal criminal law any person who violates a FERC-approved electric reliability standard. Requires FERC to issue a rule in connection with electric reliability standards to prohibit disturbances (other than planned maintenance) lasting greater than five days at certain substations. Instructs the Secretary of the Department of Homeland Security to study and report to Congress on gaps in emergency planning preparedness and management as related to specified, vulnerable populations.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
