<bill session="110" type="h" number="7239" updated="2009-01-09T07:42:30-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1222660800" datetime="2008-09-29"/></status>

	<introduced date="1222660800" datetime="2008-09-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">American Energy, American Innovation Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To reduce gasoline prices, to lessen the dependence of the United States on foreign oil, to strengthen the economy of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400412"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1222660800" datetime="2008-09-29"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, Ways and Means, Science and Technology, Oversight and Government Reform, Transportation and Infrastructure, and Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1222660800" datetime="2008-09-29"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1222660800" datetime="2008-09-29"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action date="1222660800" datetime="2008-09-29"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1222660800" datetime="2008-09-29"><text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text></action>
		<action date="1222660800" datetime="2008-09-29"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1222660800" datetime="2008-09-29"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1222660800" datetime="2008-09-29"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1222747200" datetime="2008-09-30"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text></action>
		<action date="1222747200" datetime="2008-09-30"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text></action>
		<action date="1222747200" datetime="2008-09-30"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
		<action date="1222747200" datetime="2008-09-30"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text></action>
		<action date="1222747200" datetime="2008-09-30"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2161-2162)</text></action>
		<action date="1228107600" datetime="2008-12-01"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/29/2008--Introduced.<br/>American Energy, American Innovation Act of 2008 - Directs the Secretary of Energy to publish a plan for the sale and replacement of oil from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve (SPR). Amends the Commodity Exchange Act to extend the jurisdiction of the Commodity Future Trading Commission (CFTC) to energy commodities. Establishes the National Commission on Energy Independence in the legislative branch. Amends the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 to establish a national renewable electricity standard. Declares the sense of the Senate that by calendar 2030 the United States should be energy independent. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to establish a tax credit for qualified plug-in electric drive motor vehicles and fuel-efficient motor vehicles placed in service by a taxpayer. Directs the Secretary of Energy to conduct a program of alternative fuel transportation technology research, development, demonstration, and commercial application. Increases and revises the formula for corporate fuel economy standards. Prescribes tax credits and exclusions for: (1) enhancing the efficiency of specified conventional vehicles; (2) advanced coal and coal gasification (carbon mitigation) project investments; and (3) qualified energy conservation bonds. Extends tax credits for specified alternative fuels and biofuels and qualified green buildings and sustainable design projects. Prescribes renewable energy and geothermal tax incentives. Prohibits oil or natural gas leasing in any except specified areas of the Outer Continental Shelf (OCS), and only according to certain requirements. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to establish Federal OCS Joint Regional Permitting Offices. Amends the Energy Policy Act of 1992 to require the Secretary of Energy to carry out a coal innovation direct loan program. Authorizes appropriations to the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) to establish an additional 60 full-time equivalent positions to expedite and streamline the processing of applications for new nuclear plants. Establishes an interagency working group to make recommendations to coordinate federal government actions and programs to promote increasing domestic manufacturing capacity and export of domestic nuclear energy products and services. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a tax credit for carbon dioxide sequestration. Offsets expenditures under this Act by terminating specified tax deductions and credits. Includes in gross income any compensation deferred under a nonqualified deferred compensation plan of a nonqualified entity when there is no substantial risk of forfeiture of the rights to such compensation.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
