<bill session="110" type="h" number="7251" updated="2009-01-09T07:43:53-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1222920000" datetime="2008-10-02"/></status>

	<introduced date="1222920000" datetime="2008-10-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Land-In-Trust Impact Aid and PILT Equity Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to ensure that local educational agencies receive Impact Aid payments for lands held in trust for the benefit of a federally recognized Indian tribe or individual Indian and to amend title 31 of the United States Code to ensure that local governments receive payments in lieu of taxes for lands held in trust for the benefit of a federally recognized Indian tribe or individual Indian.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400264"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1222920000" datetime="2008-10-02"><text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1222920000" datetime="2008-10-02"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1222920000" datetime="2008-10-02"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/2/2008--Introduced.<br/>Land-In-Trust Impact Aid and PILT Equity Act of 2008 - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to ensure that local educational agencies (LEAs) receive full payment under the Impact Aid program, which compensates LEAs for the financial burden of federal activities affecting their school districts, for federal property within their districts that is held in trust for federally recognized Indian tribes or individual Indians. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to make full payments in lieu of taxes (PILT) to local governments that have federal lands within their areas that are held in trust for federally recognized Indian tribes or individual Indians.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
