<bill session="110" type="h" number="7253" updated="2009-01-09T07:44:07-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1223006400" datetime="2008-10-03"/></status>

	<introduced date="1223006400" datetime="2008-10-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Economic Growth and Financial Stabilization Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance economic growth and promote the stability of the financial system of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400004"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1223006400" datetime="2008-10-03"><text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1223006400" datetime="2008-10-03"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1223006400" datetime="2008-10-03"><text>Referred to House Financial Services</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/3/2008--Introduced.<br/>Economic Growth and Financial Stabilization Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to prescribe a 0% capital gains rate for individuals. Revises the formula for: (1) the alternative tax for corporations to prescribe a 0% capital gains rate; and (2) the ordinary income tax for corporations by eliminating the two tax rate brackets above 25% and reducing the maximum amount of tax imposed. Establishes in the Department of the Treasury a Distressed Assets Loan Fund under the control of the Secretary of the Treasury to make loans available at low rates of interest to depository institutions with distressed assets. Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act and the Federal Credit Union Act to increase from $100,000 to $250,000 the maximum amount of deposit insurance and share insurance, respectively. Treats gain or loss from the sale or exchange of any applicable preferred stock by any applicable financial institution as ordinary income or loss. 
	</summary>
</bill>
