<bill session="110" type="h" number="7250" updated="2009-01-09T07:43:46-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1222920000" datetime="2008-10-02"/></status>

	<introduced date="1222920000" datetime="2008-10-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Arctic Climate Preservation Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to conduct a study on black carbon emissions and to reduce global black carbon emissions.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400193"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2008-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400301" joined="2008-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400425" joined="2008-10-02"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1222920000" datetime="2008-10-02"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Foreign Affairs, and Science and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1222920000" datetime="2008-10-02"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1222920000" datetime="2008-10-02"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text></action>
		<action date="1222920000" datetime="2008-10-02"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1222920000" datetime="2008-10-02"><text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/2/2008--Introduced.<br/>Arctic Climate Preservation Act - Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to: (1) conduct a study of black carbon and organic carbon emissions; and (2) propose regulations under the Clean Air Act to reduce emissions of black carbon. Defines &quot;black carbon&quot; as the strongly light absorbing component of carbonaceous aerosols. Directs the Secretary of State to report to Congress on the amount, type, and direction of all U.S. foreign aid for reducing black carbon pollution. States the policy of the United States with respect to international agreements and treaties relating to the reduction of black carbon emissions, protection of the Arctic environment, the the threat to polar bears from global warming, human rights under the American Declaration of the Rights and Duties of Man, and the reduction of shipping pollution through domestic means and through the International Convention for the Prevention of Pollution From Ships (MARPOL).<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
