<bill session="110" type="h" number="7265" updated="2009-01-09T07:45:30-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1223006400" datetime="2008-10-03"/></status>

	<introduced date="1223006400" datetime="2008-10-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Fixing the Federal Voting Assistance Program Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act to require the Presidential designee responsible for carrying out Federal functions under the Act to have experience in election administration and be approved by the Senate, to establish the Overseas Voting Advisory Board to oversee the administration of the Act so that American citizens who live overseas or serve in the military can participate in elections for public office, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400251"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2008-10-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1223006400" datetime="2008-10-03"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E2247)</text></action>
		<action date="1223006400" datetime="2008-10-03"><text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1223006400" datetime="2008-10-03"><text>Referred to House House Administration</text></action>
		<action date="1223006400" datetime="2008-10-03"><text>Referred to House Rules</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/3/2008--Introduced.<br/>Fixing the Federal Voting Assistance Program Act of 2008 - Amends the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act to require the presidential designee responsible for carrying out federal functions under the Act to have experience in election administration and be approved by the Senate. Establishes the Overseas Voting Advisory Board to conduct studies and issue reports with respect to various issues, including the ability of U.S. citizens who reside outside of the United States to register to vote and vote in elections for public office. 
	</summary>
</bill>
