<bill session="110" type="h" number="727" updated="2009-01-08T18:20:08-05:00">
	<status><enacted date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03" /></status>

	<introduced date="1170133200" datetime="2007-01-30"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Trauma Care Systems Planning and Development Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Trauma Care Systems Planning and Development Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Trauma Care Systems Planning and Development Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">Trauma Care Systems Planning and Development Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="enacted">Trauma Care Systems Planning and Development Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to add requirements regarding trauma care, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400160"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400367" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400183" joined="2007-03-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400419" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400122" joined="2007-03-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400268" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400241" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400052" joined="2007-01-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400285" joined="2007-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400201" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400636" joined="2007-03-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400062" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412233" joined="2007-03-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400656" joined="2007-03-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170133200" datetime="2007-01-30"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1170392400" datetime="2007-02-02"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1173758400" datetime="2007-03-13"><text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1173758400" datetime="2007-03-13"><text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text></action>
		<action date="1173931200" datetime="2007-03-15"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1173931200" datetime="2007-03-15" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1175025840" datetime="2007-03-27T17:04:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 110-77.</text></action>
		<calendar number="43" date="1175025900" datetime="2007-03-27T17:05:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 43.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1175037900" datetime="2007-03-27T20:25:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Green, Gene moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1175037900" datetime="2007-03-27T20:25:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3157-3161"/></action>
		<action date="1175037900" datetime="2007-03-27T20:25:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 727.</text></action>
		<vote date="1175038680" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-03-27T20:38:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H3157-3159"/></vote>
		<action date="1175054400" datetime="2007-03-28"><text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text></action>
		<vote date="1175140800" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2007-03-29" where="s" type="vote2" result="pass" ><text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S4224"/></vote>
		<topresident date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29" ><text>Cleared for White House.</text></topresident>
		<action date="1175227200" datetime="2007-03-30"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<topresident date="1177387200" datetime="2007-04-24" ><text>Presented to President.</text></topresident>
		<signed date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03" ><text>Signed by President.</text></signed>
		<enacted number="110-23" date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03" type="public" ><text>Became Public Law No: 110-23.</text></enacted>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/3/2007--Public Law. (This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the Senate on March 29, 2007. The summary of that version is repeated here.)<br/>Trauma Care Systems Planning and Development Act of 2007 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) collect, compile, and disseminate information on achievements and problems in providing trauma care and emergency medical services; and (2) promote the collection and categorization of trauma data in a consistent and standardized manner.<br/>(Sec. 3) Removes authorization for the National Clearinghouse on Trauma Care and Emergency Medical Services. (Sec. 4) Allows the Secretary to make grants to public and nonprofit private entities to carry out demonstration projects to improve emergency medical services in rural areas by increasing communication and coordination with state trauma systems. (Sec. 5) Authorizes the Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, to make grants to states, political subdivisions, or consortia thereof to improve access to and enhance the development of trauma care systems. Requires grant funds be used to: (1) integrate and broaden the reach of such a system; (2) strengthen, develop, and improve an existing system; (3) expand communications between the system and emergency medical services through improved equipment or a telemedicine system; (4) improve data collection and retention; or (5) increase education, training, and technical assistance opportunities. Requires the Secretary to give preference in awarding grants to applicants that: (1) have developed a process, using national standards, for designating trauma centers; (2) recognize protocols for the delivery of seriously injured patients to trauma centers; (3) implement a process for evaluating the performance of the trauma system; and (4) agree to participate in specified information systems by collecting, providing, and sharing information. Requires the Secretary to give priority to applicants that will use the grants to focus on improving access to trauma care systems. Requires the Secretary to give special consideration to projects that demonstrate strong state or local support. (Sec. 6) Revises the matching requirements for states to be eligible for grants to improve emergency medical services by decreasing the amount of matching funds required after the fourth and subsequent years of grant payments to the state. (Sec. 7) Prohibits the Secretary from making trauma care grants to a state unless the state's emergency medical services plan coordinates planning for trauma systems with state disaster emergency planning and bioterrorism hospital preparedness planning. Requires the Secretary to update the model plan for the designation of trauma centers and for triage, transfer, and transportation policies. (Sec. 8) Prohibits the Secretary from making trauma grants to a state unless the state submits to the Secretary any changes to, and any plans to address deficiencies in, the trauma care component. (Sec. 9) Removes the requirement that states, in order to receive trauma grant funds, must agree not to expend such payments to purchase any major medical or communication equipment, ambulances, or aircraft. (Sec. 10) Removes provisions related to annual reporting requirements for states. (Sec. 11) Sets forth reporting requirements. (Sec. 12) Authorizes appropriation for FY2008-FY2012. (Sec. 13) Authorizes appropriations for FY2008-FY2012 for residency training programs in emergency medicine. 
	</summary>
</bill>
