<bill session="110" type="h" number="7306" updated="2009-01-09T07:50:19-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1227157200" datetime="2008-11-20"/></status>

	<introduced date="1227157200" datetime="2008-11-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">STONE</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Stop the Treasury Office Nationalization of the Economy Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To immediately terminate the authority of the Secretary of the Treasury under the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 to purchase troubled assets and to make a portion of the unused funding for such program available to meet critical infrastructure needs in the United States.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400651"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1227157200" datetime="2008-11-20"><text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, Energy and Commerce, and Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1227157200" datetime="2008-11-20"><text>Referred to House Financial Services</text></action>
		<action date="1227157200" datetime="2008-11-20"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1227157200" datetime="2008-11-20"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1227157200" datetime="2008-11-20"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
		<action date="1227157200" datetime="2008-11-20"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1227243600" datetime="2008-11-21"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text></action>
		<action date="1227243600" datetime="2008-11-21"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text></action>
		<action date="1227243600" datetime="2008-11-21"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
		<action date="1227243600" datetime="2008-11-21"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/20/2008--Introduced.<br/>Stop the Treasury Office Nationalization of the Economy Act of 2008 or STONE - Ends the authority of the Secretary of the Treasury under the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 to purchase troubled assets. Makes $100 billion of the unused funding for such program available to meet specified critical infrastructure needs of the United States, clean water grants, and certain flood control and water resource activities. 
	</summary>
</bill>
