<bill session="110" type="h" number="735" updated="2009-01-08T18:21:07-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1185840060" datetime="2007-07-30T21:01:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1170133200" datetime="2007-01-30"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To designate the Federal building under construction at 799 First Avenue in New York, New York, as the &quot;Ronald H. Brown United States Mission to the United Nations Building&quot;.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400333"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412221" joined="2007-03-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170133200" datetime="2007-01-30"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text></action>
		<action date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text></action>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01" ><text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><text>Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management Discharged.</text></action>
		<action date="1184194560" datetime="2007-07-11T19:56:00-04:00"><text>Reported by the Committee on Transportation. H. Rept. 110-230.</text></action>
		<calendar number="86" date="1184194560" datetime="2007-07-11T19:56:00-04:00" calendar="House" ><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 86.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1185839640" datetime="2007-07-30T20:54:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Cummings moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text></action>
		<action date="1185839700" datetime="2007-07-30T20:55:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules. (consideration: CR 7/31/2007 H8935-8937)</text></action>
		<action date="1185839700" datetime="2007-07-30T20:55:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 735.</text></action>
		<vote date="1185840060" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-07-30T21:01:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote. (text: CR 7/31/2007 H8936)</text></vote>
		<action date="1185854400" datetime="2007-07-31"><text>Received in the Senate.</text></action>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1197954000" datetime="2007-12-18" ><text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1200978000" datetime="2008-01-22"><text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Boxer without amendment. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="561" date="1200978000" datetime="2008-01-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 561.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/22/2008--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Designates the federal building under construction at 799 First Avenue in New York, New York, as the &quot;Ronald H. Brown United States Mission to the United Nations Building.&quot;<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
