<bill session="110" type="h" number="74" updated="2009-01-08T16:51:35-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/></status>

	<introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Discovery Trails Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Trails System Act to authorize an additional category of national trail known as a national discovery trail, to provide special requirements for the establishment and administration of national discovery trails, and to designate the cross-country American Discovery Trail as the first national discovery trail.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400017"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400420" joined="2007-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400177" joined="2007-03-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400149" joined="2007-09-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400154" joined="2008-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="412189" joined="2007-03-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400396" joined="2007-07-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400412" joined="2007-03-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="412208" joined="2007-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400640" joined="2007-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412209" joined="2007-09-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400070" joined="2007-03-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400234" joined="2007-03-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400281" joined="2008-07-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400415" joined="2007-09-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="412212" joined="2008-09-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="2007-11-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400090" joined="2008-09-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2007-03-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400042" joined="2007-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="2007-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400349" joined="2008-09-16"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/4/2007--Introduced.<br/>National Discovery Trails Act - Amends the National Trails System Act to establish national discovery trails, which shall be extended, continuous interstate trails located so as to provide for outdoor recreation and travel and to connect representative examples of America's trails and communities. Authorizes the designation of such trails on Federal lands and, with the consent of the owner, on non-federal lands. Requires the appropriate Secretary for each national discovery trail to administer the trail in cooperation with a competent trailwide volunteer-based organization. Sets forth requirements for designation as a national discovery trail. Designates as a national discovery trail the 6,000-mile American Discovery Trail which shall extend from Cape Henlopen State Park in Delaware to Point Reyes National Seashore in California, traveling northern and southern routes from Cincinnati, Ohio, to Denver, Colorado.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
