<bill session="110" type="h" number="744" updated="2009-01-08T18:22:14-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"/></status>

	<introduced date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Iraq Policy Revitalization and Congressional Oversight Enhancement Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance congressional oversight of Operation Iraqi Freedom by requiring the President to transmit periodically to Congress a consolidated, comprehensive report to detail the terms of completion for Operation Iraqi Freedom and by requiring the President to seek to enter into a multilateral agreement to help provide for the completion of Operation Iraqi Freedom.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400041"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1170306000" datetime="2007-02-01"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E247-249)</text></action>
		<action date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"><committee name="House Foreign Affairs"/><text>Committee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1184212800" datetime="2007-07-12"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H7710)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/31/2007--Introduced.<br/>Iraq Policy Revitalization and Congressional Oversight Enhancement Act - Directs the President to: (1) transmit periodically to Congress a consolidated, comprehensive report respecting the National Strategy for Victory in Iraq and the New Way Forward in Iraq plan; and (2) seek to enter into a multilateral agreement with Coalition countries, the Republic of Iraq, appropriate states in the Middle East region, and appropriate multilateral organizations to help provide for the completion of Operation Iraqi Freedom.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
