<bill session="110" type="h" number="761" updated="2009-01-08T18:24:28-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1185247260" datetime="2007-07-23T12:21:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of Interior to convey to The Missouri River Basin Lewis and Clark Interpretive Trail and Visitor Center Foundation, Inc. certain Federal land associated with the Lewis and Clark National Historic Trail in Nebraska, to be used as an historical interpretive site along the trail.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400640"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412217" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400400" joined="2007-01-31"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action date="1181793600" datetime="2007-06-14"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28"><text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands Discharged.</text></action>
		<action date="1185246000" datetime="2007-07-23T12:00:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-247.</text></action>
		<calendar number="156" date="1185246060" datetime="2007-07-23T12:01:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 156.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1185247080" datetime="2007-07-23T12:18:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Grijalva moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1185247140" datetime="2007-07-23T12:19:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8193-8194"/></action>
		<action date="1185247140" datetime="2007-07-23T12:19:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 761.</text></action>
		<vote date="1185247260" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-07-23T12:21:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text as passed in House" ref="CR H8193"/></vote>
		<action date="1185249600" datetime="2007-07-24"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/23/2007--Passed House amended. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to convey to the Missouri River Basin Lewis and Clark Interpretive Trail and Visitor Center Foundation, Inc., specified federal land associated with the Lewis and Clark National Historic Trail in Nebraska, to be used as an historic site and interpretive center for the Trail. Requires the National Park Service (NPS), through a written agreement with the Foundation, to ensure that the operation of the land conveyed is in accordance with NPS standards for preservation, maintenance, and interpretation. Authorizes appropriations for site and center operation.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
