<bill session="110" type="h" number="770" updated="2009-01-08T18:25:31-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"/></status>

	<introduced date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Iran Nuclear Nonproliferation Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the use of funds to carry out any covert action for the purpose of causing regime change in Iran or to carry out any military action against Iran in the absence of an imminent threat, in accordance with international law and constitutional and statutory requirements for congressional authorization.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400237"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400253" joined="2007-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2007-12-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400227" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2007-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400080" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="412221" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400295" joined="2007-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400129" joined="2007-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400424" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400423" joined="2007-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="2007-03-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="2008-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400422" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400111" joined="2007-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2007-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400201" joined="2007-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400301" joined="2007-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400100" joined="2007-02-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, and Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"><text>Referred to House Intelligence (Permanent Select)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/31/2007--Introduced.<br/>Iran Nuclear Nonproliferation Act - Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) full diplomatic, political, and economic relations between the United States and Iran cannot be normalized unless enforceable safeguards are put in place to prevent weaponization of Iran's nuclear program and the government of Iran ends its support for international terrorist groups, but the attainment of these objectives should not constitute preconditions for any diplomatic dialogue; and (2) no congressional authorization for the use of military force in any Act enacted before the date of enactment of this Act constitutes an authorization for the use of military force against Iran or its nuclear program. States as the policy of the United States not to enter into a preemptive war against Iran in the absence of an immediate threat, and then only in accordance with international law and constitutional and statutory requirements for congressional authorization. Prohibits funds available to the Department of Defense (DOD) or any other federal department or agency from being used to carry out any covert action for the purpose of causing regime change in Iran or to carry out any military action against Iran in the absence of an imminent threat.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
