<bill session="110" type="h" number="773" updated="2009-01-08T18:25:53-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"/></status>

	<introduced date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Diploma Integrity Protection Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To reduce and prevent the sale and use of fraudulent degrees in order to protect the integrity of valid higher education degrees that are used for Federal purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400259"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400031" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400227" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400080" joined="2007-05-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2007-06-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400067" joined="2007-07-31"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"><text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, Oversight and Government Reform, the Judiciary, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"><text>Referred to House Rules</text></action>
		<action date="1170392400" datetime="2007-02-02"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text></action>
		<action date="1179460800" datetime="2007-05-18"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/31/2007--Introduced.<br/>Diploma Integrity Protection Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of Education to make available to the Secretary of Homeland Security and the heads of other appropriate federal agencies a list of: (1) accrediting agencies and associations recognized by the Secretary or by the Council for Higher Education Accreditation; (2) institutions of higher education eligible under the Federal Family Education Loan (FFEL) program; and (3) foreign institutions of higher education whose authority to issue degrees is accepted in their home country and that the Secretary deems to be academically equivalent to FFEL participants in this country. Conditions a school's eligibility for student assistance funding under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 on its providing notice on its internet website of its recognition by the Secretary as a legitimate degree-granting institution for immigration and federal employment purposes. Requires an accreditation agency or association to be on such list for its authority to be recognized for any federal purpose. Requires the Secretary to establish the Diploma Mill Task Force to develop: (1) guidelines for distinguishing between legitimate and fraudulent degree-granting institutions for federal purposes; (2) a strategic diploma integrity protection plan to address the sale and use of fraudulent degrees; and (3) legislative language to effectuate such plan. Directs the Federal Trade Commission to define as an unfair and deceptive act or practice: (1) the offering of a degree by an entity that is not recognized as a legitimate degree-granting institution in accordance with the Task Force's guidelines; or (2) the issuing of any accreditation by an entity not recognized by the Secretary, any other appropriate federal agency, the Council for Higher Education Accreditation, or, in the case of a foreign entity, by the appropriate agency in its home country. Requires the Secretary to study: (1) both legitimate and fraudulent degree-granting institutions that are not properly accredited; and (2) steps taken by the Secretary to repair vulnerabilities of the FFEL program to fraudulent degree-granting institutions.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
