<bill session="110" type="h" number="775" updated="2009-01-08T18:26:06-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"/></status>

	<introduced date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Supplemental Appropriations Act for Defense and for the Reconstruction of Iraq, 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Making supplemental appropriations for defense and for the reconstruction of Iraq for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2007, and requiring the President to submit a request for additional funding after certifying substantial progress has been made in Iraq in meeting certain performance measures.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400264"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2007-02-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/31/2007--Introduced.<br/>Supplemental Appropriations Act for Defense and for the Reconstruction of Iraq, 2007 - Makes supplemental appropriations for FY2007 for defense and for the reconstruction of Iraq, with specific appropriations for: (1) military operations in Iraq; and (2) security, relief, rehabilitation, and reconstruction in Iraq. Directs the President to transmit to Congress a request for such additional appropriations for the remainder of FY2007 as the President considers necessary for defense and the reconstruction of Iraq. Expresses the sense that Congress should consider providing additional appropriations pursuant to any request by the President predicated on progress by the government of Iraq in achieving performance measures relating to: (1) Iraqi forces; (2) an oil revenue sharing law; (3) a reformed de-Baathification process; (4) the disarmament of militias; (5) Iraq economic development; and (6) Iraqi constitutional reform.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
