<bill session="110" type="h" number="780" updated="2009-01-08T18:26:43-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"/></status>

	<introduced date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Counterfeit Drug Prevention Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act with respect to counterfeit drugs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400342"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400414" joined="2007-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400160" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400052" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="2008-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400373" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412258" joined="2008-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400056" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="412219" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400345" joined="2007-02-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1170392400" datetime="2007-02-02"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/31/2007--Introduced.<br/>Counterfeit Drug Prevention Act of 2007 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to establish criminal penalties of a fine and imprisonment for not more than 20 years, or both, for any person who commits a prohibited act relating to counterfeiting knowing that: (1) the conduct concerns the rendering of a drug as a counterfeit drug; (2) the conduct will cause a drug to be a counterfeit drug; or (3) a drug, held, sold, or dispensed is a counterfeit drug. Increases the term of imprisonment to any term of years or for life if the use of a counterfeit drug is the proximate cause of a consumer's death. Modifies provisions pertaining to criminal fines for committing certain prohibited acts involving food, drugs, devices, or cosmetics.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
