<bill session="110" type="h" number="799" updated="2009-01-08T18:29:18-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1184624100" datetime="2007-07-16T19:15:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="632"/></status>

	<introduced date="1170651600" datetime="2007-02-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Appalachian Regional Development Act Amendments of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Appalachian Regional Development Act Amendments of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To reauthorize and improve the program authorized by the Appalachian Regional Development Act of 1965.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400299"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400273" joined="2007-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="412229" joined="2007-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400210" joined="2007-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400183" joined="2007-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="412224" joined="2007-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="412234" joined="2007-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="412225" joined="2007-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400295" joined="2007-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400096" joined="2007-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="412231" joined="2007-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400274" joined="2007-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="409888" joined="2007-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400254" joined="2007-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="412214" joined="2007-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400642" joined="2007-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400235" joined="2007-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400331" joined="2007-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="412227" joined="2007-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400158" joined="2007-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400281" joined="2007-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2007-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400043" joined="2007-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400641" joined="2007-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400363" joined="2007-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400114" joined="2007-02-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170651600" datetime="2007-02-05"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E264-265)</text></action>
		<action date="1170651600" datetime="2007-02-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text></action>
		<action date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1173223680" datetime="2007-03-06T19:28:00-05:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation. H. Rept. 110-33.</text></action>
		<calendar number="12" date="1173223680" datetime="2007-03-06T19:28:00-05:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 12.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1184614020" datetime="2007-07-16T16:27:00-04:00"><text>Ms. Johnson, E. B. moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1184614020" datetime="2007-07-16T16:27:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H7814-7818"/></action>
		<action date="1184614020" datetime="2007-07-16T16:27:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 799.</text></action>
		<action date="1184615340" datetime="2007-07-16T16:49:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1184624040" datetime="2007-07-16T19:14:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H7820-7821"/></action>
		<vote date="1184624100" how="roll" roll="632" datetime="2007-07-16T19:15:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" suspension="1" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 332 - 70 (Roll no. 632).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H7814-7815"/></vote>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="273" date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 273.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/16/2007--Passed House amended. Appalachian Regional Development Act Amendments of 2007 - (Sec. 2) Limits the maximum Appalachian Regional Commission contribution through non-highway grants and loans for designated at-risk counties to 70% of costs. (Sec. 3) Authorizes the Commission to provide technical assistance, make grants, or otherwise provide amounts to and contract with persons or entities in the Appalachian region for projects to: (1) promote energy efficiency to enhance economic competitiveness; (2) increase the use of renewable energy resources to produce alternative transportation fuels, electricity, and heat; and (3) support the development of conventional energy resources to produce alternative transportation fuels, electricity, and heat. (Sec. 4) Directs the Commission to designate as &quot;at-risk counties&quot; those counties in the Appalachian region that are most at risk of becoming economically distressed.<br/>(Sec. 5) Authorizes additional appropriations to the Commission through FY2011 to carry out Appalachian regional development and its economic and energy development initiative under section 3. Requires that funds approved by the Commission for a project in a state in the Appalachian region pursuant to congressional direction be derived from such state's portion of the Commission's allocation of appropriated amounts among the states. (Sec. 6) Extends, for five years, the termination date of the Appalachian Regional Development Act of 1965 (with exceptions for the Appalachian development highway system and certain definitions). (Sec. 7) Includes within the Appalachian region the following areas: (1) Metcalfe, Nicholas, and Robertson counties in Kentucky; (2) Ashtabula, Fayette, Mahoning, and Trumbull counties in Ohio; (3) Giles, Lawrence, Lewis, and Lincoln counties in Tennessee; and (4) Henry and Patrick counties in Virginia.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
