<bill session="110" type="h" number="80" updated="2009-01-08T16:52:22-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/></status>

	<introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for Federal research, development, demonstration, and commercial application activities to enable the development of farms that are net producers of both food and energy, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400017"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Referred to the Committee on Science and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text></action>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"><committee name="House Science and Technology"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text></action>
		<action date="1172811600" datetime="2007-03-02"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Credit, Energy, and Research.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/4/2007--Introduced.<br/>Directs the Secretary of Energy to enter into an arrangement with the National Academy of Sciences to: (1) develop recommendations for evaluation measures and criteria for programs under this Act; and (2) evaluate the feasibility of prize and best practices award programs as tools to promote self-powered farms. Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish an award program for up to 30 state agricultural research programs for self-powered farm demonstrations; (2) provide low-cost revolving loans and loan guarantees to eligible entities for the commercial application of energy or other technologies that will contribute to establishing self-powered farms, with highest preference given to applicants who propose to meet their energy needs from biobased feedstocks or other renewable energy sources produced on that farm; and (3) enter into an arrangement with the National Academy of Sciences for a review of the programs under this Act. 
	</summary>
</bill>
