<bill session="110" type="h" number="805" updated="2009-01-08T18:30:07-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1170651600" datetime="2007-02-05"/></status>

	<introduced date="1170651600" datetime="2007-02-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide incentives for the use of hydrogen fuel, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400114"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400183" joined="2007-03-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2007-03-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400356" joined="2007-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400400" joined="2007-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400638" joined="2007-03-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400421" joined="2007-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400649" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="2007-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400215" joined="2007-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400654" joined="2007-03-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400233" joined="2007-04-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170651600" datetime="2007-02-05"><text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1170651600" datetime="2007-02-05"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1170651600" datetime="2007-02-05"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1170651600" datetime="2007-02-05"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1170738000" datetime="2007-02-06"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text></action>
		<action date="1170738000" datetime="2007-02-06"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/5/2007--Introduced.<br/>Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) allow a tax credit for expenditures for producing energy from certain hydrogen sources; and (2) extend through 2013 the energy tax credits for fuel cell and microturbine property. Prohibits the construction after 2008 of any public building in excess of 50,000 square feet, unless such building has a fuel cell as an independent backup source of electric power. Requires the Secretary of Transportation to establish: (1) an interagency task force and comprehensive study team to study and identify the necessary regulatory actions for transitioning to the commercialization of hydrogen and fuel cell devices and fueling stations, and for transitioning from a hydrocarbon to a hydrogen economy; and (2) a cooperative program to facilitate the commercial development of such hydrogen energy sources.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
