<bill session="110" type="h" number="810" updated="2009-01-08T18:30:42-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1170651600" datetime="2007-02-05"/></status>

	<introduced date="1170651600" datetime="2007-02-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Communities from Power Line Abuse Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend certain provisions of the Federal Power Act added by the Energy Policy Act of 2005 relating to the use of eminent domain authority for the construction of electric power lines, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400178"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="412224" joined="2007-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400264" joined="2007-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="412222" joined="2007-02-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170651600" datetime="2007-02-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1170738000" datetime="2007-02-06"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/5/2007--Introduced.<br/>Protecting Communities from Power Line Abuse Act - Amends the Federal Power Act to repeal provisions regarding: (1) mandatory fair market value compensation for right-of-way acquisitions; (2) transmission facility modifications in accordance with state law; and (3) requirements for coordination of federal authorizations for interstate electric transmission facilities, including authorization to file an appeal with the President regarding denial of an application for such an authorization. Modifies requirements for acquisition of rights-of-way for electric transmission facilities located on property other than federal or state property. Provides that, if the permit holder cannot acquire by contract, or is unable to agree upon compensation with the owner of the property, the permit holder may acquire the right-of-way in accordance with state law for the state in which the property is located. (Thus repeals current law which allows the permit holder to acquire the-right-of-way through the exercise of eminent domain in a federal district court.) Requires the length of at least one year for the comment period on an application for a transmission facility permit.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
