<bill session="110" type="h" number="831" updated="2009-01-08T18:33:15-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1208902680" datetime="2008-04-22T19:18:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="207"/></status>

	<introduced date="1170651600" datetime="2007-02-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Coffman Cove Administrative Site Conveyance Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to house">Coffman Cove Administrative Site Conveyance Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Coffman Cove Administrative Site Conveyance Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the conveyance of certain Forest Service land to the city of Coffman Cove, Alaska.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400440"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170651600" datetime="2007-02-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1170997200" datetime="2007-02-09"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action date="1207108800" datetime="2008-04-02"><text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands Discharged.</text></action>
		<action date="1207108800" datetime="2008-04-02"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1207108800" datetime="2008-04-02" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1208452560" datetime="2008-04-17T14:16:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-592.</text></action>
		<calendar number="366" date="1208452560" datetime="2008-04-17T14:16:00-04:00" calendar="Union" ><text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 366.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1208885280" datetime="2008-04-22T14:28:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Rahall moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1208885280" datetime="2008-04-22T14:28:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2499-2500"/></action>
		<action date="1208885280" datetime="2008-04-22T14:28:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 831.</text></action>
		<action date="1208885460" datetime="2008-04-22T14:31:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1208902260" datetime="2008-04-22T19:11:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2531-2532"/></action>
		<vote date="1208902680" how="roll" roll="207" datetime="2008-04-22T19:18:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" suspension="1" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 382 - 0 (Roll no. 207).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H2499"/></vote>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="711" date="1208923200" datetime="2008-04-23" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 711.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/22/2008--Passed House amended. Coffman Cove Administrative Site Conveyance Act of 2008 - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to convey to the city of Coffman Cove, Alaska, without consideration and by quitclaim deed, a specified parcel of National Forest System land within the city. Excludes a certain part of such land from the conveyance. Allows the United States to reserve a right-of-way to provide access to the excluded land.<br/>Provides that if any part of the land conveyed to the city (other than a part of land sold pursuant to this Act) ceases to be used for public purposes, the land may revert to the United States. Requires, if the city sells any part of such conveyed land: (1) the amount of consideration for the sale to reflect fair market value, as determined by an appraisal; and (2) the city to pay to the Secretary an amount equal to the gross proceeds of the sale which shall be available for the Tongass National Forest. 
	</summary>
</bill>
