<bill session="110" type="h" number="836" updated="2009-01-08T18:33:49-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1170738000" datetime="2007-02-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1170738000" datetime="2007-02-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Cyber-Security Enhancement and Consumer Data Protection Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, to better assure cyber-security, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400381"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400137" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400154" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400071" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400144" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400076" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400617" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400315" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400141" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400321" joined="2007-02-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170738000" datetime="2007-02-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/6/2007--Introduced.<br/>Cyber-Security Enhancement and Consumer Data Protection Act of 2007 - Amends the federal criminal code to: (1) prohibit accessing or remotely controlling a protected computer to obtain identification information; (2) revise the definition of &quot;protected computer&quot; to include computers affecting interstate or foreign commerce or communication; (3) expand the definition of racketeering to include computer fraud; (4) redefine the crime of computer-related extortion to include threats to access without authorization (or to exceed authorized access of) a protected computer; (5) impose criminal penalties for conspiracy to commit computer fraud; (6) impose a fine and/or five year prison term for failure to notify the U.S. Secret Service or Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) of a major security breach (involving a significant risk of identity theft) in a computer system, with the intent to thwart an investigation of such breach; (7) increase to 30 years the maximum term of imprisonment for computer fraud and require forfeiture of property used to commit computer fraud; and (8) impose criminal penalties for damaging 10 or more protected computers during any one-year period. Directs the U.S. Sentencing Commission to review and amend its guidelines and policy statements to reflect congressional intent to increase criminal penalties for computer fraud. Authorizes additional appropriations in FY2007-FY2011 to the U.S. Secret Service, the Department of Justice, and the FBI to investigate and prosecute criminal activity involving computers.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
