<bill session="110" type="h" number="837" updated="2009-01-08T18:33:57-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1170738000" datetime="2007-02-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1170738000" datetime="2007-02-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Internet Stopping Adults Facilitating the Exploitation of Today's Youth Act (SAFETY) of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, to protect youth from exploitation by adults using the Internet, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400381"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400137" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2007-09-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400071" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400144" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400131" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400617" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400315" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400654" joined="2007-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400141" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400321" joined="2007-02-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170738000" datetime="2007-02-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/6/2007--Introduced.<br/>Internet Stopping Adults Facilitating the Exploitation of Today's Youth Act (SAFETY) of 2007 - Amends the federal criminal code to prohibit: (1) financial transactions in interstate or foreign commerce that facilitate access to, or the possession of, child pornography; and (2) Internet content hosting providers or email service providers from facilitating access to, or the possession of, child pornography.<br/>Amends the Victims of Child Abuse Act of 1990 to: (1) increase monetary penalties for willful failure of electronic communication service providers to report child pornography; and (2) impose new penalties for negligent failure to report.<br/>Requires the Attorney General to issue regulations governing the retention of certain records by Internet Service Providers.<br/>Increases criminal penalties for the sexual exploitation of children and for activities involving the sexual exploitation of children and child pornography.<br/>Requires commercial website operators to place warning marks prescribed by the Federal Trade Commission on web pages that contain sexually explicit materials.<br/>Authorizes appropriations for FY2008-FY2012 for the Innocent Images National Initiative.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
