<bill session="110" type="h" number="839" updated="2009-01-08T18:34:11-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1174342800" datetime="2007-03-19T19:20:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="159"/></status>

	<introduced date="1170738000" datetime="2007-02-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Arthur V. Watkins Dam Enlargement Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Arthur V. Watkins Dam Enlargement Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Arthur V. Watkins Dam Enlargement Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to study the feasibility of enlarging the Arthur V. Watkins Dam Weber Basin Project, Utah, to provide additional water for the Weber Basin Project to fulfill the purposes for which that project was authorized.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400029"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170738000" datetime="2007-02-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1170997200" datetime="2007-02-09"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text></action>
		<action date="1174326180" datetime="2007-03-19T14:43:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Grijalva moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text></action>
		<action date="1174326240" datetime="2007-03-19T14:44:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2634"/></action>
		<action date="1174326240" datetime="2007-03-19T14:44:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 839.</text></action>
		<action date="1174326420" datetime="2007-03-19T14:47:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1174342320" datetime="2007-03-19T19:12:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2639"/></action>
		<vote date="1174342800" how="roll" roll="159" datetime="2007-03-19T19:20:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" suspension="1" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 394 - 1 (Roll no. 159).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H2634"/></vote>
		<action date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. With written report No. 110-120.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="254" date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 254.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1213156800" datetime="2008-06-11"><text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S5530"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/28/2007--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the House passed version is repeated here.)<br/>Arthur V. Watkins Dam Enlargement Act - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Reclamation, to conduct a feasibility study (including an environmental evaluation and a cost allocation) on raising the height of the Arthur V. Watkins Dam for the development of additional storage to meet water supply needs within the Weber Basin Project area and the Wasatch Front, Utah.<br/>Limits the federal share to 50% of the study's cost. Directs the Secretary to accept in-kind contributions of goods or services from the Weber Basin Water Conservancy District as part of the non-federal cost share. Authorizes appropriations. Terminates the Secretary's authority to carry out this Act 10 years after its enactment.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
