<bill session="110" type="h" number="849" updated="2009-01-08T18:35:21-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1170738000" datetime="2007-02-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1170738000" datetime="2007-02-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Stop the Misuse of ITINs Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to require the Secretary of the Treasury to notify the Secretary of Homeland Security of employer returns showing the employment of individuals not authorized to be employed in the United States and to notify the employers that they must terminate the employment of those employees, to provide an opportunity for those employees to contest the information, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400144"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400385" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2007-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400229" joined="2008-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400365" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400412" joined="2007-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400153" joined="2008-02-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170738000" datetime="2007-02-06"><text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Education and Labor, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1170738000" datetime="2007-02-06"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1170738000" datetime="2007-02-06"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1170738000" datetime="2007-02-06"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text></action>
		<action date="1179460800" datetime="2007-05-18"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/6/2007--Introduced.<br/>Stop the Misuse of ITINs Act of 2007 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to require the Secretary of the Treasury to: (1) notify the Secretary of Homeland Security of any employer tax return which shows wages paid to an employee who is not authorized to be employed in the United States; and (2) provide a written notice to the employer and employee involved that such employment is illegal and must be terminated within 30 days after the date of said notice. Allows any employee who receives a notice to contest such notice and provide documentation substantiating such employee's claimed authorization to work in the United States. 
	</summary>
</bill>
