<bill session="110" type="h" number="850" updated="2009-01-08T18:35:28-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1170738000" datetime="2007-02-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1170738000" datetime="2007-02-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">IRS Illegal Immigrant Information Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish a procedure for determining whether individuals who are not authorized to be employed in the United States are so employed.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400144"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400385" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2007-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400071" joined="2008-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400229" joined="2008-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400040" joined="2008-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400412" joined="2007-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400153" joined="2008-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400628" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400651" joined="2008-02-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170738000" datetime="2007-02-06"><text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Education and Labor, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1170738000" datetime="2007-02-06"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1170738000" datetime="2007-02-06"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1170738000" datetime="2007-02-06"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1179460800" datetime="2007-05-18"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/6/2007--Introduced.<br/>IRS Illegal Immigrant Information Act of 2007 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to require: (1) the Secretary of Homeland Security to request from the Secretary of the Treasury information (including mailing address, amount of wages earned, and identity of employer) about alien workers who are no longer authorized to work in the United States; (2) the Secretary of the Treasury to provide the requested information to the Department of Homeland Security; and (3) the Secretary of Homeland Security to notify the alien worker and and the worker's employer that such employment is illegal and must be terminated within 30 days of such notice. Allows any worker who receives a notice to contest such notice and to provide documentation substantiating such worker's authorization to be employed in the United States.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
