<bill session="110" type="h" number="852" updated="2009-01-08T18:35:42-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1170738000" datetime="2007-02-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1170738000" datetime="2007-02-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Consumer Telephone Records Protection Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the obtaining of customer information from telecommunications carriers by false pretenses, and the sale or disclosure of such records obtained by false pretenses.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400193"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400627" joined="2007-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400663" joined="2007-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400109" joined="2007-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400032" joined="2007-02-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170738000" datetime="2007-02-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text></action>
		<action date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and the Internet.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/6/2007--Introduced.<br/>Consumer Telephone Records Protection Act of 2007 - Makes it unlawful for any person in interstate commerce to knowingly and intentionally: (1) obtain confidential phone records information under false pretenses; (2) sell or transfer confidential phone records information without prior authorization from the customer; and (3) receive or purchase confidential phone records information. Provides for Federal Trade Commission (FTC) enforcement of such provisions. Makes such provisions inapplicable to law enforcement agencies. Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to require a telecommunication carrier to notify a customer of any incidents in which proprietary network information relating to such customer is disclosed to someone other than the customer. 
	</summary>
</bill>
