<bill session="110" type="h" number="853" updated="2009-01-08T18:35:49-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1170738000" datetime="2007-02-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1170738000" datetime="2007-02-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Wellness and Prevention Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To promote preventive health care for Americans.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400225"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400414" joined="2007-03-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2007-04-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400276" joined="2007-03-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2007-03-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="2007-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="412213" joined="2007-03-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="2007-04-16"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170738000" datetime="2007-02-06"><text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1170738000" datetime="2007-02-06"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1170738000" datetime="2007-02-06"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1171947600" datetime="2007-02-20"><committee name="House Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1185940800" datetime="2007-08-01"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H9284)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/6/2007--Introduced.<br/>Wellness and Prevention Act of 2007 - Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services to pay up to a specified amount of the medical education loans incurred by any physician who receives board certification in preventive medicine from FY2008-FY2012. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide for a wellness program tax credit for employers that develop and implement a program that: (1) conducts health risk assessments for each program participant; (2) offers annually at least two preventive health screenings; (3) offers annual counseling sessions on at least three preventive health topics; and (4) includes as participants not less than 50% of full-time employees. Provides a tax credit for qualified employees that participate in their employer's qualified wellness program.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
