<bill session="110" type="h" number="876" updated="2009-01-08T18:38:43-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"/></status>

	<introduced date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">SAFE Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Securing Adolescents From Exploitation-Online Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To modernize and expand the reporting requirements relating to child pornography, to expand cooperation in combating child pornography, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400071"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400027" joined="2007-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400160" joined="2007-03-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400246" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="412230" joined="2008-07-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400191" joined="2007-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="412210" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2007-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400229" joined="2007-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400084" joined="2007-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400652" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400412" joined="2008-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400640" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400147" joined="2007-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412235" joined="2007-10-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400217" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412196" joined="2007-02-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400415" joined="2007-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2007-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400141" joined="2007-05-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/7/2007--Introduced.<br/>Securing Adolescents From Exploitation-Online Act of 2007 or the SAFE Act of 2007 - Amends the federal criminal code to expand the reporting requirements of electronic communication and remote computing service providers with respect to violations of child sexual exploitation and pornography laws. Requires such service providers, in reporting violations of such laws to the CyberTipline of the National Center for Missing and Exploited Children to provide: (1) information on the Internet identity of a suspected sex offender, including the electronic mail address, website address, uniform resource locator, or other identifying information; (2) the time child pornography was uploaded or discovered; (3) geographic location information for the offender; and (4) images of such child pornography. Requires the Center to forward each report which it receives from a service provider to a designated law enforcement agency. Requires service providers to preserve images of child pornography for evidentiary purposes. Grants service providers and the Center immunity from civil claims or criminal charges for complying the requirements of this Act, except for certain intentional or reckless misconduct. Requires the U.S. Trade Representative, the Attorney General, and other relevant federal officials to encourage foreign governments to combat child sexual exploitation and pornography. Authorizes appropriations for grants to the Internet Crimes Against Children Task Force. Authorizes courts to order monitoring of Internet use by a convicted sex offender as a condition for such offender's supervised release. Imposes enhanced criminal penalties for use of the Internet to violate child pornography or sexual exploitation laws. Requires the Attorney General to make publicly available reports on investigations and prosecutions of child sexual exploitation crimes.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
