<bill session="110" type="h" number="887" updated="2009-01-08T18:40:08-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"/></status>

	<introduced date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">GRAD Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Graduation Really Achieves Dreams Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for Project GRAD programs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400257"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400327" joined="2007-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400160" joined="2007-03-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2007-10-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400080" joined="2007-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400282" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400246" joined="2007-10-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400116" joined="2007-07-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400003" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400406" joined="2007-10-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400130" joined="2007-02-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2007-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400048" joined="2007-03-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="412204" joined="2007-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400653" joined="2007-10-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400195" joined="2007-11-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400125" joined="2007-11-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412186" joined="2007-10-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400440" joined="2007-07-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="412228" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="2007-12-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400240" joined="2007-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400025" joined="2007-03-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400179" joined="2007-03-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1181016000" datetime="2007-06-05"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/7/2007--Introduced.<br/>Graduation Really Achieves Dreams Act or the GRAD Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award a grant to Project GRAD USA, a nonprofit educational organization for improving high school graduation and college attendance and completion rates for disadvantaged students, to provide technical assistance and support through subgrants to existing and new programs that implement a set of integrated education reform services. Requires the grantee to select only subgrantees that serve a substantial number or percentage of low-income students. Requires the programs to identify one or more groups of public schools at which services will be provided through a feeder pattern through which elementary and secondary schools channel students having participated in program services into an identified high school. Requires program services to include: (1) research-based programs in reading, mathematics, and classroom management; (2) campus-based social services programs, including increasing family and community involvement in schools; (3) a college access program, including providing college scholarships for students who meet established criteria, increasing student and family college awareness, and assisting students to apply for college financial aid; and (4) other services the grantee identifies as necessary.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
