<bill session="110" type="h" number="888" updated="2009-01-08T18:40:15-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"/></status>

	<introduced date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Business Travel Facilitation Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the admission to the United States of nonimmigrant business facilitation visitors.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400271"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400087" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400131" joined="2007-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400046" joined="2007-12-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/7/2007--Introduced.<br/>Business Travel Facilitation Act of 2007 - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to include business facilitation visitors from a qualifying country as nonimmigrant aliens visiting the United States temporarily for business. Defines &quot;business facilitation visitor&quot; as an alien visiting the United States temporarily to: (1) provide services pursuant to a qualifying services contract; or (2) provide management or technical training to, or receive management or technical training from personnel of a U.S. entity. Sets forth conditions with respect to: (1) provision of services; and (2) provision or receipt of management or technical training. Provides a period of authorized admission of: (1) one year with a one-time six month extension for an alien providing services; and (2) one year for an alien providing or receiving management or technical training. Prohibits such aliens from changing nonimmigrant status or adjusting to immigrant status. Authorizes the Secretary of Homeland Security to prohibit business facilitation entries from a country whose nationals have engaged in a pattern of fraud involving visas or other immigration matters.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
