<bill session="110" type="h" number="889" updated="2009-01-08T18:40:22-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"/></status>

	<introduced date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Prevention of Aquatic Invasive Species Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Nonindigenous Aquatic Nuisance Prevention and Control Act of 1990 to establish vessel ballast water management requirements, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400276"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400225" joined="2007-06-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"><text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1170910800" datetime="2007-02-08"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text></action>
		<action date="1170910800" datetime="2007-02-08"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text></action>
		<action date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, and Oceans.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/7/2007--Introduced.<br/>Prevention of Aquatic Invasive Species Act of 2007 - Amends the Nonindigenous Aquatic Nuisance Prevention and Control Act of 1990 to revise certain aquatic invasive species prevention requirements to, among other things: (1) apply them to certain U.S. vessels and to certain foreign vessels (or a structure being towed by a vessel) that are en route to, or have departed from, a U.S. port; and (2) establish ballast water exchange and treatment and sediment management standards for vessels of the armed forces. Prohibits an operator of a vessel from uptaking or discharging ballast water or sediment, except in specified circumstances, from a U.S. vessel operating in U.S. or non-U.S. waters. Requires a vessel to conduct all its ballast water management operations in accordance with an aquatic invasive species plan designed to minimize the discharge of aquatic invasive species. Requires a vessel, before discharging ballast water into U.S. waters, to conduct ballast water treatment so that the discharged ballast water will contain no more than a specified level of living organisms or microbes. Prohibits an operator of a vessel, until the vessel conducts such treatment, from discharging ballast water except after certain ballast water exchange and ballast water treatment requirements are met. Sets forth civil penalties for violations of this Act. Urges the Secretary to negotiate with foreign countries to develop and implement an international program for preventing the unintentional introduction and spread of aquatic invasive species.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
