<bill session="110" type="h" number="899" updated="2009-01-08T18:41:36-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"/></status>

	<introduced date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Pigford Claims Remedy Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide a mechanism for the determination on the merits of the claims of claimants who met the class criteria in a civil action relating to racial discrimination by the Department of Agriculture but who were denied that determination.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400364"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400071" joined="2007-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400402" joined="2007-04-16"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text></action>
		<action date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/7/2007--Introduced.<br/>Pigford Claims Remedy Act of 2007 - Declares that any Pigford claimant (relating to a racial discrimination action against the Department of Agriculture) who has not previously obtained a determination on the merits of a Pigford claim may, in a civil action, obtain that determination. Asserts that it is Congress' intent that this Act be liberally construed so as to effectuate its remedial purpose of giving a full determination on the merits for each denied Pigford claim. Defines: (1) &quot;Pigford claimant&quot; as an individual who previously submitted a late-filing request under the consent decree in the case of Pigford v. Glickman (1999); and (2) &quot;Pigford claim&quot; as a discrimination complaint as defined and documented by such consent decree.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
