<bill session="110" type="h" number="905" updated="2009-01-08T18:42:21-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"/></status>

	<introduced date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="popular" as="">CUTS bill</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Commission on Unfair Tax Breaks and Subsidies (or &quot;CUTS&quot;) Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To increase accountability and equity in the Federal budget.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400412"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"><text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"><text>Referred to House Rules</text></action>
		<action date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E378)</text></action>
		<action date="1174968000" datetime="2007-03-27"><committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Organization, and Procurement.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/7/2007--Introduced.<br/>Commission on Unfair Tax Breaks and Subsidies, or CUTS Act of 2007 - Establishes the Commission on Unfair Tax Breaks and Subsidies to: (1) examine federal programs and tax laws and identify which ones provide inequitable federal subsidies; (2) review such subsidies; and (3) report to Congress. States that this Act is not intended to result in the creation of new programs or taxes. Requires the Commission to limit: (1) its activities to reviewing programs or tax laws as of the enactment of this Act with the goal of ensuring fairness and equity in its operation and application; and (2) its recommendations to the termination or reduction of payments, benefits, services, or tax advantages, rather than the termination of federal agencies or departments. 
	</summary>
</bill>
