<bill session="110" type="h" number="909" updated="2009-01-08T18:42:49-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1170910800" datetime="2007-02-08"/></status>

	<introduced date="1170910800" datetime="2007-02-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Safe Water Improvement and Modernization Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act and the Beaches Environmental Assessment and Coastal Health Act of 2000 to authorize appropriations for activities to improve the quality of coastal recreation waters, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400570"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400219" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400129" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400359" joined="2007-02-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400057" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400328" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400182" joined="2007-02-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170910800" datetime="2007-02-08"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text></action>
		<action date="1170997200" datetime="2007-02-09"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/8/2007--Introduced.<br/>Safe Water Improvement and Modernization Act of 2007 - Extends through FY2012 the authorization of appropriations for: (1) grants by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to states and local governments for coastal recreation water quality monitoring and notification programs; and (2) carrying out the Beaches Environmental Assessment and Coastal Health Act of 2000. Requires the Administrator to study the benefits of using molecular diagnostics for monitoring and assessing the quality of coastal recreation waters, including by: (1) evaluating the full range of available rapid indicator technologies; and (2) comparing the use of molecular diagnostics to culture testing of same source water. Authorizes the Administrator to award a grant or cooperative agreement to an organization to assist the Administrator in carrying out the study.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
