<bill session="110" type="h" number="925" updated="2009-01-08T18:45:04-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1170910800" datetime="2007-02-08"/></status>

	<introduced date="1170910800" datetime="2007-02-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Emergency Farm Assistance Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide emergency agricultural disaster assistance for agricultural producers, manufacturers, and workers in the State of California, to appropriate funds for Pacific salmon emergency disaster assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400297"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400290" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400618" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400330" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400403" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412190" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400267" joined="2007-03-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400065" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400124" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400423" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412189" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400396" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400384" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400355" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400245" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400231" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400663" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400356" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400057" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400166" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400009" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400617" joined="2007-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400371" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400025" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400062" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="2007-02-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170910800" datetime="2007-02-08"><text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committees on the Budget, Natural Resources, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1170910800" datetime="2007-02-08"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action date="1170910800" datetime="2007-02-08"><text>Referred to House Budget</text></action>
		<action date="1170910800" datetime="2007-02-08"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1170910800" datetime="2007-02-08"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1170997200" datetime="2007-02-09"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text></action>
		<action date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, and Oceans.</text></action>
		<action date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"><committee name="House Natural Resources"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text></action>
		<action date="1172811600" datetime="2007-03-02"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Horticulture and Organic Agriculture.</text></action>
		<action date="1172811600" datetime="2007-03-02"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry.</text></action>
		<action date="1172811600" datetime="2007-03-02"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/8/2007--Introduced.<br/>Emergency Farm Assistance Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (Secretary) to provide assistance: (1) to producers of specialty crops in disaster counties that suffered losses in 2005 or 2006; (2) to citrus producers in disaster counties that suffered losses in 2007; (3) to producers of other specialty crops in disaster counties that suffered losses in 2007; (4) to dairy producers in disaster counties that suffered losses in 2006; and (5) for livestock indemnity payments to producers in disaster counties that incurred losses in 2006 or 2007, or both. Directs the Secretary to make grants to California for an expedited disaster assistance program to qualified small businesses that suffered losses during the 2005, 2006, or 2007 crop year as a result of weather-related agricultural losses to the California specialty crop or livestock production sectors. Directs the Secretary to provide assistance to tree or fruit and tree nut producers in disaster counties that suffered losses in 2005, 2006, or 2007, or any combination of such years. Defines &quot;tree&quot; to include: (1) a tree (including a Christmas tree, ornamental tree, nursery tree, and potted tree); (2) a bush (including a shrub, nursery shrub, nursery bush, ornamental bush, ornamental shrub, potted bush, and potted shrub); and (3) a vine (including a nursery vine and ornamental vine). Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to provide unemployment assistance and temporary mortgage rental assistance to California agricultural workers (including low-income migrant and seasonal farmworkers) who are unemployed due to disasters in 2007. Directs the Secretary to provide: (1) food coupons and surplus commodities to such workers; and (2) emergency grants for California low-income migrant and seasonal farmworkers who are unemployed due to disasters in 2007. Appropriates additional funds to the Secretary of Commerce for emergency disaster assistance to fishing communities, Indian tribes, and small businesses adversely affected by harvesting restrictions on Klamath River Fall chinook salmon.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
