<bill session="110" type="h" number="933" updated="2009-01-08T18:46:16-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1170910800" datetime="2007-02-08"/></status>

	<introduced date="1170910800" datetime="2007-02-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Witness Security and Protection Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish within the United States Marshals Service a short term State witness protection program to provide assistance to State and local district attorneys to protect their witnesses in cases involving homicide, serious violent felonies, and serious drug offenses, and to provide Federal grants for such protection.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400090"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400073" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400385" joined="2007-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400130" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400415" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2007-03-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="2007-05-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400349" joined="2007-02-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170910800" datetime="2007-02-08"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1170997200" datetime="2007-02-09"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR 2/12/2007 E309-310)</text></action>
		<action date="1174276800" datetime="2007-03-19"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text></action>
		<action date="1177387200" datetime="2007-04-24"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1189051200" datetime="2007-09-06"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H10197-10198)</text></action>
		<action date="1190001600" datetime="2007-09-17"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H10409)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/8/2007--Introduced.<br/>Witness Security and Protection Act of 2007 - Amends the federal judicial code to establish in the U. S. Marshals Service a Short Term State Witness Protection Section to provide protection for witnesses in state and local trials involving homicide or a serious violent felony or serious drug offense, pursuant to cooperative agreements with state and local district attorneys and the U.S. attorney for the District of Columbia. Directs the Section to give priority in awarding grants and providing services to prosecutor's offices in states with an average of at least 100 murders per year during the five-year period immediately preceding an application for protection. Authorizes: (1) the Attorney General to make grants to state and local district attorneys and to the U.S. attorney for the District of Columbia for providing such witness protection; and (2) each recipient to use the grant to provide witness protection or to credit the grant to the Section to cover the Section's costs of providing witness protection. Permits grants to be awarded only in states with an average of not less than 100 murders per year during the most recent five-year period.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
