<bill session="110" type="h" number="960" updated="2009-01-08T18:50:13-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1170910800" datetime="2007-02-08"/></status>

	<introduced date="1170910800" datetime="2007-02-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Enhancing America's Security through Redeployment from Iraq Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance the national security interests of the United States both at home and abroad by setting a deliberate timetable for the redeployment of United States Armed Forces from Iraq by December 31, 2007, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412232"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400130" joined="2007-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="2007-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400230" joined="2007-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412209" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2007-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="412219" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400215" joined="2007-02-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170910800" datetime="2007-02-08"><text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1170910800" datetime="2007-02-08"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1170910800" datetime="2007-02-08"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"><committee name="House Foreign Affairs"/><text>Committee Hearings Held.</text></action>
		<action date="1181016000" datetime="2007-06-05"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H5985)</text></action>
		<action date="1182225600" datetime="2007-06-19"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H6727)</text></action>
		<action date="1182484800" datetime="2007-06-22"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H7003-7004)</text></action>
		<action date="1184126400" datetime="2007-07-11"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H7495-7496)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/8/2007--Introduced.<br/>Enhancing America's Security Through Redeployment from Iraq Act - Requires that, no later than December 31, 2007, all U.S. Armed Forces serving in Iraq be redeployed outside of Iraq, either to locations within the Middle East or Southwest Asia regions or other regions or nations, or to the United States. Provides redeployment exceptions with respect to: (1) special operations forces performing counter-terrorism operations or support operations for Iraqi security forces; (2) military liaison teams; (3) air support operations for Iraqi security forces; (4) counter-terrorism operations in Iraq; and (5) security for U.S. diplomatic missions in Iraq. Allows funds appropriated to the Department of Defense (DOD) for Operation Iraqi Freedom to be obligated or expended after such deadline only for personnel performing such excepted operations. Expresses the sense of Congress that the United States should: (1) take a leadership role in diplomatic efforts and negotiations for the long-term stability of Iraq; and (2) convene an international conference to provide economic aid for rebuilding the infrastructure of Iraq and other efforts essential to ensure its long-term stability.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
