<bill session="110" type="h" number="968" updated="2009-01-08T18:51:09-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1170910800" datetime="2007-02-08"/></status>

	<introduced date="1170910800" datetime="2007-02-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Fund for Excellence in American Indian Education Amendments Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act to modify provisions relating to the National Fund for Excellence in American Indian Education.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400412"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170910800" datetime="2007-02-08"><text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1170910800" datetime="2007-02-08"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1170910800" datetime="2007-02-08"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1170997200" datetime="2007-02-09"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR 2/12/2007 E300-301)</text></action>
		<action date="1181016000" datetime="2007-06-05"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/8/2007--Introduced.<br/>National Fund for Excellence in American Indian Education Amendments Act of 2007 - Amends the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act with respect to the National Fund for Excellence in American Indian Education (Foundation). Requires the Foundation Board to appoint a chief operating officer for the Foundation separate from the Secretary of the Interior (who currently acts as chief operating officer). Places limitations on the administrative costs of the Foundation. Authorizes appropriations for FY2008-FY2010. Authorizes the Secretary to provide funds to pay the operating expenses of the Foundation. 
	</summary>
</bill>
