<bill session="110" type="h" number="992" updated="2009-01-08T18:54:11-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1171256400" datetime="2007-02-12"/></status>

	<introduced date="1171256400" datetime="2007-02-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Cloned Food Labeling Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act and the Federal Meat Inspection Act to require that food that contains product from a cloned animal be labeled accordingly, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400103"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2008-09-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2008-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-01-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400102" joined="2008-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400246" joined="2008-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400096" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400129" joined="2007-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2008-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400124" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400630" joined="2008-04-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="2008-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="2008-01-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2007-03-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400346" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2008-01-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2008-01-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2007-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412186" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2008-06-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400215" joined="2008-01-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400163" joined="2008-05-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400100" joined="2007-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="2008-01-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1171256400" datetime="2007-02-12"><text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1171256400" datetime="2007-02-12"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
		<action date="1171256400" datetime="2007-02-12"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1172811600" datetime="2007-03-02"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry.</text></action>
		<action date="1172811600" datetime="2007-03-02"><committee name="House Agriculture"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Specialty Crops, Rural Development, and Foreign Agriculture.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/12/2007--Introduced.<br/>Cloned Food Labeling Act - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act and the Federal Meat Inspection Act to deem as misbranded a food or meat food product that contains any part of a cloned animal and does not bear a conspicuous label including a notice of that information. Requires individuals to maintain a verifiable recordkeeping audit trail that will permit verification of compliance with this Act. Deems as misbranded a food that bears a label indicating that it does not contain cloned product, unless the label is in accordance with applicable regulations that may not: (1) require such a label to include a statement indicating that the fact that a food does not contain such product has no bearing on the safety of the food for human consumption; and (2) prohibit such a label on the basis that, in the case of the type of food involved, there is no version of the food in commercial distribution that does contain such product. Sets forth civil penalties for violation of this Act. Exempts a person who establishes a guaranty, signed by the person residing in the United States from whom the food was received in good faith, that the food does not contain any cloned product. Allows a person to commence a civil action against a person who is alleged to have violated this Act or the applicable Secretary where a failure of the Secretary to perform any act or duty that is not discretionary is alleged.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
