<bill session="110" type="h" number="994" updated="2009-01-08T18:54:25-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1171256400" datetime="2007-02-12"/></status>

	<introduced date="1171256400" datetime="2007-02-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Nuclear Regulatory Commission to conduct an Independent Safety Assessment of the Indian Point Energy Center.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412222"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400122" joined="2007-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400246" joined="2007-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="2007-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2007-02-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1171256400" datetime="2007-02-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/12/2007--Introduced.<br/>Directs the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) to report to Congress regarding: (1) a focused, in-depth Independent Safety Assessment of the design, construction, maintenance, and operational safety performance of certain systems at the Indian Point Energy Center, Units 2 and 3, Westchester County, New York; and (2) a comprehensive evaluation of the radiological emergency plan for the Center, conducted by the NRC and the Department of Homeland Security. Requires that such Independent Safety Assessment be: (1) conducted by an Independent Safety Assessment Team; (2) monitored by an Independent Safety Assessment Observation Group and by an Independent Safety Assessment Citizens' Review Team; and (3) equal in scope, depth, and breadth to the Independent Safety Assessment of the Maine Yankee Nuclear Power Plant, located near Bath, Maine, conducted by the NRC in 1996. Prescribes conditions for a final NRC decision to renew the operating licenses for Units 2 and 3 at the Center.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
