<bill session="110" type="hc" number="107" updated="2009-01-08T15:40:24-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/></status>

	<introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the Congress that neither the President, the Vice President, nor any Member of Congress, justice or judge of the United States, or political appointee in the executive branch of the Government should belong to a club that discriminates on the basis of sex or race.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400251"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400371" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400346" joined="2007-03-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committees on House Administration, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Referred to House House Administration</text></action>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1175227200" datetime="2007-03-30"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E708)</text></action>
		<action date="1177041600" datetime="2007-04-20"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/29/2007--Introduced.<br/>Fair Play-Equal Access in Membership Resolution - Expresses the sense of Congress that neither the President, the Vice President, nor any Member of Congress, federal justice or judge, or political appointee in the executive branch should belong to a club that discriminates on the basis of sex or race. 
	</summary>
</bill>
