<bill session="110" type="hc" number="119" updated="2009-01-08T15:41:54-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1176868800" datetime="2007-04-18"/></status>

	<introduced date="1176868800" datetime="2007-04-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the Congress that the President should immediately and unequivocally call for the enforcement of existing immigration laws in order to reduce the threat of a terrorist attack and to reduce the massive influx of illegal aliens into the United States.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400153"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400570" joined="2007-10-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1176868800" datetime="2007-04-18"><text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Homeland Security, and Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1176868800" datetime="2007-04-18"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1176868800" datetime="2007-04-18"><text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text></action>
		<action date="1176868800" datetime="2007-04-18"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1178251200" datetime="2007-05-04"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/18/2007--Introduced.<br/>States that the President and the Secretary of Homeland Security should: (1) use every tool available to them to secure the borders against illegal entry; (2) seek state and local law enforcement assistance in enforcing immigration laws; and (3) warn Mexico that any further actions it takes to encourage illegal immigration to the United States will be viewed as interference with our domestic laws in violation of the Vienna Convention on Consular Relations. States that the President should announce that he will oppose any proposal to grant legal status or amnesty to illegal aliens. 
	</summary>
</bill>
