<bill session="110" type="hc" number="126" updated="2009-01-08T15:42:49-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1177300800" datetime="2007-04-23"/></status>

	<introduced date="1177300800" datetime="2007-04-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Supporting the goals and ideals of the Day of Silence with respect to discrimination and harassment faced by lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgender individuals in schools.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400122"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="2007-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400268" joined="2007-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="412186" joined="2007-11-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400308" joined="2007-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400289" joined="2007-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400184" joined="2007-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400013" joined="2007-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400246" joined="2007-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400129" joined="2007-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400269" joined="2007-04-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1177300800" datetime="2007-04-23"><text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1177300800" datetime="2007-04-23"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1177300800" datetime="2007-04-23"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1178251200" datetime="2007-05-04"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text></action>
		<action date="1183953600" datetime="2007-07-09"><committee name="House Education and Labor"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/23/2007--Introduced.<br/>Supports the goals and ideals of the Day of Silence (during which students vow to remain silent to bring attention to the harassment and discrimination faced by lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgender people in schools). Encourages each city and state to adopt laws to prohibit discrimination and harassment against students, teachers, and other school staff regardless of their sexual orientation and gender identity and expression. 
	</summary>
</bill>
