<bill session="110" type="hc" number="156" updated="2009-01-08T15:46:53-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing support for the Declaration on the Rights of Indigenous Peoples and urging the United States Ambassador to the United Nations General Assembly to adopt without amendment the Declaration as approved by the United Nations Human Rights Council on June 29, 2006.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400128"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400041" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400001" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400152" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400333" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="2007-07-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1180065600" datetime="2007-05-25"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1148-1149)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/23/2007--Introduced.<br/>States that: (1) Congress finds that the relationship between the United States and the indigenous peoples of the United States, the United States Tribal Nations, grounded in the Constitution and implemented through Indian treaties, federal statutes, and policies, may be considered a model by other countries in recognizing the rights of self-determination and self-governance; (2) the interests of tribal nations may be further advanced and protected by adoption of such rights as U.S. policy; and (3) Congress recommends that the U.S. Ambassador to the U.N. General Assembly support the Declaration on the Rights of Indigenous Peoples when it comes before the General Assembly during their fall 2007 session. 
	</summary>
</bill>
