<bill session="110" type="hc" number="175" updated="2009-01-08T15:49:20-05:00">
	<status><vote2 date="1185768000" datetime="2007-07-30" where="s" result="pass" how="by Unanimous Consent" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of Congress that courts with fiduciary responsibility for a child of a deceased member of the Armed Forces who receives a death gratuity payment under section 1477 of title 10, United States Code, should take into consideration the expression of clear intent of the member regarding the distribution of funds on behalf of the child.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400234"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412209" joined="2007-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400220" joined="2007-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400042" joined="2007-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="412208" joined="2007-06-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1185212940" datetime="2007-07-23T14:49:00-04:00"><text>Ms. Jackson-Lee moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution.</text></action>
		<action date="1185212940" datetime="2007-07-23T14:49:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8226-8228"/></action>
		<action date="1185212940" datetime="2007-07-23T14:49:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Con. Res. 175.</text></action>
		<vote date="1185213840" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-07-23T15:04:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text as passed in House" ref="CR H8226"/></vote>
		<action date="1185249600" datetime="2007-07-24"><text>Received in the Senate.</text></action>
		<vote date="1185768000" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2007-07-30" where="s" type="vote2" result="pass" ><text>Resolution agreed to in Senate without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S10335-10336"/><reference label="text as passed Senate" ref="CR S10336"/></vote>
		<action date="1185854400" datetime="2007-07-31"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/30/2007--Passed Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Expresses the sense of Congress that courts with fiduciary responsibility for a child of a deceased member of the Armed Forces who receives a death gratuity payment from the Department of Defense (DOD) should take into consideration the expression of clear intent of the member regarding the distribution of funds on behalf of the child.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
