<bill session="110" type="hc" number="17" updated="2009-01-08T15:28:32-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"/></status>

	<introduced date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of Congress that the people of the United States should grieve for the loss of life that defined the Third Reich and celebrate the continued education efforts for tolerance and justice, reaffirming the commitment of the United States to the fight against intolerance and prejudice in any form, and honoring the legacy of transparent procedure, government accountability, the rule of law, the pursuit of justice, and the struggle for universal freedom and human rights.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400199"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2008-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2008-06-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1170651600" datetime="2007-02-05"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Europe.</text></action>
		<action date="1170651600" datetime="2007-02-05"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Organizations, Human Rights, and Oversight.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="Europe" activity="Referral" />
		<committee name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="International Organizations, Human Rights, and Oversight" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign policy"/>
		<term name="Civil liberties"/>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Congressional tributes"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice"/>
		<term name="Equality before the law"/>
		<term name="Europe"/>
		<term name="Germany"/>
		<term name="Government ethics"/>
		<term name="History"/>
		<term name="Human rights"/>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="Jewish holocaust (1939-1945)"/>
		<term name="Minorities"/>
		<term name="Nazism"/>
		<term name="Pluralism (Social sciences)"/>
		<term name="Politics and government"/>
		<term name="Prejudice"/>
		<term name="Racism"/>
		<term name="Rule of law"/>
		<term name="Victims of crimes"/>
		<term name="War crimes"/>
		<term name="World War II"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/5/2007--Introduced.<br/>Expresses the sense of Congress that the people of the United States should grieve for the loss of life that defined the Third Reich and celebrate the continued education efforts for tolerance and justice. States that: (1) the United States reaffirms its commitment to the fight against intolerance and prejudice; (2) Congress urges all members of the international community to honor those individuals of all races, creeds, and colors who were killed by the Nazis; and (3) the United States honors the primacy of transparent procedure, government accountability, the rule of law, the pursuit of justice, and the struggle for universal freedom and human rights. 
	</summary>
</bill>
