<bill session="110" type="hc" number="189" updated="2009-01-08T15:51:01-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1185163200" datetime="2007-07-23"/></status>

	<introduced date="1185163200" datetime="2007-07-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Urging all sides to the political crisis in Ukraine to abide by the May 27, 2007, agreement which calls for a new round of parliamentary elections on September 30, 2007, and to ensure a free and fair, transparent democratic system in Ukraine based on the rule of law.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400170"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400663" joined="2007-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400268" joined="2007-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400147" joined="2007-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400196" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400048" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400087" joined="2007-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400238" joined="2007-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400378" joined="2007-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400309" joined="2007-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400211" joined="2007-08-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1185163200" datetime="2007-07-23"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1595)</text></action>
		<action date="1185163200" datetime="2007-07-23"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/23/2007--Introduced.<br/>Welcomes the strong relationship formed between the United States and Ukraine since the restoration of Ukraine's independence in 1991 and especially following the Orange Revolution of 2004. Applauds Ukraine for holding free presidential elections. Urges the leadership and political parties of Ukraine to conduct elections as scheduled on September 30, 2007. Expresses support for the efforts of the Ukrainian people to consolidate the democratic gains of the Orange Revolution of 2004. Pledges assistance to the further development of a democratic system in Ukraine based on the rule of law, a free market economy, and consolidation of Ukraine's security and sovereignty. 
	</summary>
</bill>
