<bill session="110" type="hc" number="183" updated="2009-01-08T15:50:17-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1184212800" datetime="2007-07-12"/></status>

	<introduced date="1184212800" datetime="2007-07-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Calling on the Government of the Republic of Azerbaijan to immediately release Farhad Aliyev and Rafiq Aliyev from detention during trial, to assure that their right to a fair and open trial before an independent and impartial tribunal will be carried out, and to comply with all its international human rights agreements and commitments respecting the rule of law, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400170"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400332" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400297" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400038" joined="2007-07-18" withdrawn="2007-12-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400196" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400003" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400618" joined="2007-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400400" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400076" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400359" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400036" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400429" joined="2007-09-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1184212800" datetime="2007-07-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1184299200" datetime="2007-07-13"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1519)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/12/2007--Introduced.<br/>Calls on the government of the Republic of Azerbaijan to: (1) release Farhad Aliyev and Rafiq Aliyev from detention during trial and to assure their right to a fair and open trial; (2) implement visitation rights for family and medical and international legal advisers for Farhad and Rafiq Aliyev; and (3) fulfill its international obligations, including obligations relating to its membership in the Council of Europe, the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE), the Convention on Human Rights, and the Energy Charter Treaty. Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the U.S. government should use all available means, including diplomatic channels, to encourage the government of Azerbaijan to release Farhad and Rafiq Aliyev from detention during trial and prosecute those individuals who beat and attack journalists; (2) the U.S. government should coordinate actions with appropriate international organizations; and (3) the OSCE should monitor such legal proceedings for compliance with the Helsinki Final Act. 
	</summary>
</bill>
