<bill session="110" type="hc" number="20" updated="2009-01-08T15:28:53-05:00">
	<status><vote2 date="1173931200" datetime="2007-03-15" where="s" result="pass" how="by Unanimous Consent" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1168318800" datetime="2007-01-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Calling on the Government of the United Kingdom to immediately establish a full, independent, and public judicial inquiry into the murder of Northern Ireland defense attorney Patrick Finucane, as recommended by Judge Peter Cory as part of the Weston Park Agreement, in order to move forward on the Northern Ireland peace process.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400380"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400144" joined="2007-01-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400420" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400344" joined="2007-01-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400268" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400219" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412186" joined="2007-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400145" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400291" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400257" joined="2007-01-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400308" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400003" joined="2007-01-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2007-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400343" joined="2007-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400641" joined="2007-01-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400132" joined="2007-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400087" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2007-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400346" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400264" joined="2007-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400285" joined="2007-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400055" joined="2007-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400251" joined="2007-01-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400122" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400430" joined="2007-01-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400309" joined="2007-01-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1168318800" datetime="2007-01-09"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1169528400" datetime="2007-01-23"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1169528400" datetime="2007-01-23" ><text>Committee Agreed to Seek Consideration Under Suspension of the Rules, by Unanimous Consent.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1170177240" datetime="2007-01-30T13:14:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Lantos moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1170177240" datetime="2007-01-30T13:14:00-05:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H1000-1004"/></action>
		<action date="1170177240" datetime="2007-01-30T13:14:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Con. Res. 20.</text></action>
		<action date="1170178800" datetime="2007-01-30T13:40:00-05:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1170187620" datetime="2007-01-30T16:07:00-05:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H1019-1020"/></action>
		<vote date="1170188160" how="roll" roll="63" datetime="2007-01-30T16:16:00-05:00" where="h" type="vote" suspension="1" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 364 - 34, 25 Present (Roll no. 63).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H1000-1001"/></vote>
		<action date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"><text>Received in the Senate.</text></action>
		<action date="1170651600" datetime="2007-02-05"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Europe.</text></action>
		<action date="1170651600" datetime="2007-02-05"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Organizations, Human Rights, and Oversight.</text></action>
		<action date="1171688400" datetime="2007-02-17"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
		<action date="1173931200" datetime="2007-03-15"><text>Senate Committee on Foreign Relations discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text></action>
		<action date="1173931200" datetime="2007-03-15"><text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S3236-3237"/></action>
		<vote date="1173931200" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2007-03-15" where="s" type="vote2" result="pass" ><text>Resolution agreed to in Senate without amendment and an amended preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text></vote>
		<action date="1174276800" datetime="2007-03-19"><text>Notwithstanding the Senate's previous adoption of H.Con.Res. 20, the adoption of the amendment to the preamble was vitiated by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S3283"/></action>
		<action date="1174276800" datetime="2007-03-19"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/15/2007--Passed Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the House on January 30, 2007. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Expresses deepest condolences to the family of Patrick Finucane on his death, commends their steadfast pursuit of justice in his brutal murder, and thanks his wife Geraldine and son Michael for their willingness to testify on this matter before committees of the House of Representatives. Supports Administration efforts in seeking full implementation of the Weston Park Agreement and establishment of an independent judicial inquiry into Mr. Finucane's murder. Calls on the government of the United Kingdom to: (1) reconsider its position on the matter of an inquiry into Mr. Finucane's murder; (2) amend the Inquiries Act of 2005; and (3) take fully into account objections raised by Judge Cory, U.S. government officials, other governments, international bodies, and Mr. Finucane's family. Urges the government of the United Kingdom to establish a full, independent, and public judicial inquiry into Mr. Finucane's murder which would enjoy the support of his family, the people of Northern Ireland, and the international community as recommended by Judge Cory. 
	</summary>
</bill>
