<bill session="110" type="hc" number="200" updated="2009-01-08T15:52:22-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1191356520" datetime="2007-10-02T17:22:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="931"/></status>

	<introduced date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of Congress regarding the immediate and unconditional release of Daw Aung San Suu Kyi.</title>
		<title type="official" as="amended by house">A concurrent resolution expressing the sense of Congress regarding the immediate and unconditional release of Daw Aung San Suu Kyi and the severely deteriorating human rights situation in Burma.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400219"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400352" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400041" joined="2007-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400344" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400230" joined="2007-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412186" joined="2007-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400227" joined="2007-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400423" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400343" joined="2007-09-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400103" joined="2007-09-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400087" joined="2007-09-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="2007-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2007-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400662" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400315" joined="2007-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400259" joined="2007-09-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2007-09-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400346" joined="2007-09-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400215" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412250" joined="2007-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400184" joined="2007-09-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412204" joined="2007-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400055" joined="2007-09-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400363" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400355" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400025" joined="2007-09-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400301" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400251" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400320" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400380" joined="2007-09-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400163" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400122" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2007-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400385" joined="2007-09-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400430" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400435" joined="2007-09-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400245" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400231" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400252" joined="2007-09-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1190779200" datetime="2007-09-26"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1190779200" datetime="2007-09-26" ><text>Committee Agreed to Seek Consideration Under Suspension of the Rules, (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1191348000" datetime="2007-10-02T15:00:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Lantos moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1191348060" datetime="2007-10-02T15:01:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H11109-11116"/></action>
		<action date="1191348060" datetime="2007-10-02T15:01:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Con. Res. 200.</text></action>
		<action date="1191350640" datetime="2007-10-02T15:44:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1191356220" datetime="2007-10-02T17:17:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H11128"/></action>
		<vote date="1191356520" how="roll" roll="931" datetime="2007-10-02T17:22:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" suspension="1" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 413 - 2 (Roll no. 931).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H11109-11110"/></vote>
		<action date="1191356520" datetime="2007-10-02T17:22:00-04:00"><text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action date="1191384000" datetime="2007-10-03"><text>Received in the Senate and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/2/2007--Passed House amended. Condemns the Burmese junta's crackdown on peaceful protesters in the strongest possible terms, and demands that the junta end its violent crackdown on dissent. Demands that the People's Republic of China (PRC) and other countries that provide political and economic support to Burma's military junta end such support until the Burmese regime's violent campaign against peaceful protest has ceased and the Burmese government has met the opposition's political demands. Insists that Burma's military regime begin a tripartite political dialogue with Daw Aung San Suu Kyi, the National League for Democracy, and ethnic nationalities toward national reconciliation and the full restoration of democracy. Demands the release of Daw Aung San Suu Kyi, detained Buddhist monks, and all other political prisoners and prisoners of conscience. Calls on governments around the world, including the nations of the European Union (EU) and the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN), to tighten their sanctions against Burma. Calls on the U.N. Security Council to pass a resolution imposing multilateral sanctions on Burma's military regime, including a complete arms embargo, and to take other appropriate action to respond to the growing threat the State Peace and Development Council (SPDC) poses in Burma. Calls on the U.S. government to work with its global partners to bring to justice those Burmese military and government leaders who have ordered or participated in any massacre during or after the protests or who may be guilty of crimes against humanity. Calls on the members of ASEAN to suspend Burma's membership in such organization.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
