<bill session="110" type="hc" number="247" updated="2009-01-08T15:58:14-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1194325200" datetime="2007-11-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1194325200" datetime="2007-11-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing support for advancing vital United States interests through increased engagement in health programs that alleviate disease and poverty, and reduce premature death in developing nations, especially through programs that combat high levels of infectious disease, improve children's and women's health, decrease malnutrition, reduce unintended pregnancies, fight the spread of HIV/AIDS, encourage healthy behaviors, and strengthen health care capacity.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400312"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400661" joined="2007-11-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400222" joined="2007-11-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-11-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400048" joined="2007-11-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400259" joined="2007-11-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2007-11-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-12-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2007-11-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412221" joined="2007-11-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400422" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400653" joined="2007-11-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400122" joined="2007-12-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400350" joined="2007-11-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400333" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="2007-11-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400424" joined="2007-11-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400198" joined="2007-11-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400415" joined="2008-01-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400124" joined="2008-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400201" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2007-11-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400423" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="2007-11-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400090" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="2007-11-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400425" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400179" joined="2007-12-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1194325200" datetime="2007-11-06"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1194325200" datetime="2007-11-06"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1194325200" datetime="2007-11-06"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/6/2007--Introduced.<br/>Recognizes that: (1) contributing to improving health in developing nations is in the vital interest of the United States as it helps protect the health of the American people, facilitates development among partner nations, and cultivates a positive U.S. image; and (2) investments in health, particularly investments that reach disadvantaged populations, contribute to poverty alleviation. Acknowledges the need to strengthen health care systems to meet essential health needs.<br/>Expresses support for U.S. investments in reducing the global burdens of HIV/AIDS and malaria through the President's Emergency Program for AIDS Relief and the President's Malaria Initiative.<br/>Encourages the U.S. government to expand adoption and implementation of policies and programs that alleviate the greatest burden of disease in developing nations in the most efficient and cost-effective manner possible.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
