<bill session="110" type="hc" number="252" updated="2009-01-08T15:58:56-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1194584400" datetime="2007-11-09"/></status>

	<introduced date="1194584400" datetime="2007-11-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of Congress that no Federal or State requirement to increase energy efficient lighting in public buildings should require a hospital, school, day care center, mental health facility, or nursing home to install or utilize such energy efficient lighting if the lighting contains mercury.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400052"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1194584400" datetime="2007-11-09"><text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1194584400" datetime="2007-11-09"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1194584400" datetime="2007-11-09"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1194930000" datetime="2007-11-13"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text></action>
		<action date="1194930000" datetime="2007-11-13"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/9/2007--Introduced.<br/>Expresses the sense of Congress that no federal or state requirement to increase energy efficient lighting in public buildings should require a hospital, school, day care center, mental health facility, or nursing home to install or utilize lighting that contains mercury.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
