<bill session="110" type="hc" number="283" updated="2009-01-08T16:02:30-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1202443980" datetime="2008-02-07T12:13:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="34"/></status>

	<introduced date="1201064400" datetime="2008-01-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Calling for a peaceful resolution to the current electoral crisis in Kenya.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400312"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400073" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400048" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412199" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400616" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400087" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400618" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412221" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400422" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400653" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400380" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400350" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400333" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400424" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400074" joined="2008-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400201" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400423" joined="2008-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400204" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400090" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400240" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400438" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400130" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400030" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400435" joined="2008-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400231" joined="2008-02-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1201064400" datetime="2008-01-23"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1202326620" datetime="2008-02-06T15:37:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Payne moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1202326620" datetime="2008-02-06T15:37:00-05:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H576-580"/></action>
		<action date="1202326620" datetime="2008-02-06T15:37:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Con. Res. 283.</text></action>
		<action date="1202327940" datetime="2008-02-06T15:59:00-05:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1202443500" datetime="2008-02-07T12:05:00-05:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H640"/></action>
		<vote date="1202443980" how="roll" roll="34" datetime="2008-02-07T12:13:00-05:00" where="h" type="vote" suspension="1" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 405 - 1 (Roll no. 34). (text: CR 2/6/2008 H576-577)</text></vote>
		<action date="1202446800" datetime="2008-02-08"><text>Received in the Senate and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/7/2008--Passed House amended. Commends the Kenyan people for their commitment to democracy and respect for the democratic process as evidenced by the high voter turnout and peaceful voting on election day. Condemns the ongoing violence in Kenya and urges all parties concerned to immediately end use of violence as a means to achieve their political objectives. Calls on the two leading presidential candidates to accept offers of external and internal assistance to help find a solution to the current crisis which has the support of the people of Kenya. Calls on Kenyan security forces to refrain from using excessive force and to respect the human rights of Kenyan citizens. Calls for an immediate end to the restrictions on the media, and on the rights of peaceful assembly and association. Condemns threats to civil society groups, journalists, religious leaders, and human rights activists making every effort towards a peaceful, just, and equitable political solution to the current electoral crisis. Calls on the international community, United Nations aid organizations, and all neighboring countries to: (1) assist those affected by violence; and (2) use all the diplomatic means to persuade relevant political actors to commit to a peaceful resolution to the crisis. Urges the President to: (1) support diplomatic efforts to facilitate a dialogue between leaders of the Party of National Unity, the Orange Democratic Movement, and other relevant actors; (2) consider the imposition of targeted sanctions on such leaders who refuse to engage in meaningful dialogue to end the current crisis; and (3) review current U.S. aid to Kenya to restrict all non-essential assistance to Kenya unless the parties are able to establish a peaceful political resolution to the crisis which is credible to the Kenyan people.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
