<bill session="110" type="hc" number="31" updated="2009-01-08T15:30:30-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1169095680" datetime="2007-01-17T12:48:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="27"/></status>

	<introduced date="1168578000" datetime="2007-01-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Honoring the Mare Island Original 21ers for their efforts to remedy racial discrimination in employment at Mare Island Naval Shipyard.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400278"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1168578000" datetime="2007-01-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1168975080" datetime="2007-01-16T15:18:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Miller, George moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution.</text></action>
		<action date="1168975080" datetime="2007-01-16T15:18:00-05:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H536-538"/></action>
		<action date="1168975080" datetime="2007-01-16T15:18:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Con. Res. 31.</text></action>
		<action date="1168976100" datetime="2007-01-16T15:35:00-05:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1169094120" datetime="2007-01-17T12:22:00-05:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H595"/></action>
		<vote date="1169095680" how="roll" roll="27" datetime="2007-01-17T12:48:00-05:00" where="h" type="vote" suspension="1" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 416 - 0 (Roll no. 27). (text: CR 1/16/2007 H536)</text></vote>
		<action date="1169096400" datetime="2007-01-18"><text>Received in the Senate and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/17/2007--Passed House without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Recognizes: (1) the historic accomplishments of the Mare Island Original 21ers in combating employment discrimination against African-American shipyard workers; (2) the importance of the Committee on Equal Employment Opportunity as a forerunner to the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC); and (3) the importance of title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
