<bill session="110" type="hc" number="388" updated="2009-01-08T16:16:20-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1221690300" datetime="2008-09-17T19:25:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1215489600" datetime="2008-07-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of Congress that the Department of Defense and the Federal Voting Assistance Program should take certain additional and timely measures to ensure that members of the Armed Forces and their dependents are provided with reasonable information on how to register to vote and vote in the 2008 general elections.</title>
		<title type="official" as="amended by house">Expressing the sense of Congress that the Department of Defense and the Federal Voting Assistance Program should take certain additional and timely measures to ensure that members of the Armed Forces and their dependents and citizens living overseas are provided with reasonable information on how to register to vote and vote in the 2008 general elections.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400034"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412218" joined="2008-07-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400381" joined="2008-07-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400137" joined="2008-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412190" joined="2008-07-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412230" joined="2008-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400191" joined="2008-07-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400276" joined="2008-07-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400077" joined="2008-07-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400176" joined="2008-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400274" joined="2008-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400254" joined="2008-09-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400433" joined="2008-07-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400224" joined="2008-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400648" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400172" joined="2008-07-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400115" joined="2008-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400328" joined="2008-07-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400189" joined="2008-09-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400171" joined="2008-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400119" joined="2008-07-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400654" joined="2008-07-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400157" joined="2008-09-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1215489600" datetime="2008-07-08"><text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1215489600" datetime="2008-07-08"><text>Referred to House House Administration</text></action>
		<action date="1215489600" datetime="2008-07-08"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1216958400" datetime="2008-07-25"><committee name="House Armed Services"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text></action>
		<action date="1221689940" datetime="2008-09-17T19:19:00-04:00"><text>Mrs. Davis (CA) moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1221689940" datetime="2008-09-17T19:19:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8371-8373"/></action>
		<action date="1221689940" datetime="2008-09-17T19:19:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Con. Res. 388.</text></action>
		<vote date="1221690300" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-09-17T19:25:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H8371-8372"/></vote>
		<action date="1221690300" datetime="2008-09-17T19:25:00-04:00"><text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action date="1222056000" datetime="2008-09-22"><text>Received in the Senate.</text></action>
		<action date="1222920000" datetime="2008-10-02"><text>Referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/17/2008--Passed House amended. Declares the sense of Congress that: (1) the Secretary of Defense and the Federal Voting Assistance Program (FVAP) should inform members of the Armed Forces and their eligible dependents, with monthly electronic reminders, about opportunities to register to vote and to request absentee ballots for the 2008 elections; (2) state and local election officials should work with the FVAP to develop methods for obtaining updated addresses and contact information, if possible, for any such individuals, and any citizens living overseas, with undeliverable ballot addresses; and (3) the Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness should report to specified congressional committees on all related efforts. Expresses the sense of Congress about related duties of states and local jurisdictions. Urges the Department of Defense, the FVAP, the Election Assistance Commission (EAC), and state governments to examine recommendations in the EAC September 2007 survey findings regarding the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act. 
	</summary>
</bill>
