<bill session="110" type="hc" number="392" updated="2009-01-08T16:16:50-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1216267200" datetime="2008-07-17"/></status>

	<introduced date="1216267200" datetime="2008-07-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Supporting the goal of increased and sustainable homeownership in the United States and recognizing the importance of homeownership programs, fair lending laws, and fair housing laws in achieving that goal.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400170"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400092" joined="2008-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400030" joined="2008-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400270" joined="2008-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2008-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400653" joined="2008-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400251" joined="2008-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400217" joined="2008-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400208" joined="2008-07-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1216267200" datetime="2008-07-17"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1498)</text></action>
		<action date="1216267200" datetime="2008-07-17"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/17/2008--Introduced.<br/>Supports: (1) the goal of increasing U.S. homeownership; and (2) first-time homeownership programs, including the With Ownership, Wealth Initiative of the Congressional Black Caucus Foundation, the Congressional Hispanic Caucus Institute National Housing Initiative, and initiatives of the National Coalition for Asian Pacific American Community Development. Recognizes homeownership's importance in establishing financial independence. Urges federal, state, and local governments to: (1) take appropriate actions to encourage homeownership and fair housing practices; (2) confront all forms of predatory lending with swift legislative action; and (3) fund private fair housing organizations to protect and educate the public. Recommits Congress to making fair housing and homeownership a 110th Congress priority. 
	</summary>
</bill>
