<bill session="110" type="hc" number="52" updated="2009-01-08T15:33:28-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1172686920" datetime="2007-02-28T14:22:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="111"/></status>

	<introduced date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Supporting the goals and ideals of American Heart Month.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400275"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1170392400" datetime="2007-02-02"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1172552400" datetime="2007-02-27"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H1941)</text></action>
		<action date="1172609760" datetime="2007-02-27T16:56:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Pallone moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution.</text></action>
		<action date="1172609760" datetime="2007-02-27T16:56:00-05:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H1927-1929"/></action>
		<action date="1172609760" datetime="2007-02-27T16:56:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Con. Res. 52.</text></action>
		<action date="1172610300" datetime="2007-02-27T17:05:00-05:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1172686380" datetime="2007-02-28T14:13:00-05:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2010"/></action>
		<vote date="1172686920" how="roll" roll="111" datetime="2007-02-28T14:22:00-05:00" where="h" type="vote" suspension="1" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 412 - 0 (Roll no. 111).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H1927-1928"/></vote>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><text>Received in the Senate and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/28/2007--Passed House without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Expresses support for the goals and ideals of American Heart Month. Reaffirms our nation's commitment to fighting heart disease by promoting awareness about its causes, risks, and prevention and by promoting new education programs, supporting research, and expanding access to medical treatment. Encourages every American to exercise regularly and maintain a healthy weight, develop good eating habits, avoid tobacco, drugs, and excessive alcohol, and have regular checkups to take advantage of screenings that can detect heart-disease related problems early.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
