<bill session="110" type="hc" number="80" updated="2009-01-08T15:36:55-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1182198540" datetime="2007-06-18T17:29:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1173070800" datetime="2007-03-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Calling on the Government of Uganda and the Lord's Resistance Army (LRA) to recommit to a political solution to the conflict in northern Uganda and to recommence vital peace talks, and urging immediate and substantial support for the ongoing peace process from the United States and the international community.</title>
		<title type="official" as="amended by house">Calling on the Government of Uganda and the Lord's Resistance Army (LRA) to recommit to a political solution to the conflict in northern Uganda by engaging in good-faith negotiations, and urging immediate and substantial support for the ongoing peace process from the United States and the international community.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412199"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400647" joined="2007-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400661" joined="2007-03-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400640" joined="2007-03-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400415" joined="2007-03-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400379" joined="2007-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400073" joined="2007-03-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400280" joined="2007-05-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-03-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400423" joined="2007-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2007-03-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400071" joined="2007-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="2007-03-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2007-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400204" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2007-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2007-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400240" joined="2007-03-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400422" joined="2007-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400400" joined="2007-05-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400363" joined="2007-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400025" joined="2007-03-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="412225" joined="2007-03-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400130" joined="2007-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400062" joined="2007-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400350" joined="2007-03-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2007-03-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400217" joined="2007-03-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2007-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400333" joined="2007-03-20"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1173070800" datetime="2007-03-05"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H2140)</text></action>
		<action date="1173070800" datetime="2007-03-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23" ><text>Committee Agreed to Seek Consideration Under Suspension of the Rules, (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1182197160" datetime="2007-06-18T17:06:00-04:00"><text>Ms. Watson moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1182197160" datetime="2007-06-18T17:06:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H6607-6610"/></action>
		<action date="1182197160" datetime="2007-06-18T17:06:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Con. Res. 80.</text></action>
		<vote date="1182198540" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-06-18T17:29:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H6607-6608"/></vote>
		<action date="1182198540" datetime="2007-06-18T17:29:00-04:00"><text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action date="1182225600" datetime="2007-06-19"><text>Received in the Senate and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/18/2007--Passed House amended. Disapproves of the Lord's Resistance Army (LRA) leadership's inconsistent commitment to peacefully resolving the conflict in Uganda. Urges the LRA and the government of Uganda to engage in good-faith negotiations to pursue a political solution to the conflict. Encourages all regional parties to cease human rights violations and address, within the context of a broader national reconciliation process in Uganda, issues of accountability and impunity for those crimes against humanity already committed. Urges leaders on both sides of the conflict in Uganda to renounce any intentions and halt any preparations to resume violence and to ensure that this message is conveyed to armed elements under their control. Calls on the Secretary of State, the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, and the heads of other similar governmental agencies and nongovernmental organizations within the international community to continue efforts to alleviate the humanitarian crisis in northern Uganda and to support a peaceful resolution to this crisis.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
