<bill session="110" type="hj" number="72" updated="2009-01-08T16:36:37-05:00">
	<status><enacted date="1198213200" datetime="2007-12-21" /></status>

	<introduced date="1197954000" datetime="2007-12-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Making further continuing appropriations for the fiscal year 2008, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400300"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1197954000" datetime="2007-12-18"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text></action>
		<action date="1198089660" datetime="2007-12-19T14:41:00-05:00"><text>Rule H. Res. 893 passed House.</text></action>
		<action date="1198089720" datetime="2007-12-19T14:42:00-05:00"><text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 893.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H16889"/></action>
		<action date="1198089720" datetime="2007-12-19T14:42:00-05:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2764 and H.J. Res. 72.</text></action>
		<action date="1198089720" datetime="2007-12-19T14:42:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.J. Res. 72.</text></action>
		<action date="1198089840" datetime="2007-12-19T14:44:00-05:00"><text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H16889"/></action>
		<vote date="1198089840" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-12-19T14:44:00-05:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On passage Passed by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H16889"/></vote>
		<vote date="1198040400" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2007-12-19" where="s" type="vote2" result="pass" ><text>Received in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S15980-15981"/></vote>
		<action date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<topresident date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19" ><text>Cleared for White House.</text></topresident>
		<topresident date="1198126800" datetime="2007-12-20" ><text>Presented to President.</text></topresident>
		<signed date="1198213200" datetime="2007-12-21" ><text>Signed by President.</text></signed>
		<enacted number="110-149" date="1198213200" datetime="2007-12-21" type="public" ><text>Became Public Law No: 110-149.</text></enacted>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	12/21/2007--Public Law. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Amends Public Law 110-92 to extend through December 31, 2007, specified continuing appropriations for FY2008. Makes specified appropriations for payment to the heirs at law of Julia Carson, a former Representative from Indiana. Continues in effect throughout FY2008 the authority of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide hospital care, medical services, and nursing home care to any veteran who participated in a test conducted by the Department of Defense Deseret Test Center as part of a program for chemical and biological warfare testing from 1962 through 1973 (including the program designated as “Project Shipboard Hazard and Defense (SHAD)” and related land-based tests). Continues in effect throughout FY2008 the Secretary's authority to furnish, when requested, an appropriate government headstone or marker at U.S. expense for the grave of an individual eligible for burial in a national cemetery, or an individual who at the time of death was entitled to military retired pay, who is buried in a private cemetery.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
