<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1048" updated="2009-01-09T10:03:16-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"/></status>

	<introduced date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Condemning the detention of Dr. Nguyen Quoc Quan, a citizen of the United States, by the Government of Vietnam, and expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the United States should remove permanent normal trade relations status with Vietnam unless Dr. Nguyen is released.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400245"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2008-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400344" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400268" joined="2008-04-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2008-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400071" joined="2008-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400229" joined="2008-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400098" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400617" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400435" joined="2008-04-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1205899200" datetime="2008-03-19"><committee name="House Ways and Means"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/13/2008--Introduced.<br/>Calls for the release of Dr. Nguyen Quoc Quan and other political detainees by the government of Vietnam. Condemns the ongoing human rights abuses in Vietnam. Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that the United States should: (1) re-designate Vietnam as a Country of Particular Concern; (2) demand the government of Vietnam comply with internationally-recognized standards for basic freedoms and human rights; and (3) remove Vietnam's permanent normal trade relations status unless all political and religious prisoners are released and significant and immediate human rights reforms are made by the government of Vietnam.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
