<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1055" updated="2009-01-09T10:04:07-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1205467200" datetime="2008-03-14"/></status>

	<introduced date="1205467200" datetime="2008-03-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Recognizing the enduring value of the International Convention on the Elimination of All Forms of Racial Discrimination (ICERD) as a cornerstone of global efforts to combat racial discrimination and uphold human rights, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400170"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400616" joined="2008-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400080" joined="2008-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400333" joined="2008-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400271" joined="2008-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2008-04-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400384" joined="2008-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2008-04-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400378" joined="2008-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2008-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2008-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2008-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400204" joined="2008-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400240" joined="2008-04-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1205467200" datetime="2008-03-14"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1205467200" datetime="2008-03-14"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1205467200" datetime="2008-03-14"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1212465600" datetime="2008-06-03"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/14/2008--Introduced.<br/>Recognizes the enduring value of the International Convention on the Elimination of All Forms of Racial Discrimination (ICERD) as a cornerstone of global efforts to combat racial discrimination and uphold human rights. Commends the United States for meeting its ICERD reporting obligations. Calls upon the U.S. government to support existing laws and programs aimed at redressing past injustices that have contributed to ongoing racial discrimination and present day disparities. 
	</summary>
</bill>
