<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1068" updated="2009-01-09T10:05:44-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1208281980" datetime="2008-04-15T14:53:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1207022400" datetime="2008-04-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Permitting active duty members of the Armed Forces who are assigned to a Congressional liaison office of the Department of Defense at the House of Representatives to obtain membership in the exercise facility established for employees of the House of Representatives.</title>
		<title type="official" as="amended by house">Permitting active duty members of the Armed Forces who are assigned to a Congressional liaison office of the Armed Forces at the House of Representatives to obtain membership in the exercise facility established for employees of the House of Representatives.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400047"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400119" joined="2008-04-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1207022400" datetime="2008-04-01"><text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text></action>
		<action date="1207108800" datetime="2008-04-02"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1207108800" datetime="2008-04-02" ><text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1208211120" datetime="2008-04-14T19:12:00-04:00"><text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on House Administration. H. Rept. 110-587.</text></action>
		<calendar number="205" date="1208211120" datetime="2008-04-14T19:12:00-04:00" calendar="House" ><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 205.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1208281860" datetime="2008-04-15T14:51:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Brady (PA) moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1208281860" datetime="2008-04-15T14:51:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2298"/></action>
		<action date="1208281860" datetime="2008-04-15T14:51:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 1068.</text></action>
		<vote date="1208281980" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-04-15T14:53:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H2298"/></vote>
		<action date="1208282040" datetime="2008-04-15T14:54:00-04:00"><text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/15/2008--Passed House amended. (This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on April 14, 2007. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Permits any active duty member of the Armed Forces who is assigned to a congressional liaison office of the Armed Forces at the House of Representatives to obtain membership in the exercise facility established for House employees in the same manner as such individuals and in accordance with such regulations as the Committee on House Administration may promulgate. 
	</summary>
</bill>
