<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1083" updated="2009-01-09T10:07:40-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1207839060" datetime="2008-04-10T11:51:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="179"/></status>

	<introduced date="1207627200" datetime="2008-04-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2537) to amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act relating to beach monitoring, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400663"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1207691520" datetime="2008-04-08T18:52:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-572, by Ms. Matsui.</text></action>
		<action date="1207691520" datetime="2008-04-08T18:52:00-04:00"><text>All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure now printed in the bill.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1207691580" datetime="2008-04-08T18:53:00-04:00" ><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 200.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1207833480" datetime="2008-04-10T10:18:00-04:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2175-2176"/></action>
		<action date="1207833660" datetime="2008-04-10T10:21:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1083.</text></action>
		<action date="1207836300" datetime="2008-04-10T11:05:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text></action>
		<action date="1207836360" datetime="2008-04-10T11:06:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the end of debate on the H. Res. 1083, the Chair put the question on adoption, and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mrs. Matsui demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question until later in the legislative day.</text></action>
		<action date="1207838580" datetime="2008-04-10T11:43:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text></action>
		<vote date="1207839060" how="roll" roll="179" datetime="2008-04-10T11:51:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 224 - 192 (Roll no. 179).</text></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/10/2008--Passed House without amendment. Sets forth the rule for consideration of H.R. 2537 (Beach Protection Act of 2007).<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
