<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1014" updated="2009-01-09T09:58:51-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1204747980" datetime="2008-03-05T16:13:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="96"/></status>

	<introduced date="1204606800" datetime="2008-03-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1424) to amend section 712 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, section 2705 of the Public Health Service Act, and section 9812 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to require equity in the provision of mental health and substance-related disorder benefits under group health plans.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412195"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1204675920" datetime="2008-03-04T20:12:00-05:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-538, by Ms. Castor.</text></action>
		<action date="1204675920" datetime="2008-03-04T20:12:00-05:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1424 with 2 hours of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1204675980" datetime="2008-03-04T20:13:00-05:00" ><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 192.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1204739820" datetime="2008-03-05T13:57:00-05:00"><text>By direction of the Committee on Rules, Ms Castor called up H. Res. 1014 for its immediate consideration.</text></action>
		<action date="1204739820" datetime="2008-03-05T13:57:00-05:00"><text>POINT OF ORDER - The Broun (GA) raised a point of order against the provisions of H.Res. 1014 because it violates the Congressional Budget Act. The Chair announced that the desposition of the point of order would be resolved by the question of consideration of H. Res. 1014. The House proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the point of order at the end of which the Chair will put the question of consideration.</text></action>
		<action date="1204742400" datetime="2008-03-05T14:40:00-05:00"><text>On motion to consider the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 215 - 192, 1 Present (Roll no. 94).</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H1259-1262"/></action>
		<action date="1204742400" datetime="2008-03-05T14:40:00-05:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H1259-1272"/></action>
		<action date="1204742460" datetime="2008-03-05T14:41:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1014.</text></action>
		<action date="1204747560" datetime="2008-03-05T16:06:00-05:00"><text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 215 - 195 (Roll no. 95).</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H1271"/></action>
		<vote date="1204747980" how="roll" roll="96" datetime="2008-03-05T16:13:00-05:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 209 - 198 (Roll no. 96).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H1259"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/5/2008--Passed House without amendment. Sets forth the rule for consideration of H.R. 1424 (Paul Wellstone Mental Health and Addiction Equity Act of 2007).<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
