<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1089" updated="2009-01-09T10:08:28-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1207627200" datetime="2008-04-08"/></status>

	<introduced date="1207627200" datetime="2008-04-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Calling on the government of Vietnam to release from prison, end the detention without trial, and cease the harassment and house arrest of the people who signed the Manifesto on Freedom and Democracy for Vietnam, and expressing the sense of Congress that the President should encourage Vietnam to release such people from prison and to direct the Secretary of State to establish a Countries of Particular Concern list to condemn countries like Vietnam, which engage in &quot;particularly severe violations&quot; of human rights.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400356"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400229" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400245" joined="2008-04-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1207627200" datetime="2008-04-08"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1207800000" datetime="2008-04-10"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR H2167)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/8/2008--Introduced.<br/>Calls on the government of Vietnam to release from prison, end the detention without trial, and cease the harassment and house arrest of the people who signed the Manifesto on Freedom and Democracy for Vietnam. Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the members of the Bloc 8406 should be commended for their efforts to bring democracy and human rights to the Vietnamese people; and (2) the President should encourage Vietnam to release such people from prison, including U.S. citizen Dr. Nguyen Quoc Quan, and direct the Secretary of State to establish a Countries of Particular Concern list to condemn countries like Vietnam, which engage in &quot;particularly severe violations&quot; of human rights. 
	</summary>
</bill>
