<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1028" updated="2009-01-09T10:00:43-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1204779600" datetime="2008-03-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1204779600" datetime="2008-03-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Reasserting congressional prerogatives in foreign policy and reaffirming the importance of following constitutional processes when the United States Government enters into agreements regarding the use or maintenance of the United States Armed Forces or the use of the financial resources of the United States to assist a foreign government or people and clarifying the nature and scope of status of forces agreements.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400237"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2008-03-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400080" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2008-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="2008-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400245" joined="2008-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="2008-04-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2008-03-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400013" joined="2008-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400422" joined="2008-03-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2008-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400074" joined="2008-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2008-04-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400240" joined="2008-05-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1204779600" datetime="2008-03-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/6/2008--Introduced.<br/>Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that approval by an Act of Congress is required for: (1) any agreement, understanding, or commitment, other than a treaty, entered into by the President or his designee, whether characterized or denominated as a status of forces agreement or otherwise, which purports to impose a binding or enforceable obligation on the United States to use or maintain the U.S. Armed Forces to assist a foreign country, government, or people, either immediately or upon the happening of certain events; (2) any agreement, other than a treaty, between the United States and another country that requires the use of the financial resources of the United States; and (3) any agreement, other than a treaty, between the Republic of Iraq and the United States that imposes burdens in excess of those customarily included in a status of forces agreement.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
