<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1123" updated="2009-01-09T10:13:02-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1208404800" datetime="2008-04-17"/></status>

	<introduced date="1208404800" datetime="2008-04-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Calling on the President of the United States not to commit the United States to any status of forces agreement or any other bilateral agreement with the Republic of Iraq that involves the continued presence of the United States Armed Forces in Iraq unless the agreement includes a provision under which the Republic of Iraq agrees to reimburse the United States for all costs incurred by the United States related to the presence of United States Armed Forces in Iraq after the effective date of the agreement.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400343"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400209" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400102" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400348" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400116" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400071" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400076" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400211" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400394" joined="2008-04-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1208404800" datetime="2008-04-17"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/17/2008--Introduced.<br/>Calls on the President not to commit the United States to any status of forces agreement or any other bilateral agreement with the Republic of Iraq that involves the presence of the U.S. Armed Forces in Iraq unless under the agreement Iraq agrees to reimburse the United States for all costs related to the presence of the U.S. Armed Forces in Iraq after such agreement's effective date, including pay and allowance costs for U.S. Armed Forces members serving in Iraq.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
