<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1120" updated="2009-01-09T10:12:39-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1208404800" datetime="2008-04-17"/></status>

	<introduced date="1208404800" datetime="2008-04-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Supports the establishment of an NCAA Division I Football Bowl Subdivision Championship playoff system in the interest of fairness and to bring parity to all NCAA teams.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400001"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400627" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400376" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400255" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400654" joined="2008-12-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1208404800" datetime="2008-04-17"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E644)</text></action>
		<action date="1208404800" datetime="2008-04-17"><text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1208404800" datetime="2008-04-17"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1208404800" datetime="2008-04-17"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/17/2008--Introduced.<br/>Rejects the National Collegiate Athletic Association (NCAA) Division I A Bowl Championship Series (BCS) football playoff system as an illegal restraint of trade that violates the Sherman Anti-Trust Act.<br/>Calls for: (1) the Department of Justice's Antitrust Division to investigate and bring appropriate action to have the BCS system declared illegal and to require a playoff to determine a national champion; and (2) establishment of an NCAA Division I Football Bowl Subdivision Championship playoff system in the interest of fairness and to bring parity to all NCAA teams.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
