<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1157" updated="2009-01-09T10:18:15-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1209584100" datetime="2008-04-30T16:35:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="228"/></status>

	<introduced date="1209441600" datetime="2008-04-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 5522) to require the Secretary of Labor to issue interim and final occupational safety and health standards regarding worker exposure to combustible dust, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400263"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1209506040" datetime="2008-04-29T18:54:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-613, by Mr. McGovern.</text></action>
		<action date="1209506040" datetime="2008-04-29T18:54:00-04:00"><text>All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Education and Labor now printed in the bill.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1209506040" datetime="2008-04-29T18:54:00-04:00" ><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 212.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1209575340" datetime="2008-04-30T14:09:00-04:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2891-2894"/></action>
		<action date="1209575520" datetime="2008-04-30T14:12:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1157.</text></action>
		<action date="1209576720" datetime="2008-04-30T14:32:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H. Res. 1157, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Lincoln Diaz-Balart demanded the yeas and nays which were ordered and pursuant to the rule, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question until later in the legislative day.</text></action>
		<action date="1209582060" datetime="2008-04-30T16:01:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2907-2908"/></action>
		<action date="1209583680" datetime="2008-04-30T16:28:00-04:00"><text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 226 - 194 (Roll no. 227).</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2894, H2907-2908"/></action>
		<vote date="1209584100" how="roll" roll="228" datetime="2008-04-30T16:35:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 222 - 193 (Roll no. 228).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H2891"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/29/2008--Introduced.<br/>Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 5522) to require the Secretary of Labor to issue interim and final occupational safety and health standards regarding worker exposure to combustible dust.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
