<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1189" updated="2009-01-09T10:22:09-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1210783500" datetime="2008-05-14T13:45:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="311"/></status>

	<introduced date="1210651200" datetime="2008-05-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the conference report to accompany the bill (H.R. 2419) to provide for the continuation of agricultural programs through fiscal year 2012, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400065"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1210718580" datetime="2008-05-13T19:43:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-629, by Mr. Cardoza.</text></action>
		<action date="1210718580" datetime="2008-05-13T19:43:00-04:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to H.R. 2419 with 1 hour of general debate. Motion to recommit allowed.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1210718580" datetime="2008-05-13T19:43:00-04:00" ><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 216.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1210772640" datetime="2008-05-14T10:44:00-04:00"><text>By the direction of the Committee on Rules, Mr. Cardoza called up H. Res. 1189, and asked for its immediate consideration.</text></action>
		<action date="1210772760" datetime="2008-05-14T10:46:00-04:00"><text>POINT OF ORDER - Mr. Flake raised a point of order against the provisions of H. Res. 1189 because it violates the Congressional Budget Act. The Chair announced that the disposition of the point of order would be resolved by the question of consideration of H. Res. 1189. The House proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the point of order at the end of which the Chair will put the question on consideration.</text></action>
		<action date="1210773720" datetime="2008-05-14T11:02:00-04:00"><text>POINT OF ORDER - Mr. Flake raised a point of order against the provisions of H. Res. 1189 because it violates the earmark rule. The Chair announced that the disposition of the point of order would be resolved by the question of consideration of H. Res. 1189. The House proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the point of order at the end of which the Chair will put the question on consideration.</text></action>
		<action date="1210776720" datetime="2008-05-14T11:52:00-04:00"><text>Will the House now consider the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 228 - 189 (Roll no. 309).</text></action>
		<action date="1210776960" datetime="2008-05-14T11:56:00-04:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3784-3799"/></action>
		<action date="1210777080" datetime="2008-05-14T11:58:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1189.</text></action>
		<action date="1210782900" datetime="2008-05-14T13:35:00-04:00"><text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 232 - 188 (Roll no. 310).</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3798"/></action>
		<vote date="1210783500" how="roll" roll="311" datetime="2008-05-14T13:45:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 228 - 193 (Roll no. 311).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H3784"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/13/2008--Introduced.<br/>Sets forth the rule for consideration of the conference report to accompany the bill (H.R. 2419) to provide for the continuation of agricultural programs through fiscal year 2012.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
