<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1127" updated="2009-01-09T10:13:43-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1213808940" datetime="2008-06-18T14:09:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1208836800" datetime="2008-04-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Condemning the endemic restrictions on freedom of the press and media and public expression in the Middle East and the concurrent and widespread presence of anti-Semitic material, Holocaust denial, and incitement to violence in the Arab media and press.</title>
		<title type="official" as="amended by house">Resolution condemning the endemic restrictions on freedom of the press and media and public expression in the Middle East and the concurrent and widespread presence of anti-Semitic incitement to violence and Holocaust denial in the Arab media and press.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400003"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400222" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400128" joined="2008-06-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400219" joined="2008-06-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400060" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400618" joined="2008-04-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400380" joined="2008-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400122" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400271" joined="2008-04-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400430" joined="2008-04-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400344" joined="2008-04-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400361" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2008-04-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400662" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400652" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400433" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400055" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400437" joined="2008-04-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="412198" joined="2008-04-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="412188" joined="2008-04-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400087" joined="2008-04-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2008-04-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400346" joined="2008-04-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="2008-04-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400400" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400638" joined="2008-04-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2008-04-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="412186" joined="2008-04-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400649" joined="2008-04-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400371" joined="2008-04-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400315" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400024" joined="2008-04-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400363" joined="2008-04-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400025" joined="2008-04-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400425" joined="2008-04-30"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1208836800" datetime="2008-04-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30" ><text>Committee Agreed to Seek Consideration Under Suspension of the Rules, (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1213807560" datetime="2008-06-18T13:46:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Ackerman moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1213807620" datetime="2008-06-18T13:47:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H5522-5526"/></action>
		<action date="1213807620" datetime="2008-06-18T13:47:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 1127.</text></action>
		<vote date="1213808940" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-06-18T14:09:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H5522-5523"/></vote>
		<action date="1213808940" datetime="2008-06-18T14:09:00-04:00"><text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/18/2008--Passed House amended. Condemns the restrictions on freedom of the press and expression in the Arab world and the widespread presence of anti-Semitic material, Holocaust denial, and incitement to violence in the Arab media. Deplores the practices utilized by the governments in the Middle East to exert control over the press and on public expression. Expresses concern that many of the Arab governments to which United States has turned for assistance in ending the Israeli-Palestinian conflict are responsible for using their government-controlled media to promulgate incendiary speech regarding Israel and the Jewish people that makes U.S. efforts to help resolve the Arab-Israeli conflict all the more difficult. Calls on the President to: (1) raise the issue of the lack of media freedom in the Middle East and the proliferation of anti-Semitic incitement; and (2) take into account the compliance of governments throughout the region with international norms and obligations regarding media freedom and anti-Semitic incitement when determining U.S. assistance. Calls on U.S. allies and governments throughout the Middle East to publicly repudiate purveyors of anti-Semitic incitement.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
