<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1126" updated="2009-01-09T10:13:32-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1208993400" datetime="2008-04-23T20:30:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="219"/></status>

	<introduced date="1208836800" datetime="2008-04-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for the consideration of the bill (H.R. 2830) to authorize appropriations for the Coast Guard for fiscal year 2008, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412224"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1208905560" datetime="2008-04-22T20:06:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-604, by Mr. Arcuri.</text></action>
		<action date="1208905560" datetime="2008-04-22T20:06:00-04:00"><text>All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. In lieu of the amendments in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, Homeland Security, and the Judiciary now printed in the bill, it shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in part A of the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution. In the engrossment of H.R. 2830, the Clerk shall add the text of H.R. 2399, as passed by the House, as new matter at the end of H.R. 2830; conform the title of H.R. 2830 to reflect the addition to the engrossment of H.R. 2399 and to further conform the engrossment as necessary.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1208905620" datetime="2008-04-22T20:07:00-04:00" ><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 209.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1208969760" datetime="2008-04-23T13:56:00-04:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2586-2593"/></action>
		<action date="1208970000" datetime="2008-04-23T14:00:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1126.</text></action>
		<action date="1208975220" datetime="2008-04-23T15:27:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House continued with further debate on H. Res. 1126.</text></action>
		<action date="1208975580" datetime="2008-04-23T15:33:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H. Res. 1126 Mr. Arcuri moved the previous question and by voice vote, the Chair announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Sessions demanded a recorded vote which was ordered, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of ordering the previous question until later in the legislative day.</text></action>
		<action date="1208992560" datetime="2008-04-23T20:16:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2594-2595, H2628-2629"/></action>
		<action date="1208992980" datetime="2008-04-23T20:23:00-04:00"><text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by recorded vote: 220 - 187 (Roll No. 218). (consideration: CR H2594-2595, H2628-2629; text CR H2595)</text></action>
		<vote date="1208993400" how="roll" roll="219" datetime="2008-04-23T20:30:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 223 - 183 (Roll no. 219).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H2586"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/22/2008--Introduced.<br/>Sets forth the rule for consideration of H.R. 2830 to authorize appropriations for the Coast Guard for fiscal year 2008, and for other purposes.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
