<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1176" updated="2009-01-09T10:20:30-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1210784460" datetime="2008-05-14T14:01:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="313"/></status>

	<introduced date="1210046400" datetime="2008-05-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Supporting the goals and ideals of National Train Day.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400048"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1210046400" datetime="2008-05-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text></action>
		<action date="1210132800" datetime="2008-05-07"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
		<action date="1210702680" datetime="2008-05-13T15:18:00-04:00"><text>Ms. Brown, Corrine moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution.</text></action>
		<action date="1210702680" datetime="2008-05-13T15:18:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3712-3714"/></action>
		<action date="1210702680" datetime="2008-05-13T15:18:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 1176.</text></action>
		<action date="1210703760" datetime="2008-05-13T15:36:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Simpson objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text></action>
		<action date="1210783980" datetime="2008-05-14T13:53:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3800"/></action>
		<vote date="1210784460" how="roll" roll="313" datetime="2008-05-14T14:01:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" suspension="1" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 415 - 0 (Roll no. 313). (text: CR 5/13/2008 H3712)</text></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/14/2008--Passed House without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.) Recognizes the contribution trains make to the national transportation system. Supports the goals and ideals of National Train Day. Urges the people of the United States to recognize such a day as an opportunity to learn more about trains. 
	</summary>
</bill>
