<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1146" updated="2009-01-09T10:16:47-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1209009600" datetime="2008-04-24"/></status>

	<introduced date="1209009600" datetime="2008-04-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the International Joint Commission should adopt a water level management plan for Lake Ontario and the St. Lawrence River that strongly takes into account environmental considerations and the concerns of the public and the affected States and maximizes hydropower production at existing facilities, and further urges the Secretary of State not to approve a plan that fails to do so.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400264"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412224" joined="2008-04-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400642" joined="2008-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400378" joined="2008-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2008-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400120" joined="2008-06-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400119" joined="2008-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2008-06-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1209009600" datetime="2008-04-24"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E715-716)</text></action>
		<action date="1209009600" datetime="2008-04-24"><text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1209009600" datetime="2008-04-24"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1209009600" datetime="2008-04-24"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1209096000" datetime="2008-04-25"><committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/24/2008--Introduced.<br/>Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that: (1) the International Joint Commission's proposed Plan 2007 does not provide the necessary level of environmental protections and benefits for Lake Ontario and the St. Lawrence River; (2) the views of the public and the state that has jurisdiction of waters to be regulated must be fully considered when a new plan for the management of water levels is selected; (3) any water level management plan should make every effort to maximize hydropower production at existing facilities; and (4) the Secretary of State should not approve a plan that fails to meet such criteria.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
