<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1247" updated="2009-01-09T10:29:24-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1213824120" datetime="2008-06-18T18:22:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1212638400" datetime="2008-06-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Supporting the goals and ideals of &quot;American Eagle Day&quot;, and celebrating the recovery and restoration of the American bald eagle, the national symbol of the United States.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412235"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1212638400" datetime="2008-06-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1213725060" datetime="2008-06-17T14:51:00-04:00"><text>Ms. Bordallo moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1213725180" datetime="2008-06-17T14:53:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H5421-5426"/></action>
		<action date="1213725180" datetime="2008-06-17T14:53:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 1247.</text></action>
		<action date="1213727340" datetime="2008-06-17T15:29:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1213822440" datetime="2008-06-18T17:54:00-04:00"><text>Ms. Woolsey asked unanimous consent that the ordering of the yeas and nays be vacated to the end that the question be put de novo. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action date="1213824120" datetime="2008-06-18T18:22:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H5550"/></action>
		<vote date="1213824120" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-06-18T18:22:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by voice vote. (text: CR 6/17/2008 H5422)</text></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/18/2008--Passed House amended. Expresses support for the goals and ideals of American Eagle Day. Encourages educational entities, organizations, businesses, conservation groups, and government agencies with a shared interest in conserving endangered species to collaborate on education information for use in schools.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
