<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1228" updated="2009-01-09T10:26:57-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"/></status>

	<introduced date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Ensuring access to affordable and quality health care without exacerbating the Federal budget or contributing to market inflation while providing greater choices for consumers.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400659"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412256" joined="2008-07-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/22/2008--Introduced.<br/>Calls for the following principles for a market-based approach to be included in any health care bill considered by the 110th Congress: (1) the ability to receive point-of-service health care in preventative, emergency, and rehabilitative settings in rural and urban areas; (2) refundable tax credits for the purchase of health insurance by low-income recipients, combined with laws that permit association and small business health plans; (3) medical liability reform; (4) safe and effective health service with measurable results through health information technology; (5) building new incentives into health plans to encourage wellness and prevention and to provide incentives for people to make smart choices involving their health, health care, and health insurance coverage; and (6) giving consumers the ability to choose the best health care plan and options to meet their needs through portable health insurance and Health Savings Accounts.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
