<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1227" updated="2009-01-09T10:26:50-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1222196040" datetime="2008-09-23T15:54:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Condemning sexual violence in the Democratic Republic of the Congo and calling on the international community to take immediate actions to respond to the violence.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400251"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400041" joined="2008-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400280" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2008-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400407" joined="2008-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412221" joined="2008-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400430" joined="2008-07-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400198" joined="2008-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400268" joined="2008-09-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400063" joined="2008-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400124" joined="2008-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400423" joined="2008-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400274" joined="2008-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412189" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="2008-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400396" joined="2008-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400355" joined="2008-07-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400130" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400030" joined="2008-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2008-07-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400245" joined="2008-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400048" joined="2008-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400103" joined="2008-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400087" joined="2008-07-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2008-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2008-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="2008-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400013" joined="2008-07-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400350" joined="2008-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400111" joined="2008-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2008-06-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400284" joined="2008-06-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="412186" joined="2008-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412228" joined="2008-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2008-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400204" joined="2008-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400062" joined="2008-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400425" joined="2008-06-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1222195500" datetime="2008-09-23T15:45:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Crowley moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1222195500" datetime="2008-09-23T15:45:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8632-8633"/></action>
		<action date="1222195500" datetime="2008-09-23T15:45:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 1227.</text></action>
		<vote date="1222196040" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-09-23T15:54:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H8632-8633"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/23/2008--Passed House amended. Condemns all forms of sexual violence, including rape, in the Democratic Republic of the Congo. Calls on the government of the Democratic Republic of the Congo to address the large-scale sexual violence in the Democratic Republic of the Congo. Urges: (1) an increased U.S. and donor country effort to provide greater assistance for police and military human rights training in the Democratic Republic of the Congo; and (2) the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) to increase its assistance to victims of sexual violence in the Democratic Republic of the Congo. Urges the Secretary of State to appoint a special envoy to the Democratic Republic of the Congo to sustain U.S. engagement in a peace process and stabilization programs. Encourages: (1) the international community to ensure greater coordination in its response to sexual violence and to provide further humanitarian assistance in the eastern Democratic Republic of the Congo; and (2) the protection of women and girls and the promotion of their rights. Reaffirms support for constitutional government, the rule of law, human rights, and democratic processes in the Democratic Republic of the Congo. Calls on the Secretary General of the United Nations and the permanent members of the U.N. Security Council to: (1) ensure that the United Nations Mission in the Democratic Republic of the Congo (MONUC) is fully funded and deployed in areas where sexual violence is most prevalent; (2) include an adequate number of female troops and police in MONUC; and (3) hold all MONUC and associated personnel who have committed acts of rape or sexual exploitation accountable for their crimes and ensure that they are permanently barred from serving in any future peacekeeping operation. Encourages a transparent process for the government of the Democratic Republic of the Congo's review of mining contracts. Urges U.S. companies in the Democratic Republic of the Congo to exert oversight concerning where their products are coming from and who is benefiting from the trade.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
