<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1258" updated="2009-01-09T10:30:49-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1213070400" datetime="2008-06-10"/></status>

	<introduced date="1213070400" datetime="2008-06-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Impeaching George W. Bush, President of the United States, of high crimes and misdemeanors.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400227"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2008-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2008-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400430" joined="2008-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400129" joined="2008-06-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2008-09-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="2008-07-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="2008-09-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2008-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2008-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400013" joined="2008-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2008-06-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1213207260" datetime="2008-06-11T15:01:00-04:00"><text>Consideration initiated pursuant to a previous order. (consideration: CR 6/11/2008 H5266; text of measure as introduced: CR 6/10/2008 H5192-5211)</text></action>
		<action date="1213207320" datetime="2008-06-11T15:02:00-04:00"><text>The Chair put the question de novo on the Kucinich motion to refer the resolution.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H5266"/></action>
		<action date="1213207680" datetime="2008-06-11T15:08:00-04:00"><text>On motion to refer the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 251 - 166 (Roll No. 401).</text></action>
		<action date="1213156800" datetime="2008-06-11"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/10/2008--Introduced.<br/>Impeaches President George W. Bush for high crimes and misdemeanors.<br/>Sets forth articles of impeachment stating that President Bush, in violation of his oath of office: (1) illegally spent public dollars on a secret propaganda program to manufacture a false cause for war against Iraq; (2) misused intelligence reports to deceive Congress and the public about a connection between Saddam Hussein and al Qaeda and the the terrorist attacks of September 11, 2001; (3) mislead Congress and the public into believing that Iraq possessed weapons of mass destruction and posed an imminent threat to the United States; (4) illegally misspent funds to begin a war in secret prior to congressional authorization; (5) invaded Iraq in violation of U.S. law, the United Nations Charter, and international criminal law and failed to obtain a declaration of war; (6) failed to protect U.S. troops in Iraq by not providing them with body and vehicle armor and promoted false stories about the deaths and injuries of members of the U.S. military; (7) used public funds to construct permanent U.S. military bases in Iraq; (8) invaded Iraq to obtain control of its oil resources; (9) created a secret task force to guide U.S. energy and military policy in usurpation of the role of Congress in legislating such policy; (10) misused classified intelligence information and conspired to identify a covert agent of the Central Intelligence Agency (CIA); (11) established policies granting U.S. government contractors in Iraq immunity from prosecution; (12) recklessly misspent public dollars on private contractors in Iraq; (13) detained U.S. citizens and foreign captives indefinitely and without charge; (14) authorized torture of captives in Afghanistan and Iraq; (15) kidnapped and transported individuals to countries known to practice torture; (16) authorized the arrest and detention of at least 2,500 children as enemy combatants in violation of the Geneva Convention; (17) mislead Congress and the public about threats from Iran; (18) created secret laws through the issuance of legal opinions by the Department of Justice and violated the Posse Comitatus Act; (19) authorized warrantless electronic surveillance of U.S. citizens; (20) directed telecommunication companies to create databases of the private telephone numbers and emails of U.S. citizens; (21) used signing statements to claim the right to violate laws enacted by Congress; (22) failed to comply with congressional subpoenas and instructed former executive branch employees not to comply with such subpoenas; (23) tampered with the conduct of free and fair elections and corrupted the administration of justice; (24) conspired to violate the voting rights of U.S. citizens; (25) pursued policies calculated to destroy the Medicare program; (26) failed to prepare for the predictable disasters caused by Hurricane Katrina; (27) mislead Congress and the public in an effort to undermine efforts to address global climate change; and (28) failed to take proper steps to protect the United States against the terrorist attacks of September 11, 2001, obstructed investigations into such attacks, and recklessly endangered the health of first responders near the site of such attacks.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
