<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1213" updated="2009-01-09T10:25:09-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1211387940" datetime="2008-05-21T13:39:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1211256000" datetime="2008-05-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 5658) to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2009 for military activities of the Department of Defense, to prescribe military personnel strengths for fiscal year 2009, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400170"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1211325000" datetime="2008-05-20T20:10:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-661, by Mr. Hastings (FL).</text></action>
		<action date="1211325000" datetime="2008-05-20T20:10:00-04:00"><text>All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1211325000" datetime="2008-05-20T20:10:00-04:00" ><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 224.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1211380980" datetime="2008-05-21T11:43:00-04:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H4337-4341"/></action>
		<action date="1211381040" datetime="2008-05-21T11:44:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1213.</text></action>
		<action date="1211426340" datetime="2008-05-21T12:19:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.Res. 1213, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Hastings (WA) demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on ordering the previous question on H.Res. 1213 until later in the legislative day.</text></action>
		<action date="1211387460" datetime="2008-05-21T13:31:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H4347-4348"/></action>
		<action date="1211387940" datetime="2008-05-21T13:39:00-04:00"><text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 235 - 186 (Roll no. 340).</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H4347-4348"/></action>
		<vote date="1211387940" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-05-21T13:39:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H4337"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/20/2008--Introduced.<br/>Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 5658) to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2009 for military activities of the Department of Defense, to prescribe military personnel strengths for fiscal year 2009.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
