<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1273" updated="2009-01-09T10:32:40-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1213243200" datetime="2008-06-12"/></status>

	<introduced date="1213243200" datetime="2008-06-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding the human rights crisis of Laotian and Hmong people in Laos and Thailand.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400215"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400618" joined="2008-07-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400330" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400065" joined="2008-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2008-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2008-07-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="2008-07-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400230" joined="2008-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400343" joined="2008-06-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400013" joined="2008-06-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412240" joined="2008-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400318" joined="2008-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400218" joined="2008-06-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400435" joined="2008-06-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1213243200" datetime="2008-06-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/12/2008--Introduced.<br/>Urges the Lao government to: (1) cease military and security force attacks and actions against Lao and Hmong civilians and dissident Laotian political and minority religious groups; (2) provide international access to closed areas and military zones in Laos where Laotians and Hmong are being killed, persecuted, or have been internally displaced or fled; and (3) release the leaders of the Lao Students Movement for Democracy of October 1999 and other Lao political and religious opposition leaders and prisoners of conscience. Urges His Majesty King Bhumibol Adulyadej of Thailand, the Royal Thai government, and commanders of the Thai Army and military to: (1) allow access to, and relief for, the Lao and Hmong political refugees and asylum seekers at Ban Huay Nam Khao and elsewhere in Thailand; (2) allow Lao and Hmong refugees and asylum seekers to have sanctuary in Thailand until they can be assisted by the international community; and (3) refrain from further repatriation of Lao and Hmong refugees and asylum seekers in Thailand.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
