<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1294" updated="2009-01-09T10:35:22-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1214499840" datetime="2008-06-26T14:04:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1214193600" datetime="2008-06-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Supporting the goals and ideals of National Save for Retirement Week.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400647"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400206" joined="2008-06-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1214193600" datetime="2008-06-23"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action date="1214325600" datetime="2008-06-24T13:40:00-04:00"><text>Ms. Schwartz moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution.</text></action>
		<action date="1214325600" datetime="2008-06-24T13:40:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H5932-5934"/></action>
		<action date="1214325600" datetime="2008-06-24T13:40:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 1294.</text></action>
		<action date="1214326440" datetime="2008-06-24T13:54:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Johnson, Sam objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text></action>
		<action date="1214499840" datetime="2008-06-26T14:04:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H6121"/></action>
		<vote date="1214499840" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-06-26T14:04:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote. (text: CR 6/24/2008 H5932)</text></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/26/2008--Passed House without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Supports the goals and ideals of National Save for Retirement Week (October 19-25, 2008). Supports the need to raise public awareness of efficiently utilizing substantial tax revenues that currently subsidize retirement savings, revenues in excess of $170 billion for the 2007 Fiscal Year Budget. Supports the need to raise public awareness of the importance to save adequately for retirement and the availability of tax-preferred employer-sponsored retirement savings vehicles.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
