<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1344" updated="2009-01-09T10:42:00-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1216848060" datetime="2008-07-23T18:21:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="523"/></status>

	<introduced date="1216094400" datetime="2008-07-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3999) to amend title 23, United States Code, to improve the safety of Federal-aid highway bridges, to strengthen bridge inspection standards and processes, to increase investment in the reconstruction of structurally deficient bridges on the National Highway System, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412224"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1216156500" datetime="2008-07-15T18:15:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-760, by Mr. Arcuri.</text></action>
		<action date="1216156500" datetime="2008-07-15T18:15:00-04:00"><text>All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in part A of the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1216156500" datetime="2008-07-15T18:15:00-04:00" ><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 249.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1216844520" datetime="2008-07-23T17:22:00-04:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H7013-7018"/></action>
		<action date="1216844520" datetime="2008-07-23T17:22:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1344.</text></action>
		<action date="1216847520" datetime="2008-07-23T18:12:00-04:00"><text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (Roll No. 522).</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H7017"/></action>
		<vote date="1216848060" how="roll" roll="523" datetime="2008-07-23T18:21:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 228 - 193 (Roll no. 523).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H7013"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/15/2008--Introduced.<br/>Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3999) to amend title 23, United States Code, to improve the safety of Federal-aid highway bridges, to strengthen bridge inspection standards and processes, to increase investment in the reconstruction of structurally deficient bridges on the National Highway System.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
