<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1362" updated="2009-01-09T10:44:24-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1216958160" datetime="2008-07-24T12:56:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1216699200" datetime="2008-07-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for the consideration of the Senate amendment to the bill (H.R. 5501) to authorize appropriations for fiscal years 2009 through 2013 to provide assistance to foreign countries to combat HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, and malaria, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400170"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1216775400" datetime="2008-07-22T22:10:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-766, by Mr. Hastings (FL).</text></action>
		<action date="1216775400" datetime="2008-07-22T22:10:00-04:00"><text>Upon the adoption of this resolution it shall be in order to take from the Speaker's table the bill H.R. 5501, with the Senate amendment thereto, and consider in the House a motion offered by the chairman of the Committee on Foreign Affairs or his designee, that the House concur in the Senate amendment. The motion shall be debatable for one hour, equally divided and controlled and the previous question shall be considered as ordered on the motion to its adoption without intervening motion.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1216775460" datetime="2008-07-22T22:11:00-04:00" ><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 251.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1216906380" datetime="2008-07-24T10:33:00-04:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H7065-7071, H7079"/></action>
		<action date="1216906440" datetime="2008-07-24T10:34:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1362.</text></action>
		<action date="1216908840" datetime="2008-07-24T11:14:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.Res. 1362, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question, and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Lincoln Diaz-Balart (FL) demanded the yeas and nays, and further proceedings on ordering the previous question were postponed until later in the legislative day.</text></action>
		<action date="1216958160" datetime="2008-07-24T12:56:00-04:00"><text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 231 - 185 (Roll no. 526).</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H7069-7071, H7079"/><reference label="text" ref="CR H7070"/></action>
		<vote date="1216958160" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-07-24T12:56:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H7065"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/22/2008--Introduced.<br/>Sets forth the rule for consideration of the Senate amendment to H.R. 5501(Tom Lantos and Henry J. Hyde United States Global Leadership Against HIV/AIDS, Tuberculosis, and Malaria Reauthorization Act of 2008).<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
