<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1355" updated="2009-01-09T10:43:29-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1216856820" datetime="2008-07-23T20:47:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1216267200" datetime="2008-07-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing support for designation of Disability Pride Day and recognizing that all people, including those living with disabilities, have the right, responsibility, and ability to be active, contributing members of our society and fully engaged as citizens.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400093"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400198" joined="2008-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400082" joined="2008-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400350" joined="2008-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2008-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400120" joined="2008-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400163" joined="2008-07-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1216267200" datetime="2008-07-17"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1216856280" datetime="2008-07-23T20:38:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Davis (IL) moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution.</text></action>
		<action date="1216856280" datetime="2008-07-23T20:38:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H7038-7039"/></action>
		<action date="1216856280" datetime="2008-07-23T20:38:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 1355.</text></action>
		<vote date="1216856820" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-07-23T20:47:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H7038"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/23/2008--Passed House without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Supports the goals and ideals of Disability Pride Day. Acknowledges the efforts of the city of Chicago's 5th Annual Disability Pride Parade organizers to raise awareness concerning the value of people with disabilities. Invites the Nation to join in celebrating the pride, the power, and the potential of people with disabilities by celebrating Disability Pride Day. Urges public officials and the general public to honor Americans with disabilities by educating themselves on ways to support and encourage understanding of persons with disabilities in schools, within the diverse workforce, as well as in our communities.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
