<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1363" updated="2009-01-09T10:44:31-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1216831680" datetime="2008-07-23T13:48:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="517"/></status>

	<introduced date="1216699200" datetime="2008-07-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the Senate amendment to the House amendments to the Senate amendment to the bill (H.R. 3221) to provide needed housing reform and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412195"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1216775760" datetime="2008-07-22T22:16:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-767, by Ms. Castor.</text></action>
		<action date="1216775760" datetime="2008-07-22T22:16:00-04:00"><text>Upon the adoption of this resolution it shall be in order to take from the Speaker's table the bill H.R. 3221 with the Senate amendment thereto, and to consider in the House a motion offered by the chairman of the Committee on Financial Services or his designee, that the House concur in the Senate amendment to the House amendment numbered 1 with the amendment printed in the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution. The motion shall be debatable for 2 hours. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the motion to its adoption without</text></action>
		<calendar date="1216775820" datetime="2008-07-22T22:17:00-04:00" ><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 252.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1216824420" datetime="2008-07-23T11:47:00-04:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H6840-6852, H6852-6854"/></action>
		<action date="1216824540" datetime="2008-07-23T11:49:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1363.</text></action>
		<action date="1216831080" datetime="2008-07-23T13:38:00-04:00"><text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 226 - 183 (Roll no. 516).</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H6852-6853"/></action>
		<vote date="1216831680" how="roll" roll="517" datetime="2008-07-23T13:48:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 223 - 201 (Roll no. 517).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H6840-6841"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/22/2008--Introduced.<br/>Sets forth the rule for consideration of the Senate amendment to the House amendments to the Senate amendment to the bill (H.R. 3221) to provide needed housing reform.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
