<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1318" updated="2009-01-09T10:38:24-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1215630360" datetime="2008-07-09T16:06:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="475"/></status>

	<introduced date="1215489600" datetime="2008-07-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 5811) to amend title 44, United States Code, to require preservation of certain electronic records by Federal agencies, to require a certification and reports relating to Presidential records, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412239"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1215554460" datetime="2008-07-08T19:01:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-745, by Mr. Welch (VT).</text></action>
		<action date="1215554460" datetime="2008-07-08T19:01:00-04:00"><text>All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform now printed in the bill shall be considered as adopted.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1215554460" datetime="2008-07-08T19:01:00-04:00" ><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 246.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1215611220" datetime="2008-07-09T10:47:00-04:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H6238-6243"/></action>
		<action date="1215611340" datetime="2008-07-09T10:49:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1318.</text></action>
		<action date="1215613560" datetime="2008-07-09T11:26:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.Res. 1318, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question and by voice vote announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Welch demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on ordering the previous question on H.Res. 1318 until later in the legislative day.</text></action>
		<action date="1215627960" datetime="2008-07-09T15:26:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H6293-6294"/></action>
		<action date="1215629700" datetime="2008-07-09T15:55:00-04:00"><text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by recorded vote: 228 - 193 (Roll no. 474).</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H6293-6294"/></action>
		<vote date="1215630360" how="roll" roll="475" datetime="2008-07-09T16:06:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 229 - 193 (Roll no. 475).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H6238"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/8/2008--Introduced.<br/>Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 5811) to amend title 44, United States Code, to require preservation of certain electronic records by Federal agencies, to require a certification and reports relating to Presidential records.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
