<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1399" updated="2009-01-09T10:49:11-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1217546940" datetime="2008-07-31T20:29:00-04:00" /></status>

	<introduced date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for proceedings during the period from August 1, 2008, through September 4, 2008.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400263"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1217546880" datetime="2008-07-31T20:28:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-816, by Mr. McGovern.</text></action>
		<action date="1217546880" datetime="2008-07-31T20:28:00-04:00"><text>The resolution provides for House proceedings.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1217546940" datetime="2008-07-31T20:29:00-04:00" ><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 258.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1221064500" datetime="2008-09-10T13:35:00-04:00"><text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1419, H. Res. 1399 is laid on the table.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/31/2008--Reported to House without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Provides that, when the House adjourns pursuant to this resolution on any legislative day between August 1 and September 4, 2008, it shall stand adjourned until 11 a.m. on the third constitutional day thereafter. Authorizes the Speaker to appoint Members to perform the duties (Speaker pro tempore) of the Chair during such period. Authorizes the Speaker, on each such day, to dispense with legislative business. Considers the Journal of the proceedings of the previous day as approved. Provides that, unless the Speaker determines otherwise, after the third daily order of business under Rule XIV (Order and Priority of Business) and any proceedings that may be sought under Rule XV, the House shall stand adjourned.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
