<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1345" updated="2009-01-09T10:42:12-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1216094400" datetime="2008-07-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1216094400" datetime="2008-07-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Impeaching George W. Bush, President of the United States, of high crimes and misdemeanors.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400227"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2008-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2008-09-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400430" joined="2008-07-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2008-07-16"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1216154460" datetime="2008-07-15T17:41:00-04:00"><text>ORDER OF PROCEDURE - Ms. Lofgren asked unanimous consent that if Mr. Kucinich offers a resolution as a question of the privileges of the House at any time on the legislative day of July 15, 2008 - (1) the previous question shall be considered as ordered thereon without intervening motion except one motion to refer and one motion to table (which shall have precedence in the order stated); and (2) the Speaker may postpone further proceedings on such a vote on any such motion as through under clause 8(a)(1)(A) of rule 20. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action date="1216154520" datetime="2008-07-15T17:42:00-04:00"><text>QUESTION OF THE PRIVILEGES OF THE HOUSE - Mr. Kucinich rose to a question of the privileges of the House and offered a resolution. The Chair directed the Clerk to report the resolution.</text></action>
		<action date="1216156200" datetime="2008-07-15T18:10:00-04:00"><text>The Clerk completed the reading of H.Res. 1345 and the Chair announced that the resolution met the required threshold under the rule. The Chair announced further that under a previous special order of the House, the previous question on the resolution was ordered without intervening motion, except one motion to refer or one motion to table.</text></action>
		<action date="1216156200" datetime="2008-07-15T18:10:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Kucinich moved to refer to Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1216157940" datetime="2008-07-15T18:39:00-04:00"><text>On motion to refer Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 238 - 180 (Roll no. 492).</text></action>
		<action date="1216094400" datetime="2008-07-15"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/15/2008--Introduced.<br/>Impeaches President George W. Bush for high crimes and misdemeanors.<br/>Sets forth an article of impeachment stating that President Bush, in violation of his oath of office, deceived Congress with fabricated threats of Iraq weapons of mass destruction to fraudulently obtain support for the authorization of use of force against Iraq and to commit troops to combat in Iraq.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
