<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1339" updated="2009-01-09T10:41:18-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1216224600" datetime="2008-07-16T13:10:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="498"/></status>

	<introduced date="1216008000" datetime="2008-07-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 415) to amend the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate segments of the Taunton River in the Commonwealth of Massachusetts as a component of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400263"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1216071900" datetime="2008-07-14T18:45:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-758, by Mr. McGovern.</text></action>
		<action date="1216071900" datetime="2008-07-14T18:45:00-04:00"><text>The rule waives all points of order against consideration of the bill except clauses 9 and 10 of rule XXI. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Natural Resources now printed in the bill shall be considered as an original bill for the purpose of amendment.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1216071900" datetime="2008-07-14T18:45:00-04:00" ><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 247.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1216217340" datetime="2008-07-16T11:09:00-04:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H6587-6596"/></action>
		<action date="1216217340" datetime="2008-07-16T11:09:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1339.</text></action>
		<action date="1216264560" datetime="2008-07-16T12:16:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.Res. 1339, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question and by voice vote announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Hastings (WA) demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on ordering the previous question until later in the legislative day.</text></action>
		<action date="1216264560" datetime="2008-07-16T12:16:00-04:00"><text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of ordering the previous question and on adoption of both H.Res. 1343 and H.Res. 1339, which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1216266900" datetime="2008-07-16T12:55:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H6598-6599"/></action>
		<action date="1216224120" datetime="2008-07-16T13:02:00-04:00"><text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 223 - 198 (Roll no. 497).</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H6596, H6598"/></action>
		<vote date="1216224600" how="roll" roll="498" datetime="2008-07-16T13:10:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 224 - 195 (Roll no. 498).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H6587"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/14/2008--Introduced.<br/>Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 415) to amend the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate segments of the Taunton River in the Commonwealth of Massachusetts as a component of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
