<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1361" updated="2009-01-09T10:44:17-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1222203300" datetime="2008-09-23T17:55:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1216699200" datetime="2008-07-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the United States should lead a high-level diplomatic effort to defeat the campaign by some members of the Organization of the Islamic Conference to divert the United Nation's Durban Review Conference from a review of problems in their own and other countries by attacking Israel, promoting anti-Semitism, and undermining the Universal Charter of Human Rights and to ensure that the Durban Review Conference serves as a forum to review commitments to combat all forms of racism.</title>
		<title type="official" as="amended by house">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the United States should lead a high-level diplomatic effort to ensure that the Durban Review Conference serves as a forum to review implementation of commitments made at the 2001 Durban Conference to combat all forms of racism by defeating the campaign by some members of the Organization of the Islamic Conference to divert the United Nation's Durban Review Conference from a review of problems in their own and other countries by attacking Israel, promoting anti-Semitism, and undermining the Universal Declaration of Human Rights.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400025"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400160" joined="2008-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400080" joined="2008-09-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400380" joined="2008-07-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400122" joined="2008-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400430" joined="2008-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="2008-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400344" joined="2008-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400361" joined="2008-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400003" joined="2008-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400071" joined="2008-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400652" joined="2008-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2008-09-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412198" joined="2008-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400144" joined="2008-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2008-09-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="2008-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400422" joined="2008-07-22" withdrawn="2008-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400195" joined="2008-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2008-07-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2008-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400371" joined="2008-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2008-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400024" joined="2008-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400363" joined="2008-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400425" joined="2008-07-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1216699200" datetime="2008-07-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1216872000" datetime="2008-07-24"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1216872000" datetime="2008-07-24" ><text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1222201380" datetime="2008-09-23T17:23:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Berman moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1222201380" datetime="2008-09-23T17:23:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8647-8652"/></action>
		<action date="1222201380" datetime="2008-09-23T17:23:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 1361.</text></action>
		<vote date="1222203300" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-09-23T17:55:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H8647-8648"/></vote>
		<action date="1222203300" datetime="2008-09-23T17:55:00-04:00"><text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/22/2008--Introduced.<br/>Acknowledges that the 2001 World Conference Against Racism marked an important recognition of the historic wounds caused by slavery, colonialism, and racial discrimination. Calls on the President to urge other heads of state to condition participation in the 2009 Durban Review Conference process on concrete action by the United Nations and member states to ensure that it and they will reject any effort to inject anti-Semitism, hatred, and discrimination onto the Conference agenda.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
