<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1409" updated="2009-01-09T10:50:35-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"/></status>

	<introduced date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Recognizing the great strides made by the majority of countries participating in the Summer Olympic Games to increase the participation of women in sports and in the Summer Olympic Games, calling on the International Olympic Committee and all countries to take concrete steps to increase the participation of women in the 2012 Summer Olympic Games, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400103"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400041" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400130" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400013" joined="2008-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400251" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400378" joined="2008-09-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="412200" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412228" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2008-08-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/1/2008--Introduced.<br/>Recognizes the great strides made by the majority of competing countries to increase the participation of women in the Summer Olympic Games and in sports. Applauds countries with policies that enable women's participation in sports to coexist with traditional cultural and religious practices.<br/>Urges: (1) the International Olympic Committee to advocate for improved opportunities for women to participate in sports and to work with all countries to provide financial support and adequate facilities for women athletes; and (2) the Committee and all countries to increase efforts to enhance such participation, to strive to make the 2012 Summer Olympic Games the first at which women are on delegations from every participating country, and to ensure a record number of women competitors at the 2012 Games.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
