<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1488" updated="2009-01-09T11:00:42-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1222275180" datetime="2008-09-24T13:53:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="630"/></status>

	<introduced date="1222142400" datetime="2008-09-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the Senate amendment to the bill (H.R. 2638) making appropriations for the Department of Homeland Security for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2008, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400263"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1222268940" datetime="2008-09-24T00:09:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-875, by Mr. McGovern.</text></action>
		<action date="1222268940" datetime="2008-09-24T00:09:00-04:00"><text>It shall be in order to take from the Speaker's table the bill H.R. 2638, with the Senate amendment thereto and to move to agree to the Senate amendment with an amendment printed in the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1222269000" datetime="2008-09-24T00:10:00-04:00" ><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 270.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1222266600" datetime="2008-09-24T11:30:00-04:00"><text>By the direction of the Committee on Rules, Mr. McGovern called up H. Res. 1488 and asked for its immediate consideration.</text></action>
		<action date="1222266600" datetime="2008-09-24T11:30:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Flake proposed a point of order against the provisions of H. Res. 1488 by stating the resolution violates the Congressional Budget Act. The Chair announced the disposition of the point of order would be resolved by the question of consideration of H. Res. 1488. The House proceeded with ten minutes of debate on the point of order at the end of which the Chair will put the question on consideration.</text></action>
		<action date="1222267680" datetime="2008-09-24T11:48:00-04:00"><text>Mr. McGovern moved that the House now consider the resolution.</text></action>
		<action date="1222312380" datetime="2008-09-24T12:13:00-04:00"><text>Will the House now consider the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 242 - 168 (Roll no. 628).</text></action>
		<action date="1222312380" datetime="2008-09-24T12:13:00-04:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H9218-9231"/></action>
		<action date="1222312380" datetime="2008-09-24T12:13:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1488.</text></action>
		<action date="1222274640" datetime="2008-09-24T13:44:00-04:00"><text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 231 - 198 (Roll no. 629).</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H9228-9230"/></action>
		<vote date="1222275180" how="roll" roll="630" datetime="2008-09-24T13:53:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 228 - 202 (Roll no. 630).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H9218"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/24/2008--Passed House without amendment. Sets forth the rule for consideration of the Senate amendment to H.R. 2638 (Consolidated Security, Disaster Assistance, and Continuing Appropriations Act, 2009). Agrees to the Senate amendment with an amendment printed in the accompanying report of the Committee on Rules. Requires the chairman of the Committee on Appropriations to insert in the daily issue of the Congressional Record dated September 24, 2008, such material as he may deem explanatory of the motion to agree. 
	</summary>
</bill>
