<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1463" updated="2009-01-09T10:57:33-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1222107360" datetime="2008-09-22T15:16:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1221710400" datetime="2008-09-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Recognizing the benefits of service-learning as a teaching strategy to effectively engage youth in the community and classroom, and supporting the goals of the National Learn and Serve Challenge.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400321"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400370" joined="2008-09-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400663" joined="2008-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400326" joined="2008-09-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2008-09-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400215" joined="2008-09-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1221710400" datetime="2008-09-18"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1222106940" datetime="2008-09-22T15:09:00-04:00"><text>Mrs. Davis (CA) moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1222106940" datetime="2008-09-22T15:09:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8527-8528"/></action>
		<action date="1222106940" datetime="2008-09-22T15:09:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 1463.</text></action>
		<vote date="1222107360" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-09-22T15:16:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H8527"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/22/2008--Passed House amended. Recognizes the benefits of service-learning in improving academic outcomes for youth, engaging youth in positive community experiences, and helping them make more constructive choices in life. Encourages schools, school districts, college campuses, community-based organizations, non-profits, and faith-based organizations to provide youth with more service-learning opportunities. Expresses support for the goals of the annual National Learn and Serve Challenge, that spotlights the value of service-learning to youth, schools, college campuses, and communities.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
