<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1461" updated="2009-01-09T10:57:17-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1222378080" datetime="2008-09-25T18:28:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1221710400" datetime="2008-09-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Recognizing the 10th anniversary of the terrorist bombings of the United States embassies in Nairobi, Kenya, and Dar es Salaam, Tanzania, and the memorializing of the citizens and families of the United States, the Republic of Kenya, and the United Republic of Tanzania whose lives were lost and injured as a result of these attacks.</title>
		<title type="official" as="amended by house">Recognizing the 10th anniversary of the terrorist bombings of the United States embassies in Nairobi, Kenya and Dar es Salaam, Tanzania, and memorializing the citizens and families of the United States, the Republic of Kenya, and the United Republic of Tanzania whose lives were lost or suffered injury as a result of these attacks.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400363"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400025" joined="2008-09-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1221710400" datetime="2008-09-18"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1222200120" datetime="2008-09-23T17:02:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Scott (GA) moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1222200120" datetime="2008-09-23T17:02:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8643-8645"/><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR H8643-8644"/></action>
		<action date="1222200120" datetime="2008-09-23T17:02:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 1461.</text></action>
		<action date="1222200540" datetime="2008-09-23T17:09:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Ms. Ros-Lehtinen objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text></action>
		<action date="1222378080" datetime="2008-09-25T18:28:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text></action>
		<vote date="1222378080" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-09-25T18:28:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text></vote>
		<action date="1222378140" datetime="2008-09-25T18:29:00-04:00"><text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/25/2008--Passed House amended. Recognizes the historic significance of the 10th anniversary of the al Qaeda bombings of the U.S. embassies in Nairobi, Kenya, and Dar Es Salaam, Tanzania. Mourns the loss of those killed and remembers their families and colleagues. Expresses gratitude to the people of Kenya and Tanzania for their assistance following the attacks. Reaffirms the House of Representatives': (1) support for the people of Kenya and Tanzania in striving for future opportunity and democracy; and (2) resolve to defeat al Qaeda and other terrorist organizations.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
