<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1434" updated="2009-01-09T10:53:41-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1221594480" datetime="2008-09-16T16:48:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1221451200" datetime="2008-09-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 6842) to require the District of Columbia to revise its laws regarding the use and possession of firearms as necessary to comply with the requirements of the decision of the Supreme Court in the case of District of Columbia v. Heller, in a manner that protects the security interests of the Federal government and the people who work in, reside in, or visit the District of Columbia and does not undermine the efforts of law enforcement, homeland security, and military officials to protect the Nation's capital from crime and terrorism.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400263"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1221522960" datetime="2008-09-15T20:56:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-852, by Mr. McGovern.</text></action>
		<action date="1221522960" datetime="2008-09-15T20:56:00-04:00"><text>All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. The amendment recommended by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform now printed in the bill shall be considered as adopted in the House and in the Committee of the Whole.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1221522960" datetime="2008-09-15T20:56:00-04:00" ><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 264.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1221587460" datetime="2008-09-16T14:51:00-04:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8168-8178"/></action>
		<action date="1221587460" datetime="2008-09-16T14:51:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1434.</text></action>
		<action date="1221591540" datetime="2008-09-16T15:59:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H. Res. 1434, the Chair put the question on adoption of ordering the previous question and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Session demanded the yeas and nays, and further proceedings on the question of adoption were postponed until later in the legislative day.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8179-8180"/></action>
		<action date="1221593880" datetime="2008-09-16T16:38:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H8179-8180"/></action>
		<action date="1221594480" datetime="2008-09-16T16:48:00-04:00"><text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 241 - 183 (Roll no. 597).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H8168"/></action>
		<vote date="1221594480" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-09-16T16:48:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H8168"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/15/2008--Reported to House without amendment. Sets forth the rule for consideration of H.R. 6842 (National Capital Security and Safety Act). 
	</summary>
</bill>
