<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1517" updated="2009-01-09T11:04:16-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1222688760" datetime="2008-09-29T08:46:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="671"/></status>

	<introduced date="1222574400" datetime="2008-09-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the Senate amendment to the bill (H.R. 3997) to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide earnings assistance and tax relief to members of the uniformed services, volunteer firefighters, and Peace Corps volunteers, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400378"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1222700460" datetime="2008-09-29T00:01:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-903, by Ms. Slaughter.</text></action>
		<action date="1222700460" datetime="2008-09-29T00:01:00-04:00"><text>Provides for consideration of the Senate amendment to the House amendment to the Senate amendment to H.R. 3997. The resolution makes in order a motion by the Chairman of the Committee on Financial Services to concur in the Senate amendment to the House amendment to the Senate amendment with the text of the House amendment printed in this report.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1222700640" datetime="2008-09-29T00:04:00-04:00" ><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 286.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1222700640" datetime="2008-09-29T00:04:00-04:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter. (consideration: CR 9/28/2008 H10316-10327)</text></action>
		<action date="1222700700" datetime="2008-09-29T00:05:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1517.</text></action>
		<action date="1222660920" datetime="2008-09-29T01:02:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.Res. 1517, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question on H.Res. 1517 and by voice vote, announced that the ayes prevailed. Mr. Dreier demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of ordering the previous question until September 29, 2008.</text></action>
		<action date="1222687800" datetime="2008-09-29T08:30:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H10334-10335"/></action>
		<action date="1222688220" datetime="2008-09-29T08:37:00-04:00"><text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 217 - 196 (Roll no. 670).</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H10334"/></action>
		<vote date="1222688760" how="roll" roll="671" datetime="2008-09-29T08:46:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 220 - 198 (Roll no. 671). (text: CR 9/28/2008 H10316)</text></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/28/2008--Introduced.<br/>Sets forth the rule for consideration of the Senate amendment to the bill (H.R. 3997) to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide earnings assistance and tax relief to members of the uniformed services, volunteer firefighters, and Peace Corps volunteers.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
