<bill session="110" type="hr" number="1502" updated="2009-01-09T11:02:35-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1222434060" datetime="2008-09-26T10:01:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="646"/></status>

	<introduced date="1222315200" datetime="2008-09-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 7060) to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide incentives for energy production and conservation, to extend certain expiring provisions, to provide individual income tax relief, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412224"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1222380000" datetime="2008-09-25T19:00:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-887, by Mr. Arcuri.</text></action>
		<action date="1222380000" datetime="2008-09-25T19:00:00-04:00"><text>Waives all points of order against consideration of the bill except those arising under clause 10 for rule XXI.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1222380000" datetime="2008-09-25T19:00:00-04:00" ><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 278.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1222380060" datetime="2008-09-25T19:01:00-04:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H9938-9947"/></action>
		<action date="1222380180" datetime="2008-09-25T19:03:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1502.</text></action>
		<action date="1222381980" datetime="2008-09-25T19:33:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.Res. 1502, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question and by voice vote, announced that the nays had prevailed. Mr. Arcuri demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on ordering the previous question on H.Res. 1502 until a time to be determined.</text></action>
		<action date="1222431360" datetime="2008-09-26T09:16:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H9979-9980"/></action>
		<action date="1222433460" datetime="2008-09-26T09:51:00-04:00"><text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 206 - 186 (Roll no. 645).</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H9979-9980"/></action>
		<vote date="1222434060" how="roll" roll="646" datetime="2008-09-26T10:01:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 215 - 188 (Roll no. 646). (text: CR 9/25/2008 H9938)</text></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/25/2008--Introduced.<br/>Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 7060) to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide incentives for energy production and conservation, to extend certain expiring provisions, to provide individual income tax relief.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
