<bill session="110" type="hr" number="243" updated="2009-01-09T08:23:34-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1178144160" datetime="2007-05-02T19:16:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="286"/></status>

	<introduced date="1173844800" datetime="2007-03-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Calling on the Government of the Socialist Republic of Vietnam to immediately and unconditionally release Father Nguyen Van Ly, Nguyen Van Dai, Le Thi Cong Nhan, and other political prisoners and prisoners of conscience, and for other purposes.</title>
		<title type="official" as="amended by house">Calling on the Government of the Socialist Republic of Vietnam to immediately and unconditionally release Father Nguyen Van Ly, Nguyen Van Dai, Le Thi Cong Nhan, Le Quoc Quan, and other political prisoners and prisoners of conscience, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400380"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400142" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400336" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400122" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400348" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400095" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400071" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400662" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400241" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400052" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400264" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400433" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400288" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400055" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400640" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400098" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400343" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400346" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400320" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400421" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400244" joined="2007-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400617" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400391" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="2007-03-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400141" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400108" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400435" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400309" joined="2007-03-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1173844800" datetime="2007-03-14"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1175227200" datetime="2007-03-30"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E703)</text></action>
		<action date="1176955200" datetime="2007-04-19"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1176955200" datetime="2007-04-19" ><text>Committee Agreed to Seek Consideration Under Suspension of the Rules, (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1178046360" datetime="2007-05-01T16:06:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Sires moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1178046420" datetime="2007-05-01T16:07:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H4246-4253"/></action>
		<action date="1178046420" datetime="2007-05-01T16:07:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 243.</text></action>
		<action date="1178048040" datetime="2007-05-01T16:34:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1178143740" datetime="2007-05-02T19:09:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H4379"/></action>
		<vote date="1178144160" how="roll" roll="286" datetime="2007-05-02T19:16:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" suspension="1" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 404 - 0, 3 Present (Roll no. 286). (text: CR 5/01/2007 H4246-4247)</text></vote>
		<action date="1178144160" datetime="2007-05-02T19:16:00-04:00"><text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action date="1178144220" datetime="2007-05-02T19:17:00-04:00"><text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 1429.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/2/2007--Passed House amended. Condemns the arbitrary arrests of Father Nguyen Van Ly, Nguyen Van Dai, Le Quoc Quan, and Le Thi Cong Nhan by the government of the Socialist Republic of Vietnam and calls for their immediate release, as well as the immediate release of all other political and religious prisoners. Condemns the violations of the freedoms of speech, religion, movement, association, and the lack of due process in Vietnam. Challenges Vietnam's qualifications to be a member of the U.N. Security Council unless the government of Vietnam begins to respect human rights and fundamental freedoms. Urges the government of Vietnam to consider the implications of its actions for the broader U.S.-Vietnam relationship. Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that the United States should: (1) make a top concern the immediate release, legal status, and humanitarian needs of Father Nguyen Van Ly, Nguyen Van Dai, Le Quoc Quan, and Le Thi Cong Nhan, and use funds from the Human Rights Defenders Fund to assist with their legal defense and the needs of their families; (2) urge the government of Vietnam to comply with international standards for basic freedoms and human rights; (3) make clear to the government of Vietnam that it must adhere to the rule of law and respect the freedom of religion and expression in order to broaden its relations with the United States; (4) consider re-imposing on Vietnam the country of particular concern designation; and (5) initiate new foreign assistance programs to advance the capacity and networking abilities of Vietnamese civil society. 
	</summary>
</bill>
