<bill session="110" type="hr" number="266" updated="2009-01-09T08:26:23-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1175016420" datetime="2007-03-27T14:27:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="193"/></status>

	<introduced date="1174881600" datetime="2007-03-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Supporting the goals and ideals of Professional Social Work Month and World Social Work Day.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412219"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400647" joined="2007-03-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="2007-03-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400339" joined="2007-03-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2007-03-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400097" joined="2007-03-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400208" joined="2007-03-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1174881600" datetime="2007-03-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1174931460" datetime="2007-03-26T14:51:00-04:00"><text>Ms. Shea-Porter moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution.</text></action>
		<action date="1174931460" datetime="2007-03-26T14:51:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3028-3029"/></action>
		<action date="1174931460" datetime="2007-03-26T14:51:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 266.</text></action>
		<action date="1174932060" datetime="2007-03-26T15:01:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1175015820" datetime="2007-03-27T14:17:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3098-3099"/></action>
		<vote date="1175016420" how="roll" roll="193" datetime="2007-03-27T14:27:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" suspension="1" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 417 - 2 (Roll no. 193). (text: CR 3/26/2007 H3028)</text></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/27/2007--Passed House without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Supports the goals and ideals of Professional Social Work Month and World Social Work Day. Acknowledges the diligent efforts of the individuals and groups who promote the importance of social work and who are observing Professional Social Work Month and World Social Work Day. Encourages the American people to engage in appropriate ceremonies and activities to further promote awareness of the life-changing role of social workers. Recognizes with gratitude the contributions of the millions of caring individuals who have chosen to serve their communities through social work. Encourages young people to seek out educational and professional opportunities to become social workers.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
