<bill session="110" type="hr" number="284" updated="2009-01-09T08:28:35-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/></status>

	<introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to strengthen the point of order against the consideration of legislation that contains congressional earmarks.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400134"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400279" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400441" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400131" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400570" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400400" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400320" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412201" joined="2007-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="412191" joined="2007-03-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/29/2007--Introduced.<br/>Amends Rule XXI (Restrictions on Certain Bills) of the Rules of the House of Representatives to provide that a point of order may be cognizable by the Chair against consideration of legislation if any list of earmarks, limited tax, and tariff benefits contained in the legislation, or any statement denying the existence of such items, is inaccurate. Requires inclusion on the required list of any provision or report language inserted by the chairman of a standing committee or any subcommittee with subject matter jurisdiction over the measure containing such provision or language that would be a congressional earmark, limited tax, or tariff benefit except that it was not requested by a Member, if such provision or report language is either targeted to the chairman's congressional district or unrelated to the purpose of the underlying measure.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
