<bill session="110" type="hr" number="299" updated="2009-01-09T08:30:24-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1177437120" datetime="2007-04-24T14:52:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="250"/></status>

	<introduced date="1176782400" datetime="2007-04-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that Congress should increase public awareness of child abuse and neglect and should continue to work with the States to reduce the incidence of child abuse and neglect through such programs as the Child Welfare Services and Promoting Safe and Stable Families programs.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400262"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400268" joined="2007-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400176" joined="2007-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="2007-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400324" joined="2007-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400270" joined="2007-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400240" joined="2007-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400429" joined="2007-04-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1176782400" datetime="2007-04-17"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
		<action date="1177472520" datetime="2007-04-24T12:42:00-04:00"><text>Mr. McDermott moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution.</text></action>
		<action date="1177472520" datetime="2007-04-24T12:42:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3790-3792"/></action>
		<action date="1177472520" datetime="2007-04-24T12:42:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 299.</text></action>
		<action date="1177473300" datetime="2007-04-24T12:55:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1177436580" datetime="2007-04-24T14:43:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3804-3805"/></action>
		<vote date="1177437120" how="roll" roll="250" datetime="2007-04-24T14:52:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" suspension="1" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 411 - 0 (Roll no. 250).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H3790"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/24/2007--Passed House without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)<br/>Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that Congress should increase public awareness of child abuse and neglect and should continue to work with the states to reduct the incidence of child abuse and neglect through such programs as the Child Welfare Services and Promoting Safe and Stable Families programs.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
