<bill session="110" type="hr" number="306" updated="2009-01-09T08:31:14-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1176917100" datetime="2007-04-18T14:25:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="221"/></status>

	<introduced date="1176782400" datetime="2007-04-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Offering heartfelt condolences to the victims and their families regarding the horrific violence at Virginia Tech in Blacksburg, Virginia, and to the students, faculty, administration and staff and their families who have been deeply affected by the tragic events that occurred there.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400043"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400060" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400364" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400137" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400095" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400154" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400658" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400098" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400153" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400283" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400435" joined="2007-04-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1176782400" datetime="2007-04-17"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1176903660" datetime="2007-04-18T10:41:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Scott (VA) moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution.</text></action>
		<action date="1176903660" datetime="2007-04-18T10:41:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3486-3492"/></action>
		<action date="1176903660" datetime="2007-04-18T10:41:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 306.</text></action>
		<action date="1176906360" datetime="2007-04-18T11:26:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1176916500" datetime="2007-04-18T14:15:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3510-3511"/></action>
		<vote date="1176917100" how="roll" roll="221" datetime="2007-04-18T14:25:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" suspension="1" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 421 - 0 (Roll no. 221).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H3486"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/18/2007--Passed House without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Offers heartfelt condolences to the victims and their families regarding the horrific violence at Virginia Tech in Blacksburg, Virginia, and to the students, faculty, administration and staff and their families who have been deeply affected by these tragic events. Expresses hope that losses from the mass shooting will lead to a national commitment to take steps to help our communities prevent such tragedies from occurring in the future. Recognizes that Virginia Tech has served as an exemplary institution of teaching, learning, and research for well over a century, and that the University's historic and proud traditions will continue.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
