<bill session="110" type="hr" number="302" updated="2009-01-09T08:30:46-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1176914340" datetime="2007-04-18T13:39:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1176782400" datetime="2007-04-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1361) to improve the disaster relief programs of the Small Business Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400170"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1176845520" datetime="2007-04-17T18:32:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-97, by Mr. Hastings (FL).</text></action>
		<action date="1176845520" datetime="2007-04-17T18:32:00-04:00"><text>All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Small Business now printed in the bill, modified by the amendment printed in part A of the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution, shall be considered as adopted in the House and in the Committee of the Whole.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1176845520" datetime="2007-04-17T18:32:00-04:00" ><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 38.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1176912960" datetime="2007-04-18T13:16:00-04:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3506-3508"/></action>
		<action date="1176913200" datetime="2007-04-18T13:20:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 302.</text></action>
		<action date="1176914340" datetime="2007-04-18T13:39:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3508"/></action>
		<vote date="1176914340" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-04-18T13:39:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H3506"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/18/2007--Passed House without amendment. Sets forth the rule for consideration of H.R. 1361 (Relief for Entrepreneurs: Coordination of Objectives and Values for Effective Recovery Act of 2007, or the RECOVER Act).<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
