<bill session="110" type="hr" number="309" updated="2009-01-09T08:31:35-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1176782400" datetime="2007-04-17"/></status>

	<introduced date="1176782400" datetime="2007-04-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the United States should support independence for Kosovo.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400122"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400222" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400219" joined="2007-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400289" joined="2007-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400430" joined="2007-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="2007-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400647" joined="2007-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400323" joined="2007-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400343" joined="2007-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400087" joined="2007-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400346" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412222" joined="2007-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400251" joined="2007-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400139" joined="2007-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400024" joined="2007-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400025" joined="2007-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400301" joined="2007-04-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1176782400" datetime="2007-04-17"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/17/2007--Introduced.<br/>Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that the United States should: (1) support Kosovo's independence in accordance with its currently constituted borders; (2) in the absence of timely action by the U.N. Security Council, be prepared to act in conjunction with like-minded democracies to confer diplomatic recognition on Kosovo's independence; and (3) support Kosovo's integration into international and Euro-Atlantic institutions, including admission to the Partnership for Peace program of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO), with the ultimate goal of full NATO membership. Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that: (1) the government of Kosovo should ensure the full political and economic rights of Serb and other minority communities in Kosovo; and (2) develop a cooperative relationship with the government of Serbia in recognition of Serbia's legitimate interests in the safety of the Serb population in Kosovo and in the preservation of the patrimonial sites of the Serbian Orthodox Church in Kosovo. Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that the government of Serbia should focus its energies toward achieving a prosperous and peaceful future through regional cooperation and integration into Euro-Atlantic institutions, including NATO and the European Union (EU), and toward the establishment of constructive relations with the government of Kosovo.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
