<bill session="110" type="hr" number="319" updated="2009-01-09T08:32:50-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1176990480" datetime="2007-04-19T10:48:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1176868800" datetime="2007-04-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1495) to provide for the conservation and development of water and related resources, to authorize the Secretary of the Army to construct various projects for improvements to rivers and harbors of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400663"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1176928920" datetime="2007-04-18T17:42:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-100, by Ms. Matsui.</text></action>
		<action date="1176928920" datetime="2007-04-18T17:42:00-04:00"><text>All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure now printed in the bill.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1176928920" datetime="2007-04-18T17:42:00-04:00" ><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 41.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1176989040" datetime="2007-04-19T10:24:00-04:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3566-3568"/></action>
		<action date="1176989340" datetime="2007-04-19T10:29:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 319.</text></action>
		<action date="1176989340" datetime="2007-04-19T10:29:00-04:00"><text>AMENDMENT MODIFICATION - Ms. Matsui asked unanimous consent that during consideration of H.R. 1495, amendment number 1 printed in House Report 110-100 be considered in a modified form. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action date="1176990480" datetime="2007-04-19T10:48:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3568"/></action>
		<vote date="1176990480" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-04-19T10:48:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H3566"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/19/2007--Passed House without amendment. Sets forth the rule for consideration of H.R. 1495 (Water Resources Development Act of 2007).<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
