<bill session="110" type="hr" number="36" updated="2009-01-09T07:58:27-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"/></status>

	<introduced date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the United States should declare its support for the independence of Kosova.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400231"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400344" joined="2007-01-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1167973200" datetime="2007-01-05"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1170651600" datetime="2007-02-05"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Europe.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/5/2007--Introduced.<br/>Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that the United States should: (1) support the independence of Kosova within its existing borders as a sovereign and democratic state; (2) establish a monitoring body in conjunction with the United Nations, the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO), and other multilateral organizations to ensure that the new state of Kosova provides for the protection of minority and community rights, and to facilitate an orderly transition from a U.N. protectorate to a democratic government; (3) work with the Council of Europe to develop and implement anti-racism programs throughout the Balkans; (4) work with the United Nations and NATO to facilitate the return of Albanians and Serbs to their pre-war homes in Mitrovica and other parts of Kosova; (5) provide assistance, trade, and other programs to support an independent Kosova; and (6) recognize the danger that delay in the resolution of Kosova's final status poses for the political and economic viability of Kosova, its neighbors, and Southeast Europe.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
