<bill session="110" type="hr" number="387" updated="2009-01-09T08:41:01-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1178822040" datetime="2007-05-10T15:34:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="327"/></status>

	<introduced date="1178683200" datetime="2007-05-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2237) to provide for the redeployment of United States Armed Forces and defense contractors from Iraq, providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2206) making emergency supplemental appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2007, and for other purposes, and providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2207) making supplemental appropriations for agricultural and other emergency assistance for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2007, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400378"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1178764200" datetime="2007-05-09T23:30:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-143, by Ms. Slaughter.</text></action>
		<action date="1178764200" datetime="2007-05-09T23:30:00-04:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2237, H.R. 2206 and H.R. 2207.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1178764200" datetime="2007-05-09T23:30:00-04:00" ><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 59.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1178853360" datetime="2007-05-10T12:16:00-04:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H4772-4779"/></action>
		<action date="1178853540" datetime="2007-05-10T12:19:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 387.</text></action>
		<action date="1178814420" datetime="2007-05-10T13:27:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H. Res 387, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Dreier demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceeding on ordering the previous question until later in the legislative day.</text></action>
		<action date="1178821080" datetime="2007-05-10T15:18:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business. (consideration: CR 5/11/2007 H4794-4795)</text></action>
		<action date="1178821560" datetime="2007-05-10T15:26:00-04:00"><text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 222 - 201 (Roll no. 326).</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H4779"/></action>
		<vote date="1178822040" how="roll" roll="327" datetime="2007-05-10T15:34:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 219 - 199 (Roll no. 327).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H4772"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/10/2007--Passed House without amendment. Sets forth the rule for consideration of: (1) H.R. 2237 (redeployment of U.S. Armed Forces and defense contractors from Iraq); (2) H.R. 2206 (U.S. Troop Readiness, Veterans' Care, Katrina Recovery, and Iraq Accountability Appropriations Act, 2007); and (3) H.R. 2207 (Agricultural Disaster Assistance and Western States Emergency Unfinished Business Appropriations Act, 2007).<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
