<bill session="110" type="hr" number="386" updated="2009-01-09T08:40:54-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1179250200" datetime="2007-05-15T14:30:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1178683200" datetime="2007-05-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Recognizing the Coast Guard, the Coast Guard Auxiliary, and the National Safe Boating Council for their efforts to promote National Safe Boating Week.</title>
		<title type="official" as="amended by house">Recognizing the Coast Guard, the Coast Guard Auxiliary, and other boating safety organizations for their efforts to promote National Safe Boating Week.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400658"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400041" joined="2007-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400273" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400235" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400244" joined="2007-05-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1178683200" datetime="2007-05-09"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text></action>
		<action date="1178769600" datetime="2007-05-10"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text></action>
		<action date="1179249480" datetime="2007-05-15T14:18:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Cummings moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1179249480" datetime="2007-05-15T14:18:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H5010-5012"/></action>
		<action date="1179249480" datetime="2007-05-15T14:18:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 386.</text></action>
		<vote date="1179250200" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-05-15T14:30:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H5010"/></vote>
		<action date="1179250200" datetime="2007-05-15T14:30:00-04:00"><text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/15/2007--Passed House amended. Supports: (1) initiatives for recreational boating safety education and accident prevention to minimize the number of annual recreational boating fatalities; and (2) the goals of National Safe Boating Week. Recognizes the Coast Guard, the Coast Guard Auxiliary, and other boating safety organizations for their efforts each year during May to highlight the importance of safe recreational boating.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
