<bill session="110" type="hr" number="404" updated="2009-01-09T08:42:59-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1179460440" datetime="2007-05-17T12:54:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="374"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179201600" datetime="2007-05-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1427) to reform the regulation of certain housing-related Government-sponsored enterprises, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412239"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179275580" datetime="2007-05-15T21:33:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-152, by Mr. Welch (VT).</text></action>
		<action date="1179275580" datetime="2007-05-15T21:33:00-04:00"><text>All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Financial Services now printed in the bill, modified by the amendment printed in the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1179275640" datetime="2007-05-15T21:34:00-04:00" ><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 62.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1179408540" datetime="2007-05-17T10:29:00-04:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H5338-5343"/></action>
		<action date="1179408600" datetime="2007-05-17T10:30:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 404.</text></action>
		<action date="1179411240" datetime="2007-05-17T11:14:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H5343"/></action>
		<action date="1179411240" datetime="2007-05-17T11:14:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of the debate on H. Res. 404, the Chair put the question on adoption of the resolution and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Sessions demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption until later in the legislative day.</text></action>
		<action date="1179460080" datetime="2007-05-17T12:48:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H5354-5355"/></action>
		<vote date="1179460440" how="roll" roll="374" datetime="2007-05-17T12:54:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 223 - 186 (Roll no. 374).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H5338-5339"/></vote>
		<action date="1179460500" datetime="2007-05-17T12:55:00-04:00"><text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 1585.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/17/2007--Passed House without amendment. Sets forth the rule for consideration of H.R. 1427 (Federal Housing Finance Reform Act of 2007).<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
