<bill session="110" type="hr" number="445" updated="2009-01-09T08:47:52-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the United States should support a mutually-agreed solution for the future status of Kosovo and reject an imposed solution for the status of Kosovo.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400631"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400071" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="412231" joined="2007-12-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400152" joined="2007-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400055" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412202" joined="2007-09-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/24/2007--Introduced.<br/>Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that the United States should: (1) support a mutually-agreed solution for Kosovo's future status for both Serbia and Kosovo; (2) insist on fulfillment of all agreed-upon democratic standards set forth by the United Nations before supporting final status for Kosovo; (3) restrain from any unilateral action toward Kosovo's independence, especially actions outside the United Nations; (4) work together with the European Union (EU) in supporting the political and economic development of the province of Kosovo and Serbia; (5) support the full integration of the province of Kosovo and Serbia into international and Euro-Atlantic institutions; and (6) reaffirm its commitment to southeastern Europe. Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that: (1) the provincial government of Kosovo should ensure the full political and economic rights of Serbs and other minority communities in Kosovo; (2) the international community should recognize that additional negotiations and diplomacy does not represent a delay of the Kosovo process, and that the government of Serbia currently has legal sovereignty over Kosovo; and (3) the government of Serbia should continue toward a peaceful future through integration into Euro-Atlantic institutions and toward the establishment of constructive relations with the provincial government of Kosovo. 
	</summary>
</bill>
