<bill session="110" type="hr" number="452" updated="2009-01-09T08:48:42-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1181086560" datetime="2007-06-05T20:36:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="430"/></status>

	<introduced date="1181016000" datetime="2007-06-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Raising a question of the Privileges of the House.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400036"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1181077380" datetime="2007-06-05T18:03:00-04:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H5966-5971"/></action>
		<action date="1181077800" datetime="2007-06-05T18:10:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 452.</text></action>
		<action date="1181079960" datetime="2007-06-05T18:46:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H5971"/></action>
		<action date="1181080020" datetime="2007-06-05T18:47:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H. Res. 452, the Chair put the question on adoption of the resolution and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Boehner demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the resolution until later in the legislative day.</text></action>
		<action date="1181086200" datetime="2007-06-05T20:30:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H5979-5980"/></action>
		<vote date="1181086560" how="roll" roll="430" datetime="2007-06-05T20:36:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 373 - 26, 13 Present (Roll no. 430).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H5966-5967"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/5/2007--Passed House without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Requires the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct to: (1) investigate without further delay alleged illegal conduct and violations of House rules by Representative William J. Jefferson; and (2) report its findings and recommendations to the House, including a recommendation regarding whether Representative Jefferson should be expelled from the House. 
	</summary>
</bill>
