<bill session="110" type="hr" number="485" updated="2009-01-09T08:52:37-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1182188940" datetime="2007-06-18T14:49:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1181793600" datetime="2007-06-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing appreciation for the profound public service and educational contributions of Donald Jeffry Herbert, fondly known as &quot;Mr. Wizard&quot;.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400119"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400257" joined="2007-06-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400027" joined="2007-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400317" joined="2007-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400151" joined="2007-06-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400165" joined="2007-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400229" joined="2007-06-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400412" joined="2007-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400642" joined="2007-06-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400005" joined="2007-06-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1181793600" datetime="2007-06-14"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1182188100" datetime="2007-06-18T14:35:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Grijalva moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution.</text></action>
		<action date="1182188100" datetime="2007-06-18T14:35:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H6586-6588"/></action>
		<action date="1182188100" datetime="2007-06-18T14:35:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 485.</text></action>
		<vote date="1182188940" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-06-18T14:49:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H6586-6587"/></vote>
		<action date="1185249600" datetime="2007-07-24"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/18/2007--Passed House without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Expresses the appreciation of the House of Representatives for the profound public service and educational contributions of Donald Jeffry Herbert (television's &quot;Mr. Wizard&quot;). Recognizes the profound impact of higher educational institutions that train teachers. Encourages students to honor the heritage of Don Herbert by exploring our world through science, technology, engineering, and mathematics fields. Tenders the condolences of the House to the family of Don Herbert, and thanks them for their strong familial support of him.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
