<bill session="110" type="hr" number="506" updated="2009-01-09T08:55:15-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1182312000" datetime="2007-06-20"/></status>

	<introduced date="1182312000" datetime="2007-06-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Condemning ongoing human rights abuses in Vietnam, and expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that the United States should remove permanent normal trade relations status with Vietnam unless all political and religious prisoners are released and significant and immediate human rights reforms are made by the Government of Vietnam.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400245"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400004" joined="2007-06-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400380" joined="2007-06-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400268" joined="2007-06-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400055" joined="2007-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400098" joined="2007-06-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400356" joined="2007-06-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400653" joined="2007-06-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400141" joined="2007-06-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400435" joined="2007-06-20"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1182312000" datetime="2007-06-20"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1182312000" datetime="2007-06-20"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1182312000" datetime="2007-06-20"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/20/2007--Introduced.<br/>Condemns the ongoing human rights abuses in Vietnam and calls for the release of all political and religious prisoners there. Urges the United States to: (1) re-designate Vietnam as a Country of Particular Concern; (2) demand that the government of Vietnam comply with internationally recognized standards for basic freedoms and human rights; and (3) remove permanent normal trade relations status with Vietnam unless all political and religious prisoners are released and significant and immediate human rights reforms are made by the government of Vietnam.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
