<bill session="110" type="hr" number="548" updated="2009-01-09T09:00:19-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1190743980" datetime="2007-09-25T15:13:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="899"/></status>

	<introduced date="1184558400" datetime="2007-07-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the ongoing concern of the House of Representatives for Lebanon's democratic institutions and unwavering support for the administration of justice upon those responsible for the assassination of Lebanese public figures opposing Syrian control of Lebanon.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400003"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400123" joined="2007-09-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400041" joined="2007-07-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400031" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400257" joined="2007-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400289" joined="2007-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="412224" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400380" joined="2007-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400271" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400430" joined="2007-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="2007-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400268" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400361" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="412192" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400196" joined="2007-07-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2007-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400132" joined="2007-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400409" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400152" joined="2007-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400055" joined="2007-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400355" joined="2007-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="412198" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400231" joined="2007-07-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400648" joined="2007-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400308" joined="2007-09-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400087" joined="2007-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400346" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="412240" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="412222" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400422" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400426" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400195" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400251" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400175" joined="2007-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2007-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="412186" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400326" joined="2007-09-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400649" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400371" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400641" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400315" joined="2007-07-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400636" joined="2007-07-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400024" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400363" joined="2007-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400025" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="412194" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400435" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="412191" joined="2007-09-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400622" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400252" joined="2007-07-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1184558400" datetime="2007-07-16"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1185854400" datetime="2007-07-31"><text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1185854400" datetime="2007-07-31" ><text>Committee Agreed to Seek Consideration Under Suspension of the Rules, (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1190775900" datetime="2007-09-25T12:05:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Ackerman moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended.</text></action>
		<action date="1190776020" datetime="2007-09-25T12:07:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H10776-10778"/></action>
		<action date="1190776020" datetime="2007-09-25T12:07:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 548.</text></action>
		<action date="1190776560" datetime="2007-09-25T12:16:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1190742600" datetime="2007-09-25T14:50:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H10801-10802"/></action>
		<vote date="1190743980" how="roll" roll="899" datetime="2007-09-25T15:13:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" suspension="1" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 415 - 2 (Roll no. 899).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H10776-10777"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/25/2007--Passed House amended. Condemns: (1) the attempts by Hezbollah and other pro-Syrian groups to undermine the democratically-elected and legitimate government of Lebanon by extra-legal means; and (2) the campaign of assassinations targeting members of parliament and public figures opposed to Syrian interference in Lebanon, and bombings in civilian areas intended to intimidate the Lebanese people. Calls on the Lebanese parliament to elect a new President in accordance with Lebanon's constitution. Declares that the association of political parties with terrorist organizations, militias, and other armed elements outside of the official military and security institutions hinders the emergence of a fully-democratic Lebanon. Confirms U.S. support for U.N. Security Council resolutions concerning Lebanon, and the mandate of the international community for the arms embargo and disarmament of all armed groups in Lebanon, particularly Hezbollah and Palestinian factions in Lebanon. Condemns Syria and Iran for their ongoing roles in arming terrorist organizations, Lebanese militias, and other militias operating in Lebanon. Declares that the United States should consider Syria's obstructive role in Lebanon when assessing U.S.-Syria relations. Expresses appreciation to Belgium, China, Cyprus, Denmark, Finland, France, Germany, Ghana, Greece, Guatemala, Hungary, India, Indonesia, Ireland, Italy, the Republic of Korea, Luxembourg, Malaysia, Nepal, Netherlands, Norway, Poland, Portugal, Qatar, Slovakia, Slovenia, Spain, Sweden, Tanzania, and Turkey for their contributions of military personnel to the United Nations Interim Force in Lebanon (UNIFIL). Urges the government of Lebanon to request UNIFIL's assistance to secure the Lebanese-Syrian border against the entry of illicit arms or related material, and pledges American support for this action. Calls on the international community to support the mission of UNIFIL and efforts by the U.N. Secretary-General to improve the monitoring of the Lebanese border. Affirms U.S. support for efforts to bring to justice those responsible for the terrorist bombing of February 14, 2005, and both prior and subsequent politically inspired assassinations, and for the Special Tribunal for Lebanon. Pledges support for the government of Lebanon and the Lebanese people against the campaign of intimidation, terror, and murder. Commends the many Lebanese who continue to adhere to the principles of the Cedar Revolution and support the government of Lebanon. Applauds the government of Lebanon's efforts to extend Lebanon's sovereignty over the entire country through the internal deployments of the Lebanese Armed Forces, including direct action against the Fatah al Islam group. Reaffirms the House's intention to provide financial and material assistance to support the sovereignty, territorial integrity, unity, and political independence of Lebanon under the exclusive authority of the government of Lebanon.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
