<bill session="110" type="hr" number="594" updated="2009-01-09T09:06:16-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1185988140" datetime="2007-08-01T14:09:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="785"/></status>

	<introduced date="1185854400" datetime="2007-07-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3162) to amend titles XVIII, XIX, and XXI of the Social Security Act to extend and improve the children's health insurance program, to improve beneficiary protections under the Medicare, Medicaid, and CHIP program, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412195"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1185950520" datetime="2007-08-01T03:42:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-285, by Ms. Castor.</text></action>
		<action date="1185950520" datetime="2007-08-01T03:42:00-04:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3162 with 2 hours of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1185950640" datetime="2007-08-01T03:44:00-04:00" ><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 96.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1185979500" datetime="2007-08-01T11:45:00-04:00"><text>Ms. Castor called up the resolution for consideration.</text></action>
		<action date="1185979560" datetime="2007-08-01T11:46:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with twenty minutes of debate on Mr. Sessions point of order that the resolution violates section 426(a) of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974. In accordance with section 426(b)(2) of the Act, Mr. Sessions met the threshold burden to identify the specific language in the resolution on which the point of order is predicated. Pursuant to section 426(b)(3) of the Act, after that debate the Chair will put the question of consideration.</text></action>
		<action date="1186024200" datetime="2007-08-01T12:10:00-04:00"><text>On motion to consider the resolution. Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 222 - 197 (Roll no. 782).</text></action>
		<action date="1186024200" datetime="2007-08-01T12:10:00-04:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H9287-9298, H9299-9302"/></action>
		<action date="1186024200" datetime="2007-08-01T12:10:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 594.</text></action>
		<action date="1185986220" datetime="2007-08-01T13:37:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House resumed debate on H. Res. 594.</text></action>
		<action date="1185987720" datetime="2007-08-01T14:02:00-04:00"><text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 228 - 190 (Roll no. 784).</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H9300-9301"/></action>
		<vote date="1185988140" how="roll" roll="785" datetime="2007-08-01T14:09:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 224 - 197 (Roll No. 785).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H9287-9288"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/1/2007--Passed House without amendment. Sets forth the rule for consideration of H.R. 3162 (Children's Health and Medicare Protection Act of 2007)<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
