<bill session="110" type="hr" number="601" updated="2009-01-09T09:07:04-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1186066380" datetime="2007-08-02T11:53:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="794"/></status>

	<introduced date="1185940800" datetime="2007-08-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3159) to mandate minimum periods of rest and recuperation for units and members of the regular and reserve components of the Armed Forces between deployments for Operation Iraqi Freedom or Operation Enduring Freedom.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400378"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1186020000" datetime="2007-08-01T23:00:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-292, by Ms. Slaughter.</text></action>
		<action date="1186020000" datetime="2007-08-01T23:00:00-04:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3159 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1186020060" datetime="2007-08-01T23:01:00-04:00" ><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 102.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1186057140" datetime="2007-08-02T09:19:00-04:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H9549-9557"/></action>
		<action date="1186057200" datetime="2007-08-02T09:20:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 601.</text></action>
		<action date="1186060740" datetime="2007-08-02T10:19:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H. Res. 601, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mrs. Slaughter demaned the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question on ordering the previous question until later in the legislative day.</text></action>
		<action date="1186065540" datetime="2007-08-02T11:39:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H9564-9565"/></action>
		<action date="1186065960" datetime="2007-08-02T11:46:00-04:00"><text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 225 - 201 (Roll no. 793).</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H9564"/></action>
		<vote date="1186066380" how="roll" roll="794" datetime="2007-08-02T11:53:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 224 - 200 (Roll no. 794).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H9549"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/2/2007--Passed House without amendment. Sets forth the rule for consideration of H.R. 3159 (Ensuring Military Readiness Through Stability and Predictability Deployment Policy Act of 2007).<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
