<bill session="110" type="hr" number="660" updated="2009-01-09T09:14:15-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1190258040" datetime="2007-09-19T12:14:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="880"/></status>

	<introduced date="1190088000" datetime="2007-09-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2761) to extend the Terrorism Insurance Program of the Department of the Treasury, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412224"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1190150700" datetime="2007-09-18T18:25:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-333, by Mr. Arcuri.</text></action>
		<action date="1190150700" datetime="2007-09-18T18:25:00-04:00"><text>All points of order against consideration of the bill except clauses 9 and 10 of Rules XXI. The rule provides that the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Financial Services now printed in the bill, modified by the amendment printed in Part A of this report, shall be considered as adopted. The rule makes in order only those further amendments printed in Part B of this report.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1190150700" datetime="2007-09-18T18:25:00-04:00" ><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 117.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1190208660" datetime="2007-09-19T10:31:00-04:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H10516-10524"/></action>
		<action date="1190208780" datetime="2007-09-19T10:33:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 660.</text></action>
		<action date="1190212380" datetime="2007-09-19T11:33:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H. Res. 660, Mr. Arcuri moved the previous question and by voice vote, the Chair announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Arcuri demanded the Yeas and Nays which were ordered, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of ordering the previous question until later in the legislative day.</text></action>
		<action date="1190213940" datetime="2007-09-19T11:59:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H10525-10526"/></action>
		<action date="1190257560" datetime="2007-09-19T12:06:00-04:00"><text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 224 - 197 (Roll no. 879).</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H10523-10524, H10524-10525"/></action>
		<vote date="1190258040" how="roll" roll="880" datetime="2007-09-19T12:14:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 223 - 195 (Roll no. 880).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H10516-10517"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/19/2007--Passed House without amendment. Sets forth the rule for consideration of H.R. 2761 (Terrorism Risk Insurance Revision and Extension Act of 2007). 
	</summary>
</bill>
