<bill session="110" type="hr" number="664" updated="2009-01-09T09:14:45-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1190298660" datetime="2007-09-20T11:31:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="888"/></status>

	<introduced date="1190174400" datetime="2007-09-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 2881) to amend title 49, United States Code, to authorize appropriations for the Federal Aviation Administration for fiscal years 2008 through 2011, to improve aviation safety and capacity, to provide stable funding for the national aviation system, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412239"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1190234700" datetime="2007-09-19T17:45:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-335, by Mr. Welch (VT).</text></action>
		<action date="1190234700" datetime="2007-09-19T17:45:00-04:00"><text>All points of order againist consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. In lieu of the amendment in the nature of substitute recommended by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure now printed in the bill, the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in part A of the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution, modified by the amendment printed in part B of such report, shall be considered as adopted in the House and in the Commmittee of the Whole.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1190234760" datetime="2007-09-19T17:46:00-04:00" ><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 118.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1190294400" datetime="2007-09-20T10:20:00-04:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H10631-10633, H10634-10635"/></action>
		<action date="1190294400" datetime="2007-09-20T10:20:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 664.</text></action>
		<action date="1190297040" datetime="2007-09-20T11:04:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House resumed debate on H. Res. 664.</text></action>
		<action date="1190298060" datetime="2007-09-20T11:21:00-04:00"><text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 223 - 189 (Roll no. 887).</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H10634-10635"/></action>
		<vote date="1190298660" how="roll" roll="888" datetime="2007-09-20T11:31:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 218 - 196 (Roll no. 888).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H10631"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/20/2007--Passed House without amendment. Sets forth the rule for consideration of H.R. 2881 (FAA Reauthorization Act of 2007).<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
