<bill session="110" type="hr" number="683" updated="2009-01-09T09:17:03-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1190951460" datetime="2007-09-27T12:51:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="918"/></status>

	<introduced date="1190779200" datetime="2007-09-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3121) to restore the financial solvency of the national flood insurance program and to provide for such program to make available multiperil coverage for damage resulting from windstorms and floods, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400663"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1190842380" datetime="2007-09-26T18:33:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-351, by Ms. Matsui.</text></action>
		<action date="1190842380" datetime="2007-09-26T18:33:00-04:00"><text>All points of order againist consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Financial Services now printed in the bill, modified by the amendment printed in part A of the report of the Committee on Rules acompanying this resolution, shall be considered as adopted in the House and in the Committee of the Whole.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1190842440" datetime="2007-09-26T18:34:00-04:00" ><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 125.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1190900760" datetime="2007-09-27T10:46:00-04:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H10947-10953"/></action>
		<action date="1190900940" datetime="2007-09-27T10:49:00-04:00"><text>Point of order raised by Mr. Dreier on the content of the measure. Mr. Dreier stated that the provisions of H.Res. 683 violate House earmark rules. Point of order overruled by the Chair.</text></action>
		<action date="1190901060" datetime="2007-09-27T10:51:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 683.</text></action>
		<action date="1190905140" datetime="2007-09-27T11:59:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House resumed debate on H. Res. 683.</text></action>
		<action date="1190948820" datetime="2007-09-27T12:07:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.Res. 682, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question and by voice vote, announced that ayes had prevailed. Ms. Matsui demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question on ordering the previous question until later in the legislative day.</text></action>
		<action date="1190950500" datetime="2007-09-27T12:35:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H10955-10956"/></action>
		<action date="1190950980" datetime="2007-09-27T12:43:00-04:00"><text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by recorded vote: 220 - 193, 1 Present (Roll no. 917).</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H10955"/></action>
		<vote date="1190951460" how="roll" roll="918" datetime="2007-09-27T12:51:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 220 - 188, 1 Present (Roll no. 918).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H10947"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/27/2007--Passed House without amendment. Sets forth the rule for consideration of H.R. 3121 (Flood Insurance Reform and Modernization Act of 2007). 
	</summary>
</bill>
