<bill session="110" type="hr" number="68" updated="2009-01-09T08:02:19-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1168923600" datetime="2007-01-16"/></status>

	<introduced date="1168923600" datetime="2007-01-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Recognizing the dangers posed by nuclear weapons and calling on the President to engage in nonproliferation strategies designed to eliminate these weapons of mass destruction from United States and worldwide arsenals.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400436"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400253" joined="2007-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400227" joined="2007-01-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2007-03-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400080" joined="2008-05-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2007-01-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400129" joined="2007-01-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400184" joined="2007-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400130" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="2007-01-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400103" joined="2007-10-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2007-06-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400013" joined="2007-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400422" joined="2007-10-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2007-01-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400366" joined="2007-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2007-09-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2007-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400204" joined="2007-09-20"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1168923600" datetime="2007-01-16"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1168923600" datetime="2007-01-16"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1168923600" datetime="2007-01-16"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1170651600" datetime="2007-02-05"><committee name="House Foreign Affairs"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Terrorism, Nonproliferation, and Trade.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/16/2007--Introduced.<br/>Requests the President to inform Congress and the Secretary General of the United Nations regarding U.S. efforts and measures taken with respect to implementation and observance of Article VI of the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons (NPT) and certain U.N. resolutions calling for U.S. and world nuclear disarmament. Calls on the President to implement and observe all NPT obligations and commitments and to revise national policies on nuclear weapons accordingly. Urges the President, in the interests of protecting and advancing human, national, and global security, to: (1) declare that the United States will not use nuclear weapons first, and that pending their elimination, such weapons serve only to deter a nuclear attack by a hostile state or other entity; (2) initiate and conclude multilateral negotiations on verifiable steps nuclear states shall take to reduce and eventually eliminate nuclear weapons; (3) cooperate with the Russian Federation to remove from deployment nuclear weapons that are operational; (4) reaffirm the moratorium on nuclear testing and work for ratification of the Comprehensive Test Ban Treaty; (5) terminate all efforts to enhance U.S. military capabilities of the U.S. nuclear arsenal and to develop ballistic missile defenses; and (6) support initiatives to ban weapons in outer space.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
