<bill session="110" type="hr" number="706" updated="2009-01-09T09:19:54-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1191297600" datetime="2007-10-02"/></status>

	<introduced date="1191297600" datetime="2007-10-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Honoring all members of the Armed Forces and civilian personnel serving in harm's way and pledging to debate policy decisions regarding the war in Iraq without attacking the integrity of any person, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412222"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400199" joined="2007-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2007-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400122" joined="2007-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400246" joined="2007-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400129" joined="2007-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400412" joined="2007-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400262" joined="2007-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2007-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="2007-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400048" joined="2007-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="412199" joined="2007-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400251" joined="2007-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400378" joined="2007-10-02"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1191297600" datetime="2007-10-02"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
		<action date="1192766400" datetime="2007-10-19"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/2/2007--Introduced.<br/>Recognizes the service of General John Batiste, General Paul Eaton, Army specialist Buddhika Jayamaha, Sergeant Wesley D. Smith, Sergeant Jeremy Roebuck, Sergeant Edward Sandmeier, as well as other members of the Armed Forces serving in good standing in the defense of the United States, and honors the personal sacrifices made by these men and their families, and other members and their families. Recognizes the service and mourns the loss of Sergeant Omar Mora, Staff Sergeant Yance T. Gray, and the 3,784 members who have died in Iraq as of September 27, 2007, and extends sympathies to their families. Recognizes the service and sacrifice of Staff Sergeant Jeremy A. Murphy and the more than 24,000 members wounded in Iraq. Rejects commentator Rush Limbaugh's opinion that any of the individuals listed above are &quot;phony soldiers.&quot; Condemns the personal attacks made by Rush Limbaugh impugning the integrity and professionalism of any members. Honors all members and civilian personnel serving in harm's way, and their families. Pledges to debate policy decisions regarding the war in Iraq without attacking the integrity of any person, regardless of his or her position on the war.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
