<bill session="110" type="hr" number="704" updated="2009-01-09T09:19:39-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1191553440" datetime="2007-10-04T12:04:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="942"/></status>

	<introduced date="1191297600" datetime="2007-10-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3246) to amend title 40, United States Code, to provide a comprehensive regional approach to economic and infrastructure development in the most severely economically distressed regions in the Nation.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412224"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1191361680" datetime="2007-10-02T18:48:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-361, by Mr. Arcuri.</text></action>
		<action date="1191361680" datetime="2007-10-02T18:48:00-04:00"><text>The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure now printed in the bill, modified by the amendment printed in the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution, shall be considered as adopted.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1191361740" datetime="2007-10-02T18:49:00-04:00" ><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 130.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1191505620" datetime="2007-10-04T10:47:00-04:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H11259-11261"/></action>
		<action date="1191505740" datetime="2007-10-04T10:49:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 704.</text></action>
		<action date="1191506580" datetime="2007-10-04T11:03:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.Res. 704, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Hastings (WA) demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on ordering the previous question until later in the legislative day.</text></action>
		<action date="1191509400" datetime="2007-10-04T11:50:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H11267-11268"/></action>
		<action date="1191509820" datetime="2007-10-04T11:57:00-04:00"><text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 224 - 194 (Roll no. 941).</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H11261, H11267-11268"/></action>
		<vote date="1191553440" how="roll" roll="942" datetime="2007-10-04T12:04:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 227 - 188 (Roll no. 942).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H11259"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/4/2007--Passed House without amendment. Sets forth the rule for consideration of H.R. 3246 (Regional Economic and Infrastructure Development Act of 2007).<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
