<bill session="110" type="hr" number="719" updated="2009-01-09T09:21:33-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1192074120" datetime="2007-10-10T12:42:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="954"/></status>

	<introduced date="1191902400" datetime="2007-10-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3056) to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to repeal the authority of the Internal Revenue Service to use private debt collection companies, to delay implementation of withholding taxes on government contractors, to revise the tax rules on expatriation, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400065"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1191970620" datetime="2007-10-09T19:57:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-368, by Mr. Cardoza.</text></action>
		<action date="1191970620" datetime="2007-10-09T19:57:00-04:00"><text>All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 or rule XXI. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Ways and Means now printed in the bill, modified by the amendment printed in the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution, shall be considered as adopted</text></action>
		<calendar date="1191970620" datetime="2007-10-09T19:57:00-04:00" ><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 131.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1192023180" datetime="2007-10-10T10:33:00-04:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H11400-11410"/></action>
		<action date="1192023180" datetime="2007-10-10T10:33:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 719.</text></action>
		<action date="1192026480" datetime="2007-10-10T11:28:00-04:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.Res. 719, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Sessions objected to the voice vote based upon the absence of a quorum. The Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of ordering the previous question until later in the legislative day. The point of no quorum is considered as withdrawn.</text></action>
		<action date="1192073100" datetime="2007-10-10T12:25:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H11414-11415"/></action>
		<action date="1192073640" datetime="2007-10-10T12:34:00-04:00"><text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 220 - 198 (Roll no. 953).</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H11414"/></action>
		<vote date="1192074120" how="roll" roll="954" datetime="2007-10-10T12:42:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 217 - 198 (Roll no. 954).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H11400"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/10/2007--Passed House without amendment. Sets forth the rule for consideration of H.R. 3056 (Tax Collection Responsibility Act of 2007).<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
