<bill session="110" type="hr" number="762" updated="2009-01-09T09:26:54-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1193091420" datetime="2007-10-22T19:17:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="985"/></status>

	<introduced date="1193025600" datetime="2007-10-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Supporting the goals of National Bullying Prevention Awareness Week.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400257"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1193025600" datetime="2007-10-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1193079180" datetime="2007-10-22T15:53:00-04:00"><text>Mrs. McCarthy (NY) moved to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution.</text></action>
		<action date="1193079180" datetime="2007-10-22T15:53:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H11806-11808"/></action>
		<action date="1193079180" datetime="2007-10-22T15:53:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H. Res. 762.</text></action>
		<action date="1193079900" datetime="2007-10-22T16:05:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text></action>
		<action date="1193090940" datetime="2007-10-22T19:09:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H11819-11820"/></action>
		<vote date="1193091420" how="roll" roll="985" datetime="2007-10-22T19:17:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" suspension="1" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and agree to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 375 - 0, 1 Present (Roll no. 985).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H11806-11807"/></vote>
		<action date="1195016400" datetime="2007-11-14"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Healthy Families and Communities.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/22/2007--Passed House without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Recognizes that bullying of school-aged children is a national concern and unhealthy for our families and communities. Commends national and community organizations, schools, parents, recreation programs, and religious institutions for promoting greater public awareness about bullying and bullying prevention activities. Supports the goals of National Bullying Prevention Awareness Week.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
