<bill session="110" type="hr" number="774" updated="2009-01-09T09:28:19-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1193332800" datetime="2007-10-25T14:20:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="1007"/></status>

	<introduced date="1193198400" datetime="2007-10-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3963) to amend title XXI of the Social Security Act to extend and improve the Children's Health Insurance Program, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400378"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1193280840" datetime="2007-10-24T23:54:00-04:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-408, by Ms. Slaughter.</text></action>
		<action date="1193280840" datetime="2007-10-24T23:54:00-04:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3963 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1193280840" datetime="2007-10-24T23:54:00-04:00" ><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 141.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1193322000" datetime="2007-10-25T11:20:00-04:00"><text>By direction of the Committee on Rules, Mrs. Slaughter called up H. Res. 774 and asked for its immediate consideration.</text></action>
		<action date="1193322000" datetime="2007-10-25T11:20:00-04:00"><text>POINT OF ORDER - Mr. Sessions stated that the provisions of H. Res. 774 contain a waiver which violated the Budget Act. The Chair announced that the necessary threshhold had been met which requires that the specific language objected to be identified. Pursuant to the rule, the House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the question of consideration of the resolution.</text></action>
		<action date="1193324040" datetime="2007-10-25T11:54:00-04:00"><text>On motion to consider the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 216 - 181 (Roll no. 1003).</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H12027-12029"/></action>
		<action date="1193324160" datetime="2007-10-25T11:56:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Price (GA) moved to reconsider the vote.</text></action>
		<action date="1193324160" datetime="2007-10-25T11:56:00-04:00"><text>Ms. Slaughter moved to table the motion to reconsider.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H12029-12030"/></action>
		<action date="1193368440" datetime="2007-10-25T12:14:00-04:00"><text>On motion to table the motion to reconsider Agreed to by recorded vote: 218 - 183 (Roll no. 1004).</text></action>
		<action date="1193369520" datetime="2007-10-25T12:32:00-04:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H12031-12042"/></action>
		<action date="1193369520" datetime="2007-10-25T12:32:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 774.</text></action>
		<action date="1193332260" datetime="2007-10-25T14:11:00-04:00"><text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 221 - 188 (Roll no. 1006).</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H12040-12041"/></action>
		<vote date="1193332800" how="roll" roll="1007" datetime="2007-10-25T14:20:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 215 - 187 (Roll no. 1007).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H12027"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/25/2007--Passed House without amendment. Sets forth the rule for consideration of H.R. 3963 (Children's Health Insurance Program Reauthorization Act of 2007).<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
