<bill session="110" type="hr" number="817" updated="2009-01-09T09:33:51-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1195069200" datetime="2007-11-14T15:40:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="1098"/></status>

	<introduced date="1194930000" datetime="2007-11-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the conference report to accompany the bill (H.R. 3074) making appropriations for the Departments of Transportation, and Housing and Urban Development, and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2008, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412224"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1195001700" datetime="2007-11-13T20:55:00-05:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-447, by Mr. Arcuri.</text></action>
		<action date="1195001700" datetime="2007-11-13T20:55:00-05:00"><text>All points of order against the conference report and against its consideration includes a waiver of clause 8 of rule XXII.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1195001700" datetime="2007-11-13T20:55:00-05:00" ><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 154.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1195062540" datetime="2007-11-14T13:49:00-05:00"><text>By direction of the Committee on Rules, Mr. Arcuri called up H.Res. 817, and asked for its immediate consideration.</text></action>
		<action date="1195062540" datetime="2007-11-14T13:49:00-05:00"><text>POINT OF ORDER - Mr. Flake raised a point of order against the provisions of H. Res. 817 because it waives all points of order against the conference report to accompany H.R. 3074 and against its consideration. The Chair announced that the disposition of the point of order would be resolved by the question of consideration of H. Res. 817. The House proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the point of order at the end of which the Chair will put the question on consideration.</text></action>
		<action date="1195063800" datetime="2007-11-14T14:10:00-05:00"><text>On motion to consider the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 197 - 186 (Roll no. 1093).</text></action>
		<action date="1195064400" datetime="2007-11-14T14:20:00-05:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H13885-13888, H13889-13891, H13891-13896"/></action>
		<action date="1195064460" datetime="2007-11-14T14:21:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 817.</text></action>
		<action date="1195068360" datetime="2007-11-14T15:26:00-05:00"><text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by recorded vote: 221 - 195 (Roll no. 1096).</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H13892-13893"/></action>
		<action date="1195068420" datetime="2007-11-14T15:27:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Diaz-Balart, L. moved to reconsider ordering the previous question.</text></action>
		<action date="1195068420" datetime="2007-11-14T15:27:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Arcuri moved to table the motion to reconsider.</text></action>
		<action date="1195068780" datetime="2007-11-14T15:33:00-05:00"><text>On motion to table the motion to reconsider Agreed to by recorded vote: 221 - 196 (Roll No. 1097).</text></action>
		<vote date="1195069200" how="roll" roll="1098" datetime="2007-11-14T15:40:00-05:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 224 - 194 (Roll no. 1098).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H13885-13886"/></vote>
		<action date="1195069200" datetime="2007-11-14T15:40:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Diaz-Balart, L. moved to reconsider adoption of the resolution.</text></action>
		<action date="1195069200" datetime="2007-11-14T15:40:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Arcuri moved to table the motion to reconsider.</text></action>
		<action date="1195069560" datetime="2007-11-14T15:46:00-05:00"><text>On motion to table the motion to reconsider Agreed to by recorded vote: 213 - 194 (Roll No. 1099).</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/14/2007--Passed House without amendment. Waives points of order against consideration of the conference report on H.R. 3074 (Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2008).<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
