<bill session="110" type="hr" number="836" updated="2009-01-09T09:36:15-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1196892060" datetime="2007-12-05T18:01:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" how="without objection" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1196744400" datetime="2007-12-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Granting the authority provided under clause 4(c)(3) of rule X of the Rules of the House of Representatives to the Committee on Education and Labor for purposes of its investigation into the deaths of 9 individuals that occurred at the Crandall Canyon Mine near Huntington, Utah.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400278"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1196744400" datetime="2007-12-04"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text></action>
		<action date="1196892000" datetime="2007-12-05T18:00:00-05:00"><text>Reported by the Committee on Rules. H. Rept. 110-473.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1196892000" datetime="2007-12-05T18:00:00-05:00" ><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 162.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1196892060" datetime="2007-12-05T18:01:00-05:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H14226-14117"/></action>
		<vote date="1196892060" how="without objection" datetime="2007-12-05T18:01:00-05:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to without objection.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H14226"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	12/5/2007--Passed House without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Grants the Committee on Education and Labor the authority provided under Rule X (Organization of Committees) of the Rules of the House of Representatives to adopt a rule authorizing and regulating the taking of depositions by its members or counsel, including pursuant to subpoena under Rule XI (Procedures of Committees and Unfinished Business), in furtherance of the Committee's investigation into: (1) the deaths of nine individuals that occurred during August 2007 at the Crandall Canyon Mine (also known as the Genwal Mine) near Huntington, Utah; (2 ) the events that may have led to those deaths; (3) the administration of relevant laws by government agencies, including the Department of Labor and the Mine Safety and Health Administration; and (4) other related matters.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
