<bill session="110" type="hr" number="846" updated="2009-01-09T09:37:30-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1197003300" datetime="2007-12-06T12:55:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="1137"/></status>

	<introduced date="1196830800" datetime="2007-12-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for the consideration of the Senate amendments to the bill (H.R. 6) to reduce our Nation's dependency on foreign oil by investing in clean, renewable, and alternative energy resources, promoting new emerging energy technologies, developing greater efficiency, and creating a Strategic Energy Efficiency and Renewables Reserve to invest in alternative energy, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412239"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<calendar date="1196913120" datetime="2007-12-05T23:52:00-05:00" ><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 163.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1196913120" datetime="2007-12-05T23:52:00-05:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-474, by Mr. Welch (VT).</text></action>
		<action date="1196913120" datetime="2007-12-05T23:52:00-05:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 6.</text></action>
		<action date="1196950740" datetime="2007-12-06T10:19:00-05:00"><text>CONSIDERATION OF H. RES. 846 - By direction of the Committee on Rules, Mr. Welch called up H. Res. 846 and asked for its immediate consideration.</text></action>
		<action date="1196950740" datetime="2007-12-06T10:19:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Flake raised a point of order against the provisions of H. Res. 846 on the grounds that it allows for an unfunded mandate. Pursuant to the rule, the Chair announced that the threshold for identifying specific language related to an unfunded mandate had been met and that the question would be put on the consideration of the resolution. Subsequently, the House proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the question of consideration of H. Res. 846.</text></action>
		<action date="1196953560" datetime="2007-12-06T11:06:00-05:00"><text>On motion to consider the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 214 - 188 (Roll no. 1134).</text></action>
		<action date="1196954220" datetime="2007-12-06T11:17:00-05:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H14255-14259, H14260-14269"/></action>
		<action date="1196954220" datetime="2007-12-06T11:17:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 846.</text></action>
		<action date="1197002880" datetime="2007-12-06T12:48:00-05:00"><text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 216 - 192 (Roll no. 1136).</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H14768"/></action>
		<vote date="1197003300" how="roll" roll="1137" datetime="2007-12-06T12:55:00-05:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 218 - 195 (Roll no. 1137).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H14255-14256"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	12/6/2007--Passed House without amendment. Makes it in order to consider the Senate amendments to H.R. 6 (Renewable Fuels, Consumer Protection, and Energy Efficiency Act of 2007).<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
