<bill session="110" type="hr" number="860" updated="2009-01-09T09:39:15-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1197479940" datetime="2007-12-12T13:19:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1197349200" datetime="2007-12-11"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the conference report to accompany the bill (H.R. 1585) to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2008 for military activities of the Department of Defense, for military construction, and for defense activities of the Department of Energy, to prescribe military personnel strengths for such fiscal year, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412195"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1197419580" datetime="2007-12-11T20:33:00-05:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-488, by Ms. Castor.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1197419580" datetime="2007-12-11T20:33:00-05:00" ><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 167.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1197419580" datetime="2007-12-11T20:33:00-05:00"><text>Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to H.R. 1585.</text></action>
		<action date="1197469740" datetime="2007-12-12T10:29:00-05:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H15323-15327"/></action>
		<action date="1197469740" datetime="2007-12-12T10:29:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 860.</text></action>
		<action date="1197471660" datetime="2007-12-12T11:01:00-05:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H. Res. 860, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question, and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Hastings (WA) demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of ordering the previous question until later in the legislative day.</text></action>
		<action date="1197479460" datetime="2007-12-12T13:11:00-05:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H15339-15340"/></action>
		<action date="1197479940" datetime="2007-12-12T13:19:00-05:00"><text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 226 - 191 (Roll no. 1146).</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H15339"/></action>
		<vote date="1197479940" how="by voice vote" datetime="2007-12-12T13:19:00-05:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H15323"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	12/12/2007--Passed House without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Waives points of order against consideration of the conference report on H.R. 1585 (National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008).<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
