<bill session="110" type="hr" number="920" updated="2009-01-09T09:46:48-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1200373200" datetime="2008-01-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1200373200" datetime="2008-01-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Additional Earmark Disclosure Resolution</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to strengthen the earmark point of order.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400254"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1200373200" datetime="2008-01-15"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/15/2008--Introduced.<br/>Additional Earmark Disclosure Resolution - Amends rule XXI (Restrictions on Certain Bills) of the Rules of the House of Representatives to make it out of order to consider a conference report unless the accompanying joint explanatory statement includes: (1) a list of congressional earmarks, limited tax benefits, and limited tariff benefits (and the name of any requesting Member or Senator) that were not committed to the conference committee by either House, not in a report on such bill, or not in a report of a Senate committee on a companion measure; or (2) a statement that the proposition contains no congressional earmarks, limited tax benefits, or limited tariff benefits. Makes it out of order also to consider an amendment between the Houses to a bill or joint resolution unless the proponent has caused to be printed in the Congressional Record before its consideration or contained in a separate part of that amendment: (1) a list of congressional earmarks, limited tax benefits, and limited tariff benefits (and the name of any requesting Member or Senator) that were not in a report on such bill, not in the report of a Senate committee on a companion measure, or not in any earlier amendment between the Houses to such measure; or (2) a statement that the proposition contains no congressional earmarks, limited tax benefits, or limited tariff benefits.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
