<bill session="110" type="hr" number="926" updated="2009-01-09T09:47:33-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1200459600" datetime="2008-01-16"/></status>

	<introduced date="1200459600" datetime="2008-01-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Recognizing the importance of food, product safety, and U.S. trade policy.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412228"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1200459600" datetime="2008-01-16"><text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1200459600" datetime="2008-01-16"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1200459600" datetime="2008-01-16"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1200459600" datetime="2008-01-16"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text></action>
		<action date="1200459600" datetime="2008-01-16"><committee name="House Energy and Commerce"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text></action>
		<action date="1200459600" datetime="2008-01-16"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/16/2008--Introduced.<br/>Recognizes: (1) the relationship between free trade agreements and the increase of imports; (2) that adoption of additional trade agreements will likely significantly increase the number of products and food our nation imports; (3) that current U.S. trade policies must be improved to adequately ensure the safety of imported food and products; (4) the link between current U.S. trade policies and the increase in tainted imported food and unsafe products; (5) that the percentage of food imports currently inspected by the United States is inadequate and poses a risk to American families; and (6) the need to ensure the safety of imported food before additional trade agreements are ratified.<br/>Encourages: (1) federal agencies charged with keeping imported food safe to step up inspections; and (2) greater vigilance by federal agencies in ensuring imported products and food are safe.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
