<bill session="110" type="hr" number="979" updated="2009-01-09T09:54:23-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1202878800" datetime="2008-02-13"/></status>

	<introduced date="1202878800" datetime="2008-02-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Recommending that the House of Representatives find Harriet Miers and Joshua Bolten, Chief of Staff, White House, in contempt of Congress for refusal to comply with subpoenas duly issued by the Committee on the Judiciary.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400080"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1202878800" datetime="2008-02-13"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1202943960" datetime="2008-02-13T19:06:00-05:00"><text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 982 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 979 and H. Res. 980. Upon the adoption of H.Res. 982, H.Res. 979 and H.Res. 980 are hereby adopted.</text></action>
		<action date="1203013320" datetime="2008-02-14T14:22:00-05:00"><text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 982, H. Res. 979 is considered passed House.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H962"/><reference label="text as passed House" ref="CR H962"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/14/2008--Passed House without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Directs the Speaker of the House of Representatives to certify to the U.S. Attorney for the District of Columbia the report of the Committee on the Judiciary detailing the refusal of: (1) former White House Counsel Harriet Miers to appear or testify before, or to produce documents to, the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law; as directed by subpoena; and (2) White House Chief of Staff Joshua Bolten to produce documents, as also directed by subpoena. Provides that Ms. Miers and Mr. Bolten be proceeded against (for contempt of Congress).<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
