<bill session="110" type="hr" number="974" updated="2009-01-09T09:53:42-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1204047720" datetime="2008-02-26T13:42:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" how="roll" roll="74"/></status>

	<introduced date="1202792400" datetime="2008-02-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3521) to improve the Operating Fund for public housing of the Department of Housing and Urban Development.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412228"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1202861820" datetime="2008-02-12T20:17:00-05:00"><text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-524, by Ms. Sutton.</text></action>
		<action date="1202861820" datetime="2008-02-12T20:17:00-05:00"><text>It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Financial Services now printed in the bill. H. Res. 955 is laid upon the table.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1202861820" datetime="2008-02-12T20:17:00-05:00" ><text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 186.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1204086600" datetime="2008-02-26T12:30:00-05:00"><text>Considered as privileged matter.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H1037-1044"/></action>
		<action date="1204086600" datetime="2008-02-26T12:30:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 974.</text></action>
		<action date="1204045320" datetime="2008-02-26T13:02:00-05:00"><text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H. Res. 974, Mr. Hastings of Florida moved the previous question on adoption of the resolution and by voice vote, the Chair announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Sessions demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of ordering the previous question until later in the legislative day.</text></action>
		<action date="1204046880" datetime="2008-02-26T13:28:00-05:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H1044-1046"/></action>
		<action date="1204047300" datetime="2008-02-26T13:35:00-05:00"><text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 212 - 198 (Roll no. 73).</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H1044, H1044-1045"/></action>
		<vote date="1204047720" how="roll" roll="74" datetime="2008-02-26T13:42:00-05:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 218 - 190 (Roll no. 74).</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H1037"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/26/2008--Passed House without amendment. Sets forth the rule for consideration of H.R. 3521 (Public Housing Asset Management Improvement Act of 2007). 
	</summary>
</bill>
