<bill session="110" type="s" number="1002" updated="2009-01-09T13:51:15-05:00">
	<status><enacted date="1177300800" datetime="2007-04-23" /></status>

	<introduced date="1174968000" datetime="2007-03-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Older Americans Reauthorization Technical Corrections Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">Older Americans Reauthorization Technical Corrections Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="enacted">Older Americans Reauthorization Technical Corrections Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Older Americans Act of 1965 to reinstate certain provisions relating to the nutrition services incentive program.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300059"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300041" joined="2007-03-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300083" joined="2007-03-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<vote date="1174968000" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2007-03-27" where="s" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>Introduced in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S3983-3984"/><reference label="text as passed Senate" ref="CR S3984"/></vote>
		<action date="1175038620" datetime="2007-03-27T20:37:00-04:00"><text>Received in the House.</text></action>
		<action date="1174968000" datetime="2007-03-27"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<action date="1174968000" datetime="2007-03-27"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
		<action date="1175112720" datetime="2007-03-28T17:12:00-04:00"><text>Committee on Education and Labor discharged.</text></action>
		<action date="1175112780" datetime="2007-03-28T17:13:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Loebsack asked unanimous consent to discharge from committee and consider.</text></action>
		<action date="1175112780" datetime="2007-03-28T17:13:00-04:00"><text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H3236-3237"/></action>
		<vote date="1175112780" how="without objection" datetime="2007-03-28T17:13:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote2" result="pass" ><text>On passage Passed without objection.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H3236-3237"/></vote>
		<topresident date="1175054400" datetime="2007-03-28" ><text>Cleared for White House.</text></topresident>
		<topresident date="1176350400" datetime="2007-04-12" ><text>Presented to President.</text></topresident>
		<signed date="1177300800" datetime="2007-04-23" ><text>Signed by President.</text></signed>
		<enacted number="110-19" date="1177300800" datetime="2007-04-23" type="public" ><text>Became Public Law No: 110-19.</text></enacted>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/23/2007--Public Law. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Older Americans Reauthorization Technical Corrections Act - Amends the Older Americans Act of 1965 with respect to incentives for effective performance by states and tribal organizations in the efficient delivery of nutritious meals to older individuals. Repeals certain provisions regarding state agency and tribal grantee commodity purchases, as added by the Older Americans Act Amendments of 2006. Restores former commodity purchase provisions, with revisions. Entitles each state agency and tribal grantee to use its allotments to obtain from the Secretary of Agriculture commodities available through any food program of the Department of Agriculture (USDA) at the rates at which such commodities are valued for such program. (Currently, such purchases are not limited to commodities from USDA food programs, but may be any U.S. agricultural commodity and other foods.) Repeals the authority of a state agency or tribal grantee to opt to use part or all of the amounts it receives to pay a school food authority to obtain U.S. agricultural commodities for its nutrition projects. Prescribes requirements for Secretary of Agriculture determination of state agency and tribal grantee allotments. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Secretary of Agriculture to agree on reimbursement amounts and procedures.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
