<bill session="110" type="s" number="1007" updated="2009-01-09T13:51:57-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1222142400" datetime="2008-09-23" /></status>

	<introduced date="1175054400" datetime="2007-03-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">United States-Brazil Energy Cooperation Pact of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Western Hemisphere Energy Compact</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of State to work with the Government of Brazil and other foreign governments to develop partnerships that will strengthen diplomatic relations and energy security by accelerating the development of biofuels production, research, and infrastructure to alleviate poverty, create jobs, and increase income, while improving energy security and protecting the environment.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300070"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2008-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300050" joined="2008-09-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1175054400" datetime="2007-03-28"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4054)</text></action>
		<action date="1175054400" datetime="2007-03-28"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1222142400" datetime="2008-09-23" ><text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1222142400" datetime="2008-09-23"><text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Dodd with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="1044" date="1222142400" datetime="2008-09-23" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1044.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/28/2007--Introduced.<br/>United States-Brazil Energy Cooperation Pact of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of State to establish the Western Hemisphere Energy Cooperation Forum which should seek to: (1) strengthen relationships between the United States and other countries of the Western Hemisphere through cooperation on energy issues; and (2) enhance cooperation between major energy producers and major energy consumers in the Western Hemisphere, particularly among the governments of Brazil, Canada, Mexico, the United States, and Venezuela. Directs the U.S. government to seek to implement: (1) an energy crisis initiative that will promote national and regional measures to respond to temporary energy supply disruptions; (2) an energy sustainability initiative to facilitate long-term supply security by fostering reliable supply sources of fuels, including energy from biomass; and (3) an energy for development initiative to promote energy access for underdeveloped areas through energy policy and infrastructure development. Directs the Secretary of State to seek Western Hemisphere governments' cooperation in establishing a Western Hemisphere Energy Industry Group, which shall increase public-private partnerships and foster private investment. Directs the Secretary of Energy to facilitate the establishment of the Oil and Gas Working Group, which should strengthen oil- and natural gas-related dialogue among international oil companies, national oil companies, and civil society groups. Directs the Secretary of State to work with Brazil to coordinate efforts to promote the production and use of biofuels among all interested countries, giving preference to the countries in the Western Hemisphere that are among the poorest and most dependent on foreign sources of fuel (particularly oil). Directs: (1) the Secretary of Agriculture to work with Brazil in joint agricultural biofuel extension activities; and (2) the Secretary of Energy to establish a grant program to finance advanced biofuels research and collaboration between academic and research institutions in the United States and Brazil. Requires each partner country (as defined by this Act) to participate in a study to determine the feasibility of increasing biofuel production and use. Directs the Secretary of State to: (1) renew tax treaty negotiations with Brazil; (2) work with Western Hemisphere governments and other countries to organize regional and hemispheric carbon trading mechanisms; and (3) seek to establish a Western Hemisphere energy crisis response mechanism. Directs the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development to seek to increase U.S. foreign assistance programming in renewable energy, including activities to reduce energy import dependence through biofuel use. Authorizes the Administrator to award grants to nongovernmental organizations for sustainable energy and job creation projects in at-risk nations, such as Haiti. Directs: (1) the Secretary of Commerce to conduct ethanol and natural gas studies; and (2) the Secretary of Energy to seek to work with Mexico to conduct a technical analysis of the status of Mexican oil and gas production, future technological and investment needs, and recommendations for maintaining and increasing hydrocarbon production.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
