<bill session="110" type="s" number="1000" updated="2009-01-09T13:50:59-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1195016400" datetime="2007-11-14" /></status>

	<introduced date="1174968000" datetime="2007-03-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Telework Enhancement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Telework Enhancement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enhance the Federal Telework Program.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300094"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300098" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-11-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2007-03-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1174968000" datetime="2007-03-27"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3843-3844)</text></action>
		<action date="1174968000" datetime="2007-03-27"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S3844"/></action>
		<action date="1181102400" datetime="2007-06-06"><text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs referred to Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1195016400" datetime="2007-11-14" ><text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1222833600" datetime="2008-10-01"><text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="1101" date="1222833600" datetime="2008-10-01" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1101.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1227070800" datetime="2008-11-19"><text>By Senator Lieberman from Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs filed written report. Report No. 110-526.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/27/2007--Introduced.<br/>Telework Enhancement Act of 2007 - Requires the head of each executive agency, the Chief Justice, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and the Majority Leader of the Senate to: (1) establish a policy under which federal employees shall participate in telework to the maximum extent possible without diminishing employee performance or organizational operations; and (2) appoint a Telework Managing Officer.<br/>Exempts from the policy executive branch employees: (1) whose duties involve the daily handling of secure materials, necessary contact with special equipment, or a daily physical presence; (2) who are assigned to national security or intelligence functions; or (3) whose functions are otherwise inappropriate for teleworking and which are designated as functions to which the policy does not apply. Provides for the Speaker, the Majority Leader, and Chief Justice to designate ineligible legislative and judicial branch employees.<br/>Requires the head of each executive agency to ensure that: (1) telework training is incorporated in the agency's new employee orientation procedures; and (2) periodic employee reviews are conducted for all employees to ascertain whether telework is appropriate for the employee's job description and the extent to which it is being utilized by the employee.<br/>Requires the Comptroller General to: (1) establish a system for evaluating telework policies and participation; and (2) publish an annual report rating each entity's policy and participation.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
