<bill session="110" type="s" number="1011" updated="2009-01-09T13:52:27-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1182916800" datetime="2007-06-27" /></status>

	<introduced date="1175054400" datetime="2007-03-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Recognizing Addiction as a Disease Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to change the name of the National Institute on Drug Abuse to the National Institute on Diseases of Addiction and to change the name of the National Institute on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism to the National Institute on Alcohol Disorders and Health.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300008"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-03-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="2007-12-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300041" joined="2007-03-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="2007-06-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1175054400" datetime="2007-03-28"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4056)</text></action>
		<action date="1175054400" datetime="2007-03-28"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1182916800" datetime="2007-06-27" ><text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1185940800" datetime="2007-08-01"><text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Reported by Senator Kennedy with an amendment. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="294" date="1185940800" datetime="2007-08-01" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 294.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/28/2007--Introduced.<br/>Recognizing Addiction as a Disease Act of 2007 - Amends the Public Health Service Act and related enactments to redesignate: (1) the National Institute on Drug Abuse as the National Institute on Diseases of Addiction; and (2) the National Institute on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism as the National Institute on Alcohol Disorders and Health.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
