<bill session="110" type="s" number="1031" updated="2009-01-09T13:55:03-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/></status>

	<introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">School Food Fresh Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 to provide coordination and direction for commodity programs, and to ensure the distribution of fresh fruits and vegetables to schools and service institutions in the United States.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300022"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/29/2007--Introduced.<br/>School Food Fresh Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to establish in the office of the Under Secretary for Food, Nutrition, and Consumer Services a task force to coordinate commodity programs. Directs the Secretary to provide five (for each of five specified food categories) competitive grants to nonprofit research institutions to evaluate commodity program products to determine: (1) consistency with program nutritional goals; (2) product acceptability by recipient agencies and consumers; and (3) commercial counterpart comparability. Amends the the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 to direct the Secretary to: (1) enter into agreements with qualifying local and regional distributors to supply fruit and vegetable items to schools and service institutions; and (2) implement a vendor monitoring program. Directs that the Secretary: (1) to the maximum extent practicable, purchase for commodity programs foods that are in their least-processed state; and (2) upon the approval of national processing agreements, make available to all schools and other recipient agencies the opportunity to divert unprocessed or minimally-processed commodity foods to subsequent processors for end product conversion.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
