<bill session="110" type="s" number="1035" updated="2009-01-09T13:55:35-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/></status>

	<introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">H-1B and L-1 Visa Fraud and Abuse Prevention Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to reduce fraud and abuse in certain visa programs for aliens working temporarily in the United States.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300038"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300048" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-09-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S4169-4173"/></action>
		<action date="1179201600" datetime="2007-05-15"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6080-6081)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/29/2007--Introduced.<br/>H-1B and L-1 Visa Fraud and Abuse Prevention Act of 2007 - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to revise employer and government requirements with respect to H-1B (specialty occupation) and L-1 (intracompany transfer) nonimmigrant aliens.<br/>Revises H-1B provisions to: (1) subject all H-1B employers (currently H-1B dependent employers) to such provisions; (2) lengthen U.S. worker displacement protection; (3) authorize the Secretary of Labor to initiate an H-1B employer investigation; and (4) increase employer penalties.<br/>Sets forth employer petition requirements for an L-1 alien coming to the United States to open, or be employed in, a new facility.<br/>Prohibits blanket L-1 petitions.<br/>Authorizes the Secretary of Homeland Security to initiate an L-1 employer investigation.<br/>Sets forth L-1 employer penalty provisions.<br/>Provides H-1B and L-1 alien whistleblower protections.<br/>Authorizes the Secretary of Labor to hire 200 additional employees to administer H-1B programs.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
