<bill session="110" type="s" number="1037" updated="2009-01-09T13:55:50-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23" /></status>

	<introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Tumalo Water Conservation Project Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Tumalo Water Conservation Project Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to assist in the planning, design, and construction of the Tumalo Irrigation District Water Conservation Project in Deschutes County, Oregon.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300090"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="2007-03-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1177473600" datetime="2007-04-25"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-86.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. With written report No. 110-114.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="247" date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 247.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/28/2007--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)<br/>Tumalo Water Conservation Project Act of 2007 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior, in cooperation with the Tumalo Irrigation District, to participate in the planning, design, and construction of the Tumalo Irrigation District Water Conservation Project in Deschutes County, Oregon. Sets the federal share of the cost of the Project at 25%. Requires the District to pay Project operation and maintenance costs. Authorizes appropriations. Terminates the Secretary's authority to carry out this Act 10 years after its enactment. 
	</summary>
</bill>
