<bill session="110" type="s" number="1034" updated="2009-01-09T13:55:26-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/></status>

	<introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Investment to Strengthen our Economy Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Rural RISE Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to create investment opportunities for rural families and access to credit for rural entrepreneurs and microenterprises, to support rural regional investment, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300022"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/29/2007--Introduced.<br/>Rural Investment to Strengthen our Economy Act of 2007 or Rural RISE Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) allow a capital loss deduction with respect to the sale or exchange of a principal residence in certain rural areas; and (2) expand the work opportunity tax credit to include a qualified small business employee as a targeted group member. Authorizes the Secretary of Education to carry out a program for the forgiveness of student loans for certain rural students who obtain a degree. Amends the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to establish a: (1) rural entrepreneurship and microenterprise program; and (2) rural regional entrepreneurship program. Requires the Secretary of Labor to award grants to: (1) regional skill alliances (business consortia) serving certain rural areas to assist in the development of job skills necessary for employment in specific industries; and (2) states to assist businesses, organizations, and agencies representing such industries in conducting planning to form such alliances.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
