<bill session="110" type="s" number="1041" updated="2009-01-09T13:56:23-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/></status>

	<introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Employee Free Choice Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the National Labor Relations Act to establish an efficient system to enable employees to form, join, or assist labor organizations, to provide for mandatory injunctions for unfair labor practices during organizing efforts, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300059"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412242" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300005" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300082" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300008" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300061" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300019" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300016" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300081" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412249" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300037" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300001" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412243" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300078" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300006" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300026" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412244" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300084" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2007-03-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4174)</text></action>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S4175-4176"/></action>
		<action date="1182225600" datetime="2007-06-19"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S7842-7843)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/29/2007--Introduced.<br/>Employee Free Choice Act of 2007- Amends the National Labor Relations Act to require the National Labor Relations Board (NLRB) to certify a bargaining representative without directing an election if a majority of the bargaining unit employees have authorized designation of the representative (card-check) and there is no other individual or labor organization currently certified or recognized as the exclusive representative of any of the employees in the unit. Sets forth special procedural requirements for reaching an initial collective bargaining agreement following certification or recognition. Revises enforcement requirements with respect to unfair labor practices during union organizing drives, particularly a preliminary investigation of an alleged unfair labor practice (ULP) which may lead to proceedings for injunctive relief. Requires that priority be given to a preliminary investigation of any charge that, while employees were seeking representation by a labor organization, or during the period after a labor organization was recognized as a representative until the first collective bargaining contract is entered into, an employer: (1) discharged or otherwise discriminated against an employee to encourage or discourage membership in the labor organization; (2) threatened to discharge or to otherwise discriminate against an employee in order to interfere with, restrain, or coerce employees in the exercise of guaranteed self-organization or collective bardaining rights; or (3) engaged in any other related ULP that significantly interferes with, restrains, or coerces employees in the exercise of such guaranteed rights. Adds to remedies for such violations: (1) back pay plus liquidated damages; and (2) additional civil penalties.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
