<bill session="110" type="s" number="1044" updated="2009-01-09T13:56:47-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/></status>

	<introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Effective Care for the Armed Forces and Veterans Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the medical care of members of the Armed Forces and veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300008"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4177-4178)</text></action>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S4178-4179"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/29/2007--Introduced.<br/>Effective Care for the Armed Forces and Veterans Act of 2007 - Prohibits the Secretary of Defense, during a period of a U.S. major military conflict, from: (1) subjecting work performed by an employee of a Department of Defense (DOD) medical facility or an employee of a private contractor of such facility to public-private competition; or (2) converting such employee or the work performed to private contractor performance. Allows an exception to prevent a negative impact on the provision of services. Requires a study by the Comptroller General on competitive outsourcing activities at DOD medical facilities. Provides: (1) a minimum budget for DOD medical services during periods of major military conflicts; and (2) a limitation on the implementation of a recommendation for the closure of Walter Reed Army Medical Center. Requires the Secretary to: (1) assign at least one case manager for every 20 recovering servicemembers; (2) screen every servicemember returning from deployment in Operations Iraqi Freedom or Enduring Freedom for traumatic brain injury (requiring two related studies); and (3) require DOD medical records management systems to communicate with such systems of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA). Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to assess the VA's ability to meet the long-term care needs of veterans over the next 50 years.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
