<bill session="110" type="s" number="1045" updated="2009-01-09T13:56:57-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/></status>

	<introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Workforce Performance Appraisal and Management Improvement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to strengthen performance management in the Federal Government, to make the annual general pay increase for Federal employees contingent on performance, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300098"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4179-4180)</text></action>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1181102400" datetime="2007-06-06"><text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs referred to Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/29/2007--Introduced.<br/>Federal Workforce Performance Appraisal and Management Improvement Act of 2007 - Revises provisions relating to the establishment of performance appraisal systems by certain federal agencies. Requires agencies to establish one or more new performance appraisal systems to promote high performance. Revises provisions relating to the responsibilities of the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) for the development of performance appraisal systems. Revises provisions relating to specific mandatory training programs for supervisors. Revises provisions relating to federal employee pay rates and systems with respect to employees whose performance rating is below the fully successful level to, among other things, prohibit a pay increase for such employees.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
