<bill session="110" type="s" number="1042" updated="2009-01-09T13:56:32-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13" /></status>

	<introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Consistency, Accuracy, Responsibility, and Excellence in Medical Imaging and Radiation Therapy Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to make the provision of technical services for medical imaging examinations and radiation therapy treatments safer, more accurate, and less costly.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300041"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412242" joined="2007-05-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300029" joined="2008-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2007-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300008" joined="2007-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="412251" joined="2008-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300052" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300037" joined="2007-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="2007-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300007" joined="2007-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300035" joined="2008-06-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400432" joined="2008-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300014" joined="2007-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300050" joined="2007-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300036" joined="2007-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300021" joined="2008-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400054" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300069" joined="2007-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300026" joined="2007-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400194" joined="2007-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2007-05-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13" ><text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/29/2007--Introduced.<br/>Consistency, Accuracy, Responsibility, and Excellence in Medical Imaging and Radiation Therapy Act of 2007 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish standards to ensure the safety and accuracy of medical imaging studies and radiation therapy treatments. Imposes such standards on personnel who perform, plan, or evaluate, or verify patient doses for, medical imaging studies and radiation therapy procedures and not on the equipment used. Exempts physicians, nurse practitioners, and physician assistants. Directs the Secretary to ensure that individuals demonstrate compliance with such standards. Requires the Secretary to provide a method for the recognition of individuals whose training and experience are determined to equal or exceed that of: (1) a graduate of an accredited educational program in that specialty; or (2) an individual who is regularly eligible to take the licensure or certification examination for that discipline. Directs the Secretary to certify qualified nonprofit organizations as approved bodies to provide accreditation to individuals that demonstrate compliance with such standards. Requires individuals who provide medical imaging services relating to mammograms to continue to meet standards under the Mammography Quality Standards Act of 1992. Deems state standards for licensure or certification of personnel, accreditation of educational programs, or administration of examinations to be in compliance with the standards under this Act unless the Secretary determines otherwise. Requires the Secretary to establish a process by which a state may appeal such a determination. Requires the Secretary to ensure that all programs under the authority of the Secretary meet such standards. Authorizes the Secretary to develop alternative standards for rural areas or health professional shortage areas as appropriate to assure access to quality medical imaging.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
