<bill session="110" type="s" number="1055" updated="2009-01-09T13:58:15-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/></status>

	<introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">American Automobile Industry Promotion Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote the future of the American automobile industry, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300008"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300019" joined="2007-04-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4187)</text></action>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S4187-4188"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/29/2007--Introduced.<br/>American Automobile Industry Promotion Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of Energy to: (1) offer to enter into an arrangement with the National Academy of Sciences to assess state-of-the-art battery technologies with potential application for electric drive transportation; (2) conduct a program of research, development, demonstration, and commercial application for electric drive transportation technology (i.e., vehicles that use electric motors for all or part of the motive power); and (3) establish and carry out an Advanced Battery Initiative to support research, development, demonstration, and commercial application of battery technologies in on-road or nonroad vehicles.<br/>Amends the Internal Revenue Code to redefine the new advanced lean burn technology motor vehicle credit for high-efficiency diesel passenger automobiles and light trucks to eliminate requirements that such motor vehicles for 2004 and later model years receive a certificate stating they meet or exceed certain weight and emission standards.<br/>Amends the Clean Air Act to: (1) define &quot;biodiesel&quot; and &quot;biodiesel blend&quot;; and (2) require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to promulgate regulations to establish standards for each biodiesel blend.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
