<bill session="110" type="s" number="1060" updated="2009-01-09T13:58:53-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02" /></status>

	<introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Recidivism Reduction and Second Chance Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Second Chance Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reauthorize the grant program for reentry of offenders into the community in the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968, to improve reentry planning and implementation, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300008"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2007-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2007-06-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="2007-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-04-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300052" joined="2007-07-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-05-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400619" joined="2007-06-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300092" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300013" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-07-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300016" joined="2007-10-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2007-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300081" joined="2007-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="412249" joined="2007-09-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="2007-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-06-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2007-10-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300006" joined="2007-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2007-07-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4191)</text></action>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S4191-4203"/></action>
		<calendar date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02" ><text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/29/2007--Introduced.<br/>Recidivism Reduction and Second Chance Act of 2007 or the Second Chance Act of 2007 - Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to reauthorize, rewrite, and expand provisions for adult and juvenile offender state and local reentry demonstration projects to provide expanded services to offenders and their families for reentry into society.<br/>Directs the Attorney General to award grants for: (1) state and local reentry courts; (2) Comprehensive and Continuous Offender Reentry Task Forces; (3) pharmacological drug treatment services to incarcerated offenders; (4) technology career training for offenders; and (5) mentoring services for reintegrating offenders into the community.<br/>Amends the Higher Education Amendments of 1998 to require the Secretary of Education to establish a program for education and employment counseling for youth offenders.<br/>Authorizes the Attorney General to award grants for: (1) the establishment of a National Adult and Juvenile Offender Reentry Resource Center; (2) drug treatment programs as an alternative to imprisonment; (3) evaluation of methods to improve academic and vocational education for incarcerated offenders; (4) demonstration programs to reduce the use of alcohol and other drugs in long-term substance abusers; (5) incentive grants to improve drug treatment to offenders in prisons, jails, and juvenile facilities; (6) pharmacological drug treatment services to incarcerated offenders; (7) prison-based family treatment programs for incarcerated parents of minor children; and (8) a study of parole or post-incarceration supervision violations and revocations.<br/>Requires the Director of the Bureau of Prisons to establish: (1) a prisoner reentry program; and (2) a pilot program for the release of elderly nonviolent offenders (age 60 or older).<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
