<bill session="110" type="s" number="1065" updated="2009-01-09T13:59:33-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/></status>

	<introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Heroes at Home Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the diagnosis and treatment of traumatic brain injury in members and former members of the Armed Forces, to review and expand telehealth and telemental health programs of the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300022"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412242" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2007-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400619" joined="2007-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2007-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300084" joined="2007-04-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4204-4207)</text></action>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/29/2007--Introduced.<br/>Heroes at Home Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of Defense to establish a protocol for the assessment and documentation of the cognitive (including memory) functioning of each member of the Armed Forces deployed in Operations Enduring Freedom or Iraqi Freedom before such deployment in order to facilitate their cognitive functioning upon their return. Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish a program on training and certification of family caregivers of veterans and members with traumatic brain injury. Authorizes such Secretaries to jointly: (1) establish a demonstration project to assess the feasibility and advisability of using telehealth technology to assess cognitive functioning of members who have sustained head trauma in order to improve their diagnosis and treatment; and (2) conduct an ongoing study of all matters relating to the telehealth and telemental health services of the Departments of Defense and Veterans Affairs, respectively.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
