<bill session="110" type="s" number="1072" updated="2009-01-09T14:00:29-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/></status>

	<introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Agency Environmental Responsibility Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require Federal agencies to conduct their environmental, transportation, and energy-related activities in support of their respective missions in an environmentally, economically, and fiscally sound manner, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300094"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4210)</text></action>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/29/2007--Introduced.<br/>Federal Agency Environmental Responsibility Act - Declares that it is U.S. policy that federal agencies conduct their environmental, transportation, and energy-related activities in an environmentally, economically, and fiscally sound, integrated, continuously improving, efficient, and sustainable manner.<br/>Sets forth requirements for agency heads concerning: (1) energy efficiency and reduction in greenhouse gas emissions; (2) renewable energy sources and energy generation projects; (3) reduction in water consumption intensity; (4) sustainable environmental practices and management systems; (5) toxic and hazardous materials and cost-effective waste prevention and recycling programs; (6) fuel consumption; and (7) the acquisition and disposal of electronic products.<br/>Requires the Chairman of the Council on Environmental Quality to establish a Steering Committee on Strengthening Federal Environmental, Energy, and Transportation Management to advise the Chairman and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) on performance of their functions under this Act. Establishes within the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) a Federal Environmental Office to advise the Council on agency activities and a presidential leadership award program.<br/>Provides for exemption authority.<br/>Sets forth requirements for federal agency purchases of a commercially available, off-the-shelf product that uses an external standby power device or that contains an internal standby power function. Requires the Secretary of Energy to maintain a list of products subject to such requirements and a list of products that meet the requirements.<br/>Limits public utility contracts for renewable energy to 20 years.<br/>Exempts specified project costs for energy-efficient technologies from requirements concerning a project's estimated maximum costs.<br/>Requires the Administrator of the General Services Administration (GSA): (1) to implement a program to use energy-efficient light bulbs in federal buildings to replace low efficiency bulbs as they burn out; and (2) and the Secretary of Energy and the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) to work with industry to develop consensus national standards for energy-efficient light bulb disposal and with manufacturers and importers of energy-efficient bulbs to develop standards for labeling bulbs containing mercury or other toxic substances.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
