<bill session="110" type="s" number="1073" updated="2009-01-09T14:00:38-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/></status>

	<introduced date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Clean Fuels and Vehicles Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Clean Air Act to promote the use of fuels with low lifecycle greenhouse gas emissions, to establish a greenhouse gas performance standard for motor vehicle fuels, to require a significant decrease in greenhouse gas emissions from motor vehicles, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300043"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-03-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4210-4211)</text></action>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S4211-4212"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/29/2007--Introduced.<br/>Clean Fuels and Vehicles Act of 2007 - Amends the Clean Air Act to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to: (1) establish a process for determining the lifecycle greenhouse gas (GHG) emissions of a fuel; and (2) determine the average quantity of lifecycle GHG emissions per unit of energy delivered to a motor vehicle, or the fuel emission baseline.<br/>Requires the Administrator to include in regulations procedures by which the Administrator shall: (1) determine the lifecycle GHG emissions of a fuel and the fuel emissions baseline; (2) make such determinations and related information available to consumers; (3) label fuels with low lifecycle GHG emissions; and (4) provide information about adverse impacts of the fuel on land use and land cover, water, soil, and air quality, and public health.<br/>Directs the Administrator to: (1) establish a credit trading program to address the lifecycle GHG emissions from fuels available for use in motor vehicles; and (2) require each major oil company, refiner, or fuel importer that produces or sells fuels available for use in motor vehicles to reduce the average lifecycle GHG emissions per unit of energy delivered to a motor vehicle through fuel to specified levels. Permits a provider of a fuel that achieves a greater than required reduction in lifecycle GHG emissions to generate credits.<br/>Directs the Administrator to: (1) determine the average quantity of GHG emissions per mile for new vehicles; and (2) require each automobile manufacturer to reduce the average quantity of GHG emissions per vehicle mile of the aggregate quantity and variety of automobiles to specified levels.<br/>Redefines the term &quot;alternative fueled automobile&quot; to mean an automobile that is a dedicated, dual fueled, or optimized dual fueled automobile. Specifies a formula the Administrator shall use to measure the fuel economy for any model of dual fueled automobile manufactured in model years 2001-2015.<br/>Extends through model years up to 2015 the maximum increase in average fuel economy for a manufacturer attributable to dual fueled automobiles of 1.2 miles a gallon.<br/>Requires the Secretary of Transportation to: (1) require each manufacturer of alternative fuel vehicles that run on fuels with low lifecycle GHG emissions to install a green fuel cap on such vehicles; and (2) prohibit a manufacturer from installing a green cap on an automobile that does not run on such fuel.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
