<bill session="110" type="s" number="1081" updated="2009-01-09T14:01:43-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1176177600" datetime="2007-04-10"/></status>

	<introduced date="1176177600" datetime="2007-04-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Flat Tax Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to impose a flat tax only on individual taxable earned income and business taxable income, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300092"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1176177600" datetime="2007-04-10"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4294)</text></action>
		<action date="1176177600" datetime="2007-04-10"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/10/2007--Introduced.<br/>Flat Tax Act of 2007 - Replaces the income tax with a flat tax of 20 percent of taxable earned income of individual taxpayers. Defines &quot;taxable earned income&quot; as the excess of earned income (wages, salaries, professional fees) over a standard deduction, a deduction for cash charitable contributions, and a deduction for home mortgage interest. Sets forth definitions and special rules for surviving spouses, heads of household, and dependents.<br/>Imposes a flat tax of 20 percent on business taxable income. Defines &quot;business taxable income&quot; as gross active income (other than investment income) reduced by: (1) the cost of business inputs (cost of specified goods, services, travel, and entertainment expenditures); (2) employee compensation; and (3) the cost of personal and real property used in business activities. Disallows a deduction from gross active business income for purchases of goods and services provided to employees or owners and certain lobbying and political expenditures.<br/>Repeals: (1) estate, gift, and generation-skipping transfer taxes; (2) financing of presidential election campaigns provisions; and (3) coal industry health benefits provisions.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
