<bill session="110" type="s" number="1089" updated="2009-01-09T14:02:51-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1185336000" datetime="2007-07-25" /></status>

	<introduced date="1176264000" datetime="2007-04-11"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Alaska Natural Gas Pipeline Act to allow the Federal Coordinator for Alaska Natural Gas Transportation Projects to hire employees more efficiently, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300075"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="2007-04-11"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1176264000" datetime="2007-04-11"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4382-4383)</text></action>
		<action date="1176264000" datetime="2007-04-11"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1179806400" datetime="2007-05-22"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Energy. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-112.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1185336000" datetime="2007-07-25" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1190001600" datetime="2007-09-17"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 110-178.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="376" date="1190001600" datetime="2007-09-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 376.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/17/2007--Reported to Senate amended. Amends the Alaska Natural Gas Pipeline Act and the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 to authorize the Federal Coordinator for Alaska Natural Gas Transportation Projects to: (1) appoint and terminate personnel as determined appropriate, without regard to the requirements of federal civil service code, especially those governing appointments in the competitive service; and (2) procure temporary and intermittent services. Grants the Federal Coordinator the authority provided to the Secretary of the Interior to establish, change, and abolish reasonable filing and service fees, charges, and commissions, require deposits of payments, and provide refunds, but only with respect to the Coordinator's duties. Declares that such payment and refund authority does not affect the Secretary's authority to establish, change, and abolish reasonable filing and service fees, charges, and commissions, require deposits of payments, and provide refunds under the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976. Authorizes the Federal Coordinator to use amounts collected under such authority without further appropriation. Grants the U.S. Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit original and exclusive jurisdiction to determine the validity of any determination, permit, approval, authorization, review, or other related action taken under federal law relating to an Alaska natural gas transportation project.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
