<bill session="110" type="s" number="1096" updated="2009-01-09T14:03:47-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1176350400" datetime="2007-04-12"/></status>

	<introduced date="1176350400" datetime="2007-04-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans' Housing Benefits Enhancement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to provide certain housing benefits to disabled members of the Armed Forces, to expand certain benefits for disabled veterans with severe burns, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300027"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300029" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400621" joined="2007-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300054" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300014" joined="2007-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300001" joined="2007-04-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1176350400" datetime="2007-04-12"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4440-4441)</text></action>
		<action date="1176350400" datetime="2007-04-12"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/12/2007--Introduced.<br/>Veterans' Housing Benefits Enhancement Act of 2007 - Authorizes the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, in the case of a member of the Armed Forces determined to have a total disability permanent in nature which was incurred or aggravated in the line of active duty, to furnish home improvements and structural alterations for the member for the disability while the member is hospitalized or receiving outpatient care, medical services, or treatment, if the Secretary determines that the member is likely to be discharged or released from the Armed Forces for such disability. Authorizes the provision of specially adapted housing assistance for: (1) disabled veterans whose disability is due to a severe burn injury; and (2) disabled members residing temporarily in housing owned by a family member. Makes veterans and members with a severe burn disability eligible for automobile and automotive adaptive equipment assistance.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
