<bill session="110" type="s" number="1108" updated="2009-01-09T14:05:18-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1176350400" datetime="2007-04-12"/></status>

	<introduced date="1176350400" datetime="2007-04-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Part D Outreach and Enrollment Enhancement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide a special enrollment period for individuals who qualify for an income-related subsidy under the Medicare prescription drug program and to provide funding for the conduct of outreach and education with respect to the premium and cost-sharing subsidies under such program, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300090"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300061" joined="2008-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300068" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-11-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-04-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1176350400" datetime="2007-04-12"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4448-4450)</text></action>
		<action date="1176350400" datetime="2007-04-12"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S450-4451"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/12/2007--Introduced.<br/>Medicare Part D Outreach and Enrollment Enhancement Act of 2007 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to provide a special 90-day enrollment period for individuals who qualify for an income-related subsidy under the Medicare prescription drug program under part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program), with waiver of any late enrollment fee. Makes appropriations to the National Center on Senior Benefits Outreach and Enrollment to provide outreach and enrollment assistance with respect to premium and cost-sharing subsidies under the drug program. Requires the Commissioner of Social Security, when conducting Medicare eligibility screening, to screen also for an individual's eligibility for medical assistance under SSA title XIX (Medicaid) for any Medicare cost-sharing, and, if the results are positive, report the pertinent information to the appropriate state Medicaid agency for the individual's eligibility determination and enrollment for Medicare cost-sharing under the state plan. Directs the Assistant Secretary of the Administration on Aging to study and report to Congress on screening processes used by government needs-based programs.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
