<bill session="110" type="s" number="1105" updated="2009-01-09T14:04:54-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1176350400" datetime="2007-04-12"/></status>

	<introduced date="1176350400" datetime="2007-04-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Matthew Shepard Local Law Enforcement Hate Crimes Prevention Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide Federal assistance to States, local jurisdictions, and Indian tribes to prosecute hate crimes, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300059"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412242" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300008" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400619" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300092" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300068" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300081" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412249" joined="2007-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300077" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300001" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412243" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300078" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300006" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300084" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300090" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="2007-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2007-04-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1176350400" datetime="2007-04-12"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4445-4447)</text></action>
		<action date="1176350400" datetime="2007-04-12"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1190692800" datetime="2007-09-25"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S12026-12027)</text></action>
		<action date="1190779200" datetime="2007-09-26"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S12087-12089)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/12/2007--Introduced.<br/>Matthew Shepard Local Law Enforcement Hate Crimes Prevention Act of 2007 - Authorizes the Attorney General to provide technical, forensic, prosecutorial, or other assistance in the criminal investigation or prosecution of any crime that: (1) constitutes a crime of violence under federal law or a felony under state, local, or Indian tribal laws; and (2) is motivated by prejudice based on the actual or perceived race, color, religion, national origin, gender, sexual orientation, gender identity, or disability of the victim or is a violation of state, local, or tribal hate crime laws. Directs the Attorney General to give priority for such assistance: (1) with respect to crimes committed by offenders who have committed crimes in more than one state; and (2) to rural jurisdictions that have difficulty covering the extraordinary investigation or prosecution expenses. Authorizes the Attorney General to award grants to assist state, local, and Indian law enforcement agencies with such extraordinary expenses.<br/>Directs the Office of Justice Programs to: (1) work closely with funded jurisdictions to ensure that the concerns and needs of all affected parties are addressed; and (2) award grants to state, local or tribal programs designed to combat hate crimes committed by juveniles. Amends the federal criminal code to impose criminal penalties for causing (or attempting to cause) bodily injury to any person using fire, a firearm, or any explosive or incendiary device because of the actual or perceived race, color, religion, national origin, gender, sexual orientation, gender identity, or disability of such person. Amends the Hate Crimes Statistics Act to require Attorney General to: (1) acquire data on crimes that manifest evidence of prejudice based on gender and gender identity; and (2) include in an annual summary of such data crimes committed by, and against, juveniles.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
