<bill session="110" type="s" number="1102" updated="2009-01-09T14:04:31-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1176350400" datetime="2007-04-12"/></status>

	<introduced date="1176350400" datetime="2007-04-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Part D Equity for Low-Income Seniors Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to expedite the application and eligibility process for low-income subsidies under the Medicare prescription drug program and to revise the resource standards used to determine eligibility for an income-related subsidy, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300009"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2008-05-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2008-05-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300061" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300068" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-11-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300090" joined="2007-04-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1176350400" datetime="2007-04-12"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4442-4444)</text></action>
		<action date="1176350400" datetime="2007-04-12"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S4444-4445"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/12/2007--Introduced.<br/>Part D Equity for Low-Income Seniors Act of 2007 - Amends part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to direct the Commissioner of Social Security to provide for an expedited process for the qualification for low-income assistance through a request to the Secretary of the Treasury for tax return and other information. Increases the alternative resource standard for determination of eligibility for a low-income subsidy for 2008, indexed for inflation for succeeding years. Requires indexing of deductibles and cost-sharing above the annual out-of-pocket threshold for individuals with income below 150% of the poverty line.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
