<bill session="110" type="s" number="1118" updated="2009-01-09T14:06:35-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1176696000" datetime="2007-04-16"/></status>

	<introduced date="1176696000" datetime="2007-04-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Fuel Efficiency Energy Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the energy security of the United States by raising average fuel economy standards, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300037"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300029" joined="2007-04-16"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1176696000" datetime="2007-04-16"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4507)</text></action>
		<action date="1176696000" datetime="2007-04-16"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text></action>
		<action date="1181620800" datetime="2007-06-12"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S7508-7511)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/16/2007--Introduced.<br/>Fuel Efficiency Energy Act of 2007 - Amends corporate average fuel economy (CAFE) provisions to revise the definition of: (1) &quot;automobile&quot; to mean any vehicle that is propelled by fuel, or by alternative fuel, and is manufactured primarily for use on public streets, roads, and highways (currently, four-wheeled vehicles that are so propelled and manufactured for such use and that are up to 6,000 pounds and certain vehicles between 6,000 and 10,000 pounds); and (2) &quot;passenger automobile&quot; to eliminate the exception for 4-wheel drive automobiles and vehicles weighing more than 6,000 pounds. Defines &quot;medium-duty truck&quot; as a truck with a gross vehicle weight between 10,000 and 26,000 pounds. Requires the Secretary of Transportation to: (1) prescribe separate increased minimum CAFE standards for different classes of automobiles manufactured beginning for model year 2012, but adds an increase of 4% per year in such standard for model years 2013 through 2030; and (2) establish CAFE standards for medium-duty trucks that are consistent with hybridization beginning for model year 2012. Revises the calculation of fuel economy standards for dual fueled automobiles and gaseous fuel dual fueled automobiles manufactured in model year 2012 and beyond to require using the same calculation provisions as used for gas or diesel fueled vehicles. Repeals provisions allowing the Department of Transportation (DOT) to extend manufacturing credits for such automobiles.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
