<bill session="110" type="s" number="1115" updated="2009-01-09T14:06:12-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1176696000" datetime="2007-04-16"/></status>

	<introduced date="1176696000" datetime="2007-04-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Energy Efficiency Promotion Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">United States Energy Storage Competitiveness Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote the efficient use of oil, natural gas, and electricity, reduce oil consumption, and heighten energy efficiency standards for consumer products and industrial equipment, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300009"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412242" joined="2007-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300029" joined="2007-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300070" joined="2007-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400619" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300037" joined="2007-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300001" joined="2007-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300075" joined="2007-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300036" joined="2007-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-04-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1176696000" datetime="2007-04-16"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4494-4495)</text></action>
		<action date="1176696000" datetime="2007-04-16"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S4495-4505"/></action>
		<action date="1177300800" datetime="2007-04-23"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 110-85.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/16/2007--Introduced.<br/>Energy Efficiency Promotion Act of 2007 - Amends the National Energy Conservation Policy Act with respect to advanced lighting technologies. Amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act with respect to the expediting of new energy efficiency standards. Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 with respect to high efficiency vehicles, advanced batteries, and energy storage. United States Energy Storage Competitiveness Act of 2007 - Instructs the Secretary of Energy to: (1) implement a research, development, and demonstration program to support the ability of the United States to remain globally competitive in energy storage systems for motor transportation and electricity transmission and distribution; and (2) establish an Energy Storage Advisory Council. Instructs the Secretary to develop a strategic plan to achieve specified national goals to reduce gasoline usage. Amends the National Energy Conservation Policy Act, the Energy Conservation and Production Act, and the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act with respect to: (1) federal fleet conservation requirements; (2) requirements for federal purchase of renewable energy-generated electricity; (3) energy savings performance contracts; (4) energy management requirements for federal buildings; (5) combined heat and power and district energy installations at federal sites; (6) federal building energy efficiency performance standards; and (7) application of the International Energy Conservation Code to public and assisted housing. Amends the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 with respect to utility energy efficiency programs. Instructs the Secretary to: (1) provide technical assistance regarding implementation of the energy efficiency and demand response programs to state energy offices, public utility regulatory commissions, and nonregulated utilities; and (2) award grants to institutions of higher education to implement projects to improve energy efficiency on institution grounds. Declares that Congress encourages each local educational agency receiving certain federal funds to develop a policy to reduce the incidence of school bus idling.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
