<bill session="110" type="s" number="1156" updated="2009-01-09T14:11:33-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1176868800" datetime="2007-04-18"/></status>

	<introduced date="1176868800" datetime="2007-04-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Best Pharmaceuticals for Children Amendments of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to reauthorize the Best Pharmaceuticals for Children program.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300034"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2007-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300081" joined="2007-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="2007-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-04-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1176868800" datetime="2007-04-18"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4694-4695)</text></action>
		<action date="1176868800" datetime="2007-04-18"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S4695-4699"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/18/2007--Introduced.<br/>Best Pharmaceuticals for Children Amendments of 2007 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to make changes to provisions in regard to market exclusivity for pediatric drug studies on new drugs or already approved drugs, including to: (1) require that appropriate labeling changes are timely made; and (2) prohibit the Secretary of Health and Human Services from extending the period of market exclusivity later than nine months prior to the expiration of such period.<br/>Requires an applicant or holder who does not agree with a request to conduct pediatric studies to submit to the Secretary the reasons such pediatric formulation cannot be developed. Directs the Secretary to: (1) publish a notice identifying any drug for which a pediatric formulation was developed, studied, and found to be safe and effective that is not introduced onto the market within one year; and (2) create an internal review committee to review all written requests issued and all reports submitted. Reduces market exclusivity for pediatric studies from six months to three months for drugs for which combined annual gross sales exceed $1 billion.<br/>Requires the Secretary to order the labeling of a drug to include information about the result of a pediatric study whether such study does or does not demonstrate that the drug is safe and effective.<br/>Requires the Comptroller General to submit a report to Congress that addresses the effectiveness of providing market exclusivity for pediatric studies in ensuring that medicines used by children are tested and properly labeled.<br/>Includes pediatric pharmacological research within the pediatric research loan repayment program.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
