<bill session="110" type="s" number="1160" updated="2009-01-09T14:12:04-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1176955200" datetime="2007-04-19"/></status>

	<introduced date="1176955200" datetime="2007-04-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Specialty Crops Competition Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure an abundant and affordable supply of highly nutritious fruits, vegetables, and other specialty crops for American consumers and international markets by enhancing the competitiveness of United States-grown specialty crops.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300093"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="2007-09-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300029" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300030" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400619" joined="2007-04-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2007-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300092" joined="2007-07-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300019" joined="2007-10-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300078" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300036" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400054" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400194" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300090" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2007-09-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1176955200" datetime="2007-04-19"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4754)</text></action>
		<action date="1176955200" datetime="2007-04-19"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/19/2007--Introduced.<br/>Specialty Crops Competition Act of 2007 - Defines &quot;specialty crop&quot; as fruits, vegetables, tree nuts, dried fruits, nursery crops, floriculture, and horticulture. Amends the Agricultural Adjustment Act to provide for marketing order specialty crop food safety programs. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to: (1) carry out fruit and vegetable market news activities; (2) make grants to states to enhance specialty crop competitiveness; (3) prepare a foreign market access strategy plan; (4) establish in the Department of Agriculture an office for the protection of intellectual property rights in plants and plant-derived materials; (5) make grants for market analysis of antidumping and countervailing duty cases; (6) establish a program of specialty crop research and grants; (7) establish an invasive pest threat identification and mitigation program; (8) establish the national clean plant network to provide diagnostic and pathogen elimination services; (9) establish the nutrition education program review committee; (10) carry out an integrated pest management initiative; and (11) carry out a specialty crop census every five years. Amends the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to obligate funds for specialty crop operating loans. Amends the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 to: (1) increase and extend specialty crop technical assistance; (2) make nursery tree growers eligible for tree program assistance; (3) provide for increased fruit, vegetable, and specialty crop purchases; and (4) remove the income limitation from the environmental quality incentives program. Amends the Agricultural Risk Protection Act of 2000 to increase and extend funding for value-added agricultural market development grants. Revises specified plant patent provisions. Amends the Plant Protection Act to revise compensation provisions. Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to restore import and entry agricultural inspection functions to the Department of Agriculture. Establishes the international agricultural inspection program within the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service (APHIS). Amends the Specialty Crops Competitiveness Act of 2004 to direct the Secretary to provide emergency assistance to specialty crop producers who suffer qualifying losses in disaster-designated counties. Amends the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to expand the fresh fruit and vegetable program. Amends the Food Stamp Act of 1977 to include food stamp nutrition education (as defined by this Act) within the scope of the food stamp program. Establishes a food stamp fruit and vegetable electronic benefit transfer pilot program. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) make transportation infrastructure grants to eligible state and local governments, shippers, and specialty crop producers; and (2) carry out food safety initiatives. Establishes in the Department an Office of Pest Management Policy. Amends the Housing Act of 1949 to provide loans and grants for housing farm laborers admitted for temporary residence (H-2A visas).<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
