<bill session="110" type="s" number="1163" updated="2009-01-09T14:12:26-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1182916800" datetime="2007-06-27" /></status>

	<introduced date="1176955200" datetime="2007-04-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Blinded Veterans Paired Organ Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Blinded Veterans Paired Organ Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to improve compensation and specially adapted housing for veterans in certain cases of impairment of vision involving both eyes, and to provide for the use of the National Directory of New Hires for income verification purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300001"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="412249" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300050" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-06-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400194" joined="2007-04-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1176955200" datetime="2007-04-19"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4755-4756)</text></action>
		<action date="1176955200" datetime="2007-04-19"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1182916800" datetime="2007-06-27" ><text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Reported by Senator Akaka with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 110-143.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="328" date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 328.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1193976000" datetime="2007-11-02"><text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S13735-13736"/><reference label="text of measure as reported in Senate" ref="CR S13735-13736"/></action>
		<action date="1193976000" datetime="2007-11-02"><text>The committee substitute agreed to by Unanimous Consent.</text></action>
		<action date="1193976000" datetime="2007-11-02"><text>Measure read the third time by Unanimous Consent.</text></action>
		<action date="1193976000" datetime="2007-11-02"><text>Senate incorporated this measure in H.R. 797 as an amendment.</text></action>
		<action date="1193976000" datetime="2007-11-02"><text>Senate passed companion measure H.R. 797 in lieu of this measure by Unanimous Consent.</text></action>
		<action date="1193976000" datetime="2007-11-02"><text>Returned to the Calendar. Calendar No. 328.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S13736"/></action>
		<action date="1193976000" datetime="2007-11-02"><text>See also H.R. 797.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/3/2007--Reported to Senate amended. Blinded Veterans Paired Organ Act of 2007 - Title I: Low-Vision Benefits Matters - (Sec. 101) Modifies the rate of service-connected total blindness in veterans required for the payment of veterans' disability compensation to a visual acuity of 20/200 (currently, 5/200) or less. (Sec. 102) Modifies the standard for awarding disability compensation to veterans for loss of vision to require payment of compensation for impairment of vision (under current law, blindness) involving both eyes due to a service-connected or non-service-connected disability. Defines such impairment as a visual acuity of 20/200 or less or of a peripheral field of vision of 20 degrees or less. (Sec. 103) Requires the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (Secretary) to furnish to the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) information on veterans under the age of 65 for comparison with information on such individuals in the National Directory of New Hires to determine eligibility for certain veterans' health care, compensation, and retirement benefits. Requires the Secretary to notify such veterans that the information is being furnished for such purposes. Authorizes the Secretary to terminate, deny, suspend, or reduce any benefit or service by reason of information obtained from the HHS Secretary only if the Secretary independently verifies the information received. Requires the Secretary to allow an adversely affected individual an opportunity to contest such findings. Terminates, on September 30, 2012, the authority to obtain comparison information from the HHS Secretary. Title II: Burial and Memorial Affairs Matters - (Sec. 201) Authorizes the Secretary, upon request, to furnish in lieu of a headstone or marker a medallion or other device to signify a deceased's status as a veteran to be affixed to a headstone or marker purchased at private expense. (Sec. 202) States that, as of October 1, 2006, a specified federal regulation requiring a state or other political entity to apply to the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) for reimbursement of a veteran's interment costs within two years after the permanent burial cremation of the body shall have no force and effect as it pertains to unclaimed remains of a deceased veteran. Allows grants to states for establishing, expanding, or improving veterans' cemeteries to also be used for operating and maintaining such cemeteries. Limits to $5 million the aggregate amount of grants awarded in a fiscal year for such purposes. (Sec. 203) Repeals the December 31, 2007, termination date of the authority of the Secretary to furnish a government headstone or marker for the grave of certain veterans buried in private cemeteries, notwithstanding that the grave is marked by a headstone or marker furnished at private expense.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
