<bill session="110" type="s" number="1182" updated="2009-01-09T14:14:56-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1185336000" datetime="2007-07-25" /></status>

	<introduced date="1177041600" datetime="2007-04-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Quinebaug and Shetucket Rivers Valley National Heritage Corridor Amendments Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Quinebaug and Shetucket Rivers Valley National Heritage Corridor Amendments Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Quinebaug and Shetucket Rivers Valley National Heritage Corridor Act of 1994 to increase the authorization of appropriations and modify the date on which the authority of the Secretary of the Interior terminates under the Act.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300034"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-04-20"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1177041600" datetime="2007-04-20"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4815)</text></action>
		<action date="1177041600" datetime="2007-04-20"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1184212800" datetime="2007-07-12"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1185336000" datetime="2007-07-25" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1190001600" datetime="2007-09-17"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 110-159.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="357" date="1190001600" datetime="2007-09-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 357.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/17/2007--Reported to Senate amended. Quinebaug and Shetucket Rivers Valley National Heritage Corridor Amendments Act of 2007 - Amends the Quinebaug and Shetucket Rivers Valley National Heritage Corridor Act of 1994 to extend the authority of the Secretary of the Interior to make grants or provide any assistance under the Act for the Quinebaug and Shetucket Rivers Valley National Heritage Corridor to September 30, 2015. Requires the Secretary to conduct an evaluation of the accomplishments of the Corridor by no later than three years before the date on which the authority for federal funding terminates for the Corridor, and based upon the evaluation, to prepare and submit to specified congressional committees a report that includes recommendations for the future role of the National Park Service (NPS), if any, with respect to the Corridor. Increases the total amount that may be appropriated for the Corridor. 
	</summary>
</bill>
