<bill session="110" type="s" number="1204" updated="2009-01-09T14:17:49-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1177473600" datetime="2007-04-25"/></status>

	<introduced date="1177473600" datetime="2007-04-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Shaken Baby Syndrome Prevention Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enhance Federal efforts focused on public awareness and education about the risks and dangers associated with Shaken Baby Syndrome.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300034"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300070" joined="2008-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2007-06-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="2007-05-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-12-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300006" joined="2008-06-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2008-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2007-09-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1177473600" datetime="2007-04-25"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5088)</text></action>
		<action date="1177473600" datetime="2007-04-25"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/25/2007--Introduced.<br/>Shaken Baby Syndrome Prevention Act of 2007 - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through various federal agencies, to develop a national Shaken Baby Syndrome public health campaign. Requires the Secretary to: (1) develop a National Action Plan and effective strategies to increase awareness of opportunities to prevent Shaken Baby Syndrome; and (2) coordinate the Plan and strategies with evidence-based strategies and efforts that support families with infants and other young children. Directs the Secretary to carry out communication, education, and training about Shaken Baby Syndrome prevention, including efforts to communicate with the general public, such as by: (1) disseminating effective prevention practices and techniques to parents and caregivers; (2) producing evidence-based educational and information materials; and (3) carrying out Shaken Baby Syndrome training.<br/>Requires the Secretary to work to ensure that the parents and caregivers of children are connected to effective supports through the coordination of existing programs and networks or the establishment of new programs, including a 24-hour phone hotline and the development of an Internet website for round-the-clock support.<br/>Establishes a Shaken Baby Awareness Advisory Council to develop recommendations: (1) regarding the National Action Plan and effective strategies; and (2) related to support services for families and caregivers of young children.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
