<bill session="110" type="s" number="1219" updated="2009-01-09T14:19:46-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1177473600" datetime="2007-04-25"/></status>

	<introduced date="1177473600" datetime="2007-04-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Taxpayer Protection and Assistance Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide taxpayer protection and assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300009"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-04-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-04-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2007-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300080" joined="2007-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300001" joined="2007-04-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-04-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300090" joined="2007-04-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1177473600" datetime="2007-04-25"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5101-5102)</text></action>
		<action date="1177473600" datetime="2007-04-25"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S5102-5105"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/25/2007--Introduced.<br/>Taxpayer Protection and Assistance Act of 2007 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to authorize the Secretary of the Treasury to: (1) make grants for tax return preparation clinics for low-income taxpayers; (2) allow enrolled agents licensed to practice before the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) to use designation of &quot;EA&quot; or &quot;E.A.&quot;; (3) regulate and test paid income tax preparers; (4) contract for the development or administration of examinations for paid income tax preparers; (5) require the registration of refund anticipation loan facilitators; and (6) award demonstration project grants to assist low-income taxpayers without bank accounts to obtain such accounts with federally-insured depository institutions.<br/>Establishes in the IRS the Office of Professional Responsibility to administer the regulation of paid income tax preparers. Requires such Office to make public any sanctions imposed on such preparers.<br/>Requires refund anticipation loan facilitators to make specified disclosures to taxpayers about refund loan transactions.<br/>Grants the National Taxpayer Advocate authority to issue taxpayer assistance orders in cases involving closing agreements and compromises.<br/>Grants the Secretary authority to consider all facts and circumstances involving a taxpayer in evaluating an offer in compromise of tax liability.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
