<bill session="110" type="s" number="1216" updated="2009-01-09T14:19:24-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1177473600" datetime="2007-04-25"/></status>

	<introduced date="1177473600" datetime="2007-04-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Laser Visa Extension Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to allow certain nationals of Mexico entering the State of New Mexico on a temporary basis to travel up to 100 miles from the international border between the State of New Mexico and Mexico, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300036"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2007-04-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1177473600" datetime="2007-04-25"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5101)</text></action>
		<action date="1177473600" datetime="2007-04-25"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S5101"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/25/2007--Introduced.<br/>Laser Visa Extension Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to permit a national of Mexico to travel up to 100 miles from the international border between Mexico and New Mexico if such national: (1) possesses a valid machine-readable biometric border crossing identification card issued by a Department of State consular officer; (2) enters New Mexico through a port of entry where such card is processed using a machine reader; (3) has successfully completed any required background check; and (4) is admitted into the United States as a nonimmigrant tourist or business visitor. Authorizes the Secretary to limit the travel of an otherwise qualifying national of Mexico to less than 100 miles from the Mexico-New Mexico border if such national was previously admitted into the United States as a nonimmigrant and violated the terms and conditions of such status. 
	</summary>
</bill>
