<bill session="110" type="s" number="1218" updated="2009-01-09T14:19:39-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1177473600" datetime="2007-04-25"/></status>

	<introduced date="1177473600" datetime="2007-04-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare for All Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide quality, affordable health care for all Americans.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300059"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1177473600" datetime="2007-04-25"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/25/2007--Introduced.<br/>Medicare for All Act - Amends the Social Security Act to add a new title XXII (Medicare for All) under which: (1) each eligible individual is entitled to benefits which include the full range and scope of benefits available under the original fee-for-service program under parts A (Hospital Insurance) and B (Supplementary Medical Insurance) of title XVIII (Medicare), with parity in coverage of mental health benefits, subject to appropriate cost sharing; (2) each enrollee is free to choose his or her own doctor and private health plan; and (3) benefits are similar to or no less than the health benefits coverage under FEHBP (Federal Employees Health Benefits Program). Establishes the Medicare for All Trust Fund. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose: (1) on the income of every enrolled individual a tax equal to 1.7% of wages received in excess of $25,000; (2) on every employer an excise tax equal to 7% of the wages paid to each enrolled employee; and (3) on the self-employment income of every enrolled individual, a tax equal to the applicable percentage of the self-employment income for such taxable year in excess of $25,000. Sets forth provisions governing application of this Act to collective bargaining agreements.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
