<bill session="110" type="s" number="1221" updated="2009-01-09T14:20:02-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1177473600" datetime="2007-04-25"/></status>

	<introduced date="1177473600" datetime="2007-04-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Countdown to Coverage Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the enactment of comprehensive health care reform.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300060"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1177473600" datetime="2007-04-25"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5105)</text></action>
		<action date="1177473600" datetime="2007-04-25"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S5105-5106"/></action>
		<action date="1181102400" datetime="2007-06-06"><text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs referred to Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/25/2007--Introduced.<br/>Countdown to Coverage Act of 2007 - Provides that if legislation ensuring accessible, affordable, and meaningful health insurance for all Americans is not enacted before the adjournment sine die of the 111th Congress: (1) federal contributions under the Federal Employees Health Benefits (FEHB) Program for Members of Congress shall be prohibited; and (2) Members shall pay 100% of all premiums for such Programs. Requires the Institute of Medicine to notify the Office of Personnel Management (OPM), the Secretary of the Senate, and the Chief Administrative Officer (CAO) of the House of Representatives: (1) that such legislation has not been enacted, if it has not been; and (2) the dates and adjustments required to take effect under this Act. Requires, upon receipt of such notice, OPM, the Secretary, and the CAO to make such adjustments.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
