<bill session="110" type="s" number="1225" updated="2009-01-09T14:20:35-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1177560000" datetime="2007-04-26"/></status>

	<introduced date="1177560000" datetime="2007-04-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Immigrant Accountability Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a process for aliens who meet certain conditions to be granted permanent resident status.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300050"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1177560000" datetime="2007-04-26"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/26/2007--Introduced.<br/>Immigrant Accountability Act of 2007 - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act establish a points-based process for qualifying aliens unlawfully in the United States as of January 7, 2004, to be granted permanent resident status. Provides that a qualifying alien applicant: (1) who has passed security and criminal checks shall be issued a conditional resident orange card under which the alien shall be granted employment authorization pending final permanent resident status adjudication; and (2) with an orange card who has earned at least 65% of the base points under this Act shall have his or her status adjusted to permanent resident. Requires an alien adjusting to permanent resident status to: (1) satisfy physical presence and admissibility requirements; (2) pay appropriate fees, fines, and taxes; (3) demonstrate basic citizenship skills; and (4) register for selective service if otherwise required. (States that an alien may be required to undergo a medical examination.) Sets forth the following base point categories: (1) U.S. employment; (2) U.S. presence; (3) education; (4) family relations; (5) English language ability; and (6) contributions to society. Sets forth provisions respecting: (1) status adjustment for spouses and children; (2) grounds of inadmissibility; (3) confidentiality of information; (4) penalties for false application information; (5) public benefits; and (6) removal. Makes orange card holders eligible for Army or Air Force enlistment.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
