<bill session="110" type="s" number="1231" updated="2009-01-09T14:21:20-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1177560000" datetime="2007-04-26"/></status>

	<introduced date="1177560000" datetime="2007-04-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Preparing, Recruiting, and Retaining Education Professionals Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend part A of title II of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to enhance teacher training and teacher preparation programs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300081"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1177560000" datetime="2007-04-26"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5202)</text></action>
		<action date="1177560000" datetime="2007-04-26"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S5202-5209"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/26/2007--Introduced.<br/>Preparing, Recruiting, and Retaining Education Professionals Act of 2007 - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 (HEA) to reauthorize and revise title II part A requirements for teacher quality enhancement grants for states and partnerships (II-A). Revises state grant, partnership grant, and recruitment grant requirements to include requirements relating to: (1) early childhood education; (2) exemplary, highly competent, and highly qualified teachers as these are defined under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965; (3) teacher mentoring; (4) professional development; (5) parental involvement; and (6) high-need schools and local educational agencies. Revises requirements for peer review panel grant evaluation and for teacher preparation program accountability.<br/>Requires states to submit teacher quality plans. Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award grants to institutions of higher education that are II-A partner institutions to create Academies for Faculty Excellence.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
