<bill session="110" type="s" number="1235" updated="2009-01-09T14:21:53-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1177560000" datetime="2007-04-26"/></status>

	<introduced date="1177560000" datetime="2007-04-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Daniel Faulkner Law Enforcement Officers and Judges Protection Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to impose appropriate penalties for the assault or murder of a Federal law enforcement officer or Federal judge, for the retaliatory assault or murder of a family member of a Federal law enforcement officer or Federal judge, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300027"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300035" joined="2008-09-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1177560000" datetime="2007-04-26"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/26/2007--Introduced.<br/>Daniel Faulkner Law Enforcement Officers and Judges Protection Act of 2007 - Amends the federal criminal code to: (1) impose mandatory minimum prison terms for homicide, manslaughter, and kidnapping of federal judges and law enforcement officers; (2) expand the penalties for assaulting or interfering with federal officers and employees and for assaults against federal law enforcement officers and judges; (3) impose mandatory minimum prison terms for retaliating against a federal judge or law enforcement officer on account of the performance of official duties by murdering, kidnapping, assaulting, or threatening a family member of such judge or officer; and (4) authorize federal judges, U.S. attorneys, and Justice Department employees to carry firearms.<br/>Places limits on the award of civil damages and attorney's fees against judicial officers for injuries incurred by an individual during the commission of a felony or crime of violence.<br/>Amends the federal judicial code to place limits on habeas corpus petitions for review of a state court conviction for murder of a public safety officer or judge engaged in the performance of official duties.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
