<bill session="110" type="s" number="1247" updated="2009-01-09T14:23:27-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1201669200" datetime="2008-01-30" /></status>

	<introduced date="1177560000" datetime="2007-04-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Weir Farm National Historic Site Amendment Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Weir Farm National Historic Site Establishment Act of 1990 to limit the development of any property acquired by the Secretary of the Interior for the development of visitor and administrative facilities for the Weir Farm National Historic Site, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300067"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-09-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1177560000" datetime="2007-04-26"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1189483200" datetime="2007-09-11"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-213.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1201669200" datetime="2008-01-30" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1207800000" datetime="2008-04-10"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 110-289.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="641" date="1207800000" datetime="2008-04-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 641.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/26/2007--Introduced.<br/>Weir Farm National Historic Site Amendment Act - Amends the Weir Farm National Historic Site Establishment Act of 1990 to: (1) require that property acquired for the development of visitor and administrative facilities for the Weir Farm National Historic Site in Connecticut be located in Fairfield county, Connecticut; (2) limit the development of any such property acquired in order to ensure that any property acquired for the development of such facilities conforms to the natural and undeveloped landscape of the property; (3) state that such limitation shall neither prohibit acquiring any property for the development of such facilities which, on the date of acquisition, is developed in a manner that does not conform to the natural and undeveloped landscape nor require any action to ensure that the acquired property conforms to the natural and undeveloped landscape of the property; and (4) require, prior to and as a prerequisite to any development of visitor and administrative facilities on the acquired property, one or more agreements with the local governmental entity that has jurisdiction over any property acquired for the development of such facilities.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
