<bill session="110" type="s" number="1269" updated="2009-01-09T14:26:26-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1178078400" datetime="2007-05-02"/></status>

	<introduced date="1178078400" datetime="2007-05-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">ENFORCE Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Engaging the Nation to Fight for Our Right to Control Entry Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Fairness in Immigration Litigation Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve border security in the United States and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300055"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1178078400" datetime="2007-05-02"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5505-5507)</text></action>
		<action date="1178078400" datetime="2007-05-02"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/2/2007--Introduced.<br/>Engaging the Nation to Fight for Our Right to Control Entry Act or ENFORCE Act - Directs the Commissioner of the United States Customs and Border Protection (USCBP) to establish: (1) a National Border Neighborhood Watch Program (Program) to permit retired law enforcement officers and civilian volunteers to assist in carrying out such Program; and (2) a Border Regiment Assisting in Valuable Enforcement Force (BRAVE Force), which shall consist of retired law enforcement officers, employed to carry out the Program. Directs USCBP to provide for civilian participation. Imposes criminal penalties for federal document forgery, counterfeiting, or alteration. Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act (INA) to provide additional penalties for an alien who is illegally in the United States. Increases criminal penalties for first-time illegal entry. Provides for a field office of the Office of Investigations of United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement in Tulsa, Oklahoma. Authorizes assistance to Cameron University, Lawton, Oklahoma, for a demonstration project to assess the feasibility of establishing a nationwide e-learning training course to be used by state, local, and tribal law enforcement officers to enhance the ability of such officers to assist federal immigration officers in the enforcement of immigration laws of the United States. Citizenship Reform Act of 2007 - Provides citizenship at birth for a person born in the United States and subject to the jurisdiction of the United States only if such child was born in the United States to parents, one of whom is: (1) a U.S. national; or (2) a lawful permanent resident alien residing in the United States. Prohibits any federal agency from establishing an individual's identity, and prohibits providing any public benefits funded in whole or in part by federal funds, without specified documents. Requires independent verification of birth records provided in support of a social security application. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to: (1) work with states to establish a common data protocol for electronic birth and death registration systems; and (2) coordinate implementation of electronic verification of a person's life and death. Provides for: (1) temporary social security cards for nonimmigrants; and (2) mandatory employer and subsequent employee notification of social security number mismatches and multiple uses. States that state and local law enforcement personnel have the inherent authority to arrest, detain, or transfer to federal custody, aliens in the United States (including detention transportation across state lines) in the enforcement of the immigration laws. Provides for individual taxpayer identification number (TIN) sharing between the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) and the Department of Homeland Security (DHS). Provides for fencing and security improvements along the southern U.S. border from the Pacific Ocean to the Gulf of Mexico, including creation and control of a specified border zone. Requires a study and report on the use of technology to prevent unlawful immigration. Makes it unlawful to operate a day laborer center if the operator knows, or should know, that the center is being used to secure employment for illegal aliens. Makes it unlawful under INA to hire or refer an alien for employment knowing, or having reason to know, that the alien is unauthorized for employment. Limits higher education benefits for illegal aliens. Fairness in Immigration Litigation Act of 2007 - Revises specified immigration litigation provisions.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
