<bill session="110" type="s" number="1263" updated="2009-01-09T14:25:39-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1178078400" datetime="2007-05-02"/></status>

	<introduced date="1178078400" datetime="2007-05-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Petroleum Consumer Price Gouging Protection Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect the welfare of consumers by prohibiting price gouging with respect to gasoline and petroleum distillates during natural disasters and abnormal market disruptions, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300018"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="2007-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300008" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2007-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300081" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300037" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412243" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300078" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300084" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2007-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300090" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2007-05-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1178078400" datetime="2007-05-02"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/2/2007--Introduced.<br/>Petroleum Consumer Price Gouging Protection Act - Declares it unlawful for a supplier to sell crude oil, gasoline, or petroleum distillates at an unconscionably excessive price in an area the President declares an energy emergency area. States it is unlawful for any person to employ, in connection with the wholesale purchase or sale of crude oil, gasoline, or petroleum distillates, any manipulative or deceptive device or contrivance in contravention of Federal Trade Commission (FTC) rules. States it is unlawful for any person to report information to the FTC related to the wholesale price of crude oil, gasoline, or petroleum distillates if the person: (1) knows, or reasonably should know, the information to be false or misleading; and (2) intends the false or misleading data to affect market data compiled by the FTC for statistical or analytical purposes. Authorizes the President to declare a federal energy emergency if the well-being of U.S. citizens is at risk because of a shortage or imminent shortage of adequate supplies of crude oil, gasoline, or petroleum distillates because of: (1) a disruption in the national distribution system; or (2) significant pricing anomalies in the national energy markets for such products. Empowers the FTC and state attorneys general to enforce this Act.<br/>Declares that this Act does not preempt state law.<br/>Sets forth civil and criminal penalties for violations of this Act.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
