<bill session="110" type="s" number="126" updated="2009-01-09T11:23:28-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23" /></status>

	<introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Mesa Verde National Park Boundary Expansion Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Mesa Verde National Park Boundary Expansion Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to modify the boundary of Mesa Verde National Park, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300003"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400619" joined="2007-01-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S126)</text></action>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-73.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment. With written report No. 110-93.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="223" date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 223.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/26/2007--Reported to Senate amended. Mesa Verde National Park Boundary Expansion Act of 2007 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to acquire specified land adjacent to the Mesa Verde National Park in Colorado or an interest in such land for addition to the Park. Revises the boundary of the Park to reflect the acquisition of such land. Requires the Secretary to administer any land or interest in land acquired under this Act as part of the Park. Authorizes appropriations. 
	</summary>
</bill>
