<bill session="110" type="s" number="127" updated="2009-01-09T11:23:35-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1201669200" datetime="2008-01-30" /></status>

	<introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Great Sand Dunes National Park and Preserve Act of 2000 to explain the purpose and provide for the administration of the Baca National Wildlife Refuge.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300003"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400619" joined="2007-01-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S126)</text></action>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1189483200" datetime="2007-09-11"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-213.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1201669200" datetime="2008-01-30" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1207800000" datetime="2008-04-10"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment. With written report No. 110-284.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="636" date="1207800000" datetime="2008-04-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 636.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/4/2007--Introduced.<br/>Amends the Great Sand Dunes National Park and Preserve Act of 2000 to provide that the purpose of the Baca National Wildlife Refuge shall be to restore, enhance, and maintain wetland, upland, riparian, and other habitats for native wildlife, plant, and fish species in the San Luis Valley. Instructs the Secretary of the Interior, in administering the Refuge, to: (1) emphasize migratory bird conservation; and (2) take into consideration the role of the Refuge in broader landscape conservation efforts. Provides for the Secretary, in administering water resources for the Refuge, to use decreed water rights on the Refuge in approximately the same manner that the water rights have been used historically. 
	</summary>
</bill>
