<bill session="110" type="s" number="1288" updated="2009-01-09T14:28:50-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"/></status>

	<introduced date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Women's Retirement Security Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to increase the retirement security of women and small business owners, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300090"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2007-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300026" joined="2007-05-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5580)</text></action>
		<action date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/3/2007--Introduced.<br/>Women's Retirement Security Act of 2007 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) require certain small employers who do not provide retirement plans for their employees to allow eligible employees to participate in a payroll deposit individual retirement account arrangement (automatic IRA); (2) expand eligibility for the tax credit for retirement savings contributions (saver's credit) and make such credit refundable; (3) allow certain part-time employees to participate in qualified cash or deferred arrangements; (4) allow the transfer of up to $500 of unused health plan benefits to qualified retirement plans; (5) treat wage replacement income (e.g., disability pay or unemployment compensation) as earned income for purposes of IRA contribution limits; (6) allow a limited tax exclusion for certain lifetime annuity payments and for qualified retirement planning services; (7) allow certain small employers a tax credit for contributions to employee pension plans; and (8) allow self-employed individuals to deduct pension plan contributions from their self-employment income.<br/>Sets forth special rules for: (1) preservation of retirement plan assets distributed under a qualified domestic relations order; (2) eligibility of surviving and divorced spouses for benefits under the Railroad Retirement Act; and (3) military retired pay subject to court orders in domestic relations proceedings. Authorizes the Secretary of the Treasury to make grants to qualified low-income taxpayer clinics to provide retirement savings counseling to low-income taxpayers.<br/>Requires the Commissioner of Social Security to prepare a financial reference handbook and a retirement readiness checklist for distribution to social security recipients.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
