<bill session="110" type="s" number="1283" updated="2009-01-09T14:28:11-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"/></status>

	<introduced date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Wounded Warrior Assistance Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to improve the management of medical care, personnel actions, and quality of life issues for members of the Armed Forces who are receiving medical care in an outpatient status, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300080"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300068" joined="2007-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300021" joined="2007-05-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5570-5571)</text></action>
		<action date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/3/2007--Introduced.<br/>Wounded Warrior Assistance Act of 2007 - Requires a member of the Armed Forces (member) in an outpatient status at a military medical treatment facility (facility) to be assigned a medical care case manager and a service member advocate, each of whom have completed a training program and curriculum for such management. Directs the Secretary of Defense to establish a: (1) Department of Defense (DOD)-wide Ombudsman Office; (2) toll-free hotline for reporting deficiencies in medical services and medical support facilities; (3) standardized training program and curriculum for military personnel and health care professionals involved in the disability evaluation system; and (4) pilot program to track and assist outpatient members who are still in need of medical treatment. Requires the Secretary of the military department concerned to: (1) notify appropriate Members of Congress of the hospitalization of members evacuated from a theater of combat; and (2) ensure that members appearing before medical evaluation boards have access to an independent medical advocate. Requires reports concerning: (1) enhanced training for individuals providing assistance to recovering members; (2) the adequacy and quality of medical and medical-support facilities at each military installation; and (3) traumatic brain injury classifications. Directs the Secretary to: (1) provide a process for the transition of members from the DOD health care and disability systems to those of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA); (2) allow reserve members to use facilities closest to home for the treatment of injuries sustained in a combat theater of operations; (3) develop a plan and conduct research for reducing post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) in combat veterans; (4) study the provision of support services for families of recovering members; (5) evaluate the Polytrauma Liaison Officer/Non-Commissioned Officer program; (6) study waiting periods for appointments at VA facilities; and (7) study the development of a joint soldier tracking system for recovering members. Establishes the: (1) Department of Defense Medical Support Fund; and (2) Oversight Board for Wounded Warriors.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
