<bill session="110" type="s" number="1305" updated="2009-01-09T14:31:02-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1178251200" datetime="2007-05-04" /></status>

	<introduced date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Support Our Troops Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill making emergency war appropriations for American troops overseas, without unnecessary pork barrel spending and without mandating surrender or retreat in Iraq, for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2007, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400576"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400105" joined="2007-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300041" joined="2007-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300062" joined="2007-05-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"><text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1178251200" datetime="2007-05-04" ><text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 133.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/3/2007--Introduced.<br/>Support Our Troops Act of 2007 - Makes emergency appropriations for FY2007 for the Global War on Terror, including for: (1) the Department of Agriculture for the Foreign Agricultural Service; and (2) the Department of Justice for salaries and expenses, the U.S. Marshals Service, the National Security Division, the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI), the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives, and the Federal Prison System. Makes emergency appropriations for the Department of Defense (DOD) for: (1) military personnel; (2) operation and maintenance; (3) the Afghanistan Security Forces Fund; (4) the Iraq Security Forces Fund; (5) the Iraq Freedom Fund; (6) the Joint Improvised Explosive Device Defeat Fund; (7) procurement; (8) research, development, test and evaluation; (9) revolving and management funds; (10) the Defense Health Program; (11) defense drug interdiction and counter-drug activities; and (12) the Intelligence Community Management Account. Makes emergency appropriations for: (1) the Department of Energy (DOE) for defense nuclear nonproliferation; (2) DOD for military construction; (3) diplomatic and consular programs; (4) the Office of Inspector General; (5) educational and cultural exchange programs; (6) international peacekeeping activities; (7) international broadcasting operations; (8) the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) for the Child Survival and Health Programs Fund; (9) international disaster and famine assistance; and (10) the Economic Support Fund. Makes emergency appropriations for the Department of State for: (1) assistance for Eastern Europe and the Baltic states; (2) international narcotics and law enforcement; (3) migration and refugee assistance; (4) the United States Emergency Refugee and Migration Assistance Fund; and (5) nonproliferation, anti-terrorism, demining, and related programs. Makes emergency appropriations for: (1) the Department of the Treasury for international affairs technical assistance; (2) the Foreign Military Financing Program; (3) peacekeeping operations; and (3) the Department of Defense Base Closure Account, 2005.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
