<bill session="110" type="s" number="1321" updated="2009-01-09T14:33:01-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1178510400" datetime="2007-05-07" /></status>

	<introduced date="1178510400" datetime="2007-05-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Energy Savings Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Biofuels for Energy Security and Transportation Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Carbon Capture and Sequestration Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Energy Efficiency Promotion Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">United States Energy Storage Competitiveness Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">An original bill to enhance the energy security of the United States by promoting biofuels, energy efficiency, and carbon capture and storage, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300009"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<calendar date="1178510400" datetime="2007-05-07" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources ordered to be reported an original measure.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1178510400" datetime="2007-05-07"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Bingaman. With written report No. 110-65.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="140" date="1178510400" datetime="2007-05-07" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 140.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/7/2007--Introduced.<br/>Energy Savings Act of 2007 - Biofuels for Energy Security and Transportation Act of 2007 - Sets forth a schedule for motor vehicle fuel, home heating oil, and boiler fuel to contain specified volumes of renewable fuel by calendar year 2022.<br/>Prescribes a pilot program to establish refueling infrastructure corridors for gasoline blends containing renewable fuel.<br/>Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to: (1) increase funding for bioenergy research and development; (2) establish bioresearch centers that target biofuels; and (3) authorize loan guarantees for renewable fuel facilities.<br/>Establishes a grants program for: (1) renewable fuel production in states with low rates of ethanol production; and (2) transportation of biomass to local biorefineries.<br/>Directs the Secretary of Energy to establish a biorefinery information center.<br/>Amends the Energy Policy Act of 1992 to direct the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to impose a fuel tank cap labeling requirement for alternative fueled vehicles.<br/>Requires studies on specified renewable fuels and biofuels.<br/>Energy Efficiency Promotion Act of 2007 - Amends the National Energy Conservation Policy Act regarding advanced lighting technologies.<br/>Amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to prescribe new energy efficiency standards.<br/>Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 with respect to high efficiency vehicles, advanced batteries, and energy storage.<br/>United States Energy Storage Competitiveness Act of 2007 - Instructs the Secretary of Energy to: (1) implement a research and development program for energy storage systems for motor transportation and electricity transmission and distribution; and (2) establish an Energy Storage Advisory Council.<br/>Sets forth national goals for: (1) energy savings in transportation; and (2) national energy efficiency improvement.<br/>Amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act regarding federal fleet conservation requirements. Prescribes requirements for implementation of energy efficiency and renewable energy initiatives with respect to federal facilities. Extends programs assisting state and local governments with energy efficiency programs.<br/>Amends the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 regarding utility energy efficiency programs.<br/>Provides: (1) technical assistance to governmental entities for energy efficiency and demand response programs, including an energy and environmental block grant; and (2) energy efficiency grants to institutions of higher education.<br/>Carbon Capture and Sequestration Act of 2007 - Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to establish a carbon capture and storage research and demonstration program.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
