<bill session="110" type="s" number="1335" updated="2009-01-09T14:34:48-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1178596800" datetime="2007-05-08"/></status>

	<introduced date="1178596800" datetime="2007-05-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">S.I. Hayakawa Official English Language Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 4, United States Code, to declare English as the official language of the Government of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300055"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400105" joined="2008-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300088" joined="2008-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300041" joined="2007-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400576" joined="2008-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300035" joined="2008-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300014" joined="2007-05-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300021" joined="2007-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400054" joined="2007-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400194" joined="2007-10-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1178596800" datetime="2007-05-08"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5735-5736)</text></action>
		<action date="1178596800" datetime="2007-05-08"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/8/2007--Introduced.<br/>S.I. Hayakawa Official English Language Act of 2007 - Makes English the official language of the U.S. government. Requires the government to: (1) conduct its official activities in English, including preparing publications, income tax forms, and informational materials in English; and (2) preserve and enhance the role of English as the official language of the United States. Provides that no person has a right, entitlement, or claim to have the government act, communicate, perform, or provide services or materials in any other language, unless expressly provided for in an applicable provision of law. Provides that this Act may not: (1) apply to the use of a language other than English for religious purposes, for training in foreign languages for international communication, or in school programs designed to encourage students to learn foreign languages; or (2) be considered to prevent the U.S. government from providing interpreters for persons over age 62. Repeals provisions of the Voting Rights Act of 1965 regarding bilingual election requirements and regarding congressional findings of voting discrimination against language minorities, prohibition of English-only elections, and other remedial measures. Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to require that all public ceremonies in which the oath of allegiance is administered pursuant to such Act be conducted solely in English. Specifies that this Act may not be construed to preempt any state law.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
