<bill session="110" type="s" number="1332" updated="2009-01-09T14:34:25-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1178596800" datetime="2007-05-08"/></status>

	<introduced date="1178596800" datetime="2007-05-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Mental Health in Schools Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to revise and extend projects relating to children and violence to provide access to school-based comprehensive mental health programs.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300059"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2008-05-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300041" joined="2007-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300068" joined="2007-09-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300001" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300036" joined="2007-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2007-10-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1178596800" datetime="2007-05-08"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5731)</text></action>
		<action date="1178596800" datetime="2007-05-08"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S5732-5733"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/8/2007--Introduced.<br/>Mental Health in Schools Act of 2007 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to expand the program to provide grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements to develop ways to assist children in dealing with violence to include assisting local communities and schools in applying a public health approach to mental health services, including providing comprehensive services and supports and incorporating strategies of positive behavioral interventions and supports. Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services to implement a comprehensive school mental health program that incorporates positive behavioral interventions and supports. Establishes eligibility requirements for the program, including requiring: (1) a partnership between a local educational agency and at least one community program or agency that is involved in mental health; (2) the program to provide for in-service training of all school personnel; and (3) sustainability of the program after funding terminates. Requires the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration to develop a process for evaluating activities under the grant program to include the development of student and family outcome measures and local educational outcome measures.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
