<bill session="110" type="s" number="1345" updated="2009-01-09T14:36:01-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1178683200" datetime="2007-05-09"/></status>

	<introduced date="1178683200" datetime="2007-05-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Clarification of Federal Employment Protections Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to affirm that Federal employees are protected from discrimination on the basis of sexual orientation and to repudiate any assertion to the contrary.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300001"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-05-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1178683200" datetime="2007-05-09"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5872-5873)</text></action>
		<action date="1178683200" datetime="2007-05-09"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S5873"/></action>
		<action date="1181102400" datetime="2007-06-06"><text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs referred to Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/9/2007--Introduced.<br/>Clarification of Federal Employment Protections Act - Repudiates, in order to dispel any public confusion, any assertion that federal employees are not protected from discrimination on the basis of sexual orientation. Prohibits any federal employee who has authority to take, direct others to take, recommend, or approve any personnel action, from discriminating for or against any federal employee or applicant for federal employment on the basis of sexual orientation. Affirms that, in the absence of such prohibition, discrimination against federal employees and applicants for federal employment on the basis of sexual orientation is already prohibited under current law.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
