<bill session="110" type="s" number="1341" updated="2009-01-09T14:35:32-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1201669200" datetime="2008-01-30" /></status>

	<introduced date="1178683200" datetime="2007-05-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Las Cienegas Enhancement and Saguaro National Park Boundary Adjustment Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the exchange of certain Bureau of Land Management land in Pima County, Arizona, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300062"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300071" joined="2007-05-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1178683200" datetime="2007-05-09"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5871)</text></action>
		<action date="1178683200" datetime="2007-05-09"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1190865600" datetime="2007-09-27"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-266.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1201669200" datetime="2008-01-30" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1207800000" datetime="2008-04-10"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 110-292.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="644" date="1207800000" datetime="2008-04-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 644.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/9/2007--Introduced.<br/>Las Cienegas Enhancement and Saguaro National Park Boundary Adjustment Act - Requires the Secretary of the Interior, if Las Cienegas Conservation, LLC offers to convey to the Secretary title to the Empirita-Simonson parcel of land and the Bloom parcel of land (the non-federal land), to accept the offer and simultaneously convey to Las Cienegas Conservation, LLC the Sahuarita parcel of land (the federal land). Requires the values of the federal and non-federal lands exchanged to be equal, as determined by appraisals. Requires Las Cienegas Conservation, LLC, to: (1) pay the costs of carrying out the exchange of such lands; (2) enter into an agreement with Pima County, Arizona, to convey to Pima County a certain well site; and (3) relinquish to Pima County any water rights to such well site held by Las Cienegas Conservation, LLC. Requires: (1) the Empirita-Simonson parcel of non-federal land, upon acquisition by the Secretary, to become part of the Las Cienegas National Conservation Area; and (2) the Bloom parcel of non-federal, upon acquisition by the Secretary, to become part of the Saguaro National Park. Modifies the boundary of the Las Cienegas National Conservation Area to exclude the 40-acre tract that is leased by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) to the town of Elgin, Arizona, for a sanitary landfill. Instructs the Secretary to provide to the Secretary of Agriculture a right-of-way through the non-federal land for motorized public road access to the boundary of the Coronado National Forest.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
