<bill session="110" type="s" number="1359" updated="2009-01-09T14:37:50-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1178769600" datetime="2007-05-10"/></status>

	<introduced date="1178769600" datetime="2007-05-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Lupus Research, Education, Awareness, Communication, and Healthcare Amendments of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to enhance public and health professional awareness and understanding of lupus and to strengthen the Nation's research efforts to identify the causes and cure of lupus.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300076"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2008-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2007-10-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="2008-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300008" joined="2007-10-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300068" joined="2007-10-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300007" joined="2007-05-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-05-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-10-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300001" joined="2007-05-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412244" joined="2007-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400194" joined="2007-07-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2007-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2007-09-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1178769600" datetime="2007-05-10"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/10/2007--Introduced.<br/>Lupus Research, Education, Awareness, Communication, and Healthcare Amendments of 2007 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Director of the National Institute of Arthritis and Musculoskeletal and Skin Diseases to expand research on lupus to include: (1) basic research to discover the pathogenesis and pathophysiology of the disease; and (2) research to validate lupus biomarkers. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to work with a consortium of academic health institutions to undertake an epidemiological study to determine the prevalence and incidence of lupus in the United States. Requires the Director of CDC to: (1) enter into a cooperative agreement with such consortium to develop, implement, and manage a system for lupus data collection and analysis; and (2) ensure that such consortium represents different geographic areas and includes individuals of racial and ethnic backgrounds disproportionately affected by lupus. Requires the Secretary to enter into a contract with the Institute of Medicine to study and make recommendations related to lupus, to include: (1) evaluating federal and state activities related to lupus and recommending ways to expand such activities; (2) identifying gaps in federal research; and (3) recommending ways to improve the quality of life for people with lupus. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Office on Women's Health, to conduct and support a national lupus public awareness and health professional education campaign, with an emphasis on reaching populations at highest risk for the disease.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
