<bill session="110" type="s" number="1364" updated="2009-01-09T14:38:28-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1178769600" datetime="2007-05-10"/></status>

	<introduced date="1178769600" datetime="2007-05-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Healthy Kids Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend titles XIX and XXI of the Social Security Act to extend the State Children's Health Insurance Program (SCHIP) and streamline enrollment under SCHIP and Medicaid, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300038"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-06-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1178769600" datetime="2007-05-10"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5937-5938)</text></action>
		<action date="1178769600" datetime="2007-05-10"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced in Senate" ref="CR S5938-5948"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/10/2007--Introduced.<br/>Healthy Kids Act of 2007 - Amends title XXI (State Children's Health Insurance Program) (SCHIP) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to extend the SCHIP program. Provides for two-year initial availability of SCHIP allotments and redistribution of unused allotments to address state funding shortfalls.<br/>Provides for bonus payments for states that implement administrative policies to streamline enrollment procedures under Medicaid and SCHIP. Gives states the option to provide for &quot;express lane&quot; and simplified determinations of a child's financial eligibility for medical assistance under SSA title XIX (Medicaid) or child health assistance under SCHIP. Gives states the option to expand or add coverage of certain pregnant women and legal immigrants under Medicaid or SCHIP. Prohibits limitations on SCHIP enrollment. Gives states the option to require certain individuals to present satisfactory documentary evidence of proof of citizenship or nationality for purposes of Medicaid eligibility. Provides for increased federal matching rate for language services under Medicaid or SCHIP. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to make grants to promote innovative outreach and enrollment under Medicaid and SCHIP. Requires coverage of early and periodic screening, diagnostic, and treatment (EPSDT) services, including dental services under SCHIP. Directs the HHS Secretary to establish a program to encourage and support the development of new and emerging quality and performance measures for pediatric care providers. Directs the Secretary to establish: (1) pediatric care delivery demonstration projects; (2) a medical home demonstration project under Medicaid and SCHIP; and (3) disease prevention and treatment demonstration projects for ethnic and racial minority children. Directs the Comptroller General to report on design and implementation of a demonstration project evaluating quality and performance measures for children's inpatient hospital services. Establishes the Commission on Children's Health Coverage.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
