<bill session="110" type="s" number="1365" updated="2009-01-09T14:38:35-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1201669200" datetime="2008-01-30" /></status>

	<introduced date="1178769600" datetime="2007-05-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Omnibus Parks and Public Lands Management Act of 1996 to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to enter into cooperative agreements with any of the management partners of the Boston Harbor Islands National Recreation Area, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300060"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-05-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1178769600" datetime="2007-05-10"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1194498000" datetime="2007-11-08"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-282.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1201669200" datetime="2008-01-30" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1207800000" datetime="2008-04-10"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 110-293.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="645" date="1207800000" datetime="2008-04-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 645.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/10/2007--Introduced.<br/>Amends the Omnibus Parks and Public Lands Management Act of 1996 relating to the Boston Harbor Islands National Recreation Area to permit the Secretary of the Interior to enter into cooperative agreements with the Commonwealth of Massachusetts, a political subdivision of the Commonwealth of Massachusetts, or any member of the Boston Harbor Islands Partnership for the management of the Recreation Area, construction of recreation area facilities, or any other purpose consistent with the purposes of the Recreation Area. 
	</summary>
</bill>
