<bill session="110" type="s" number="1376" updated="2009-01-09T14:39:58-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179115200" datetime="2007-05-14"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179115200" datetime="2007-05-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">340B Program Improvement and Integrity Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to revise and expand the drug discount program under section 340B of such Act to improve the provision of discounts on drug purchases for certain safety net provides.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300009"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="2008-05-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="2008-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2008-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="2007-06-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2008-09-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300016" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2008-07-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400546" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-06-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412243" joined="2008-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="300075" joined="2007-11-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300021" joined="2007-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2008-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2008-09-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400194" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2007-08-02"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179115200" datetime="2007-05-14"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6057)</text></action>
		<action date="1179115200" datetime="2007-05-14"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S6057-6060"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/14/2007--Introduced.<br/>340B Program Improvement and Integrity Act of 2007 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to expand the drug discount program to allow participation as a covered entity by certain children's hospitals, critical access hospitals, and rural referral centers or sole community hospitals. Prohibits enrolled hospitals from obtaining covered outpatient drugs through a group purchasing arrangement. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish reasonable exceptions to such prohibition, including for drugs unavailable through the program and to facilitate generic substitution when a generic covered drug is available at a lower price. Expands the program to include a drug used in connection with an inpatient or outpatient service by enrolled hospitals. (Currently, only outpatient drugs are covered under the program.)<br/>Requires hospitals enrolled in the 340B drug discount program to provide to each state a credit on the estimated annual costs to such hospital of single source and innovator multiple source drugs and noninnovator multiple source drugs provided to Medicaid recipients for inpatient use. Sets forth a formula for calculating the credit. Allows a hospital to avoid paying such credits under certain circumstances. Requires the Secretary to: (1) carry out activities to improve compliance by manufacturers and covered entities with the requirements of the drug discount program; and (2) establish an administrative process for resolving claims by covered entities and manufacturers of violations of such requirements.<br/>Requires manufacturers to offer each covered entity covered drugs for purchase at or below the applicable ceiling price if such a drug is made available to any other purchaser at any price.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
