<bill session="110" type="s" number="1372" updated="2009-01-09T14:39:26-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1178856000" datetime="2007-05-11"/></status>

	<introduced date="1178856000" datetime="2007-05-11"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Nanotechnology Infrastructure Enhancement Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for a Center for Nanotechnology Research and Engineering.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300080"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2007-06-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1178856000" datetime="2007-05-11"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/11/2007--Introduced.<br/>Nanotechnology Infrastructure Enhancement Act - Requires the Director of the National Science Foundation (NSF) to establish a geographically diverse, interdisciplinary Center for Nanotechnology Research and Engineering (the Center) to focus on: (1) the science and engineering of manufacturing at the nanoscale in multiple dimensions; or (2) nanotechnology for sustainable energy, water, agriculture, and the environment. Allows the Center to be a Nanoscale Science and Engineering Center or a National Nanotechnology Infrastructure Network node. Requires that the Center shall consist of: (1) a lead academic institution located in an EPSCoR (the Experimental Program to Stimulate Competitive Research) state; and (2) at least one additional academic institution located in a second EPSCoR state. Permits the Center to include other institutions within or outside of the United States. Requires the Center to: (1) conduct state-of-the-art research on nanomanufacturing; (2) collaborate with other NSF grantees, and with grantees from other federal agencies, working on nanomanufacturing; (3) share resources with the programs of such grantees for the purpose of mutual advantage; and (4) work toward a nanomanufacturing network that encourages extensive industrial collaboration. 
	</summary>
</bill>
