<bill session="110" type="s" number="1370" updated="2009-01-09T14:39:11-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1178856000" datetime="2007-05-11"/></status>

	<introduced date="1178856000" datetime="2007-05-11"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Clean Energy Investment Assurance Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to ensure more investment and innovation in clean energy technologies.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300018"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-05-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-05-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300090" joined="2007-05-11"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1178856000" datetime="2007-05-11"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6019-6021)</text></action>
		<action date="1178856000" datetime="2007-05-11"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/11/2007--Introduced.<br/>Clean Energy Investment Assurance Act of 2007 - Amends Internal Revenue Code provisions relating to the tax credit for the production of electricity from renewable resources to: (1) extend such credit through 2013; (2) allow a credit for the production of thermal energy; (3) allow a credit for investment in resources that produce electricity without carbon emissions; and (4) modify the definition of &quot;closed-loop biomass&quot; and &quot;nonhydroelectric dams&quot; for purposes of such tax credit.<br/>Extends through 2013 the tax credit for holders of clean renewable energy bonds. Increases the annual national limitation for such bonds to $5 billion between 2009 and 2014.<br/>Extends through 2016 the tax credit for residential energy efficient property expenditures. Eliminates the 30% limitation on solar electric property expenditures. Allows such credit for energy storage air conditioner property used in a principal residence. Calculates the maximum allowable amounts of such credit for solar property based upon kilowatt capacity.<br/>Extends through 2016 the energy investment tax credit.<br/>Extends through 2012 the tax credits for: (1) nonbusiness energy property expenditures; and (2) new energy efficient homes.<br/>Extends through 2014 the tax deduction for energy efficient commercial buildings. Increases the rate of such deduction to $2.25 per square foot.<br/>Assigns a five-year recovery period for the depreciation of any qualified energy management device (&quot;smart meter&quot;) that is placed in service before 2012 and that measures and records electricity usage data on a time-differentiated basis of at least 10 minutes.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
