<bill session="110" type="s" number="1384" updated="2009-01-09T14:40:59-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179115200" datetime="2007-05-14"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179115200" datetime="2007-05-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to repeal authority for adjustments to per diem payments to homeless veterans service centers for receipt of other sources of income, to extend authorities for certain programs to benefit homeless veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300001"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2008-05-21"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179115200" datetime="2007-05-14"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6063-6064)</text></action>
		<action date="1179115200" datetime="2007-05-14"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S6064"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/14/2007--Introduced.<br/>Repeals the requirement that the Secretary of Veterans Affairs adjust the per diem payments made to veterans under the homeless veterans' comprehensive services program of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to exclude sources of income from other federal, state, or local governments, departments, agencies, or entities. Directs the Secretary to carry out a demonstration program to prevent veterans who are at risk of homelessness after discharge or release from active military duty from becoming homeless. Amends a demonstration program of referral and counseling for veterans transitioning from certain institutions who are at risk of homelessness to: (1) remove the &quot;demonstration&quot; designation of the program; (2) require the program to be carried out in 12 (under current law, at least six) locations; and (3) extend the program through FY2012. Allows homeless veterans' comprehensive services grant funds to be used to provide funding for service center staff. Repeals a provision limiting to FY2003 and FY2004 the funding for VA domiciliary care programs for homeless veterans. Requires the Secretary to ensure that such programs are adequate, with respect to capacity and safety, to meet the needs of women veterans.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
