<bill session="110" type="s" number="1398" updated="2009-01-09T14:42:42-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179201600" datetime="2007-05-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179201600" datetime="2007-05-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Inflammatory Bowel Disease Research Enhancement Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to expand the research and prevention activities of the National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases, and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention with respect to inflammatory bowel disease.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300082"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2008-09-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2007-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2007-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300052" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-06-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300081" joined="2007-09-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="2007-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2008-06-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2008-06-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2007-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2007-07-30"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179201600" datetime="2007-05-15"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S6137-6138"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/15/2007--Introduced.<br/>Inflammatory Bowel Disease Research Enhancement Act - Requires the Director of the National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases to expand, intensify, and coordinate the Institute's research activities on inflammatory bowel disease, with a focus on: (1) genetic research on susceptibility for inflammatory bowel disease; (2) research targeted to increase knowledge about the causes and complications of inflammatory bowel disease in children; (3) animal model research; (4) clinical research; (5) expansion of the Institute's Inflammatory Bowel Disease Centers program with a focus on pediatric research; (6) training of qualified health professionals in biomedical research focused on inflammatory bowel disease; and (7) other research priorities identified in specified scientific agendas.<br/>Requires the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to expand the Inflammatory Bowel Disease Epidemiology Program to include additional studies focused on: (1) the incidence and prevalence of pediatric inflammatory bowel disease in the United States; (2) genetic and environmental factors associated with the disease; (3) age, race or ethnicity, gender, and family history of individuals diagnosed with the disease; and (4) treatment approaches and outcomes. 
	</summary>
</bill>
