<bill session="110" type="s" number="1397" updated="2009-01-09T14:42:33-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179201600" datetime="2007-05-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179201600" datetime="2007-05-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Skilled Worker Immigration and Fairness Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase the allocation of visas for certain highly skilled workers and to reduce fraud and abuse in certain visa programs for aliens working temporarily in the United States.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300067"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300098" joined="2007-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300050" joined="2007-05-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179201600" datetime="2007-05-15"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/15/2007--Introduced.<br/>Skilled Worker Immigration and Fairness Act - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to exempt from the annual H-1B (specialty occupation/fashion models) visa cap an alien who has: (1) earned a master's or higher degree in science, technology, engineering, or mathematics from an institution of higher education outside of the United States; or (2) been awarded a medical specialty certification based on post-doctoral training and experience in the United States.<br/>Sets H-1B annual limits at: (1) 115,000 for FY2007; and (2) for each subsequent fiscal year, the greater of 115,000 or a market-based calculation.<br/>Exempts from numerical limitations on employment-based immigrants: (1) aliens who have earned advanced degrees in science, technology, engineering, or math and have been working in their fields in the United States under a nonimmigrant visa in the three years prior to filing for adjustment; (2) recipients of national interest waivers; and (3) immediate relatives of employment-based immigrants. Permits an alien (and dependents) to file for adjustment of status whether or not an employment-based immigrant visa is immediately available if: (1) a petition on behalf of the alien has been approved; or (2) adjudication of such petition is pending. Revises H-1B provisions with respect to: (1) application fraud and misrepresentation; (2) employer penalties; (3) Department of Labor investigations; (4) Department of Labor and Department of Homeland Security (DHS) information sharing; (5) information provided to an H-1B nonimmigrant upon visa issuance; (6) prohibiting H-1B-exclusive employment advertising; and (7) prohibiting an employer of fewer than 50 employees in the United States from having more than 50% H-1B nonimmigrant employees.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
