<bill session="110" type="s" number="1415" updated="2009-01-09T14:44:52-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179288000" datetime="2007-05-16"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179288000" datetime="2007-05-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Cancer Screening, Treatment, and Survivorship Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act and the Social Security Act to improve screening and treatment of cancers, provide for survivorship services, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300051"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="2007-06-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2007-10-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2007-06-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2008-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2007-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300001" joined="2007-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-05-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2007-06-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2007-06-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179288000" datetime="2007-05-16"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6198)</text></action>
		<action date="1179288000" datetime="2007-05-16"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/16/2007--Introduced.<br/>Cancer Screening, Treatment, and Survivorship Act of 2007 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to make matching grants to states or Indian tribes for: (1) cancer screening and referrals; (2) developing and disseminating public information and education programs for the detection and control of certain cancers; (3) improving the education, training and skills of health professionals in detecting certain cancers; and (4) establishing mechanisms to monitor the quality of screening procedures. Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to allow states to provide coverage under Medicaid for individuals not otherwise eligible who are under the age 65 and who: (1) have been screened for cancer and have been referred for treatment; or (2) have been diagnosed or treated for cancer.<br/>Requires the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH), acting through the Director of the National Cancer Institute (NCI), to expand research programs to identify and improve cancer screening and testing protocols and tools, with particular emphasis on those cancers with the highest incidence of mortality and disability. Directs the Secretary to award grants for activities to raise public awareness to ensure widespread use of cancer screening programs and access to the best available screening and testing services.<br/>Requires the Director of NIH to: (1) expand cancer survivorship research activities at NCI-designated cancer centers; and (2) provide assistance to such centers for research to evaluate models of survivorship care.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
