<bill session="110" type="s" number="1411" updated="2009-01-09T14:44:22-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179288000" datetime="2007-05-16"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179288000" datetime="2007-05-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Government Greenhouse Gas Registry Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Clean Air Act to establish within the Environmental Protection Agency an office to measure and report on greenhouse gas emissions of Federal agencies.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300064"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2008-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-05-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-05-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179288000" datetime="2007-05-16"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6195-6196)</text></action>
		<action date="1179288000" datetime="2007-05-16"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S6196"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/16/2007--Introduced.<br/>Federal Government Greenhouse Gas Registry Act of 2007 - Amends the Clean Air Act to establish within the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) the Federal Emissions Inventory Office. Sets forth the Offices' duties, including: (1) developing and using a greenhouse gas emission inventory or other system to measure and verify direct emissions (emissions directly from a source owned or controlled by the federal government), energy indirect emissions (emissions resulting from the production of electricity purchased and used by the federal government), indirect emissions (emissions resulting from the conduct of a project or activity by the federal government), and offsets of those emissions; and (2) establishing an emission baseline for the federal government.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
