<bill session="110" type="s" number="1418" updated="2009-01-09T14:45:15-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1202878800" datetime="2008-02-13" /></status>

	<introduced date="1179374400" datetime="2007-05-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">United States Commitment to Global Child Survival Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">United States Commitment to Global Child Survival Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide assistance to improve the health of newborns, children, and mothers in developing countries, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300034"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-07-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="2007-10-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-11-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-06-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2007-12-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2008-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="2007-10-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300068" joined="2007-12-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2007-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2008-06-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412248" joined="2008-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-06-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2007-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300090" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2007-07-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179374400" datetime="2007-05-17"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6269-6270)</text></action>
		<action date="1179374400" datetime="2007-05-17"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S6270-6272"/></action>
		<calendar date="1202878800" datetime="2008-02-13" ><text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1207713600" datetime="2008-04-09"><text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Biden with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 110-282.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="633" date="1207713600" datetime="2008-04-09" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 633.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/9/2008--Reported to Senate amended. United States Commitment to Global Child Survival Act of 2007 - (Sec. 2) States that the purposes of this Act are to: (1) develop a strategy to reduce mortality and improve the health of newborns, children, and mothers; and (2) establish a task force to assess, monitor, and evaluate the progress and contributions of relevant U.S. departments and agencies. (Sec. 3) Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to authorize the President to furnish assistance to improve the health of newborns, children, and mothers in developing countries, including activities relating to: (1) newborn care and treatment; (2) childhood illness and immunization services; (3) child and maternal nutrition; (4) maternity and obstetric services; (5) safe water, hygiene, and environmental toxins such as lead; (6) health services and health information systems; and (7) HIV/AIDS, malaria, tuberculosis and child spacing. Directs the President, to report annually (for five years) to Congress on the implementation of such assistance. States that such report shall include the most recent report submitted to the President by the Interagency Task Force on Child Survival and Maternal Health in Developing Countries. (Sec. 4) Directs the President to: (1) develop a comprehensive strategy to improve the health of newborns, children, and mothers in developing countries; and (2) report to Congress. (Sec. 5) Establishes the Interagency Task Force on Child Survival and Maternal Health in Developing Countries which shall assess, monitor, and evaluate the progress and contributions of relevant U.S. departments and agencies. (Sec. 6) Authorizes FY2008-FY2012 appropriations.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
