<bill session="110" type="s" number="1427" updated="2009-01-09T14:46:36-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179374400" datetime="2007-05-17"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179374400" datetime="2007-05-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Emergency Management Improvement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Federal Emergency Management Agency as an independent agency, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300022"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300001" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2007-05-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179374400" datetime="2007-05-17"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6303-6304)</text></action>
		<action date="1179374400" datetime="2007-05-17"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S6304-6308"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/17/2007--Introduced.<br/>Federal Emergency Management Improvement Act of 2007 - Reestablishes the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) as an independent establishment in the executive branch. Requires FEMA to be headed by a Director appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. Designates the Director as the principal advisor to the President, the Homeland Security Council, and the Secretary of Homeland Security for all matters relating to emergency management in the United States. Directs the President to designate the Director to serve as a Cabinet member in the event of natural disasters, terrorist acts, or other man-made disasters.<br/>Sets forth provisions regarding FEMA's primary mission and the Director's responsibilities. Provides for 10 regional offices in FEMA, each headed by a Regional Administrator. Requires each Regional Administrator to: (1) establish a Regional Advisory Council; and (2) oversee multi-agency strike teams. Establishes a National Integration Center as FEMA's principal operations center. Requires the Director to: (1) ensure that the National Response Plan provides for a clear chain of command to lead and coordinate the federal response to disasters; (2) enter into a memorandum of understanding with specified individuals to collaborate on developing standards for deployment capabilities, including credentialing of personnel and typing of resources; and (3) appoint a Disability Coordinator. Transfers specified functions and personnel to FEMA. Authorizes the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to make necessary determinations regarding such functions and incidental dispositions of personnel, assets, and property.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
