<bill session="110" type="s" number="1432" updated="2009-01-09T14:47:17-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179374400" datetime="2007-05-17"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179374400" datetime="2007-05-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Food Outreach and Opportunity Development for a Healthy America Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Food Stamp Act of 1977 and the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to improve access to healthy foods, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400050"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2007-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300081" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-05-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179374400" datetime="2007-05-17"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/17/2007--Introduced.<br/>Food Outreach and Opportunity Development for a Healthy America Act of 2007 - Amends the Food Stamp Act of 1977 to: (1) extend assistance for community food projects; and (2) obligate funds for food stamp nutrition education. Amends the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to: (1) extend the fresh fruit and vegetable program; (2) extend the farm-to-cafeteria program; and (3) authorize Department of Agriculture and Department of Defense (DOD) geographic preferences to purchase locally produced agricultural or food products. Amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to revise the farmland protection program. Gives priority to farm and ranchland with prime, unique, or other productive soils at risk of nonagricultural development. Provides for: (1) grants to eligible state or local entities to purchase conservation easements; and (2) grant agreements with eligible state or local entities to purchase conservation easements using a combination of their own funds and grant funds. Amends the Farmer-to-Consumer Direct Marketing Act of 1976 to establish the Farmers' Market Promotion Program Plus to make grants to eligible entities to establish and promote direct farmer-to-consumer marketing opportunities. Amends the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 to extend the seniors farmers' market nutrition program. Amends the Specialty Crops Competitiveness Act of 2004 to direct the Secretary of Agriculture, through the Agricultural Marketing Service, to: (1) establish a grant program for eligible entities to conduct enterprise feasibility studies, including studies of consumer preference; and (2) provide loans and loan guarantees to eligible entities and individual producers to develop processing, distribution, and information infrastructure for locally or regionally produced food. 
	</summary>
</bill>
