<bill session="110" type="s" number="1433" updated="2009-01-09T14:47:24-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1201669200" datetime="2008-01-30" /></status>

	<introduced date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Thomas P. O'Hara Public Land Career Opportunity Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act to provide competitive status to certain Federal employees in the State of Alaska.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300075"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6401-6402)</text></action>
		<action date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S6402"/></action>
		<action date="1190260800" datetime="2007-09-20"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-216.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1201669200" datetime="2008-01-30" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1207800000" datetime="2008-04-10"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment. With written report No. 110-295.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="647" date="1207800000" datetime="2008-04-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 647.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/21/2007--Introduced.<br/>Thomas P. O'Hara Public Land Career Opportunity Act of 2007 - Amends the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act to provide competitive status to certain permanent federal employees in Alaska after: (1) if the appointment is full-time, the completion of two years of competitive and satisfactory full time service; or (2) if the appointment is less than full time, the period that is equivalent to two years of competitive and satisfactory full time service. 
	</summary>
</bill>
