<bill session="110" type="s" number="1434" updated="2009-01-09T14:47:32-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Building Renewal and Energy Savings Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the National Energy Conservation Policy Act to promote the use of energy and water efficiency measures in Federal buildings, to promote energy savings performance contracts and utility energy service contracts, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300080"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2007-05-21"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6402)</text></action>
		<action date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/21/2007--Introduced.<br/>Federal Building Renewal and Energy Savings Act of 2007 - Amends the National Energy Conservation Policy Act to require each federal agency to: (1) complete a comprehensive energy and water evaluation for each of its buildings and facilities meeting minimum size or other criteria established by the Secretary of Energy; and (2) implement each energy and water efficiency measure identified in such evaluation. Requires a federal agency to: (1) use a web-based tracking system to certify compliance with this Act; and (2) enter energy use data for each of its facilities and buildings into a building energy use benchmarking system, such as the Energy Star Portfolio Manager. Instructs the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to issue quarterly scorecards for energy management activities carried out by each federal agency. Prohibits a federal agency from: (1) establishing a policy that limits the maximum term of an energy savings performance contract to a period shorter than 25 years; or (2) limiting the total amount of obligations under such contracts, or other private financing of, energy savings measures. Repeals the termination date for authority to enter into new contracts (thus making such authority permanent).<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
