<bill session="110" type="s" number="1449" updated="2009-01-09T14:49:28-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179806400" datetime="2007-05-22"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179806400" datetime="2007-05-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Rocky Mountain Science Collections Center Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Rocky Mountain Science Collections Center to assist in preserving the archeological, anthropological, paleontological, zoological, and geologic artifacts and archival documentation from the Rocky Mountain region through the construction of an on-site, secure collections facility for the Denver Museum of Nature and Science in Denver, Colorado.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400619"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300003" joined="2007-05-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179806400" datetime="2007-05-22"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6477)</text></action>
		<action date="1179806400" datetime="2007-05-22"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1194498000" datetime="2007-11-08"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-282.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/22/2007--Introduced.<br/>Rocky Mountain Science Collections Center Act of 2007 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to provide a grant to the Denver Museum of Nature &amp;amp; Science in Denver, Colorado, to pay the federal share of the cost of: (1) constructing one or more on-site collection facilities that meet the standards of the Museum; and (2) obtaining goods and services required by the Museum, including the acquisition of designs, plans, furnishings, equipment, and other support for the Museum. Requires the Museum, as a condition of receiving such assistance, to match any amounts provided to the Museum under this Act. States that, in order to meet such matching requirement, the Museum may provide to the Secretary cash, in-kind donations, and services.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
