<bill session="110" type="s" number="1443" updated="2009-01-09T14:48:42-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Clean, Affordable, and Domestic Fuels for Energy Security Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide standards for renewable fuels and coal-derived fuels.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300097"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412251" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300014" joined="2007-05-21"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179720000" datetime="2007-05-21"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/21/2007--Introduced.<br/>Clean, Affordable, and Domestic Fuels for Energy Security Act of 2007 - Instructs the President to promulgate regulations to ensure that aviation fuel, motor vehicle fuel, home heating oil, and boiler fuel sold or introduced into commerce in the United States on an annual average basis contains prescribed volumes of coal-derived fuel. Requires such coal-derived fuel to meet specified greenhouse gas emissions levels.<br/>Sets forth: (1) standards for reduction of greenhouse gas emissions levels; and (2) a calendar year schedule for the applicable volume of coal-derived fuels in billions of gallons. Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to: (1) authorize the Secretary of Energy to guarantee loans up to 100% of principal and interest for projects that produce coal-derived fuel; (2) increase the authorization of appropriations for fossil energy research and development; and (3) direct the Secretary to establish coal research centers to target transportation fuels in designated states, with an emphasis on specified technologies and procedures. Instructs the Secretary to study and report to Congress on the feasibility of developing a domestic coal-derived fuels industry.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
