<bill session="110" type="s" number="1451" updated="2009-01-09T14:49:43-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179806400" datetime="2007-05-22"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179806400" datetime="2007-05-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Quality Reform Expansion and Savings Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to encourage the development of coordinated quality reforms to improve health care delivery and reduce the cost of care in the health care system.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412247"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412242" joined="2007-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2007-09-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300047" joined="2007-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2007-09-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="2007-07-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300081" joined="2007-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300037" joined="2007-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-11-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300026" joined="2007-10-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412244" joined="2007-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300084" joined="2007-07-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179806400" datetime="2007-05-22"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6478-6479)</text></action>
		<action date="1179806400" datetime="2007-05-22"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/22/2007--Introduced.<br/>Quality Reform Expansion and Savings Act of 2007 - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to award quality reform grants to eligible entities to enhance, encourage, and expedite implementation of quality reform plans in order to: (1) encourage the coordinated development of local health care quality reforms; (2) fund the development of practices beneficial to the health care system; (3) expand information technology, electronic health records, and interoperable data systems in the health care system; (4) develop reimbursement practices that align financial incentives with health and prevention reforms to identify and encourage best practices; (5) lower the costs of health care delivery; (6) encourage experimentation in different U.S. regions; and (7) reward cooperation among local entities engaged in reforming the health care system.<br/>Requires the Secretary to establish the Quality Reform Committee, which shall: (1) approve the application of an eligible entity and recommend to the Secretary that a grant be awarded; (2) evaluate and exchange best practices related to activities carried out under the grant; (3) share research and expertise; and (4) study, identify, and report on market failures and anomalies that create economic incentives adverse to achievement of the goals of quality reform, cost reduction, health information technology expansion, and illness prevention.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
