<bill session="110" type="s" number="1463" updated="2009-01-09T14:51:12-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Secure Handling of Ammonium Nitrate Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of Homeland Security to regulate the sale of ammonium nitrate to prevent and deter the acquisition of ammonium nitrate by terrorists, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300080"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300029" joined="2007-05-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2007-05-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="2007-05-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300083" joined="2007-05-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300050" joined="2007-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300021" joined="2007-05-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/23/2007--Introduced.<br/>Secure Handling of Ammonium Nitrate Act of 2007 - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to regulate the sale and transfer of ammonium nitrate.<br/>Requires the Secretary to establish: (1) a threshold percentage for ammonium nitrate in a substance; and (2) a process by which the owner of an ammonium nitrate facility or anyone intending to purchase ammonium nitrate must register with the Department of Homeland Security (DHS). Requires the facility owner to maintain records of each sale or transfer over a two-year period.<br/>Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) exemptions involving use exclusively as an explosive material under a federal explosives license; (2) ensuring that agricultural producer access is not unduly burdened; and (3) restricting information disclosures.<br/>Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish procedures to efficiently receive applications, conduct checks, and promptly issue or deny a registration number; (2) take steps to maximize the number of applications processed during the initial six-month period; and (3) check identifying information and deny issuance of a registration number if such information appears in DHS's terrorist screening database. Provides for expedited review of applications and appeals.<br/>Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) confidentiality; (2) information sharing with law enforcement; (3) rechecking persons; (4) inspecting and auditing facility owner records; and (5) reporting theft or unexplained loss of ammonium nitrate.<br/>Prohibits: (1) taking possession of or transferring ammonium nitrate, or owning or operating a facility, without a registration number; or (2) failing to comply with this Act. Prescribes a civil penalty. Sets forth civil liability protections.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
