<bill session="110" type="s" number="1477" updated="2009-01-09T14:52:51-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" /></status>

	<introduced date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Jackson Gulch Rehabilitation Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Jackson Gulch Rehabilitation Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to carry out the Jackson Gulch rehabilitation project in the State of Colorado.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400619"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300003" joined="2007-05-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6855)</text></action>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1185422400" datetime="2007-07-26"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-152.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="974" date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 974.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/16/2008--Reported to Senate amended. Jackson Gulch Rehabilitation Act of 2008 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Commissioner of Reclamation: (1) to pay the federal share (80%) of the cost of carrying out the Jackson Gulch rehabilitation project in Colorado, subject to a reimbursement requirement; and (2) in preparing any studies related to the project, to use existing studies to the maximum extent possible, including engineering and resource information provided by, or at the direction of, federal, state, or local agencies and the Mancos Water Conservancy District.<br/>Requires the Secretary to recover from the District, as reimbursable expenses, the lesser of 35% of the project's cost or $2.9 million over a 15-year period, without interest. Directs the Secretary to credit the District for any amounts it paid before this Act's enactment for engineering work and improvements.<br/>Makes the District responsible for the operation and maintenance of any facility constructed or rehabilitated under this Act. Shields the United States from liability for damages arising out of any act, omission, or occurrence relating to a facility rehabilitated or constructed under this Act. Provides that an activity provided federal funding under this Act shall not be considered a supplemental or additional benefit under the reclamation laws or under the Act of August 11, 1939. Authorizes appropriations.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
