<bill session="110" type="s" number="1475" updated="2009-01-09T14:52:36-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Bay Area Regional Water Recycling Program Authorization Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Bay Area Regional Water Recycling Program, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300043"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-05-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6852-6853)</text></action>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S6853-6854"/></action>
		<action date="1185940800" datetime="2007-08-01"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-170.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/24/2007--Introduced.<br/>Bay Area Regional Water Recycling Program Authorization Act of 2007 - Amends the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to participate in the design, planning, and construction of recycled water projects in cooperation with: (1) Palo Alto and Mountain View, California; (2) Pittsburg, California, and the Delta Diablo Sanitation District; (3) Antioch, California, and the Delta Diablo Sanitation District; (4) the North Coast County Water District; (5) Redwood City, California; (6) the South County Regional Wastewater Authority and the Santa Clara Valley Water District; and (7) San Jose, California, and the Santa Clara Valley Water District. Expresses the intent of Congress that a comprehensive water recycling program for the San Francisco Bay Area include the San Jose Area water reclamation and reuse program authorized by the Reclamation Projects Authorization and Adjustment Act of 1992.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
