<bill session="110" type="s" number="147" updated="2009-01-09T11:26:04-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/></status>

	<introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Afghan Women Empowerment Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to empower women in Afghanistan, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300011"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300008" joined="2007-01-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2007-03-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-01-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2007-01-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/4/2007--Introduced.<br/>Afghan Women Empowerment Act of 2007 - Expresses the sense of Congress that the protection of the rights of women and girls in Afghanistan and their full participation in the reestablishment of democracy are essential to Afghanistan's reconstruction, and to achieve such reconstruction the U.S. government must commit resources to advance the rights of women throughout Afghanistan. Amends the Afghanistan Freedom Support Act of 2002 to revise the provisions respecting assistance to women and girls in Afghanistan. Extends funding authority. Expresses the sense of Congress that the President should: (1) condition the provision of such assistance on the recipient adhering to international standards for women's rights and human rights; and (2) ensure that Afghan women-led nongovernmental organizations with demonstrated experience in delivering services to Afghan women and children receive grants without ethnic, religious, or any other discrimination. 
	</summary>
</bill>
