<bill session="110" type="s" number="1491" updated="2009-01-09T14:54:31-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Ethanol Education and Expansion Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Agricultural Risk Protection Act of 2000 to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to provide grants for the installation of E-85 fuel infrastructure, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412242"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300098" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300037" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300077" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300010" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412243" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-05-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/24/2007--Introduced.<br/>Ethanol Education and Expansion Act of 2007 - Amends the Agricultural Risk Protection Act of 2000 to direct the Secretary to make grants to majority-controlled producer-based business ventures to install E-85 fuel infrastructure, including infrastructure necessary: (1) for the direct retail sale of E-85 fuel, including E-85 fuel pumps and storage tanks; and (2) to directly market E-85 fuel to gas retailers, including in-line blending equipment, pumps, storage tanks, and load-out equipment; and Provides for infrastructure installation subgrants to direct retailers of E-85 fuel located in a rural area. Defines &quot;E-85 fuel&quot; as a blend of gasoline at least 85% derived from ethanol (or any other percentage, not below 70%, as determined by the Secretary for requirements relating to cold start, safety, or vehicle functions). Requires a grant equal to 20% of the total installation costs. Amends the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 to direct the Secretary to establish a program, funded by the Commodity Credit Corporation, to make competitive grants to eligible nonprofit organizations or institutions of higher education to educate governmental and private entities that operate vehicle fleets, other interested entities, and the public about the benefits of E-85 fuel use. 
	</summary>
</bill>
