<bill session="110" type="s" number="1507" updated="2009-01-09T14:56:38-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Access to Medicare Data Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for drug and health care claims data release.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300048"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300005" joined="2007-05-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6868-6869)</text></action>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/24/2007--Introduced.<br/>Access to Medicare Data Act of 2007 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services, to: (1) enter into data release agreements on an annual basis with specified agencies to provide access to relevant data (excluding negotiated price concessions) submitted by prescription drug (PD) plans and MedicareAdvantage-Prescription Drug (MA-PD) plans under part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program) and linked to hospital, physician, and other relevant medical claims, utilization, and diagnostic Medicare and Medicaid (SSA title XIX) data; and (2) permit such agencies to link data provided under this Act with other relevant health data as needed by the agency in order to accomplish its research objectives. Directs the Secretary to: (1) enter into data use agreements with specified research centers and organizations to provide access to same kind of data; (2) permit them to link it with other relevant health data for research purposes; and (3) prepare the linked sets of data for release by July 1, 2008.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
