<bill session="110" type="s" number="1500" updated="2009-01-09T14:55:40-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1182916800" datetime="2007-06-27" /></status>

	<introduced date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Support for Democracy and Human Rights in Zimbabwe Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Support for Democracy and Human Rights in Zimbabwe Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to support democracy and human rights in Zimbabwe, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300022"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300070" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300035" joined="2007-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-06-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300050" joined="2007-06-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-06-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1182916800" datetime="2007-06-27" ><text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1185249600" datetime="2007-07-24"><text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Biden without amendment. With written report No. 110-136.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="284" date="1185249600" datetime="2007-07-24" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 284.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/24/2007--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)<br/>Support for Democracy and Human Rights in Zimbabwe Act of 2007 - States that is U.S. policy to: (1) support the people of Zimbabwe in their efforts to promote democracy and respect for human rights in Zimbabwe; and (2) call on President Mugabe to restore democracy and human rights in Zimbabwe. Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the United States welcomes the Southern African Development Community's announcement that the President of South Africa, Thabo Mbeki, will lead negotiations between the ruling and opposition parties in Zimbabwe; (2) preparations should be made to hold free elections in accordance with international standards; (3) cooperation among the United States, regional players in Africa, and the international community is an important component of a proactive strategy to support democratic rule and respect for human rights in Zimbabwe; (4) normalized relations with the government of Zimbabwe are desirable but until the government of Zimbabwe promotes democracy and the rule of law the United States will continue to isolate the government of Zimbabwe and expand financial and travel sanctions against those responsible for repressing Zimbabwe's people; and (5) the United States should use its influence in the U.N. Security Council to emphasize the threat to international peace posed by the government of Zimbabwe.<br/>Directs the Secretary of State to provide Congress with quarterly briefings on U.S. strategy for engagement with Zimbabwe. (Terminates such requirement three years after the date of the enactment of this Act.)<br/>Authorizes appropriations to support democracy and governance activities in Zimbabwe, including support for: (1) free and peaceful national elections; (2) creation of nonviolent political space; and (3) human rights programs. 
	</summary>
</bill>
