<bill session="110" type="s" number="1506" updated="2009-01-09T14:56:30-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Beach Protection Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to modify provisions relating to beach monitoring, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300064"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2007-12-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2008-03-11"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6868)</text></action>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/24/2007--Introduced.<br/>Beach Protection Act of 2007 - Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (popularly known as the Clean Water Act) to include among eligible grant activities the development and implementation of programs for source tracking, sanitary surveys, and prevention efforts to address the identified sources of beach water pollution. Authorizes appropriations for such grants for FY2007-FY2012. Requires grant recipients to identify: (1) the use of a rapid testing method; (2) measures for communication within 24 hours of the results of a water sample concerning pollutants to specified officials and all state agencies with authority to require the prevention or treatment of the sources of beach water pollution; (3) measures to develop and implement a beach water pollution source identification and tracking program for the coastal recreation waters that are not meeting applicable water quality standards for pathogens; (4) a publicly accessible and searchable global information system database with information updated within 24 hours of its availability, organized by beach and with defined standards, sampling plan, monitoring protocols, sampling results, and number and cause of beach closing and advisory days; and (5) measures to ensure that closures or advisories are made or issued within 24 hours after a state government determines that its coastal recreation waters are not meeting applicable water quality standards for pathogens.<br/>Sets forth provisions requiring: (1) a review by the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) Administrator of state and local compliance with statutory and regulatory requirements and grant conditions; (2) corrective actions by such governments not in compliance; and (3) a review by the Comptroller General such compliance review and corrective action.<br/>Amends the Beaches Environmental Assessment and Coastal Health Act of 2000 to authorize appropriations to carry out such Act through FY2012.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
