<bill session="110" type="s" number="1519" updated="2009-01-09T14:58:11-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Voluntary Medicare Quality Reporting Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for a transition to a new voluntary quality reporting program for physicians and other health professionals.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400064"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2007-06-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300092" joined="2007-05-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6889-6890)</text></action>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/24/2007--Introduced.<br/>Voluntary Medicare Quality Reporting Act - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to evaluate the quality reporting system under title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act as applied for 2007 before transition to a new voluntary Medicare quality reporting system. Directs the Secretary to enter into contracts for conducting demonstrations for defining appropriate mechanisms whereby eligible professionals may provide data on quality measures to the Secretary through an appropriate medical registry. Allows eligible professionals to continue to report to the Secretary specified quality measures for professional services in order for the Secretary to refine systems for reporting them. Prohibits use of the Physician Assistance and Quality Initiative Fund for quality reporting bonus payments in 2008. Specifies quality measures for covered professional services for the voluntary Medicare quality reporting program.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
