<bill session="110" type="s" number="1514" updated="2009-01-09T14:57:34-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Garrett Lee Smith Memorial Act Reauthorization of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to revise and extend provisions under the Garrett Lee Smith Memorial Act.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300034"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300029" joined="2007-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-11-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2007-06-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-10-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2007-10-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-06-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300081" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412249" joined="2007-12-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300037" joined="2008-09-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="2007-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400546" joined="2007-09-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-06-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300054" joined="2007-06-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300001" joined="2007-07-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-10-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300036" joined="2007-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-09-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400194" joined="2007-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300099" joined="2007-09-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300090" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="2007-07-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2008-02-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6875)</text></action>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S6875-6876"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/24/2007--Introduced.<br/>Garrett Lee Smith Memorial Act Reauthorization Act of 2007 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to revise provisions requiring centers to provide appropriate information, training, and technical assistance on youth suicide to require such information, training, and assistance on suicide among all ages, particularly for youth. Reauthorizes appropriations for FY2008-FY2012 for research, training, and technical assistance centers related to mental health, substance abuse, and the justice system and suicide.<br/>Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to ensure that a state does not receive more than one grant or cooperative agreement for the development of youth suicide early intervention and prevention strategies at any one time. (Current law requires the Secretary to ensure that each state is awarded only one such grant or cooperative agreement.) Reauthorizes appropriations for FY2008-FY2012 for such grants or cooperative agreements.<br/>Reauthorizes appropriations for FY2008-FY2012 for grants to institutions of higher education for services to students with mental and behavioral health problems.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
