<bill session="110" type="s" number="1511" updated="2009-01-09T14:57:12-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Marine and Hydrokinetic Renewable Energy Promotion Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote the development and use of marine and hydrokinetic renewable energy technologies, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300001"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300075" joined="2007-05-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6873)</text></action>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S6873-6874"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/24/2007--Introduced.<br/>Marine and Hydrokinetic Renewable Energy Promotion Act of 2007- Directs the Secretary of Energy to establish: (1) a marine and hydrokinetic renewable energy research program; and (2) an Adaptive Management and Environmental Fund to lend funds to approved applicants to cover the costs of projects that produce marine and hydrokinetic renewable energy. Instructs the Secretary of Commerce and the Secretary of the Interior to prepare jointly programmatic environmental impact statements regarding the impacts of the deployment of marine and hydrokinetic renewable energy technologies in U.S. navigable waters. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow: (1) a tax credit for electricity produced from marine and hydrokinetic renewable energy; and (2) an investment credit and five-year depreciation for equipment which produces electricity from marine and hydrokinetic renewable energy. Denies a tax credit for producing fuel from a nonconventional source (dual benefit) with respect to a marine and hydrokinetic facility for which an investment credit under this Act is claimed by the taxpayer.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
