<bill session="110" type="s" number="1522" updated="2009-01-09T14:58:33-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1201669200" datetime="2008-01-30" /></status>

	<introduced date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Fisheries Restoration and Irrigation Mitigation Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Bonneville Power Administration portions of the Fisheries Restoration and Irrigation Mitigation Act of 2000 to authorize appropriations for fiscal years 2008 through 2014, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300100"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300029" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300005" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300030" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412244" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300090" joined="2007-05-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6894)</text></action>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S6894-6895"/></action>
		<action date="1185422400" datetime="2007-07-26"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-152.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1201669200" datetime="2008-01-30" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1207800000" datetime="2008-04-10"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with amendments and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 110-297.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="649" date="1207800000" datetime="2008-04-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 649.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/24/2007--Introduced.<br/>Fisheries Restoration and Irrigation Mitigation Act of 2007 - Amends the Fisheries Restoration and Irrigation Mitigation Act of 2000 to direct the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, to give priority to any project that has a total cost of less than $2.5 million (currently, $5 million). Authorizes the Secretary, without further appropriation and without fiscal year limitation, to accept any amounts provided to the Secretary by the Administrator of the Bonneville Power Administration. Requires: (1) any amounts provided by the Bonneville Power Administration directly or through a grant to another entity for a project carried out under the Program to be credited toward the non-federal share of project costs; and (2) the Secretary's report on projects under such Act to be made after partnering with local governmental entities and the states in the Pacific Ocean drainage area (Oregon, Washington, Montana, and Idaho). Authorizes appropriations for the Act through FY2014. Sets forth limits and requirements on the amount that may be used each fiscal year for federal and state administrative expenses of carrying out this Act.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
