<bill session="110" type="s" number="1526" updated="2009-01-09T14:59:01-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"/></status>

	<introduced date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Bright Idea Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Energy to develop standards for general service lamps that will operate more efficiently and assist in reducing costs to consumers, business concerns, government entities, and other users, to require that general service lamps and related products manufactured or sold in interstate commerce after 2013 meet those standards, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300094"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300019" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300075" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2007-05-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6895)</text></action>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S6895-6896"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/24/2007--Introduced.<br/>Bright Idea Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of Energy to establish technical standards for general service lamps that provide levels of illumination equivalent to those provided by lamps generally available in 2007, but with a lumens per watt rating of at least: (1) 30 by calendar 2013; and (2) 45 by calendar 2018.<br/>Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) carry out a lighting technology research and development program regarding lamps and related technologies made available in the United States; and (2) assist manufacturers in the manufacturing of general service lamps that achieve the lumens per watt ratings prescribed by this Act.<br/>Instructs the Secretary to: (1) implement a national program consumer education program about the benefits of using light bulbs with improved efficiency ratings; and (2) report to Congress recommendations regarding the means by which the federal government may reduce or prevent the release of mercury during the manufacture, transportation, storage, or disposal of light bulbs.<br/>Directs the Commissioner [sic] of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to report to Congress regarding current lamp labeling practices by lamp manufacturers, with recommendations for a national labeling standard.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
