<bill session="110" type="s" number="1534" updated="2009-01-09T15:00:00-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1180065600" datetime="2007-05-25"/></status>

	<introduced date="1180065600" datetime="2007-05-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Iran Human Rights Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to hold the current regime in Iran accountable for its human rights record and to support a transition to democracy in Iran.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300013"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300055" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300006" joined="2007-05-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1180065600" datetime="2007-05-25"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/25/2007--Introduced.<br/>Iran Human Rights Act of 2007 - Amends the Iran Freedom Support Act to direct the President to appoint a special envoy for human rights in Iran within the Department of State to coordinate efforts to improve respect for the fundamental human rights of the people of Iran and work with organizations committed to promoting democracy in Iran. Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) there is a direct relationship between the state of freedom and democracy within Iran and the efforts of the Iranian regime to acquire nuclear weapons and the long-term success of the global war on terror; (2) it is essential that the issue of human rights violations in Iran should remain a top U.S. foreign policy priority independent of efforts to address the nuclear threat in Iran; (3) the U.S. government should explore the possibility of a regional human rights dialogue with Iran; (4) the United Nations has a significant role to play in improving human rights in Iran; and (5) the commitment to human rights and democracy of an Iranian national who has applied for a U.S. entry visa should be considered when determining visa eligibility.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
