<bill session="110" type="s" number="154" updated="2009-01-09T11:26:55-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/></status>

	<introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Coal-to-Liquid Fuel Energy Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote coal-to-liquid fuel activities.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300014"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300029" joined="2007-01-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300070" joined="2007-01-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="412251" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400621" joined="2007-01-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300016" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300041" joined="2007-01-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300037" joined="2007-01-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300010" joined="2007-01-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300080" joined="2007-01-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300097" joined="2007-01-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300075" joined="2007-01-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2007-01-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-01-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300072" joined="2008-07-31"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S142-143)</text></action>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S143-144"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/4/2007--Introduced.<br/>Coal-to-Liquid Fuel Energy Act of 2007 - Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to include among the projects eligible for Department of Energy (DOE) loan guarantees large-scale coal-to-liquid facilities that use a feedstock, the majority of which is domestic coal resources, to produce at least 10,000 barrels a day of liquid transportation fuel. Instructs the Secretary of Energy (Secretary) to make loans for use by recipients to pay the federal share of the cost of obtaining any services necessary for the planning, permitting, and construction of coal-to-liquid facilities. Directs the Secretary to promulgate regulations to support the development of coal-to-liquid manufacturing facilities and associated infrastructure on DOE and other federal lands, including military bases and military installations closed or realigned under the defense base closure and realignment. Amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to direct the Secretaries of Energy and of Defense to study and report to Congress on the feasibility and suitability of maintaining coal-to-liquid products in the Strategic Petroleum Reserve (Reserve). Authorizes the Secretary to construct storage facilities in the vicinity of pipeline infrastructure and at least one military base. Amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to authorize the Secretary to acquire, place in storage, transport, or exchange coal-to-liquid products in the Reserve. Authorizes the use of certain funds by the Air Force Research Laboratory to continue support efforts to test, qualify, and procure synthetic fuels developed from coal for aviation jet use. Amends federal law governing Armed Forces fuel procurement to authorize the Secretary of Defense to enter into agreements with private companies to develop and operate coal-to-liquid facilities on or near military installations. Instructs the Secretary of Energy to implement a research and demonstration program to evaluate the emissions of the use of Fischer-Tropsch transportation fuel, including diesel and jet fuel.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
