<bill session="110" type="s" number="1543" updated="2009-01-09T15:01:04-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1181016000" datetime="2007-06-05"/></status>

	<introduced date="1181016000" datetime="2007-06-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Geothermal Initiative Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a national geothermal initiative to encourage increased production of energy from geothermal resources, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300009"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="2007-06-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300029" joined="2007-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300082" joined="2007-06-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-09-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300030" joined="2007-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300052" joined="2007-06-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400619" joined="2007-06-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300001" joined="2007-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-06-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300075" joined="2007-06-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2007-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="412244" joined="2007-06-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300090" joined="2007-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="2007-09-20"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1181016000" datetime="2007-06-05"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S7075)</text></action>
		<action date="1181016000" datetime="2007-06-05"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S7075-7076"/></action>
		<action date="1190779200" datetime="2007-09-26"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 110-246.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/5/2007--Introduced.<br/>National Geothermal Initiative Act of 2007 - Declares a national goal to achieve 20% of total electrical energy production in the United States from geothermal resources by 2030. Establishes a national geothermal initiative under which the federal government shall seek to achieve the national goal.<br/>Requires each federal agency to give priority to programs and efforts necessary to achieve such national goal. Specifies goals for the Secretaries of Energy and of the Interior. Instructs the Secretary of Energy to implement a geothermal research and development program to achieve such goals, and the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a related comprehensive nationwide geothermal resource assessment. Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to authorize appropriations for the Intermountain West Geothermal Consortium. Directs the U.S. Agency for International Development to support international and regional development to promote the use of geothermal resources, including the African Rift Geothermal Development Facility. Directs the U.S. Trade and Development Agency to: (1) support the national geothermal initiative; and (2) provide grants and other financial support for feasibility and resource assessment studies.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
