<bill session="110" type="s" number="1577" updated="2009-01-09T15:05:18-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1221019200" datetime="2008-09-10" /></status>

	<introduced date="1181188800" datetime="2007-06-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Patient Safety and Abuse Prevention Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Patient Safety and Abuse Prevention Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend titles XVIII and XIX of the Social Security Act to require screening, including national criminal history background checks, of direct patient access employees of skilled nursing facilities, nursing facilities, and other long-term care facilities and providers, and to provide for nationwide expansion of the pilot program for national and State background checks on direct patient access employees of long-term care facilities or providers.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300061"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412242" joined="2007-12-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2007-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2007-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300068" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2007-06-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="2007-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="412243" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300036" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300006" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2008-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="2008-07-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1181188800" datetime="2007-06-07"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S7353-7354)</text></action>
		<action date="1181188800" datetime="2007-06-07"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S7354-7358"/></action>
		<calendar date="1221019200" datetime="2008-09-10" ><text>Committee on Finance. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1222056000" datetime="2008-09-22"><text>Committee on Finance. Reported by Senator Baucus with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 110-474.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="1035" date="1222056000" datetime="2008-09-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1035.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/22/2008--Reported to Senate amended. Patient Safety and Abuse Prevention Act - (Sec. 3) Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a program to identify efficient, effective, and economical procedures for long-term care (LTC) facilities or providers to conduct background checks on prospective direct patient access employees on a nationwide basis. (Sec. 4) Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to provide for mandatory state use of the National Correct Coding Initiative administered by the Secretary to promote correct coding and to control improper coding leading to inappropriate payment. Directs the Secretary to: (1) identify those methodologies of the National Correct Coding Initiative compatible to Medicaid claims; (2) identify those methodologies that should be incorporated into Medicaid claims with respect to items or services for which no national correct coding methodologies have been established under such Initiative; and (3) notify states of such methodologies and how they are to incorporate them into Medicaid claims. (Sec. 5) Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act, as amended by the Medicare Improvement for Patients and Providers Act of 2008, to extend through FY2017 and increase funding for the Medicare Improvement Fund. 
	</summary>
</bill>
