<bill session="110" type="s" number="1579" updated="2009-01-09T15:05:33-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1181188800" datetime="2007-06-07"/></status>

	<introduced date="1181188800" datetime="2007-06-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Coastal Zone Enhancement Reauthorization Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Coastal Zone Management Act.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300091"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="2007-06-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1181188800" datetime="2007-06-07"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S7366-7367)</text></action>
		<action date="1181188800" datetime="2007-06-07"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S7367-7370"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/7/2007--Introduced.<br/>Coastal Zone Enhancement Reauthorization Act of 2007 - Amends the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 to declare that it is the national policy to: (1) create and use a National Estuarine Research Reserve System; and (2) encourage innovative coastal management practices and coastal and estuarine environmental technologies to improve long-term conservation. Authorizes the Secretary of Commerce to make grants to coastal states for development of coastal zone management programs. Allows the use of state coastal zone management program grants to develop and implement coastal nonpoint pollution control program components. Revises the eligible uses of resource management improvement grants and resource management improvement grant requirements. Revises requirements for the Coastal Zone Management Fund. Requires state loan repayments to the Fund to be made available to make grants to states for intrastate as well as interstate projects. Requires such projects to apply an integrated, watershed-based management approach and advance the purpose of this Act. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to: (1) states for implementing coastal zone management program changes, or for projects that demonstrate significant potential for improving ocean resource management or integrated coastal and watershed management at the local, state, or regional level; and (2) coastal states to assist in specified community and local activities, including coastal resource protection and community revitalization. Authorizes the Secretary to conduct a cooperative program to develop and apply innovative coastal and estuarine environmental technology and methodology and to support the development, application, training and technical assistance, and transfer of effective coastal management practices. 
	</summary>
</bill>
