<bill session="110" type="s" number="158" updated="2009-01-09T11:27:26-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/></status>

	<introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Access to Affordable Health Care Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to expand access to affordable health care and to strengthen the health care safety net and make health care services more available in rural and underserved areas.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300025"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2007-01-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S149-150)</text></action>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/4/2007--Introduced.<br/>Access to Affordable Health Care Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow: (1) tax credits to small businesses for qualified employee health insurance expenses; (2) tax credits for qualified health insurance; (3) deductions for long-term care premiums; and (4) tax credits for individuals with long-term care needs. Requires the Secretary of Labor to award grants to states to assist in planning, developing, and operating qualified small employer purchasing groups for health insurance. Directs the Small Business Administration to award grants to states, local governments, and nonprofit organizations to provide health insurance information to small employers. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (the Secretary) to award demonstration grants for states to demonstrate the effectiveness of innovative ways to increase access to health insurance. Amends title XXI (State Children's Health Insurance Program) (SCHIP) to: (1) establish a special rule for redistribution of unspent FY2004 allotments; and (2) provide for additional allotments to eliminate FY2007 funding shortfalls remaining after redistribution of unspent FY2004 allotments. Renames such title the FamilyCare program and allows states to extend coverage to qualified children, parents, and pregnant women. Allows states to simplify the qualification and enrollment requirements. Requires the Secretary to provide for improved outreach and enrollment in government programs for eligible children and homeless individuals and families. Expresses the sense of the Senate that appropriations for consolidated health centers and the National Health Service Corps should be doubled over the next five fiscal years. Requires the Secretary to: (1) award grants to states for the promotion of healthy lifestyles and for the establishment and operation of worksite wellness programs for small employers and their employees; (2) expand comprehensive school health education programs; and (3) establish demonstration projects related to providing low-cost, high-quality health care and attracting educators and clinical practitioners to underserved areas. 
	</summary>
</bill>
