<bill session="110" type="s" number="160" updated="2009-01-09T11:27:42-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1213848000" datetime="2008-06-19" /></status>

	<introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Lower Brule and Crow Creek Tribal Compensation Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Lower Brule and Crow Creek Tribal Compensation Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for compensation to the Lower Brule and Crow Creek Sioux Tribes of South Dakota for damage to tribal land caused by Pick-Sloan projects along the Missouri River.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400546"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2007-05-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1213848000" datetime="2008-06-19" ><text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1222315200" datetime="2008-09-25"><text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Dorgan without amendment. With written report No. 110-505.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="1089" date="1222315200" datetime="2008-09-25" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1089.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/25/2008--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)<br/>Lower Brule and Crow Creek Tribal Compensation Act - Amends the Lower Brule Sioux Tribe Infrastructure Development Trust Fund Act to increase the aggregate amount to be deposited into the Lower Brule Sioux Tribe Infrastructure Development Trust Fund by the Secretary of the Treasury to provide compensation to the Lower Brule Tribe of South Dakota for damage to tribal land caused by Pick-Sloan projects along the Missouri River.<br/>Amends the Crow Creek Sioux Tribe Infrastructure Development Trust Fund Act of 1996 to increase the aggregate amount to be deposited into the Crow Creek Sioux Tribe Infrastructure Development Trust Fund by the Secretary to provide compensation to the Crow Creek Sioux Tribe of South Dakota for such damage.<br/>States that this Act shall be considered to be full and final compensation to the Lower Brule Sioux Tribe and the Crow Creek Sioux Tribe for damages caused by the construction of the Fort Randall Dam and the Big Bend Dam under the Pick-Sloan Missouri River Basin Program.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
