<bill session="110" type="s" number="1611" updated="2009-01-09T15:09:44-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1179288000" datetime="2007-05-16" /></status>

	<introduced date="1181707200" datetime="2007-06-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">An original bill to make technical corrections to SAFETEA-LU and other related laws relating to transit.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300034"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<calendar date="1179288000" datetime="2007-05-16" ><text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs ordered to be reported an original measure.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1181707200" datetime="2007-06-13"><text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Dodd. With written report No. 110-81.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="198" date="1181707200" datetime="2007-06-13" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 198.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/13/2007--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.) Makes technical corrections to the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users or SAFETEA-LU and other laws related to public transportation. Excludes sightseeing from the term &quot;public transportation.&quot; Names a certain program authorizing the Secretary of Transportation (Secretary) to carry out qualified projects to enhance the protection and enjoyment of national parks and public lands as the Paul S. Sarbanes Transit in Parks Program. Makes specified allocations for fixed guideway modernization through FY2009. Increases the total obligation ceiling for FY2008 for the Mass Transit Account. Makes specified changes to: (1) a certain project designated under the alternative analysis program; (2) certain project authorizations for new fixed guideway capital projects; (3) certain projects for bus and bus-related facilities; (4) the hydrogen fuel cell shuttle deployment demonstration program; and (5) the Advanced Propulsion Control System program. Directs the Secretary to resolve the delay of a certain commuter rail extension in Rhode Island by negotiating the extension of the existing agreement of a specified segment of such project. Requires the Secretary to take certain additional factors into consideration when evaluating the local matching share of costs for the extension of certain light rail lines.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
