<bill session="110" type="s" number="1614" updated="2009-01-09T15:10:02-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1181707200" datetime="2007-06-13"/></status>

	<introduced date="1181707200" datetime="2007-06-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Child Labor Protection Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to strengthen penalties for unlawful child labor.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300051"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-06-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1181707200" datetime="2007-06-13"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/13/2007--Introduced.<br/>Child Labor Protection Act of 2007 - Amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to increase civil penalties for violations of: (1) child labor requirements and prohibitions; and (2) minimum wage and maximum hours requirements. Establishes new employer minumum and maximum penalties: (1) for each employee who was the subject of a child labor violation; (2) for each such violation that causes the death or serious injury of any employee under age 18; and (3) where such violation is a repeated or willful violation. Establishes a civil penalty for each such violation that causes the death or serious injury of any employee under age 18. Defines &quot;serious injury&quot; as permanent: (1) loss or substantial impairment of one of the senses (sight, hearing, taste, smell, tactile sensation); (2) loss or substantial impairment of the function of a bodily member, organ, or mental faculty, including the loss of all or part of an arm, leg, foot, hand or other body part; or (3) paralysis or substantial impairment that causes loss of movement or mobility of an arm, leg, foot, hand or other body part. Increases the civil penalty for any repeated or willful violation of specified minimum wage or maximum hours requirements of such Act. Establishes criminal penalties for child labor violations.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
