<bill session="110" type="s" number="1617" updated="2009-01-09T15:10:19-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1181793600" datetime="2007-06-14"/></status>

	<introduced date="1181793600" datetime="2007-06-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Fuel Reduction using Electrons to End Dependence On the Mid-East (FREEDOM) Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide incentives for plug-in electric drive motor vehicles.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300052"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-06-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2007-06-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-06-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400619" joined="2007-06-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-06-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1181793600" datetime="2007-06-14"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S7733-7734)</text></action>
		<action date="1181793600" datetime="2007-06-14"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/14/2007--Introduced.<br/>Fuel Reduction using Electrons to End Dependence On the Mid-East (FREEDOM) Act of 2007 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow tax credits for: (1) the purchase of a new qualified plug-in electric drive motor vehicle; (2) the conversion of a motor vehicle to a plug-in electric drive vehicle; and (3) rebates paid by electric utilities to purchasers of or converters to plug-in electric drive vehicles. Defines &quot;new qualified plug-in electric drive motor vehicle&quot; as a motor vehicle which: (1) is powered by traction batteries with an aggregate capacity of not less than 2.5 kilowatt hours; (2) uses an offboard source of electricity to recharge batteries; and (3) has a certificate of conformity under the Clean Air Act.<br/>Allows a taxpayer election to expense 100% of the cost of facilities for manufacturing plug-in electric drive motor vehicles (and vehicle components) placed in service before January 1, 2013. Reduces such percentage to 50% for facilities placed in service after 2012, and before January 1, 2015. 
	</summary>
</bill>
