<bill session="110" type="s" number="164" updated="2009-01-09T11:28:14-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/></status>

	<introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">States Using Collaboration and Coordination to Enhance Standards for Students Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">SUCCESS Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to modernize the education system of the United States.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300059"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S157-158)</text></action>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S158-163"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/4/2007--Introduced.<br/>States Using Collaboration and Coordination to Enhance Standards for Students Act of 2007 or the SUCCESS Act - Amends the National Assessment of Educational Progress Authorization Act to require a biennial national assessment of student achievement in grades four and eight, and grade 12 student preparedness, in reading, mathematics, and science. (Currently, science is not included in such assessments and grade 12 assessments need not be biennial.) Requires the Assessment Board's national academic content and student achievement standards to be competitive with rigorous international standards and set at a level that prepares students for non-remedial higher education, participation in the 21st century workforce, and the Armed Forces. Requires the Board, at a state's request, to assist it in identifying discrepancies between its standards and national standards, and in aligning such standards. Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award competitive grants to states to establish prekindergarten through grade 16 (PK-16) student preparedness councils made up of public and private stakeholders that: (1) develop and implement measures to ensure that a state's academic content and student academic achievement standards and assessments meet the national benchmarks; and (2) establish a PK-16 longitudinal data system to track student progress toward such benchmarks. Directs the Secretary to award competitive grants to consortia of states for the development of common performance standards and assessments that compare favorably with national and international standards and assessments. Requires the Secretary to make consortia assessments available to all states.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
