<bill session="110" type="s" number="1649" updated="2009-01-09T15:14:58-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1182225600" datetime="2007-06-19"/></status>

	<introduced date="1182225600" datetime="2007-06-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Military Family Support Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for 2 programs to authorize the use of leave by caregivers for family members of certain individuals performing military service, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300042"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2007-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-06-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1182225600" datetime="2007-06-19"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S7890)</text></action>
		<action date="1182225600" datetime="2007-06-19"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S7890-7891"/></action>
		<action date="1184299200" datetime="2007-07-13"><text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs referred to Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/19/2007--Introduced.<br/>Military Family Support Act of 2007 - Directs the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to establish a program to authorize a caregiver (a federal employee at least 21 years of age capable of providing care to a child or other dependent family member of a member of the Armed Forces) to use: (1) any available sick leave for the provision of such care in the same manner as annual leave is used; and (2) any federal leave available to that caregiver as though that period of caregiving is a medical emergency. Requires the service member for whom the caregiving is provided to be performing service in support of a contingency operation or in situations for which hostile fire or imminent danger pay is authorized and to designate the caregiver for his or her family. Terminates the program on December 31, 2012.<br/>Directs the Secretary of Labor to: (1) establish a program to authorize employees of private businesses to use sick or any other leave for caregiving in the same manner as above; and (2) solicit businesses to voluntarily participate in the program. Requires caregiver designation. Terminates the program on December 31, 2012. Provides for an offsetting reduction in FY2008 appropriations for the Department of Defense (DOD) for research, development, test and evaluation.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
