<bill session="110" type="s" number="1646" updated="2009-01-09T15:14:37-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1182139200" datetime="2007-06-18"/></status>

	<introduced date="1182139200" datetime="2007-06-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Wildfire Presuppression Fuels Management Pilot Program Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Food Security Act of 1985 to require the Secretary of Agriculture to make cost-share and incentive payments for innovative fuels management conservation practices, including prescribed grazing management on private grazing land and practices that complement commensurate public land, to prevent the occurrence and spread of, and damages caused by, wildfires fueled by invasive species.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300082"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300005" joined="2008-04-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300030" joined="2008-04-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300040" joined="2007-06-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1182139200" datetime="2007-06-18"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S7817)</text></action>
		<action date="1182139200" datetime="2007-06-18"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S7817"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/18/2007--Introduced.<br/>Wildfire Presuppression Fuels Management Pilot Program Act of 2007 - Amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to extend the environmental quality incentives program. Includes private land fire presuppression activities in the program. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to make FY2008-FY2012 cost-share and incentive payments to contracting producers for fuels management conservation plans on private grazing land to help prevent wildfires fueled by invasive or noxious weed species, including activities relating to: (1) fuel breaks; (2) protection of wildlife habitat; (3) restoration of fire-damaged areas; and (4) conservation practices.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
