<bill session="110" type="s" number="1657" updated="2009-01-09T15:16:03-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1182225600" datetime="2007-06-19"/></status>

	<introduced date="1182225600" datetime="2007-06-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Energy Efficiency Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a small business energy efficiency program, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300060"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-06-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1182225600" datetime="2007-06-19"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S7897-7898)</text></action>
		<action date="1182225600" datetime="2007-06-19"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S7898-7900"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/19/2007--Introduced.<br/>Small Business Energy Efficiency Act of 2007 - Sets a deadline for final rules establishing a small business education and assistance program regarding energy efficiency. Creates in the Small Business Administration (SBA) the position of Assistant Administrator for Small Business Energy Policy. Establishes a Small Business Energy Efficiency Pilot Program to provide energy efficiency assistance to small businesses through small business development centers. Makes centers selected for the program eligible for grants. Creates a pilot program to provide information regarding telecommuting to small businesses and to encourage the businesses to offer telecommuting options to employees, including outreach regarding individuals with disabilities. Amends the Small Business Act to require the SBA Administrator, in carrying out duties related to Small Business Innovation Research Program (SBIR) and Small Business Technology Transfer Program (STTR) solicitations by federal agencies, to ensure that the agencies give priority to small businesses that participate in or conduct energy efficiency or renewable energy system research and development projects. Allows loans to be made under the Express Loan Program for purchasing a renewable energy system or for an energy efficiency project for an existing business.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
