<bill session="110" type="s" number="1650" updated="2009-01-09T15:15:06-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1182916800" datetime="2007-06-27" /></status>

	<introduced date="1182225600" datetime="2007-06-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Max Cleland Minority Serving Institution Digital and Wireless Technology Opportunity Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Max Cleland Minority Serving Institution Digital and Wireless Technology Opportunity Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a digital and wireless network technology program, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300060"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="2007-06-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-06-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="412249" joined="2007-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300080" joined="2007-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300069" joined="2007-06-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300099" joined="2007-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300090" joined="2007-06-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1182225600" datetime="2007-06-19"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
		<action date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"><text>Senate Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text></action>
		<action date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"><text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1182916800" datetime="2007-06-27" ><text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1199768400" datetime="2008-01-08"><text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Inouye under authority of the order of the Senate of 12/19/2007 with amendments. With written report No. 110-257.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="557" date="1199768400" datetime="2008-01-08" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 557.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/8/2008--Reported to Senate amended. Max Cleland Minority Serving Institution Digital and Wireless Technology Opportunity Act - Establishes in the Department of Commerce an Office of Minority Serving Institution Digital and Wireless Technology to: (1) award grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements (assistance) to eligible institutions to provide educational instruction in digital and wireless network technologies; and (2) strengthen the national digital and wireless infrastructure by increasing national investment in telecommunications and technology infrastructure at eligible institutions. Requires the Secretary of Commerce to establish an advisory council on the best approaches for involving eligible institutions in supported activities and for reviewing and evaluating submitted proposals. Requires the council to include members from minority serving institutions. Makes the following institutions eligible for such assistance: (1) a historically Black college or university; (2) a Hispanic-, Alaska Native-, or Native Hawaiian-serving institution; (3) a tribally controlled college or university; or (4) an institution determined to have enrolled a substantial number of minority, low-income students who received assistance under the Higher Education Act of 1965. Provides a matching funds requirement.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
