<bill session="110" type="s" number="1663" updated="2009-01-09T15:16:52-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26" /></status>

	<introduced date="1182225600" datetime="2007-06-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Securing Equity for the Economic Development of Low Income Areas Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">SEED Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to reauthorize the New Markets Venture Capital Program, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300060"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-06-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1182225600" datetime="2007-06-19"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S7905)</text></action>
		<action date="1182225600" datetime="2007-06-19"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S7906"/></action>
		<calendar date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26" ><text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. incorporated into measure S. 1662 ordered to be reported.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/19/2007--Introduced.<br/>Securing Equity for the Economic Development of Low Income Areas Act of 2007 or SEED Act - Amends the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to direct the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to select at least one company from each SBA geographic region when selecting companies to participate as New Markets Venture Capital companies. Establishes in the Investment Division of the SBA the Office of New Markets Venture Capital. Modifies the definition of low-income geographic area to reflect the new markets tax credit under the Internal Revenue Code. Revises the formula for the amount of operational assistance grants for new markets venture capital companies. 
	</summary>
</bill>
