<bill session="110" type="s" number="1680" updated="2009-01-09T15:19:00-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" /></status>

	<introduced date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Izembek and Alaska Peninsula Refuge and Wilderness Enhancement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Izembek and Alaska Peninsula Refuge Enhancement Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the inclusion of certain non-Federal land in the Izembek National Wildlife Refuge and the Alaska Peninsula National Wildlife Refuge in the State of Alaska, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300075"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300001" joined="2008-05-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S8239-8240)</text></action>
		<action date="1182398400" datetime="2007-06-21"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S8240-8241"/></action>
		<action date="1208232000" datetime="2008-04-15"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-485.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="975" date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 975.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/16/2008--Reported to Senate amended. Izembek and Alaska Peninsula Refuge and Wilderness Enhancement Act of 2008 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to convey to the state of Alaska federal land within the Izembek National Wildlife Refuge for the purpose of constructing a single-lane gravel road between the communities of King Cove and Cold Bay, Alaska, in exchange for non-federal land owned by the King Cove Corporation. Instructs the Secretary to initiate the preparation of an environmental impact statement as required under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969. Lists the entities that may participate as cooperating agencies during the preparation of the statement. Prohibits the conveyance of the federal and non-federal lands from being subject to any requirement under any federal law, including regulations, relating to the valuation, appraisal, or equalization of land. Requires the Secretary to determine that the land exchange, including the construction of a road between the city of King Cove and the Cold Bay Airport is in the public's interest. Bars the land exchange from being carried out before the parcel of state-owned land that is in the Kinzaroff Lagoon has been designated as a state refuge. Sets forth requirements relating to the use, barrier cables, and required dimensions of the road. Prohibits the location of support facilities for the road within the Izembek National Wildlife Refuge. Expresses the intent of Congress with respect to the issuance of any federal permits required for construction of the road. Requires the Secretary to develop a mitigation plan based on the impacts determined under the environmental impact statement. Transfers the federal land on Sitkinak Island that is withdrawn for use by the Coast Guard from the Secretary to the state upon the relinquishment or termination of the withdrawal. Adds the conveyed non-federal land to the Izembek National Wildlife Refuge or the Alaska Peninsula National Wildlife Refuge, as appropriate. Adds certain land to the Izembek National Wildlife Refuge Wilderness or Alaska Peninsula National Wildlife Refuge Wilderness. Sets forth provisions regarding the failure to begin construction of the road.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
