<bill session="110" type="s" number="1687" updated="2009-01-09T15:19:56-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1182916800" datetime="2007-06-27" /></status>

	<introduced date="1182744000" datetime="2007-06-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Global Pathogen Surveillance Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Global Pathogen Surveillance Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for global pathogen surveillance and response.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300008"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-06-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-06-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300050" joined="2007-06-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1182744000" datetime="2007-06-25"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S8359-8361)</text></action>
		<action date="1182744000" datetime="2007-06-25"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1182916800" datetime="2007-06-27" ><text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1189483200" datetime="2007-09-11"><text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Biden without amendment. With written report No. 110-152.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="350" date="1189483200" datetime="2007-09-11" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 350.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/11/2007--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.) Global Pathogen Surveillance Act of 2007 - (Sec. 4) Prohibits assistance under this Act to an eligible developing country that does not: (1) permit World Health Organization (WHO) and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDCP) personnel to investigate infectious disease outbreaks within its borders; and (2) provide pathogen surveillance data to appropriate U.S. and international agencies and organizations. Authorizes the Secretary of State (Secretary) to waive such prohibition if in the U.S. national interest. (Sec. 5) Prohibits any participating foreign national from having unsupervised access to specified agents or toxins that may be used in a biological weapon. States that such restriction may not be construed to limit the Secretary of Health and Human Services' ability to prescribe standards for the handling of such agents or toxins. (Sec. 6) Establishes a public health education and training fellowship program for eligible nationals to pursue: (1) a master of public health degree with a concentration in epidemiology; or (2) advanced public health training in epidemiology. Authorizes each fellowship recipient to take courses of study at the CDCP or at an equivalent facility on diagnosis and containment of likely bioterrorism agents. Authorizes the Secretary to permit the participation of a U.S. citizen in the fellowship program if: (1) in the U.S. national interest to do so; and (2) the U.S. citizen agrees to complete at least five years of public health employment in an eligible developing country or at an international health organization. (Sec. 7) Directs the Secretary to support short training courses in-country (not in the United States) for laboratory technicians and other public health personnel in: (1) laboratory techniques relating to the identification, diagnosis, and tracking of pathogens responsible for possible infectious disease outbreaks; and (2) syndrome surveillance reporting and rapid analysis of syndrome information using Geographic Information System (GIS) tools. (Sec. 8) Authorizes the President to furnish assistance to eligible developing countries to purchase and maintain: (1) public health laboratory equipment necessary to collect, analyze, and identify pathogens which may cause disease outbreaks or may be used as a biological weapon; and (2) related communications equipment and information technology. (Sec. 10) Authorizes a federal agency head, upon the request of a U.S. chief of diplomatic mission or an international health organization, and with the Secretary's and the employee's concurrence, to assign to the respective U.S. mission or organization any public health officer or employee of the agency for the purpose of enhancing disease and pathogen surveillance efforts in developing countries. (Sec. 11) Directs CDCP and the Department of Defense (DOD) to: (1) increase the number of personnel assigned to their respective laboratories located in eligible developing countries that conduct infectious disease research; and (2) expand the operations of those laboratories, especially in the implementation of on-site training of foreign nationals and regional outreach efforts. (Sec. 12) Authorizes: (1) the President to provide assistance to enhance the surveillance and reporting capabilities for WHO and existing regional and international health networks, and develop new health networks; and (2) the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish new country or regional foreign epidemiology training programs in eligible developing countries. (Sec. 13) Directs the Secretary to report to the appropriate congressional committees respecting program implementation under this Act. (Sec. 14) Authorizes FY2008-FY2009 appropriations.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
