<bill session="110" type="s" number="1685" updated="2009-01-09T15:19:40-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1182744000" datetime="2007-06-25"/></status>

	<introduced date="1182744000" datetime="2007-06-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Fairness in Drug Sentencing Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reduce the sentencing disparity between powder and crack cocaine violations, and to provide increased emphasis on aggravating factors relating to the seriousness of the offense and the culpability of the offender.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300052"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-06-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300092" joined="2007-06-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2007-06-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1182744000" datetime="2007-06-25"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S8358-8359)</text></action>
		<action date="1182744000" datetime="2007-06-25"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1202792400" datetime="2008-02-12"><text>Committee on the Judiciary Subcommittee on Crime and Drugs. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/25/2007--Introduced.<br/>Fairness in Drug Sentencing Act of 2007 - Amends the Controlled Substances Act and the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act to increase (by a factor of five) the amount of a controlled substance or mixture containing a cocaine base (i.e., crack cocaine) required for the imposition of mandatory minimum prison terms for trafficking in such controlled substance.<br/>Eliminates the five-year mandatory minimum prison term for first-time possession of crack cocaine.<br/>Directs the U.S. Sentencing Commission to review and amend, if appropriate, its sentencing guidelines for trafficking in a controlled substance to reflect the use of a dangerous weapon or violence in such crime and the culpability and role of the defendant in such crime.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
