<bill session="110" type="s" number="1699" updated="2009-01-09T15:21:26-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"/></status>

	<introduced date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">SKILLs Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening Kids' Interest in Learning and Libraries Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the provisions of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 regarding school library media specialists, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300081"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2008-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300068" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2007-09-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="2007-06-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S8416-8417)</text></action>
		<action date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S8417-8418"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/26/2007--Introduced.<br/>Strengthening Kids' Interest in Learning and Libraries Act or the SKILLs Act - Amends title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to authorize appropriations for FY2008 for the Improving Literacy through School Libraries grant program. Requires states and local educational agencies (LEAs) that receive school improvement funds to ensure that by the beginning of the 2010-2011 school year there is at least one highly qualified school library media specialist in every school that receives such funds. Requires Improving Literacy through School Libraries funds to be: (1) proportionally distributed to serve students in elementary, middle, and high schools; (2) used for media resources appropriate for all grades; and (3) used for professional development in information literacy instruction that is appropriate for all grades. Expands the program of grants to states and subgrants to LEAs for the recruitment, retention, and professional development of teachers to require that highly qualified school library media specialists be included in the focus of such efforts.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
