<bill session="110" type="s" number="1694" updated="2009-01-09T15:20:49-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"/></status>

	<introduced date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Pollinator Protection Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize resources for sustained research and analysis to address colony collapse disorder and the decline of North American pollinators.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300011"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300092" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400546" joined="2007-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300078" joined="2007-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2007-07-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/26/2007--Introduced.<br/>Pollinator Protection Act of 2007 - Authorizes appropriations to the Secretary of Agriculture, through the Agricultural Research Service, for: (1) personnel, facilities improvement, and additional research at Department of Agriculture Bee Research Laboratories; (2) research on honey bee physiology, insect pathology, insect chemical ecology, and honey and native bee toxicology at other Department facilities in New York, Florida, California, Utah, and Texas; and (3) research to identify causes and solutions for Colony Collapse Disorder, with specified amounts for research at the Agricultural Research Services in Beltsville, Maryland, and Tucson, Arizona. Authorizes appropriations to the Secretary, through the Cooperative State Research, Education, and Extension Service, for research grants to investigate: (1) honey bee immunology, genomics, biology, ecology, and bioinformatics; (2) pollination biology; and (3) the effects of genetically modified crops, insecticides, herbicides, parasites, and fungicides on honey bees and other beneficial insects and pollinators.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
