<bill session="110" type="s" number="1711" updated="2009-01-09T15:23:01-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1182916800" datetime="2007-06-27"/></status>

	<introduced date="1182916800" datetime="2007-06-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Drug Sentencing Reform and Cocaine Kingpin Trafficking Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to target cocaine kingpins and address sentencing disparity between crack and powder cocaine.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300008"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="2007-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2008-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="2007-10-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-12-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2008-03-11"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1182916800" datetime="2007-06-27"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S8614-8615)</text></action>
		<action date="1182916800" datetime="2007-06-27"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1202792400" datetime="2008-02-12"><text>Committee on the Judiciary Subcommittee on Crime and Drugs. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/27/2007--Introduced.<br/>Drug Sentencing Reform and Cocaine Kingpin Trafficking Act of 2007 - Amends the Controlled Substances Act and the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act to increase the amount of a controlled substance or mixture containing a cocaine base (i.e., crack cocaine) required for the imposition of mandatory minimum prison terms for crack cocaine trafficking to eliminate the sentencing disparity between crack and powder cocaine.<br/>Eliminates the five-year mandatory minimum prison term for first-time possession of crack cocaine. Directs the U.S. Sentencing Commission to review and amend, if appropriate, its sentencing guidelines for trafficking in a controlled substance to reflect the use of a dangerous weapon or violence in such crime and the culpability and the role of the defendant in such crime, taking into account certain aggravating and mitigating factors. Directs the Attorney General to make grants to improve drug treatment to offenders in prisons, jails, and juvenile facilities. Authorizes the Attorney General to make grants to establish demonstration programs to reduce the use of alcohol and other drugs by substance abusers while incarcerated and until the completion of parole or court supervision. Increases monetary penalties for drug trafficking and for the importation and exportation of controlled substances. Authorizes appropriations to the Departments of Justice, the Treasury, and Homeland Security for FY2008-FY2009 for the prosecution of, and for supporting the prosecution of, high-level drug offenses.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
