<bill session="110" type="s" number="1723" updated="2009-01-09T15:24:31-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28"/></status>

	<introduced date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Government Accountability Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Inspector General Act of 1978 to enhance the independence of the Inspectors General, to create a Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412243"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S8693-8694)</text></action>
		<action date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/28/2007--Introduced.<br/>Improving Government Accountability Act - Amends the Inspector General Act of 1978 to allow an Inspector General to be removed from office prior to the expiration of his or her term only on the grounds of permanent incapacity, inefficiency, neglect of duty, malfeasance, or conviction of a felony or conduct involving moral turpitude.<br/>Establishes the term of office of each Inspector General as seven years and permits reappointment.<br/>Requires each Inspector General to appoint a Counsel to the Inspector General.<br/>Authorizes an Inspector General to annually transmit an appropriation estimate and request to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) and to the appropriate congressional committees, in addition to the head of the establishment concerned. Requires the President to include in each annual budget specified Inspector General appropriation information.<br/>Establishes: (1) within the Executive Branch the Council of the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency; and (2) an Integrity Committee for the Council to review and refer for investigation allegations made against Inspectors General and certain staff.<br/>Prohibits an Inspector General from receiving any cash award or cash bonus.<br/>Removes specified Inspector General positions from the Level IV of the Executive Schedule and places such positions in Level III.<br/>Requires each Inspector General to be appointed without regard to political affiliation and solely on the basis of integrity and demonstrated ability in accounting, auditing, financial analysis, law, management analysis, public administration, or investigations.<br/>Requires the head of a federal entity to communicate the reasons not later than 15 days before the removal or transfer of an Inspector General.<br/>Considers each Office of Inspector General to be a separate federal agency for purposes of certain civil service provisions concerning reinstatement, retirement, and the Senior Executive Service.<br/>Sets forth requirements for Inspectors General websites.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
