<bill session="110" type="s" number="1735" updated="2009-01-09T15:26:02-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28"/></status>

	<introduced date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 49, United States Code, to improve dispute resolution provisions related to the Federal Aviation Administration personnel management system.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300087"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/28/2007--Introduced.<br/>Provides that, with respect to disputes arising after July 10, 2005, between the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) and its employees in attempting to reach an agreement concerning the implementation of proposed changes to the FAA personnel management system: (1) the services of the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service (FMCS) shall be used; (2) the Administrator and employees may by mutual agreement adopt procedures for the resolution of disputes or impasses arising in the negotiation of a collective-bargaining agreement; and (3) if the services of the FMCS have led to an impasse between the FAA and its employees in reaching an agreement with respect to implementing the proposed changes, the FAA Administrator and employees shall submit their controversy to the Federal Service Impasses Panel for binding arbitration. (Under current law, the services of the FMCS shall be used and, if the services of the FMCS do not lead to an agreement, the Administrator's proposed change to the personnel management system shall not take effect until 60 days have elapsed after the Administrator has transmitted the proposed changes, along with the objections of the employees to the changes, and the reasons for such objections, to Congress.)<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
