<bill session="110" type="s" number="1741" updated="2009-01-09T15:26:47-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28"/></status>

	<introduced date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">FHA Manufactured Housing Loan Modernization Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to modernize the manufactured housing loan insurance program under title I of the National Housing Act.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300006"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300003" joined="2007-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-08-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/28/2007--Introduced.<br/>FHA Manufactured Housing Loan Modernization Act of 2007 - Amends the National Housing Act with respect to Federal Housing Administration (FHA) housing loan insurance for manufactured homes (or lots for such homes). Exempts such loans from certain financial institution portfolio limits, increasing an allowable claim for loss from 10% to 90% of an institution's total amount of such loans, credit advances, and purchases. Makes any new contract of insurance for such loans, credit advances, or purchases conclusive evidence of an institution's insurance eligibility. (Thus requires each loan to be insured individually instead of as part of a bundle of such loans.) Increases loan limits, requiring annual indexing. Sets forth borrower premium charges, including an up-front premium of up to 2.25% and an annual premium of up to 1%. Revises requirements for the handling and disposal of any real or personal conveyed to or acquired by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD), and the pursuit of all claims against mortgagors assigned to the Secretary by mortgagees. Directs the Secretary of HUD to establish underwriting criteria that will ensure the manufactured housing program's financial soundness.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
