<bill session="110" type="s" number="1754" updated="2009-01-09T15:28:23-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1183953600" datetime="2007-07-09"/></status>

	<introduced date="1183953600" datetime="2007-07-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for a workplace wellness education campaign and an evaluation of employer-based wellness programs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300051"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300090" joined="2007-07-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1183953600" datetime="2007-07-09"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/9/2007--Introduced.<br/>Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to: (1) conduct an educational campaign on employer-based wellness programs; (2) develop an annual awards program for employers to encourage the development of creative and effective solutions to help employees maintain or improve their health; (3) enter into contracts with entities to provide employers with technical assistance in evaluating wellness programs; and (4) conduct a national worksite health policies and programs study to assess employer-based health policies and programs. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to expand the Behavioral Risk Factor Surveillance System to include a workforce component to enable employers, researchers, and health officials to: (1) assess employee health risks; (2) identify emerging problems associated with general employee health; (3) prevent disease within the employee population; and (4) improve employer-based health programs and policies. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director, to award grants for research demonstration projects to study the effect of new worksite-based health interventions and models. Directs the Secretary to carry out activities to implement guidelines or recommendations resulting from such projects.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
