<bill session="110" type="s" number="1776" updated="2009-01-09T15:31:03-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1184212800" datetime="2007-07-12"/></status>

	<introduced date="1184212800" datetime="2007-07-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Imported Food Security Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to establish a user fee program to ensure food safety, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300038"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300088" joined="2007-10-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300037" joined="2007-09-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-07-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1184212800" datetime="2007-07-12"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S9140-9141)</text></action>
		<action date="1184212800" datetime="2007-07-12"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S9141-9143"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/12/2007--Introduced.<br/>Imported Food Security Act of 2007 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) assess and collect fees on food imported into the United States; (2) provide for research on the development of tests of imported food and sampling methodologies; (3) give priority to tests that are suitable for inspections of food at U.S. ports of entry; (4) establish goals of developing certain tests for specified pathogens or substances; and (5) establish a certification system for a foreign government or foreign food establishment seeking to import food to the United States. Authorizes the Secretary to withdraw such certification of any food if: (1) such food is linked to an outbreak of human illness; (2) the food safety programs or procedures are no longer equivalent to U.S. programs and procedures; or (3) there is a refusal to allow U.S. officials to conduct audits and investigations as may be necessary. Directs the Secretary to routinely inspect food and food animals before entry into the United States.<br/>Authorizes the Secretary to deny importation of food from: (1) any foreign government that does not permit U.S. audits and inspections; and (2) any foreign government or foreign firm that does not consent to an investigation by the Secretary when food from that country or firm is linked to a food-borne illness outbreak or is otherwise found to be adulterated or mislabeled.<br/>Provides that any food imported for consumption in the United States may be detained, seized, or condemned.<br/>Directs the Secretary to establish a transitional food safety import review program.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
