<bill session="110" type="s" number="1783" updated="2009-01-09T15:31:53-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1184212800" datetime="2007-07-12"/></status>

	<introduced date="1184212800" datetime="2007-07-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Ten Steps to Transform Health Care in America Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Fair and Reliable Medical Justice Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Wired for Health Care Quality Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide 10 steps to transform health care in America.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300041"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1184212800" datetime="2007-07-12"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S9145-9149)</text></action>
		<action date="1184212800" datetime="2007-07-12"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
		<action date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S10757-10758)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/12/2007--Introduced.<br/>Ten Steps to Transform Health Care in America Act - Directs states to implement mechanisms to automatically enroll uninsured individuals in health coverage.<br/>Requires each health insurance issuer in a state to offer a certified qualified core plan that provides coverage required by the state with a standard premium.<br/>Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow individuals a standard deduction or a refundable tax credit for health insurance.<br/>Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS Secretary) to provide for the establishment in each state of a single market for all health plans offered in the state.<br/>Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to require the Secretary of Labor to promulgate regulations governing small business health plans.<br/>Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the HHS Secretary to establish the Health Insurance Consensus Standards Board to develop recommendations that harmonize inconsistent state health insurance laws.<br/>Wired for Health Care Quality Act - Establishes: (1) the Office of the National Coordinator of Health Information Technology; (2) a public-private Partnership for Health Care Improvement; and (3) the American Health Information Community.<br/>Requires the HHS Secretary to: (1) provide for the development and use of health care quality measures; and (2) develop a Health Information Technology Resource Center.<br/>Authorizes the HHS Secretary to make grants for medical residency training programs or new residency positions.<br/>Requires the HHS Secretary to develop websites to provide information on advance directives and to store and access such directives.<br/>Fair and Reliable Medical Justice Act - Authorizes the HHS Secretary to award demonstration grants to states to develop, implement, and evaluate alternatives to current tort litigation for resolving disputes over injuries allegedly caused by health care providers or organizations.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
