<bill session="110" type="s" number="1782" updated="2009-01-09T15:31:46-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1184212800" datetime="2007-07-12"/></status>

	<introduced date="1184212800" datetime="2007-07-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Arbitration Fairness Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend chapter 1 of title 9 of United States Code with respect to arbitration.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300042"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="2007-10-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2008-09-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300016" joined="2007-11-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2007-10-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1184212800" datetime="2007-07-12"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S9144)</text></action>
		<action date="1184212800" datetime="2007-07-12"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S9144-9145"/></action>
		<action date="1197435600" datetime="2007-12-12"><text>Committee on the Judiciary Subcommittee on the Constitution. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-396.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/12/2007--Introduced.<br/>Arbitration Fairness Act of 2007 - Declares that no predispute arbitration agreement shall be valid or enforceable if it requires arbitration of: (1) an employment, consumer, or franchise dispute, or (2) a dispute arising under any statute intended to protect civil rights or to regulate contracts or transactions between parties of unequal bargaining power. Declares, further, that the validity or enforceability of an agreement to arbitrate shall be determined by a court, under federal law, rather than an arbitrator, irrespective of whether the party resisting arbitration challenges the arbitration agreement specifically or in conjunction with other terms of the contract containing such agreement. Exempts arbitration provisions in collective bargaining agreements from this Act.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
