<bill session="110" type="s" number="1792" updated="2009-01-09T15:32:57-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1184558400" datetime="2007-07-16"/></status>

	<introduced date="1184558400" datetime="2007-07-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">FOREWARN Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act to improve such Act.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400050"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2007-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="2007-09-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2008-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2007-12-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="2007-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-07-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-07-16"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1184558400" datetime="2007-07-16"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
		<action date="1190779200" datetime="2007-09-26"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S12134-12135)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/16/2007--Introduced.<br/>FOREWARN Act of 2007 - Amends the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act (the Act) to to revise the terms &quot;employer,&quot; &quot;plant closing,&quot; and &quot;mass layoff&quot; for purposes of the Act. Requires an employer to: (1) give 90-day written notice (under current law, 60-day) to employees and appropriate state and local governments before ordering a plant closing or mass layoff; and (2) notify the Secretary of Labor within 60 days of such closing or layoff (including the number of employees involved). Makes an employer who violates such notice requirements liable to the employee for double the back pay (under current law, for back pay) for each day of the violation for up to 90 days (under current law, 60 days). Authorizes the Secretary to bring a civil action on behalf of one or more employees for certain relief under the Act. Directs the Secretary to make educational materials concerning employee rights and employer responsibilities available to the general public and employers.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
