<bill session="110" type="s" number="1806" updated="2009-01-09T15:34:40-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"/></status>

	<introduced date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Judicial Powers Restoration Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to restore to the judiciary the power to decide all trademark and trade name cases arising under the laws and treaties of the United States by repealing the prohibition on recognition by United States courts of certain rights relating to certain marks, trade names, and commercial names and impediments to registration of such marks, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300065"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300029" joined="2007-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2007-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300083" joined="2007-07-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR 7/18/2007 S9477)</text></action>
		<action date="1184644800" datetime="2007-07-17"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. (text of measure as introduced: CR 7/18/2007 S9477)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/17/2007--Introduced.<br/>Judicial Powers Restoration Act of 2007 - Amends the Department of Commerce and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1999 to repeal the prohibition against U.S. courts recognizing, enforcing, or otherwise validating any assertion of rights by a designated Cuban national of a mark, trade name, or commercial name that was used in connection with a business or assets that were confiscated by the Cuban government.<br/>Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to issue regulations as necessary to repeal such provisions, including removing or revoking any applicable prohibition on transactions or payments.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
