<bill session="110" type="s" number="1810" updated="2009-01-09T15:35:12-05:00">
	<status><enacted date="1223438400" datetime="2008-10-08" /></status>

	<introduced date="1184731200" datetime="2007-07-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Prenatally and Postnatally Diagnosed Conditions Awareness Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Prenatally and Postnatally Diagnosed Conditions Awareness Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Prenatally and Postnatally Diagnosed Conditions Awareness Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">Prenatally and Postnatally Diagnosed Conditions Awareness Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="enacted">Prenatally and Postnatally Diagnosed Conditions Awareness Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to increase the provision of scientifically sound information and support services to patients receiving a positive test diagnosis for Down syndrome or other prenatally and postnatally diagnosed conditions.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300013"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="2008-09-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300071" joined="2008-09-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300037" joined="2008-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400546" joined="2008-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2008-06-11"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1184731200" datetime="2007-07-18"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13" ><text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1208750400" datetime="2008-04-21"><text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Reported by Senator Kennedy with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="701" date="1208750400" datetime="2008-04-21" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 701.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1222142400" datetime="2008-09-23"><text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S9341-9343"/><reference label="text of measure as reported in Senate" ref="CR S9341-9342"/></action>
		<action date="1222142400" datetime="2008-09-23"><text>The committee substitute as amended agreed to by Unanimous Consent.</text></action>
		<vote date="1222142400" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2008-09-23" where="s" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text></vote>
		<action date="1222261380" datetime="2008-09-24T10:03:00-04:00"><text>Received in the House.</text></action>
		<action date="1222228800" datetime="2008-09-24"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<action date="1222228800" datetime="2008-09-24"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1222371540" datetime="2008-09-25T16:39:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Pallone moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text></action>
		<action date="1222371540" datetime="2008-09-25T16:39:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H9918-9920"/></action>
		<action date="1222371540" datetime="2008-09-25T16:39:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 1810.</text></action>
		<vote date="1222372200" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-09-25T16:50:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote2" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H9918"/></vote>
		<topresident date="1222315200" datetime="2008-09-25" ><text>Cleared for White House.</text></topresident>
		<topresident date="1222660800" datetime="2008-09-29" ><text>Presented to President.</text></topresident>
		<signed date="1223438400" datetime="2008-10-08" ><text>Signed by President.</text></signed>
		<enacted number="110-374" date="1223438400" datetime="2008-10-08" type="public" ><text>Became Public Law No: 110-374.</text></enacted>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/8/2008--Public Law. Prenatally and Postnatally Diagnosed Conditions Awareness Act - (Sec. 3) Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through either the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH), the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), or the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA), to authorize and oversee certain activities relating to Down syndrome or other prenatally or postnatally diagnosed conditions. Includes among such activities the awarding of grants, contracts or cooperative agreements to eligible entities to: (1) collect, synthesize, and disseminate current evidence-based information relating to such conditions; and (2) coordinate the provision of, and access to, new or existing supportive services for patients receiving a positive diagnosis for such conditions. Includes within such supportive services: (1) the establishment of a resource telephone hotline; (2) the expansion of the National Dissemination Center for Children with Disabilities; (3) the expansion of national and local peer-support programs; (4) the establishment of a national registry, or network of local registries, of families willing to adopt newborns with such conditions; and (5) the establishment of awareness and education programs for health care providers who provide, interpret, or inform parents of the results of prenatal tests for such conditions. Requires the Secretary to place an emphasis on funding partnerships between health care professional groups and disability advocacy organizations in distributing funds.<br/>Requires a grantee under this Act to make available to health care providers of parents who receive a prenatal or postnatal diagnosis: (1) up-to-date, evidence-based, written information concerning the range of outcomes for individuals living with the diagnosed condition, including physical, developmental, educational, and psychosocial outcomes; and (2) contact information regarding support services, including information hotlines, resource centers or clearinghouses, national and local peer support groups, and other educational and support programs. Requires information provided to be culturally and linguistically appropriate and to be approved by the Secretary.<br/>Requires the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to report to Congress concerning the effectiveness of current health care and family support programs serving as resources for the families of children with disabilities.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
