<bill session="110" type="s" number="1862" updated="2009-01-09T15:41:44-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1185249600" datetime="2007-07-24"/></status>

	<introduced date="1185249600" datetime="2007-07-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Southeast Arizona Land Exchange and Conservation Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the exchange and conveyance of certain National Forest land and other land in southeast Arizona, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300062"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300071" joined="2007-07-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1185249600" datetime="2007-07-24"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S9834-9835)</text></action>
		<action date="1185249600" datetime="2007-07-24"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/24/2007--Introduced.<br/>Southeast Arizona Land Exchange and Conservation Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (the Secretary) to convey to Resolution Copper Mining, LLC, all interest of the United States in and to specified federal land in Pinal County, Arizona, in exchange for Resolution Copper conveying to the United States title to: (1) the Secretary to specified non-federal land in Gila, Yavapai, Maricopa, Pinal, and Coconino Counties, Arizona, and (2) the Secretary of the Interior to specified non-federal land in Pinal and Gila Counties, Arizona. Directs the Secretary to convey specified land in Pinal County to the town of Superior, Arizona. Instructs Resolution Copper to deliver to the Secretary an executed document granting a permanent conservation easement for the easement area (the surface estate of the Apache Leap Conservation Easement Area) to an entity that is: (1) a qualified unit of government or Indian tribe; or (2) a land trust or other qualified organization. Requires Resolution Copper to determine whether the area covered by the easement should be managed to establish: (1) additional cultural and historical resource protections or measures; or (2) additional or alternative public access routes, trails, and trailheads to Apache Leap. Directs: (1) the Secretary to construct in the Global Ranger District of the Tonto National Forest one or more replacement campgrounds for the Oak Flat Campground; and (2) the Secretary of the Interior to convey to the Arizona State Parks Board approximately 2,000 acres of land under such Secretary's jurisdiction within the exterior boundary of the proposed Tam O'Shanter Area State Park for the establishment of such Park. Requires the Secretary of the Interior, upon request by the Board, to grant the Board a right-of-way for the construction of an access road on a specified route in order to provide public access to the proposed State Park. 
	</summary>
</bill>
