<bill session="110" type="s" number="1870" updated="2009-01-09T15:42:46-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1185336000" datetime="2007-07-25"/></status>

	<introduced date="1185336000" datetime="2007-07-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Clean Water Restoration Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to clarify the jurisdiction of the United States over waters of the United States.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300042"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-10-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300061" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300019" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300081" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2008-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2007-07-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1185336000" datetime="2007-07-25"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S9918-9919)</text></action>
		<action date="1185336000" datetime="2007-07-25"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S9919-9920"/></action>
		<action date="1207713600" datetime="2008-04-09"><text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/25/2007--Introduced.<br/>Clean Water Restoration Act of 2007 - Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) to replace the term &quot;navigable waters,&quot; throughout the Act, with the term &quot;waters of the United States,&quot; defined to mean all waters subject to the ebb and flow of the tide, the territorial seas, and all interstate and intrastate waters and their tributaries, including lakes, rivers, streams (including intermittent streams), mudflats, sandflats, wetlands, sloughs, prairie potholes, wet meadows, playa lakes, natural ponds, and all impoundments of the foregoing, to the fullest extent that these waters, or activities affecting them, are subject to the legislative power of Congress under the Constitution. Declares that nothing in such Act shall be construed as affecting the authority of the Secretary of the Army or the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) under the provisions of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act related to discharges: (1) composed entirely of return flows from irrigated agriculture; (2) of stormwater runoff from certain oil, gas, and mining operations composed entirely of flows from precipitation runoff conveyances, which are not contaminated by or in contact with specified materials; or (3) of dredged or fill materials resulting from normal farming, silviculture, and ranching activities or from activities with respect to which a state has an approved program, or for the purposes of maintenance of currently serviceable structures, construction or maintenance of farm or stock ponds, irrigation ditches and maintenance of drainage ditches, or farm, forest, or temporary roads for moving mining equipment in accordance with best management practices, or construction of temporary sedimentation basins on construction sites for which discharges do not include placement of fill material into the waters of the United States.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
