<bill session="110" type="s" number="1872" updated="2009-01-09T15:43:04-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1185336000" datetime="2007-07-25"/></status>

	<introduced date="1185336000" datetime="2007-07-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Farm Safety Net Improvement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 to make revenue counter-cyclical payments available to producers on a farm to ensure that the producers at least receive a minimum level of revenue from the production of a covered commodity, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300038"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-07-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1185336000" datetime="2007-07-25"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S9921-9922"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/25/2007--Introduced.<br/>Farm Safety Net Improvement Act of 2007 - Amends the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 to extend (through crop year 2012) and revise the counter-cyclical payment program.<br/>Makes payments available in a state for a covered commodity if the actual state revenue (as defined by this Act) for the commodity is less than the revenue counter-cyclical program guarantee (as defined by this Act) for the commodity. (Under current law, payments are provided if a commodity's effective price is less than its target price.)<br/>Provides recourse loans for covered commodities through crop year 2012.<br/>Directs the Secretary of Agriculture, through the Risk Management Agency, to identify necessary actions to ensure that federal crop insurance programs are properly rated to account for a rebalancing of risk resulting from enactment of this Act.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
