<bill session="110" type="s" number="1884" updated="2009-01-09T15:44:31-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1185422400" datetime="2007-07-26"/></status>

	<introduced date="1185422400" datetime="2007-07-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Harvesting Energy Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 to reauthorize and improve agricultural energy programs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400619"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1185422400" datetime="2007-07-26"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S10155-10156)</text></action>
		<action date="1185422400" datetime="2007-07-26"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/26/2007--Introduced.<br/>Harvesting Energy Act of 2007 - Extends: (1) federal procurement of biobased products; (2) biorefinery development grants; (3) the biodiesel fuel education program; (4) the energy audit and renewable energy development program; (5) the biomass research and development program; (6) assistance for renewable energy systems and energy efficiency improvements, including pyrolysis and thermochemical conversion systems; (7) cooperative research and extension projects; (8) the bioenergy program, including establishment of feedstock residue management and transition assistance programs; (9) research, extension, and educational programs on biobased technologies and products; (10) the environmental quality incentives program; and (11) high-priority research and extension initiatives.<br/>Establishes: (1) a biochar research and demonstration program; (2) a strategic biofuel feedstock reserve program; (3) a direct payment program for value-added and renewable energy enterprises; (4) a biomass feedstock pilot program; (5) biochar demonstration projects; and (6) demonstration projects for farm and rural applications of plug-in electric drive vehicles.<br/>Provides for Department of Agriculture (Department) use of flexible fuel vehicles.<br/>Directs the Secretary of Agriculture, in conjunction with the Colorado Renewable Energy Collaboratory, to carry out a renewable energy research and development program. Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish a standardized protocol for market-based trading of greenhouse gas emissions reductions from soil carbon sequestration to monitor soil carbon sequestration and increases in soil carbon stocks associated with agricultural management practices; (2) provide grants to land-grant colleges and universities to develop renewable energy and value-added curricula and provide renewable energy extension services; and (3) provide grants to nonprofit organizations to educate fleet operators and the public about biodiesel and other renewable fuels.<br/>Provides for a joint Department-Department of Energy study and report on reducing the costs of producing electricity from renewable resources.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
