<bill session="110" type="s" number="1907" updated="2009-01-09T15:47:29-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1185854400" datetime="2007-07-31"/></status>

	<introduced date="1185854400" datetime="2007-07-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Meth Mouth Correctional Costs and Reentry Support Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to understand and comprehensively address the inmate oral health problems associated with methamphetamine use, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300005"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="2008-01-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412242" joined="2008-05-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2008-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300016" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2008-07-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300026" joined="2008-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="412244" joined="2008-01-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2008-01-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1185854400" datetime="2007-07-31"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/31/2007--Introduced.<br/>Meth Mouth Correctional Costs and Reentry Support Act - Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to require the Director of the Bureau of Justice Statistics to: (1) include in criminal justice system statistics data about the oral health of federal inmates and dental care provided in federal correctional facilities; and (2) conduct a study on how methampehtamine use affects the demand for (and provision of) oral health care in such facilities.<br/>Provides for Department of Justice (DOJ) grants to states and local, territorial, and tribal governments for: (1) oral health dental programs for federal inmates; (2) evaluating the extent to which poor oral health undermines or impedes an inmate's successful reentry into the community; and (3) establishing adult and juvenile offender reentry demonstration projects for inmate oral health programs during incarceration and after release.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
