<bill session="110" type="s" number="1919" updated="2009-01-09T15:48:59-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1185940800" datetime="2007-08-01"/></status>

	<introduced date="1185940800" datetime="2007-08-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Trade Enforcement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish trade enforcement priorities for the United States, to strengthen the provisions relating to trade remedies, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300005"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2007-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300052" joined="2007-08-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1185940800" datetime="2007-08-01"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S10609-10610)</text></action>
		<action date="1185940800" datetime="2007-08-01"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Committee on Finance. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/1/2007--Introduced.<br/>Trade Enforcement Act of 2007 - Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to revise certain trade provisions to require the United States Trade Representative (USTR) to identify and report to Congress on: (1) U.S. trade enforcement priorities; (2) U.S. trade enforcement actions taken during the previous year and their impact in addressing foreign trade barriers; and (3) priority foreign country trade practices the USTR will focus U.S. trade enforcement efforts. Requires the USTR to seek satisfactory resolution of any identified priority foreign country trade practice (including elimination or compensatory trade benefits) with the country concerned under the auspices of the World Trade Organization (WTO), pursuant to a bilateral or regional trade agreement to which the United States is a party, or by any other means. Establishes the WTO Dispute Settlement Review Commission. Requires a recommendation from the International Trade Commission (ITC) before the President can impose any duty or other import restriction on an imported Chinese product that causes or threatens market disruption to a like U.S. product. Requires an ITC recommendation to take effect upon enactment of a joint resolution by Congress disapproving presidential action where the President takes action that differs from such recommendation or declines to take action because it would have an adverse impact on the U.S. economy. Amends the Tariff Act of 1930 to apply countervailing duty provisions to nonmarket economy countries. Establishes: (1) the position of Chief Trade Enforcement Officer in the Office of the USTR; (2) an interagency Trade Enforcement Working Group. Grants the ITC authority to appoint hearing officers (other than administrative law judges) to preside over intellectual property rights infringement cases before the ITC. Defines the role of the interagency trade organization with respect to the performance of the functions of the USTR.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
