<bill session="110" type="s" number="1924" updated="2009-01-09T15:49:37-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1214366400" datetime="2008-06-25" /></status>

	<introduced date="1185940800" datetime="2007-08-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Firefighters Fairness Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Federal Firefighters Fairness Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend chapter 81 of title 5, United States Code, to create a presumption that a disability or death of a Federal employee in fire protection activities caused by any of certain diseases is the result of the performance of such employee's duty.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300019"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2008-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2007-09-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2008-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2008-07-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2008-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2008-03-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-09-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-12-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-10-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="412243" joined="2007-09-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2008-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2008-06-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-09-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400194" joined="2007-09-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300099" joined="2007-08-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1185940800" datetime="2007-08-01"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1187755200" datetime="2007-08-22"><text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs referred to Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1214366400" datetime="2008-06-25" ><text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1222833600" datetime="2008-10-01"><text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="1102" date="1222833600" datetime="2008-10-01" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1102.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1226898000" datetime="2008-11-17"><text>By Senator Lieberman from Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs filed written report. Report No. 110-520.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/1/2007--Introduced.<br/>Federal Firefighters Fairness Act of 2007 - Amends federal law to provide that, in the case of an employee in fire protection activities: (1) heart disease, lung disease, specified cancers and infectious diseases shall be presumed to be proximately caused by the employee's employment; (2) the disability or death of an employee in fire protection activities due to such a disease shall be presumed to result from personal injury sustained while in the performance of such employee's duty; and (3) such presumptions may be rebutted by a preponderance of the evidence. 
	</summary>
</bill>
