<bill session="110" type="s" number="1938" updated="2009-01-09T15:51:19-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"/></status>

	<introduced date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Flood Mapping Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the reviewing, updating, and maintenance of National Flood Insurance Program rate maps, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300081"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/2/2007--Introduced.<br/>National Flood Mapping Act of 2007 - Establishes the Technical Mapping Advisory Council to make certain recommendations to the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), including: (1) how to improve in a cost-effective manner the accuracy and dissemination of flood insurance rate maps and risk data; (2) mapping standards and guidelines for flood insurance rate maps and data integrity; (3) how to maintain on an ongoing basis flood insurance rate maps and flood risk identification; and (4) procedures for delegating mapping activities to state and local mapping partners.<br/>Instructs the Administrator to: (1) report to certain congressional committees on actions taken to address such recommendations; and (2) establish an ongoing program to review, update, and maintain the National Flood Insurance Program rate maps.<br/>Requires the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Administrator, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, and the heads of each federal entity implementing such activities to work together to ensure that flood risk determination data and geospatial data are shared among federal agencies.<br/>Amends the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to repeal the limitation placed upon state contributions for updating flood maps.<br/>Directs the Administrator to contract with the National Academy of Public Administration to study and report to Congress on how the FEMA: (1) should improve interagency and intergovernmental coordination on flood mapping; and (2) can establish joint funding mechanisms with federal agencies and governmental entities to share data among all governmental users.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
