<bill session="110" type="s" number="1930" updated="2009-01-09T15:50:22-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1185940800" datetime="2007-08-01"/></status>

	<introduced date="1185940800" datetime="2007-08-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Combat Illegal Logging Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Lacey Act Amendments of 1981 to prevent illegal logging practices, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300100"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="2007-10-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300002" joined="2007-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300005" joined="2007-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2007-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-10-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300008" joined="2007-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2007-10-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="2007-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400619" joined="2007-10-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-10-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="2007-10-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2007-10-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300095" joined="2007-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-10-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300049" joined="2007-09-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1185940800" datetime="2007-08-01"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S10621-10622)</text></action>
		<action date="1185940800" datetime="2007-08-01"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S10622-10623"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/1/2007--Introduced.<br/>Combat Illegal Logging Act of 2007 - Amends the Lacey Act Amendments of 1981 to redefine the term &quot;plant&quot; to include products of plants and to exclude any common food crop or cultivar that is a species not listed: (1) in the Convention on International Trade in Endangered Species of Wild Fauna and Flora; or (2) as an endangered or threatened species under the Endangered Species Act of 1973. Redefines the term &quot;take&quot; to include harvesting, cutting, logging, or removing a plant.<br/>Makes it unlawful to import, export, transport, sell, receive, acquire, possess, or purchase in interstate or foreign commerce plants: (1) taken, transported, possessed, or sold in violation of specified foreign or state law; (2) taken, transported, or exported without the payment of royalties, taxes, or stumpage fees required by foreign or state law; or (3) exported or transshipped in violation of any limitation under foreign or state law.<br/>Makes it unlawful to import plants unless the importer files, when clearance is requested, a declaration that contains: (1) the scientific name of any plant contained in the importation; and (2) a description of the value of the importation, the quantity of the plant, and the name of the country from which the plant was taken. Sets forth requirements concerning the contents of a declaration. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to promulgate regulations to limit the applicability of, or to modify, declaration requirements.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
