<bill session="110" type="s" number="1941" updated="2009-01-09T15:51:42-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1201669200" datetime="2008-01-30" /></status>

	<introduced date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Wolf House Study Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Wolf House Study Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of the Interior to study the suitability and feasibility of designating the Wolf House, located in Norfolk, Arkansas, as a unit of the National Park System, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300068"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300080" joined="2007-08-02"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1194498000" datetime="2007-11-08"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-282.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1201669200" datetime="2008-01-30" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1207800000" datetime="2008-04-10"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 110-303.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="655" date="1207800000" datetime="2008-04-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 655.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1213156800" datetime="2008-06-11"><text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S5530"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/10/2008--Reported to Senate amended. Wolf House Study Act of 2008 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to complete a special resource study of the Wolf House, located on Highway 5 in Norfork, Arkansas, to determine: (1) the suitability and feasibility of designating the Wolf House as a unit of the National Park System; and (2) the methods and means for the protection and interpretation of the Wolf House by the National Park Service, other government entities, and private and nonprofit organizations.<br/>Requires a report to Congress containing study results and recommendations.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
