<bill session="110" type="s" number="1954" updated="2009-01-09T15:53:24-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"/></status>

	<introduced date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Pharmacy Access Improvement (PhAIm) Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to improve access to pharmacies under part D.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300005"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300002" joined="2008-06-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2008-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-10-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2008-04-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300088" joined="2008-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400619" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300013" joined="2008-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300041" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300068" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2007-09-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300037" joined="2007-09-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="2008-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400546" joined="2008-06-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300083" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300035" joined="2007-10-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400432" joined="2008-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-10-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300010" joined="2007-09-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300080" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300048" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2008-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2008-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300021" joined="2007-12-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-12-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412248" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2008-07-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300026" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="412244" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400194" joined="2007-12-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2007-10-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300090" joined="2007-08-02"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S10802)</text></action>
		<action date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/2/2007--Introduced.<br/>Pharmacy Access Improvement (PhAIm) Act of 2007 - Amends part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program ) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) with respect to participating pharmacies and standards for access to them. Requires that such standards ensure that enrollees residing in long-term care facilities have access to a long-term care network pharmacy.<br/>Requires prompt payment of clean claims to pharmacies by prescription drug plans (PDPs) and Medicare Advantage prescription drug plans (MA-PD Plans). Defines prompt payment as payment occurring within 14 days from submission for claims submitted electronically, and within 30 days for claims submitted otherwise. Requires payment of interest if a payment is not issued, mailed, or otherwise transmitted within the applicable number of calendar days.<br/>Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a 24-hour toll-free telephone number dedicated to providing Medicare prescription drug benefit information to pharmacists and pharmacy staff.<br/>Requires PDP sponsors to establish toll-free pharmacy and physician and provider hotlines.<br/>Prohibits a Medicare prescription drug card issued by a PDP sponsor from displaying the name, brand, logo, or trademark (co-branding) of any pharmacy.<br/>Provides for submission of claims by pharmacies located in or contracting with long-term care facilities.<br/>Requires the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services to analyze and report to the Secretary on the cost of dispensing covered part D drugs under a PDP or an MA-PD plan.<br/>Provides that, if the PDP sponsor uses a standard for reimbursement of pharmacies based on the cost of a drug, each contract entered into with such sponsor with respect to the plan shall require the sponsor to update the standard at least once every seven days.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
