<bill session="110" type="s" number="1958" updated="2009-01-09T15:53:55-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"/></status>

	<introduced date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Long-Term Care Hospital Patient Safety and Improvement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to ensure and foster continued patient quality of care by establishing facility and patient criteria for long-term care hospitals and related improvements under the Medicare program.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300026"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412242" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-10-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-10-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300098" joined="2007-10-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300052" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400621" joined="2007-12-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300092" joined="2007-09-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300068" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="412249" joined="2007-10-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300037" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300077" joined="2007-10-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400546" joined="2007-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300083" joined="2007-09-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300054" joined="2007-11-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400418" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300080" joined="2007-10-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300040" joined="2007-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300014" joined="2007-09-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300027" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-11-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300050" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2007-10-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300021" joined="2007-09-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300069" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400194" joined="2007-09-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300072" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300099" joined="2007-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="2007-08-02"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/2/2007--Introduced.<br/>Medicare Long-Term Care Hospital Patient Safety and Improvement Act of 2007 - Creates a cross reference to provisions in the Medicare, Medicaid, and SCHIP Balanced Budget Refinement Act of 1999 and the Medicare, Medicaid, and SCHIP Benefits Improvement and Protection Act of 2000 for the prospective payment of long-term care hospitals.<br/>Makes the base rate for a long-term care hospital for the rate year 2008 the same as that used for discharges in the previous rate year. Defines &quot;long-term care hospital&quot; and establishes new patient criteria for long-term care hospital prospective payment. Requires the Secretary to approve distinct part rehabilitation units in certain long-term care hospitals if rehabilitation services are not included within one of the major diagnostic categories.<br/>Requires the Secretary to recommend to Congress and, after rulemaking, implement national long-term care hospital facility and patient criteria.<br/>Directs the Secretary to contract with one or more appropriate utilization and quality control peer review organizations to review the medical necessity of long-term care admissions and continued stays for individuals entitled to benefits under Medicare part A. Creates a separate classification for certain long-stay cancer hospitals, including satellites or remote locations if certain requirements are met.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
