<bill session="110" type="s" number="1969" updated="2009-01-09T15:55:24-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1201669200" datetime="2008-01-30" /></status>

	<introduced date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Alexander Hamilton Boyhood Home Study Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a special resource study to determine the suitability and feasibility of designating Estate Grange and other sites related to Alexander Hamilton's life on the island of St. Croix in the United States Virgin Islands as a unit of the National Park System, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300052"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300030" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300013" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300078" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300006" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300084" joined="2007-08-02"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S10809-10810)</text></action>
		<action date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1190865600" datetime="2007-09-27"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-266.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1201669200" datetime="2008-01-30" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1207800000" datetime="2008-04-10"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with amendments. With written report No. 110-305.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="657" date="1207800000" datetime="2008-04-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 657.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/2/2007--Introduced.<br/>Alexander Hamilton Boyhood Home Study Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with the Governor of the Virgin Islands, to conduct a special resource study of Estate Grange and other sites and resources associated with Alexander Hamilton's life on St. Croix in the U.S. Virgin Islands. Instructs the Secretary to evaluate the national significance of the sites and resources and the suitability and feasibility of designating them as a unit of the National Park System.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
