<bill session="110" type="s" number="1971" updated="2009-01-09T15:55:39-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"/></status>

	<introduced date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Hire a Hero Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize a competitive grant program to assist members of the National Guard and Reserve and former and current members of the Armed Forces in securing employment in the private sector, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300060"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300005" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300010" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-09-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="412243" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300026" joined="2007-09-11"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/2/2007--Introduced.<br/>Hire a Hero Act - Expresses the sense of Congress that the federal government should support private sector employment initiatives for military personnel to help ensure that those who serve or have served in the Armed Forces have access to gainful employment. Authorizes the Chief of the National Guard Bureau (Chief) to award grants to nonprofit organizations to assist the following individuals in securing employment in the private sector: (1) a member of the National Guard or reserve; (2) a member of the Armed Forces who is nearing separation, discharge, or release; and (3) a former member of the Armed Forces. Expresses the sense of Congress that the Chief, in awarding such grants, should consider organizations that partner with private entities and associations involved in construction, energy, transportation, aerospace, domestic security, and other areas in which the employment of individuals having past military service would be of particular utility. Requires the Chief to establish fiscal control, accountability, and program performance measures for grantees.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
