<bill session="110" type="s" number="1979" updated="2009-01-09T15:56:42-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"/></status>

	<introduced date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to provide for school improvement, comprehensive, high-quality multi-year induction and mentoring for new teachers, and professional development for experienced teachers, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300081"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-08-02"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S10813-10814)</text></action>
		<action date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S10814-10816"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/2/2007--Introduced.<br/>Amends title II of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to direct the Secretary of Education to award grants to states for subgrants to local educational agencies (LEAs) to assist low-achieving, high-need schools that serve a high proportion of low-income students in implementing: (1) comprehensive, coherent, high-quality induction and mentoring programs for teachers during at least their first two years of full-time teaching; and (2) ongoing, high-impact professional development programs for teachers, principals, and administrators. Requires the induction and professional development programs to be: (1) integrated and aligned; (2) aligned with the state's school improvement efforts under title I of the ESEA; and (3) subject to a formal evaluation conducted by the state, institutions of higher education, or external agencies experienced in qualitative research. Permits LEAs to use school improvement funds under title I of the ESEA to supplement this Act's induction and professional development program grants.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
