<bill session="110" type="s" number="1981" updated="2009-01-09T15:56:58-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"/></status>

	<introduced date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">No Child Left Inside Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 regarding environmental education, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300081"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2008-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="2007-12-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400619" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2008-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2008-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300068" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2008-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="2007-12-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2007-12-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S10817, S10820-110821)</text></action>
		<action date="1186027200" datetime="2007-08-02"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S10817-10820"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/2/2007--Introduced.<br/>No Child Left Inside Act of 2007 - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to require states, as a prerequisite to receiving implementation grants, to develop environmental literacy plans, approved by the Secretary of Education, for kindergarten through grade 12 (K-12) that include environmental education standards and teacher training. Directs the Secretary to award Environmental Education Professional Development Grants to states and, through them, competitive subgrants to partnerships that include an LEA and, permissibly, institutions of higher education (IHE), other educational entities, or state or local natural resource or environmental agencies, for activities involving, among other things, teacher training and the operation of model environmental education programs. Authorizes the Secretary to award competitive matching grants to nonprofit organizations, states, LEAs, or IHEs for activities to improve and support environmental education that include: (1) advancing content and achievement standards; (2) developing or disseminating innovations or model programs; (3) research; and (4) creating new funding sources. Authorizes the use of grants to states out of the Teacher and Principal Training and Recruiting Fund for activities incorporating field-based learning, service learning, and outdoor experiential learning into the curricula and instruction. Authorizes the use of funds under the Fund for the Improvement of Education program to advance environmental education. Amends the Department of Education Organization Act to create an Office of Environmental Education to advance K-12 environmental education and administer environmental education grant programs.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
