<bill session="110" type="s" number="1998" updated="2009-01-09T15:59:13-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"/></status>

	<introduced date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">International Child Marriage Prevention and Protection Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reduce child marriage, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300038"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2008-04-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="2008-04-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2008-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300068" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2008-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="2008-07-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="2007-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2008-04-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-10-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300050" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2007-08-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S10906-10908"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/3/2007--Introduced.<br/>International Child Marriage Prevention and Protection Act of 2007 - Requires the Secretary of State to develop a comprehensive strategy to reduce the incidences of child marriage by further integrating this issue into U.S. development efforts. Requires the Secretary to report to Congress on such strategy and on child marriage and related U.S. assistance programs. Authorizes the President to provide assistance for programs to reduce the incidences of child marriage and promote the empowerment of girls, including support for the treatment and reduction of fistula in countries with high rates of such surgery. Requires the Secretary to work through the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) and other appropriate agencies as part of their ongoing research and data collection activities concerning child marriage. Requires the Secretary to include in the Department of State's Annual Country Reports on Human Rights Practices a section for each country where child marriage is prevalent, outlining the status of the practice.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
