<bill session="110" type="s" number="2005" updated="2009-01-09T16:00:15-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"/></status>

	<introduced date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Secondhand Smoke Education and Outreach Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to provide education on the health consequences of exposure to secondhand smoke, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300022"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-08-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S10933-10935)</text></action>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/3/2007--Introduced.<br/>Secondhand Smoke Education and Outreach Act of 2007 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, to award grants for: (1) educational campaigns on the health consequences of secondhand smoke in multiunit housing; and (2) projects to demonstrate ways of educating the public about the health consequences of secondhand smoking in public spaces, including public parks, playgrounds, and national parks. Directs the Secretary to award grants for regional or local education programs to provide health care providers and workers with minimum tobacco cessation training as part of their ongoing education. Allows the Secretary to contract, where appropriate, with public health organizations for evaluations of tobacco dependence treatment and educational programs under this Act.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
