<bill session="110" type="s" number="2014" updated="2009-01-09T16:01:19-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"/></status>

	<introduced date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for statewide longitudinal data systems to improve elementary and secondary education, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400050"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-08-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1186113600" datetime="2007-08-03"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/3/2007--Introduced.<br/>Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award competitive five-year matching grants to states to build or upgrade statewide pre- through high-school longitudinal data systems that include: (1) unique and consistent statewide student identifiers; (2) the ability to track student participation and performance over time; (3) unique and consistent statewide teacher identifiers that match student records to the appropriate teacher; and (4) the ability to link their data to data from higher education, workforce development, unemployment insurance, child welfare, juvenile justice, and military services information systems. Increases the state match required as a grant matures. Authorizes the Secretary to award matching grants to states to build the capacity of educators and policymakers, at the local educational agency and school level, to use data and data systems by: (1) training educational personnel to effectively collect, report, and use data; (2) developing processes to analyze and disseminate the best approaches for using the data systems to enhance teaching and learning; and (3) aligning statewide longitudinal data systems with local student information management systems and curriculum or instructional management systems. Provides such funding as is necessary to support a state education data center and state educational data coordinators.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
