<bill session="110" type="s" number="2020" updated="2009-01-09T16:02:04-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1189483200" datetime="2007-09-11" /></status>

	<introduced date="1189051200" datetime="2007-09-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Tropical Forest and Coral Conservation Reauthorization Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Tropical Forest and Coral Conservation Reauthorization Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reauthorize the Tropical Forest Conservation Act of 1998 through fiscal year 2010, to rename the Tropical Forest Conservation Act of 1998 as the &quot;Tropical Forest and Coral Conservation Act of 2007&quot;, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300070"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="2007-09-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300055" joined="2007-12-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300008" joined="2007-09-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2008-09-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300013" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-11-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-12-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2008-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-09-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300078" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300050" joined="2007-09-11"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1189051200" datetime="2007-09-06"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1189483200" datetime="2007-09-11" ><text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1192420800" datetime="2007-10-15"><text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Biden without amendment and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 110-196.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="419" date="1192420800" datetime="2007-10-15" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 419.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/15/2007--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.) Tropical Forest and Coral Conservation Reauthorization Act of 2007 - (Sec. 2) Renames the Tropical Forest Conservation Act of 1998 as The Tropical Forest and Coral Conservation Act of 2007 (Act) . (Sec. 3) Includes tropical forests and coral reefs and associated coastal marine ecosystems within the scope of such Act. (Current law refers to tropical forests.) (Sec. 4) Renames the Tropical Forest Facility as the Conservation Facility. (Sec. 5) Makes developing countries with tropical forests or coral reefs eligible for benefits. (Current law refers to tropical forests.) (Sec. 6) Authorizes U.S. government representation on the administering body that oversees the implementation of grants from a debt-for-nature swap or debt buy-back regardless of whether the United States is a party to any agreement between the eligible purchaser and the government of the beneficiary country. (Sec. 7) Eliminates the requirement that the Enterprise for the Americas Board be consulted in negotiating a Conservation Agreement. Requires U.S. government and beneficiary country government review of Conservation Fund grants in excess of $250,000. (Sec. 8) Renames: (1) the Tropical Forest Agreement as the Conservation Agreement; and (2) the Tropical Forest Fund as the Conservation Fund. (Sec. 9) Repeals Board authority to carry out activities under the Act. (Sec. 10) Revises certain reporting dates. (Sec. 11) Revises specified International Monetary Fund (IMF) criteria for country eligibility. (Sec. 12) Authorizes FY2008-FY2010 appropriations. Increases obligations for program administration, monitoring, and auditing.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
