<bill session="110" type="s" number="2030" updated="2009-01-09T16:03:19-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1189051200" datetime="2007-09-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1189051200" datetime="2007-09-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to require reporting relating to bundled contributions made by persons other than registered lobbyists.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400629"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="2007-09-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1189051200" datetime="2007-09-06"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/6/2007--Introduced.<br/>Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971, as amended by the Honest Leadership and Open Government Act of 2007, to revise requirements for disclosure of bundled contributions, particularly by an authorized committee of a candidate for the office of President or for nomination to such office (presidential candidate committee).<br/>Applies such reporting requirements to bundled contributions by persons other than registered lobbyists. Requires reporting of lobbyist contributions on a separate schedule.<br/>Sets the covered period for such reports as the two-year period preceding a presidential election, as well as any applicable reporting period during which any person provided two or more bundled contributions in an aggregate amount greater than the specified applicable amount.<br/>Increases the applicable threshold triggering such reporting requirement from $15,000 (currently applicable to any authorized committee of a candidate, a leadership PAC, or a political party committee) to $50,000 in the case of a presidential candidate committee. Excludes from the calculation of a bundled contribution any contribution by the candidate or the candidate's spouse.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
