<bill session="110" type="s" number="2042" updated="2009-01-09T16:04:48-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1189569600" datetime="2007-09-12"/></status>

	<introduced date="1189569600" datetime="2007-09-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">SMA Treatment Acceleration Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to conduct activities to rapidly advance treatments for spinal muscular atrophy, neuromuscular disease, and other pediatric diseases, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300093"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2008-06-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2008-02-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-10-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2008-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2008-06-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2007-09-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300081" joined="2007-12-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412249" joined="2007-12-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-12-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2008-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2008-06-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2008-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300021" joined="2007-10-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2008-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2008-06-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400194" joined="2007-09-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300099" joined="2007-09-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2007-12-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1189569600" datetime="2007-09-12"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S11510-11511)</text></action>
		<action date="1189569600" datetime="2007-09-12"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/12/2007--Introduced.<br/>SMA Treatment Acceleration Act - Requires the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to upgrade and unify existing spinal muscular atrophy (SMA) clinical trial sites to establish a national clinical trials network for SMA. Requires the Director of NIH to ensure that such network: (1) conducts coordinated, multisite, clinical trials of pharmacological approaches to the treatment of SMA; and (2) rapidly and effectively disseminates scientific findings to the field.<br/>Requires the Director of NIH to: (1) establish an SMA data coordinating center; and (2) expand and intensify NIH programs with respect to preclinical translation research and medicinal chemistry related to SMA.<br/>Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to enhance and provide ongoing support to the existing SMA patient registry to provide for expanded research on the epidemiology of SMA. Directs the Secretary to ensure the collection and analysis of longitudinal data related to individuals of all ages with SMA.<br/>Requires the Secretary to establish the Spinal Muscular Atrophy Coordinating Committee to: (1) coordinate activities across NIH and with other federal health programs and activities relating to SMA; and (2) conduct a study to identify barriers to the development of drugs for treating SMA and similar genetic disorders.<br/>Requires the Director of NIH to establish a trans-National Institutes of Health cooperative research initiative on SMA to ensure the success of the SMA projects led by the National Institute of Neurological Disorders and Stroke. Requires the Secretary to submit recommendations to Congress to improve and expand on incentives provided under the Orphan Drug Act and related statutes to promote SMA drug development.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
