<bill session="110" type="s" number="2044" updated="2009-01-09T16:05:02-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1189569600" datetime="2007-09-12"/></status>

	<introduced date="1189569600" datetime="2007-09-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Independent Contractor Proper Classification Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide procedures for the proper classification of employees and independent contractors, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400629"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-09-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-09-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-09-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-09-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1189569600" datetime="2007-09-12"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/12/2007--Introduced.<br/>Independent Contractor Proper Classification Act of 2007 - Amends the Revenue Act of 1978 to: (1) require employers to treat workers misclassified as independent contractors as employees for employment tax purposes upon a determination of misclassification by the Secretary of the Treasury; (2) repeal the ban on Treasury regulations or revenue rulings on employee/independent contractor classifications; and (3) eliminate the defense of industry practice as a justification for misclassifying workers as independent contractors. Requires the Secretary to establish a procedure for workers to petition for a determination of their status as employees or independent contractors. Prohibits employers from retaliating against workers filing a petition. Requires the Secretary to take certain actions upon determining that an employee has been misclassified as an independent contractor, including informing the Department of Labor of such misclassification.<br/>Requires the Secretaries of the Treasury and Labor to issue annual reports and exchange information on worker misclassification cases. Directs the Secretary of Labor to: (1) identify and track complaints involving worker misclassification for purposes of enforcing wage and hour laws; and (2) investigate industries identified by the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) as misclassifying workers.<br/>Directs the Secretary of Labor to include on workplace posters required by the Fair Labor Standards Act a notice informing workers of their right to seek a status determination (i.e., whether they are employees or independent contractors) from the IRS.<br/>Requires employers to: (1) notify their independent contractors of their federal tax obligations, the labor and employment protections inapplicable to independent contractors, and their right to seek a status determination from the IRS; and (2) maintain for three years a list of their independent contractors, including names and tax identification numbers.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
