<bill session="110" type="s" number="2062" updated="2009-01-09T16:07:18-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22" where="s" result="pass" how="by Unanimous Consent" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1190088000" datetime="2007-09-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Reauthorization Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Reauthorization Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Reauthorization Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Reauthorization Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 to reauthorize that Act, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300037"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="2008-06-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300082" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2007-10-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300075" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300036" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="412244" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2007-09-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1190088000" datetime="2007-09-18"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S11657-11658)</text></action>
		<action date="1190088000" datetime="2007-09-18"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S11658-11662"/></action>
		<calendar date="1190865600" datetime="2007-09-27" ><text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1197003600" datetime="2007-12-07"><text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Dorgan with amendments. With written report No. 110-238.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="526" date="1197003600" datetime="2007-12-07" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 526.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1197262800" datetime="2007-12-10"><text>Referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs pursuant to the order of May 27, 1988, for not to exceed 60 days.</text></action>
		<action date="1202446800" datetime="2008-02-08"><text>Senate Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs discharged pursuant to the order of May 27, 1988.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="569" date="1202446800" datetime="2008-02-08" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 569.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S4839-4844"/><reference label="text of measure as reported in Senate" ref="CR S4839-4844"/></action>
		<vote date="1211428800" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2008-05-22" where="s" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>Passed Senate with amendments by Unanimous Consent. (text: CR 6/2/2008 S4895-4899)</text></vote>
		<action date="1212379200" datetime="2008-06-02"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<action date="1212513180" datetime="2008-06-03T14:13:00-04:00"><text>Received in the House.</text></action>
		<action date="1212518760" datetime="2008-06-03T15:46:00-04:00"><text>Held at the desk.</text></action>
		<action date="1216224660" datetime="2008-07-16T13:11:00-04:00"><text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1339, S. 2062 is considered passed House as amended.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H6599"/></action>
		<action date="1216224660" datetime="2008-07-16T13:11:00-04:00"><text>House insisted on its amendment and asked for a conference pursuant to H. Res. 1339.</text></action>
		<action date="1216301460" datetime="2008-07-17T10:31:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Roskam moved that the House instruct conferees.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H6681-6688"/><reference label="text" ref="CR H6681"/></action>
		<action date="1216301460" datetime="2008-07-17T10:31:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the Roskam motion to instruct conferees on S. 2062. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the managers on the part of the House to agree to language providing that development and rehabilitation of utilities and utility services shall be eligible affordable housing activities under the Indian Housing Block Grant Program.</text></action>
		<action date="1216305480" datetime="2008-07-17T11:38:00-04:00"><text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H6688"/></action>
		<action date="1216305480" datetime="2008-07-17T11:38:00-04:00"><text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Agreed to by voice vote.</text></action>
		<action date="1216267200" datetime="2008-07-17"><text>Message on House action received in Senate and at desk: House amendment to Senate bill House requests a conference.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/16/2008--Passed House amended. Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Reauthorization Act of 2007 - (Sec.2) Reauthorizes appropriations for FY2008-FY2012 for block grants under the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 (NAHASDA) for Indian tribe affordable housing activities. Considers, for purposes of the procurement and supply of personal property and nonpersonal services for executive agencies, a tribe or tribally designated housing entity to be an executive agency when carrying out housing programs, services, functions, and activities under such tribe or entity, and its employees to be eligible to have access to such supply sources as executive agency employees. Requires, with respect to any grant made under NAHASDA that is intended to benefit one tribe, the tribal employment or contract preference laws adopted by such tribe to govern the administration of the grant or grant portion. Prohibits funds authorized under this Act from being expended for the benefit of the Cherokee Nation of Oklahoma until it is in full compliance with the Treaty of 1866 and fully recognizes all Cherokee Freedmen and their descendants as citizens of the Cherokee Nation.<br/>Requires one-year Indian housing plans under NAHASDA to include a description of grant amounts made available for the preceding fiscal year which have not been, or are not expected to be, used before the beginning of the fiscal year for which a plan is submitted. Excludes from NAHASDA program income development fees paid to an Indian tribe for certain projects assisted with a low-income housing tax credit. Permits affordable housing assistance for: (1) essential (under current law, essential non-Indian) families on Indian reservations and other Indian areas; and (2) local law enforcement officers on Indian reservations or other Indian areas. Includes among affordable housing activities that are eligible for assistance: (1) the operation and maintenance of affordable housing units; and (2) the deposit of specified funds into reserve accounts established for tribes for the purpose of accumulating funds for affordable housing activities. Exempts recipients of less than $5,000 of goods and services from NAHASDA rules and procedures for competitive procurement.<br/>Allows the disclosure of criminal conviction records to Indian tribes or tribally designated housing entities for purposes of screening adult applicants for employment in housing-related positions.<br/>(Sec. 3) Establishes self-determined housing activities for the tribal communities program under which a qualifying tribe may use a portion of its grant amounts during FY2008-FY2012 for housing activities involving the construction, acquisition, or rehabilitation of housing to benefit the low-income community served by the tribe. Prohibits the use of funds for any infrastructure, commercial and economic development, and housing operating costs.<br/>Requires the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, during 2011, to conduct, and report to Congress no later than December 31, 2011, on a review of such program's results to determine: (1) the housing constructed, acquired, or rehabilitated under the program and the effects of such housing on costs to low-income families of affordable housing; (2) the effectiveness of each recipient in achieving the results intended to be achieved, as set forth in the Indian housing plan for the Indian tribe; and (3) the need for, and effectiveness of, extending the duration of the program and increasing the amount of grants that may be used under the program. (Sec. 4) Declares that NAHASDA does not prohibit or prevent any insular area or participating jurisdiction from providing amounts to Indian tribes or tribally designated housing entities for use in accordance with the HOME Investment Partnership Act.<br/>(Sec. 5) Requires the Comptroller General to study and report to Congress on the effectiveness of NAHASDA in meeting the needs for affordable housing for low-income Indian families<br/>(Sec. 6) Requires the Secretary to carry out training and information activities that include conducting educational seminars with tribes and tribally designated housing entities on how to utilize the loan guarantee program. Extends through FY2012 the aggregate fiscal year limitation with regard to federal guarantees for financing tribal housing activities. Authorizes appropriations for FY2008-FY2012 for: (1) the costs of making such guarantees; (2) training and technical assistance to Indian housing authorities and tribally designated housing entities; and (3) block grants for affordable housing activities for Native Hawaiian families who are eligible to reside on the Hawaiian home lands. (Sec. 9) Authorizes the Secretary to guarantee notes and obligations issued by Indian tribes or tribally designated housing entities with tribal approval to finance activities carried out on Indian reservations and in other Indian areas that are eligible for financing under the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974. Requires no less than 70% of the aggregate funds received by an Indian tribe from a guaranteed loan to be used for the support of activities that benefit low-income Indian families.<br/>Requires the Secretary to: (1) establish underwriting criteria and other requirements to ensure the financial soundness of the loan guarantee program and the repayment of loans; and (2) carry out training and information activities with respect to the guarantee program. Authorizes appropriations for FY2008-2012. Imposes limitations on the amount of loan guarantees, including: (1) an annual fiscal year limitation of $200 million for FY2008-FY2012; and (2) an aggregate limitation on outstanding guarantees of $1 billion.<br/>Requires the Secretary to report to Congress on the loan guarantee program within four years after the enactment of this Act. Terminates the Secretary's authority to make new loan guarantees on October 1, 2012.<br/>(Sec. 10) Prohibits the use of funds under this Act to employ unauthorized aliens.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
