<bill session="110" type="s" number="2064" updated="2009-01-09T16:07:33-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1190088000" datetime="2007-09-18"/></status>

	<introduced date="1190088000" datetime="2007-09-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Nurse Training and Retention Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to fund comprehensive programs to ensure an adequate supply of nurses.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300038"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="2008-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="2007-09-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2008-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2007-09-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2008-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-12-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-09-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1190088000" datetime="2007-09-18"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S11665)</text></action>
		<action date="1190088000" datetime="2007-09-18"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S11665-11667"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/18/2007--Introduced.<br/>Nurse Training and Retention Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of Labor to establish a partnership grant program to award grants to eligible entities to carry out comprehensive programs to provide education to nurses and create a pipeline to nursing for incumbent ancillary healthcare workers who wish to advance their careers.<br/>Includes as eligible to receive a grant: (1) a healthcare entity that is jointly administered by a healthcare employer and a labor union representing its employees and that carries out activities using labor management training funds; (2) an entity that operates a training program that is jointly administered by one or more healthcare providers or facilities, or a trade association of healthcare providers, and one or more organizations that represent the interests of direct care healthcare workers or staff nurses who have direct input as to the organization's leadership; or (3) a state training partnership program that consists of nonprofit organizations that include equal participation from industry and labor organizations including joint labor-management training programs.<br/>Requires a healthcare employer, to be eligible for a grant, to demonstrate that it: (1) has an established program within its facility to encourage the retention of existing nurses; (2) provides wages and benefits to its nurses that are competitive for its market or that have been collectively bargained with a labor organization; and (3) provides support for programs funded under this Act through specified mechanisms.<br/>Sets forth requirements for matching funds, collaboration with nursing schools, types of programs funded, types to be provided preference, and program evaluations.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
