<bill session="110" type="s" number="2070" updated="2009-01-09T16:08:19-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1190260800" datetime="2007-09-20" /></status>

	<introduced date="1190174400" datetime="2007-09-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Government Shutdown Prevention Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prevent Government shutdowns.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400105"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300029" joined="2007-09-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300030" joined="2007-09-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300052" joined="2007-09-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-09-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300088" joined="2007-09-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300013" joined="2007-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300041" joined="2007-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400576" joined="2007-09-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300062" joined="2007-09-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300054" joined="2007-09-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400418" joined="2007-09-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300040" joined="2007-10-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300014" joined="2007-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300003" joined="2007-09-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300027" joined="2007-09-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300069" joined="2007-09-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300049" joined="2007-09-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300072" joined="2007-09-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1190174400" datetime="2007-09-19"><text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1190260800" datetime="2007-09-20" ><text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 380.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/19/2007--Introduced.<br/>Government Shutdown Prevention Act - Provides for automatic continuing appropriations if any regular appropriation for a fiscal year (or, if applicable, for each fiscal year in a biennium) does not become law before the beginning of such fiscal year, or a joint resolution making continuing appropriations is not in effect. Appropriates amounts necessary to continue any project or activity for which funds were provided in the preceding fiscal year: (1) in the corresponding regular appropriation Act for such preceding fiscal year; or (2) if such legislation did not become law, then in the joint resolution making continuing appropriations for such preceding fiscal year. Requires the appropriations and funds made available, and authority granted, for any fiscal year for a project or activity to be available for the period beginning with the first day of a lapse in appropriations and ending with the earlier of: (1) the date on which the applicable regular appropriation bill for such fiscal year becomes law (whether or not such law provides for such project or activity) or a continuing resolution making appropriations becomes law, as the case may be; or (2) the last day of such fiscal year. 
	</summary>
</bill>
