<bill session="110" type="s" number="2087" updated="2009-01-09T16:10:23-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1190865600" datetime="2007-09-27" /></status>

	<introduced date="1190692800" datetime="2007-09-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Native American Omnibus Technical Corrections Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Native American Omnibus Technical Corrections Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend certain laws relating to Native Americans to make technical corrections, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300037"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300005" joined="2007-10-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300071" joined="2007-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300062" joined="2007-10-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1190692800" datetime="2007-09-25"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1190865600" datetime="2007-09-27" ><text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1208318400" datetime="2008-04-16"><text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Dorgan without amendment. With written report No. 110-326.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="700" date="1208318400" datetime="2008-04-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 700.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/16/2008--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)<br/>Native American Omnibus Technical Corrections Act of 2007 - Amends various enactments relating to Native Americans to make technical corrections.<br/>(Sec. 2) Amends the Native American Graves Protection and Repatriation Act to define “Native American” to mean of or relating to a tribe, people, or culture that is or was indigenous to any geographic area that is now located within the boundaries of the United States.<br/>(Sec. 3) Amends the Indian Tribal Justice Technical and Legal Assistance Act of 2000 to extend through FY2012 the grant programs for tribal justice training and technical assistance and for tribal justice systems. (Sec. 4) Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to include territories and Indian tribes as eligible grant recipients under a program that addresses public safety and methamphetamine manufacturing, sale, and use in hot spots.<br/>Amends the USA PATRIOT Improvement and Reauthorization Act of 2005 to include territories and Indian tribes as eligible recipients under grant programs for drug endangered children and grant programs to address methamphetamine use by pregnant and parenting women offenders.<br/>(Sec. 5) Revises legal definitions relating to interests in land and intestate descent under the Indian Land Consolidation Act.<br/>Provides for an exception to a requirement concerning devising an Indian tribe's trust or restricted land.<br/>Prohibits the presumption of joint tenancy from applying to any devise of an interest in trust or restricted land under a will executed prior to September 1, 2008. Authorizes the Secretary to extend such date by not more than one year if the Secretary publishes notice of the extension.<br/>Requires the Secretary, upon receiving a request with respect to an interest in probate from more than one eligible purchaser, to sell the interest to the eligible purchaser that is selected by the applicable heir, devisee, or surviving spouse. (Currently, the Secretary is required to sell the interest by public auction or sealed bid.)<br/>(Sec. 6) Amends the Indian Arts and Crafts Act of 1990 to: (1) authorize any federal law enforcement officer to conduct an investigation of offenses involving the sale of goods or products misrepresented as Indian-produced on lands under federal jurisdiction; (2) authorize the Indian Arts and Crafts Board to refer an alleged offense under such Act to any federal law enforcement officer for investigation (currently, referral is limited to the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI)); (3) permit any federal law enforcement officer to investigate an alleged offense without a referral from the Board; and (4) provide penalties for the misrepresentation of Indian produced goods and products.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
