<bill session="110" type="s" number="2094" updated="2009-01-09T16:11:13-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1190779200" datetime="2007-09-26"/></status>

	<introduced date="1190779200" datetime="2007-09-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Increasing American Wages and Benefits Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Indentured Servitude Abolition Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase the wages and benefits of blue collar workers by strengthening labor provisions in the H-2B program, to provide for labor recruiter accountability, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400357"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-09-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1190779200" datetime="2007-09-26"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S12143-12145)</text></action>
		<action date="1190779200" datetime="2007-09-26"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/26/2007--Introduced.<br/>Increasing American Wages and Benefits Act of 2007 - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to authorize: (1) the Secretary of Labor to enforce federal labor laws with respect to employers of H-2B nonagricultural temporary workers; and (2) a private right of action against such employers. Specifies employer actions to be taken to recruit U.S. workers prior to filing for admission of H-2B workers. Prohibits H-2B worker entry until the Secretary certifies that prevailing wages will be paid to such workers or to U.S. workers. Sets forth H-2B and U.S. worker protections. Directs the Secretary to establish an H-2B (employer) labor certification application fee. Establishes in the Treasury the H-2B Employment Certification Application Fee Account. Indentured Servitude Abolition Act of 2007 - Requires foreign labor contractors and employers to inform foreign workers of specified employment terms and conditions at the time of recruitment. Requires that such information be provided in written form in English or in the language of the worker being recruited. Prohibits worker recruitment fees. Sets forth protection and enforcement provisions.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
