<bill session="110" type="s" number="2093" updated="2009-01-09T16:11:05-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" /></status>

	<introduced date="1190692800" datetime="2007-09-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Missisquoi and Trout Rivers Wild and Scenic River Study Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Missisquoi and Trout Rivers Wild and Scenic River Study Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate a segment of the Missisquoi and Trout Rivers in the State of Vermont for study for potential addition to the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300065"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-09-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1190692800" datetime="2007-09-25"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1217390400" datetime="2008-07-30"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="978" date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 978.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/16/2008--Reported to Senate amended. Missisquoi and Trout Rivers Wild and Scenic River Study Act of 2008 - Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate a specified segment of the Missisquoi and Trout Rivers in Vermont for study for potential addition to the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System. Authorizes appropriations. 
	</summary>
</bill>
