<bill session="110" type="s" number="2134" updated="2009-01-09T16:16:08-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1191384000" datetime="2007-10-03"/></status>

	<introduced date="1191384000" datetime="2007-10-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Defense to submit to Congress reports on the status of planning for the redeployment of the Armed Forces from Iraq and to require the Secretary of Defense, the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, and appropriate senior officials of the Department of Defense to meet with Congress to brief Congress on matters contained in the reports.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400619"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300002" joined="2007-10-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2007-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300098" joined="2007-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="412249" joined="2007-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300035" joined="2007-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300080" joined="2007-10-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-10-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1191384000" datetime="2007-10-03"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/3/2007--Introduced.<br/>Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) nothing in this Act shall be construed as a recommendation by Congress that any particular contingency plan be exercised; (2) it is necessary and prudent for the Department of Defense (DOD) to undertake robust and comprehensive contingency planning; (3) contingency planning for a redeployment of Armed Forces from Iraq should address appropriate protection for U.S. Armed Forces, civilians, contractors, and third party and Iraqi nationals who have aided the U.S. mission in Iraq, and the preservation of military equipment; and (4) such planning should describe a range of scenarios and timetables for redeployment, and describe possible missions of Armed Forces remaining in Iraq. Directs the Secretary of Defense to report to the congressional defense and appropriations committees on the status of planning for the redeployment of Armed Forces from Iraq. Requires the Secretary and the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff to brief such committees on matters contained in the reports.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
