<bill session="110" type="s" number="2147" updated="2009-01-09T16:17:47-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1191470400" datetime="2007-10-04"/></status>

	<introduced date="1191470400" datetime="2007-10-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Security Contractor Accountability Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require accountability for contractors and contract personnel under Federal contracts, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400629"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300016" joined="2007-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2007-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300001" joined="2007-10-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-12-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1191470400" datetime="2007-10-04"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S12991)</text></action>
		<action date="1191470400" datetime="2007-10-04"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/4/2007--Introduced.<br/>Security Contractor Accountability Act of 2007 - Provides that persons who, while employed under a federal agency contract in or in close proximity to an area where the Armed Forces are conducting a contingency operation, engage in conduct that would constitute an offense punishable by imprisonment for more than one year if engaged in within U.S. jurisdiction shall be punished as provided for that offense.<br/>Requires the Inspector General of the Department of Justice (DOJ) to report to Congress on the status of the Department's investigations of violations alleged to have been committed by contract personnel and findings and recommendations about the Department's capacity and effectiveness in prosecuting misconduct by contract personnel.<br/>Requires the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) to ensure, through the creation of Theater Investigative Units, that there are adequate personnel to investigate allegations of criminal violations by contract personnel. 
	</summary>
</bill>
