<bill session="110" type="s" number="2148" updated="2009-01-09T16:17:54-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1214366400" datetime="2008-06-25" /></status>

	<introduced date="1191470400" datetime="2007-10-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Senior Executive Service Diversity Assurance Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Senior Executive Service Diversity Assurance Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for greater diversity within, and to improve policy direction and oversight of, the Senior Executive Service.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300001"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1191470400" datetime="2007-10-04"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S12779)</text></action>
		<action date="1191470400" datetime="2007-10-04"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S12780"/></action>
		<action date="1192766400" datetime="2007-10-19"><text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs referred to Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia.</text></action>
		<action date="1207195200" datetime="2008-04-03"><text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia. Hearings held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1214366400" datetime="2008-06-25" ><text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1222833600" datetime="2008-10-01"><text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 110-517.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="1108" date="1222833600" datetime="2008-10-01" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1108.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/4/2007--Introduced.<br/>Senior Executive Service Diversity Assurance Act - Requires the Director of the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to establish within OPM the Senior Executive Service Resource Office to make recommendations to the Director with respect to regulations, and to provide guidance to agencies, concerning the structure, management, and diverse composition of the Senior Executive Service (SES).<br/>Makes it the Office's mission to: (1) improve the efficiency, effectiveness, and productivity of the SES through policy formulation and oversight; (2) advance the professionalism of the SES; and (3) ensure that, in seeking to achieve an SES reflective of the nation's diversity, recruitment is from qualified individuals from appropriate sources.<br/>Requires the Office to make statistics concerning career reserved positions accessible to the public through a website.<br/>Requires each agency to establish one or more SES evaluation panels, with respect to any SES position for which a vacancy announcement is posted, to: (1) review the qualifications of each candidate for a position which is to be filled by a career appointee; and (2) certify to the executive resources board the names of the best qualified candidates.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
