<bill session="110" type="s" number="215" updated="2009-01-09T11:34:50-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1168318800" datetime="2007-01-09"/></status>

	<introduced date="1168318800" datetime="2007-01-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Internet Freedom Preservation Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Communications Act of 1934 to ensure net neutrality.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300037"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2008-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-12-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-01-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="2007-01-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1168318800" datetime="2007-01-09"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S286-287)</text></action>
		<action date="1168318800" datetime="2007-01-09"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S287-288"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/9/2007--Introduced.<br/>Internet Freedom Preservation Act - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to establish certain Internet neutrality duties for broadband service providers (providers), including not interfering with, or discriminating against, the ability of any person to use broadband service in a lawful manner. Allows providers to engage in activities in furtherance of certain management and business-related practices, such as protecting network security and offering consumer protection services such as parental controls. Prohibits a provider from requiring a subscriber, as a condition on the purchase of broadband service, to purchase any cable service, telecommunications service, or IP-enabled voice service. Requires a report from the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to specified congressional committees on provider delivery of broadband content, applications, and services.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
