<bill session="110" type="s" number="2156" updated="2009-01-09T16:18:56-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" /></status>

	<introduced date="1191470400" datetime="2007-10-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Science and Engineering to Comprehensively Understand and Responsibly Enhance Water Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">SECURE Water Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Science and Engineering to Comprehensively Understand and Responsibly Enhance Water Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">SECURE Water Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize and facilitate the improvement of water management by the Bureau of Reclamation, to require the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Energy to increase the acquisition and analysis of water resources for irrigation, hydroelectric power, municipal, and environmental uses, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300009"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400619" joined="2007-10-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300036" joined="2007-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="412244" joined="2007-10-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2007-10-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1191470400" datetime="2007-10-04"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S12781-12782)</text></action>
		<action date="1191470400" datetime="2007-10-04"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S12782-12786"/></action>
		<action date="1197349200" datetime="2007-12-11"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 110-312.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="979" date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 979.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/4/2007--Introduced.<br/>Science and Engineering to Comprehensively Understand and Responsibly Enhance Water Act or the SECURE Water Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior (the Secretary), acting through the Commissioner of Reclamation, to establish a climate change adaptation program to: (1) assess each effect of, and risk resulting from, global climate change regarding the quantity of water resources located in specified areas (service areas); and (2) ensure that strategies are developed to address potential water shortages, conflicts, and other impacts to water users and the environment of each service area. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) provide grants to, or enter cooperative agreements with, eligible applicants to assist in planning, designing, or constructing improvements; and (2) enter into cooperative agreements with any university, nonprofit research institution, or organization with water or power delivery authority to fund research activities designed to conserve, increase efficiency of, or enhance management of, water resources.<br/>Directs: (1) the Secretary of Energy to assess each effect of, and risk resulting from, climate change regarding water supplies required for the generation of hydroelectric power at specified projects; and (2) the Secretary to establish and lead a climate change and water intragovernmental panel.<br/>Directs the Secretary, acting through the Director of the United States Geological Survey (USGS), to: (1) review the national streamflow information program, improve methodologies, and increase the number of sites measured; (2) develop a systematic groundwater monitoring program for each major U.S. aquifer system; (3) identify significant U.S. brackish groundwater resources; and (4) establish a water availability and use assessment program.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
