<bill session="110" type="s" number="2169" updated="2009-01-09T16:21:22-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1192507200" datetime="2007-10-16"/></status>

	<introduced date="1192507200" datetime="2007-10-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">PROMISE Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting Refinancing Opportunities for Mortgages Impacted by the Subprime Emergency Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to temporarily increase the portfolio caps applicable to Freddie Mac and Fannie Mae, to provide the necessary financing to curb foreclosures by facilitating the refinancing of at-risk subprime borrowers into safe, affordable loans, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300087"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-11-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1192507200" datetime="2007-10-16"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/16/2007--Introduced.<br/>Promoting Refinancing Opportunities for Mortgages Impacted by the Subprime Emergency Act of 2007, or the PROMISE Act - Requires the Director of the Office of Federal Housing Enterprise Oversight (OFHEO) of the Department of Housing and Urban Development to terminate, suspend, modify, or otherwise lift: (1) the limitation on growth provision set forth in the Fannie Mae Consent Decree (the OFHEO order dated May 23, 2006, in the matter of the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae)); and (2) the voluntary temporary growth limitation described in the Freddie Mac Letter (dated July 31, 2006, from the Chairman and Chief Executive Officer of the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac) to the OFHEO Director). Requires: (1) the Director to increase the mortgage portfolio limitations of both enterprises by at least 10%; and (2) the use of 85% of such increase for refinancing subprime mortgages at risk of foreclosure.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
