<bill session="110" type="s" number="2161" updated="2009-01-09T16:19:46-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1192420800" datetime="2007-10-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1192420800" datetime="2007-10-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Community Pharmacy Fairness Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure and foster continued patient safety and quality of care by making the antitrust laws apply to negotiations between groups of independent pharmacies and health plans and health insurance issuers (including health plans under parts C and D of the Medicare Program) in the same manner as such laws apply to protected activities under the National Labor Relations Act.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400194"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2008-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300047" joined="2007-10-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300088" joined="2008-04-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="300013" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300083" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300035" joined="2008-09-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300021" joined="2007-12-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412248" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412244" joined="2008-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2007-10-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1192420800" datetime="2007-10-15"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/15/2007--Introduced.<br/>Community Pharmacy Fairness Act of 2007 - Entitles independent pharmacies negotiating contract terms with a health plan for the provision of health care items or services to the same treatment under the antitrust laws as the treatment to which bargaining units recognized under the National Labor Relations Act are entitled. Treats such a pharmacy as an employee engaged in concerted activities in connection with such negotiations. Exempts actions taken in good faith reliance on this Act from being subject to criminal sanctions or civil penalties beyond actual damages incurred. Prohibits: (1) exempting from the antitrust laws any agreement or otherwise unlawful conspiracy that excludes, limits the participation or reimbursement of, or otherwise limits the scope of services to be provided by any independent pharmacy or group of independent pharmacies with respect to the performance of services that are within their scope of practice as defined or permitted by relevant law or regulation; and (2) applying this Act to negotiations between independent pharmacies and health plans pertaining to federal health benefits.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
