<bill session="110" type="s" number="2173" updated="2009-01-09T16:21:56-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1192593600" datetime="2007-10-17"/></status>

	<introduced date="1192593600" datetime="2007-10-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">FIT Kids Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Fitness Integrated with Teaching Kids Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to improve standards for physical education.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300051"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2008-06-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2008-06-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300061" joined="2008-07-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2008-06-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300040" joined="2008-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300001" joined="2008-12-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2008-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300006" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412244" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2008-07-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1192593600" datetime="2007-10-17"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S12990-12991)</text></action>
		<action date="1192593600" datetime="2007-10-17"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/17/2007--Introduced.<br/>Fitness Integrated with Teaching Kids Act or the FIT Kids Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to require annual state and local educational agency report cards to include specified information on school health and physical education programs. Includes the promotion of healthy, active lifestyles by students within ESEA grant programs that support school counseling, smaller learning communities, community learning centers, and parental involvement in their childrens' education. Revises the professional development program for teachers and principals to include training for physical and health education teachers, and training on improving students' health habits and participation in physical activities. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to fund a study by the National Academy of Sciences (NAS) that: (1) assesses the affect health and physical education have on students' ability to learn; and (2) makes recommendations for improving, and measuring improvements to, their health and physical education in schools.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
