<bill session="110" type="s" number="2172" updated="2009-01-09T16:21:46-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1192507200" datetime="2007-10-16"/></status>

	<introduced date="1192507200" datetime="2007-10-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Saffron Revolution Support Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to impose sanctions on officials of the State Peace and Development Council in Burma, to prohibit the importation of gems and hardwoods from Burma, to support democracy in Burma, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300071"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2007-10-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300055" joined="2007-10-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-10-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300035" joined="2007-10-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300062" joined="2007-10-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300040" joined="2007-10-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-10-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400054" joined="2007-11-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1192507200" datetime="2007-10-16"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S12941)</text></action>
		<action date="1192507200" datetime="2007-10-16"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/16/2007--Introduced.<br/>Saffron Revolution Support Act of 2007 - States that it is U.S. policy to: (1) support the democratic aspirations of Burma's people; (2) condemn the repression carried out by the State Peace and Development Council (SPDC); and (3) hold accountable individuals responsible for the repression of peaceful political activity in Burma. Directs the President to submit to the appropriate congressional committees a list of: (1) SPDC officials who play or have played a substantial role in political repression in Burma or in the commission of human rights abuses; and (2) other Burmese SPDC supporters. Subjects persons so identified to U.S. entry prohibition and financial sanctions (blocked property, financial transaction prohibitions, and banking sanctions). Terminates such prohibitions upon a presidential certification to the committees that the SPDC has: (1) released all political prisoners, including Aung San Suu Kyi and other members of the National League for Democracy; (2) entered into a dialogue with democratic forces led by the National League for Democracy and the ethnic minorities of Burma on transitioning to democratic government; and (3) allowed humanitarian access to populations affected by armed conflict in all regions of Burma. Amends the the Burmese Freedom and Democracy Act of 2003 to prohibit the importation into the United States of Burmese gems, teak, or other hardwood timber. Prohibits any U.S. person (as defined by this Act) from investing in Burma. Authorizes: (1) the Secretary of State to award grants to nongovernmental organizations, universities, and other organizations to establish an Internet database of SPDC human rights abuses; and (2) the President to assist nonviolent democracy activists in their efforts to promote freedom, democracy, and human rights in Burma. Directs the Secretary to report to the appropriate committees respecting countries that provide military aid to Burma. 
	</summary>
</bill>
