<bill session="110" type="s" number="2181" updated="2009-01-09T16:23:02-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1192593600" datetime="2007-10-17"/></status>

	<introduced date="1192593600" datetime="2007-10-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Home Health Care Access Protection Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to protect Medicare beneficiaries' access to home health services under the Medicare program.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300025"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-10-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300008" joined="2007-12-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2007-10-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="300092" joined="2007-12-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300081" joined="2007-10-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="2007-11-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300083" joined="2007-10-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300010" joined="2007-10-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2008-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-12-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-10-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2008-04-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300078" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300050" joined="2007-11-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300095" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-11-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2008-01-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1192593600" datetime="2007-10-17"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S12992-12993)</text></action>
		<action date="1192593600" datetime="2007-10-17"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/17/2007--Introduced.<br/>Home Health Care Access Protection Act of 2007 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act with respect to the prospective payment system (PPS) for home health services and adjustments to it for case mix changes.<br/>Prohibits any adjustment in the PPS for payment in 2008. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services, for any adjustment in a subsequent year, to evaluate changes in case mix using standards developed consistent with specified processes, taking certain criteria into account.<br/>Directs the Secretary to convene a Technical Advisory Group to advise on the development of such standards.<br/>Prohibits the Secretary from taking any action to implement or otherwise carry out provisions in the final rule published on August 29, 2007, that propose to make a case mix adjustment to the standardized payment amounts under the PPS to account for changes in coding that were not related to an underlying change in patient health status. Directs the Secretary to republish any rates specified in such rule to take into account the application of such prohibition.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
