<bill session="110" type="s" number="2182" updated="2009-01-09T16:23:12-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1192593600" datetime="2007-10-17"/></status>

	<introduced date="1192593600" datetime="2007-10-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Community Mental Health Services Improvement Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act with respect to mental health services.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300081"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2008-04-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300068" joined="2008-07-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2007-10-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="300054" joined="2008-02-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300090" joined="2007-10-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1192593600" datetime="2007-10-17"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S12993-12994)</text></action>
		<action date="1192593600" datetime="2007-10-17"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S12994-12996"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/17/2007--Introduced.<br/>Community Mental Health Services Improvement Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to award grants for: (1) services to children, adults, and older adults with mental illnesses who have co-occurring primary care conditions and chronic diseases through the co-location of primary and specialty medical care in community-based mental and behavioral health settings; (2) programs to address behavioral and mental health workforce needs in professional shortage areas; (3) expanding behavioral and mental health education and training programs; (4) tele-mental health in medically-underserved areas; and (5) developing and implementing a plan to ensure that the National Health Information Infrastructure meets the needs of mental health and substance abuse providers.<br/>Provides for reports to Congress on: (1) the paperwork burden on community mental health providers; and (2) the compensation structure for such providers.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
