<bill session="110" type="s" number="2180" updated="2009-01-09T16:22:55-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1192680000" datetime="2007-10-18" /></status>

	<introduced date="1192593600" datetime="2007-10-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Natural Resource Projects and Programs Authorization Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize certain programs and activities in the Department of the Interior, the Forest Service, and the Department of Energy, and to amend the Compact of Free Association Amendments Act of 2003, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300009"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1192593600" datetime="2007-10-17"><text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1192680000" datetime="2007-10-18" ><text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 425.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1213156800" datetime="2008-06-11"><text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S5530"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/17/2007--Introduced.<br/>Natural Resource Projects and Programs Authorization Act of 2007 - Authorizes specified programs and activities in the Department of the Interior, the Forest Service, and the Department of Energy concerning, among other things, national monuments, conservation areas, resource protection, historic sites, national trails, national heritage areas, and the clean coal power initiative. Makes amendments to various public laws, including the Alaska Natural Gas Pipeline Act, the National Trails System Act, the Steel Industry American Heritage Area Act of 1996, the Omnibus Parks and Public Lands Management Act of 1996, the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act, the Energy Policy Act of 2005, the Delaware and Lehigh National Heritage Corridor Act of 1988, the Quinebaug and Shetucket Rivers Valley National Heritage Corridor Act of 1994, the National Geologic Mapping Act of 1992, and the Compact of Free Association Amendments Act of 2003.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
