<bill session="110" type="s" number="220" updated="2009-01-09T11:35:44-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31" /></status>

	<introduced date="1168318800" datetime="2007-01-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Southern Idaho Bureau of Reclamation Repayment Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Southern Idaho Bureau of Reclamation Repayment Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize early repayment of obligations to the Bureau of Reclamation within the A &amp; B Irrigation District in the State of Idaho.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300029"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1168318800" datetime="2007-01-09"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S290-291)</text></action>
		<action date="1168318800" datetime="2007-01-09"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. With written report No. 110-26.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="52" date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 52.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1213156800" datetime="2008-06-11"><text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S5530"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/16/2007--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Southern Idaho Bureau of Reclamation Repayment Act of 2007 - Authorizes any owner of land within the A &amp;amp; B Irrigation District in Idaho to repay at any time the construction costs of District project facilities that are allocated to such land. Provides that, upon full payment of such costs, the parcels shall not be subject to specified ownership and full-cost pricing limitations under federal reclamation law, for which the Secretary shall, upon request, provide the landowner a certificate.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
