<bill session="110" type="s" number="2208" updated="2009-01-09T16:26:36-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1192766400" datetime="2007-10-19"/></status>

	<introduced date="1192766400" datetime="2007-10-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Safety for Americans from Nuclear Weapons Testing Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect public health and safety in the event that testing of nuclear weapons by the United States is resumed.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300007"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300052" joined="2007-10-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1192766400" datetime="2007-10-19"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/19/2007--Introduced.<br/>Safety for Americans from Nuclear Weapons Testing Act - Deems the resumption of underground nuclear testing at the Nevada Test Site or the use of any other location for such testing to be a major federal action significantly affecting the quality of the human environment for which a separate environmental impact statement is required under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969. Outlines information required to be included in such statement, including: (1) the possibility of radiation containment failure and the effects of such failure; (2) possible long-term effects on the water table from underground radiation leakage; and (3) information with respect to categories of weapons subject to testing.<br/>Prohibits the United States from resuming any such testing unless authorized by a law enacted after the enactment of this Act.<br/>Requires: (1) advance (seven days) public notice of each test; (2) prompt notice of each release of radiation resulting from a test; and (3) a study by the National Academy of Sciences on the safety and health of citizens in the vicinity of the Site. Establishes a Nevada Test Site Citizens Review Board to address environmental, health, and safety issues related to nuclear testing at the Site.<br/>Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to make grants to institutions of higher education to acquire and operate for ten years radiation detection equipment and sensors.<br/>Directs the Secretary of Energy, through the Department of Energy (DOE) and the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), to monitor any radiation released into the atmosphere as a result of such testing. Requires: (1) DOE radiation containment assessment; and (2) public notice of monitoring data.<br/>Requires the: (1) Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to make a grant to establish the National Center for the Study of Radiation and Human Health; and (2) Secretary of Health and Human Services to conduct a study of individuals exposed to nuclear weapons tests.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
