<bill session="110" type="s" number="2211" updated="2009-01-09T16:27:02-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1192766400" datetime="2007-10-19"/></status>

	<introduced date="1192766400" datetime="2007-10-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Global Warming and Acidification Coastal and Ocean Resiliency Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure the recovery, resiliency, and health of ocean, coastal, and Great Lakes ecosystems, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412247"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-10-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1192766400" datetime="2007-10-19"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/19/2007--Introduced.<br/>Global Warming and Acidification Coastal and Ocean Resiliency Act - Requires the Secretary of Commerce to: (1) establish a national strategy to protect, maintain, and restore coastal and marine ecosystems so that they are more resilient and better able to withstand the additional stresses associated with global warming, including relative sea level rise, and ocean acidification; and (2) revise the strategy within five years and every ten years thereafter to reflect new information.<br/>Requires the Secretary to establish an Advisory Board to provide advice on: (1) the impact of global warming and strategies and mechanisms to mitigate the impact on the ocean and coastal communities; (2) priorities for research or information collection; and (3) priority needs for achieving systematic improvements in ocean and coastal resiliency.<br/>Requires the Secretary to make grants for protecting, maintaining, or restoring the resilience and health of coastal, ocean, and Great Lakes ecosystems and resources.<br/>Requires the Secretary to arrange with the National Academy of Sciences for a report to Congress on the impact of global warming, including relative sea level rise, and ocean acidification and on effective mitigation strategies for the ocean, coastal, and Great Lakes ecosystems and U.S. resources.<br/>Amends the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 to require the Secretary to establish a coastal climate change resiliency planning and response program and to issue guidelines for the implementation of climate change resiliency planning grants (authorized by this Act) to states.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
