<bill session="110" type="s" number="2213" updated="2009-01-09T16:27:18-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1193025600" datetime="2007-10-22"/></status>

	<introduced date="1193025600" datetime="2007-10-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Cyber-Crime Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 18, United States Code, to improve prevention, investigation, and prosecution of cyber-crime, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300052"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300008" joined="2007-10-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="2007-10-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300006" joined="2007-12-11"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1193025600" datetime="2007-10-22"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S13194-13195)</text></action>
		<action date="1193025600" datetime="2007-10-22"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/22/2007--Introduced.<br/>Cyber-Crime Act of 2007 - Amends the federal criminal code to: (1) add criminal penalties for conspiracy to intentionally access a protected computer (i.e., computers serving the federal government or financial institutions); (2) redefine the crime of computer-related extortion to include threats to access without authorization (or to exceed authorized access of) a protected computer; (3) impose criminal penalties for damaging 10 or more protected computers during any one-year period; (4) expand the definition of racketeering to include computer fraud; (5) eliminate the interstate communication requirement for purposes of prosecuting computer fraud offenses; and (6) impose civil forfeiture penalties for unauthorized access to protected computers.<br/>Directs the U.S. Sentencing Commission to review and revise its sentencing guidelines and policy statements for crimes involving document and computer fraud, aggravated identity theft, and illegal wiretapping to reflect congressional intent to increase the penalties for such crimes.<br/>Authorizes additional funding for the U.S. Secret Service, the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI), and the Attorney General in FY2008-FY2012 to investigate and prosecute criminal activity involving computers.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
