<bill session="110" type="s" number="2230" updated="2009-01-09T16:29:35-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1193284800" datetime="2007-10-25"/></status>

	<introduced date="1193284800" datetime="2007-10-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Nursing Education Opportunities Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title VIII of the Public Health Service Act to expand the nurse student loan program, to establish grant programs to address the nursing shortage, to amend title VII of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to provide for a nurse faculty pilot project, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300008"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1193284800" datetime="2007-10-25"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S13440-13441)</text></action>
		<action date="1193284800" datetime="2007-10-25"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S13441-13443"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/25/2007--Introduced.<br/>Nursing Education Opportunities Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to include accelerated degree nursing students who pursue a second baccalaureate degree or a master's degree as an entry level nursing degree as eligible for financial assistance through nursing programs in the Act, including the Nursing Student Loan Program. Raises the yearly loan amounts available to all nursing students through that Program. Modifies the definition of &quot;collegiate school of nursing&quot; to include accelerated nursing degree programs.<br/>Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in the case of a nurse faculty shortage, to obligate more than 10% of traineeships for individuals in doctoral degree programs.<br/>Directs the Secretary to award grants to: (1) eligible entities to establish doctoral nursing degree programs, giving priority to such entities located in states in which there are no such programs; and (2) partnerships of eligible entities to establish doctoral nursing consortia to enhance and expand the availability of doctoral nurse faculty and education by enabling the partners to share doctoral faculty and programmatic resources.<br/>Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to authorize the Secretary to award grants to partnerships composed of an accredited nursing school at an institution of higher education and a hospital or health facility to establish up to five pilot projects to enable such hospital or facility to retain its staff of experienced nurses while providing a mechanism to have these individuals become, through an accelerated nursing education program, faculty members of an accredited nursing school.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
