<bill session="110" type="s" number="2237" updated="2009-01-09T16:30:29-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1193284800" datetime="2007-10-25"/></status>

	<introduced date="1193284800" datetime="2007-10-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Crime Control and Prevention Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Assault Weapons Ban Renewal Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Children of Addicted Parents Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Civic Justice Corps Demonstration Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Collection of Restitution Improvement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Combating Child Exploitation Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Commercial Equipment Direct Assistance Program Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Commission to Study Alternatives to Incarceration of Non-Violent Mentally Ill Offenders Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Continuity of Justice Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">COPS Improvements Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Crime Victims with Disabilities Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Cyber Security Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Dextromethorphan Abuse Reduction Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Drug Enforcement Special Agents Restoration Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Drug Sentencing Reform and Cocaine Kingpin Trafficking Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Enhanced Second Chance Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Environmental Crimes Restitution Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Extraterritorial Controlled Substance Trafficking Venue Clarification Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">FBI Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Firearms Background Check Enhancement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Forensics Grants Improvement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Full-strength Bureau Initiative Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Gang Abatement and Prevention Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Homeland Security Trust Fund Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Assistance to Domestic and Sexual Violence Victims Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Intellectual Property Protection Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Juvenile and Family Court Training, Technical Assistance, and Data Collection Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Juvenile Delinquency Court Improvement Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Juvenile Delinquency Judicial Training and Technical Assistance Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Local Drug Crisis Enhancement Grants Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Methamphetamine Production Prevention Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Model Courts Enhancements Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Mynisha's Law</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Commission on Law Enforcement and the Administration of Justice Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Domestic Violence Volunteer Attorney Network Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">PACT Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Police and Communities Together Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">PRECAUTION Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Preservation of Assets for Restitution Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Prevention Resources for Eliminating Criminal Activity Using Tailored Interventions in Our Neighborhoods Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Project to Protect America Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Electronic Voting Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Recognizing Addiction as a Disease Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Restitution for Victims of Crime Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Ryan Haight Online Pharmacy Consumer Protection Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Safe Babies Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">School Safety and Student Protection Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Violence Against Children Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to fight crime.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300008"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2008-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-11-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1193284800" datetime="2007-10-25"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S13451-13452)</text></action>
		<action date="1193284800" datetime="2007-10-25"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/25/2007--Introduced.<br/>Crime Control and Prevention Act of 2007 - Amends the federal criminal code, the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968, the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974, the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994, the Violence Against Women Act of 2000, and other federal laws to establish and reauthorize programs to prevent and control crime. Reauthorizes and expands the program for community-oriented policing services (COPS program). Authorizes the hiring of an additional 1,000 agents for the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) in FY2008-FY2012. Authorizes the hiring of additional Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA) agents.<br/>Establishes a National Commission on Law Enforcement and the Administration of Justice to study the role of law enforcement after the terrorist attacks of September 11, 2001.<br/>Authorizes appropriations for FY2008-FY2012 for: (1) early Head Start programs; (2) child abuse and prevention treatment; (3) after school programs; (4) grants for local juvenile delinquency prevention programs; (4) juvenile justice intervention programs; and (5) crime prevention in Indian tribal communities.<br/>Provides grants for community service programs for youthful offenders (16-25 years old), for improving juvenile delinquency practice in state courts, for preventing gang membership and gang violence, and for school safety. Imposes new penalties for gang-related violent crimes.<br/>Establishes a National Commission on Crime Intervention and Prevention Strategies.<br/>Reauthorizes or establishes new programs for the reduction of recidivism, for alternatives to incarceration of non-violent mentally ill offenders, and for assisting the reentry of offenders into the community after release from incarceration.<br/>Establishes programs and national task forces to combat child exploitation over the Internet. Authorizes additional funding to hire federal agents to investigate child exploitation. Imposes enhanced criminal penalties for violent crimes against children (under 18 years of age).<br/>Eliminates sentencing disparities between crack and powder cocaine. Establishes programs for combating drug addiction and drug trafficking and for assisting children of drug addicted parents.<br/>Imposes restrictions on obtaining prescription drugs over the Internet.<br/>Requires background checks of gun purchasers at gun shows. Renews the ban on assault weapons. Provides for new criminal and forfeiture penalties to combat computer fraud and copyright infringement. Enhances protections for crime victims with disabilities. Requires courts to enter orders for immediate restitution to victims of crime and protective orders to preserve assets available for payment of restitution.<br/>Establishes the Homeland Security and Neighborhood Safety Trust Fund. 
	</summary>
</bill>
