<bill session="110" type="s" number="2259" updated="2009-01-09T16:33:24-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1193716800" datetime="2007-10-30"/></status>

	<introduced date="1193716800" datetime="2007-10-30"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Santa Ana River Water Supply Enhancement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to participate in the Prado Basin Natural Treatment System Project, to authorize the Secretary to participate in the Lower Chino Dairy Area desalination demonstration and reclamation project, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300043"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1193716800" datetime="2007-10-30"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S13581-13582)</text></action>
		<action date="1193716800" datetime="2007-10-30"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S13582"/></action>
		<action date="1207627200" datetime="2008-04-08"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-460.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/30/2007--Introduced.<br/>Santa Ana River Water Supply Enhancement Act of 2007 - Amends the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Secretary of the Interior, in cooperation with: (1) the Orange County Water District (the District), to participate in the design, planning, and construction of natural treatment systems and wetlands for the flows of the Santa Ana River, California, and its tributaries into the Prado Basin; and (2) the Chino Basin Watermaster, the Inland Empire Utilities Agency, and the Santa Ana Watershed Project Authority, to participate in the design, planning, and construction of the Lower Chino Dairy Area desalination demonstration and reclamation project. Limits the federal share of total project costs. Prohibits using funds provided by the Secretary for operation and maintenance of the projects. Directs the Secretary to establish at the District a center to provide: (1) assistance in the development and advancement of membrane technologies; and (2) educational support in the advancement of public understanding and acceptance of membrane produced water supplies. Terminates the Secretary's authority to carry out this Act after 10 years.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
