<bill session="110" type="s" number="2255" updated="2009-01-09T16:32:52-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" /></status>

	<introduced date="1193630400" datetime="2007-10-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Chisholm Trail and Great Western Trail Studies Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Chisholm Trail and Great Western Trail Studies Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the National Trails System Act to provide for studies of the Chisholm Trail and Great Western Trail to determine whether to add the trails to the National Trails System, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300054"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300055" joined="2007-10-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300083" joined="2007-12-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300027" joined="2007-10-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1193630400" datetime="2007-10-29"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1213675200" datetime="2008-06-17"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-539.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="980" date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 980.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/16/2008--Reported to Senate amended. Chisholm Trail and Great Western Trail Studies Act - Amends the National Trails System Act to direct the Secretary of the Interior to conduct separate studies to consider the designation of the Chisholm Trail and the Great Western Trail for study and potential addition to the National Trails System. Requires the Secretary to identify the point at which such Trails originated south of San Antonio, Texas. 
	</summary>
</bill>
