<bill session="110" type="s" number="2276" updated="2009-01-09T16:35:46-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1193803200" datetime="2007-10-31"/></status>

	<introduced date="1193803200" datetime="2007-10-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Aeronautics Competitiveness Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enhance United States competitiveness in aeronautics, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300034"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300098" joined="2007-10-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300099" joined="2007-10-31"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1193803200" datetime="2007-10-31"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S13629)</text></action>
		<action date="1193803200" datetime="2007-10-31"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/31/2007--Introduced.<br/>Aeronautics Competitiveness Act of 2007 - Authorizes appropriations for FY2009-FY2011 for the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) for Science, Aeronautics, and Exploration for aeronautics research.<br/>Establishes an advisory committee on priorities in aeronautics research.<br/>Requires the NASA Administrator to develop particular aeronautics technologies, including for the Next Generation Air Transportation System, to a demonstration ready level.<br/>Sets the maximum number of NASA aeronautics scholarships at no more than seven at any one time. Requires the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to establish a program to provide fellowships for graduate students in research in aviation or aeronautics.<br/>Requires the Secretary of the Department of Defense (DOD) to prescribe regulations governing DOD's payment of contractors' costs for education and professional development of their aeronautics workforce.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
