<bill session="110" type="s" number="2274" updated="2009-01-09T16:35:27-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1193803200" datetime="2007-10-31"/></status>

	<introduced date="1193803200" datetime="2007-10-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Dextromethorphan Abuse Reduction Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Controlled Substances Act to prevent the abuse of dextromethorphan, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300008"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-10-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300048" joined="2007-10-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2007-10-31"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1193803200" datetime="2007-10-31"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S13626-13627)</text></action>
		<action date="1193803200" datetime="2007-10-31"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1205294400" datetime="2008-03-12"><text>Committee on the Judiciary Senate Subcommittee on Crime and Drugs. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/31/2007--Introduced.<br/>Dextromethorphan Abuse Reduction Act of 2007 - Amends the Controlled Substances Act to: (1) set forth definitions relating to dextromethorphan in unfinished or finished dosage form; (2) classify unfinished dextromethorphan as a Schedule V controlled substance; and (3) impose civil penalties for sales of products containing dextromethorphan to individuals under the age of 18.<br/>Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) manufacturers of products containing dextromethorphan should provide warnings about the dangers of dextromethorphan misuse; and (2) retailers should impose safeguards to protect against the theft of products containing dextromethorphan. Directs the Director of National Drug Control Policy to make grants to the Partnership for a Drug-Free America and the Community Anti-Drug Coalition of America for education programs to prevent the abuse of prescription and nonprescription drugs (including dextromethorphan). Authorizes the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration to make grants to certain communities to implement comprehensive community-wide strategies for addressing abuse of prescription and nonprescription drugs. 
	</summary>
</bill>
