<bill session="110" type="s" number="2287" updated="2009-01-09T16:37:11-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1193889600" datetime="2007-11-01"/></status>

	<introduced date="1193889600" datetime="2007-11-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Elimination of Double Subsidies for the Hardrock Mining Industry Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to repeal the percentage depletion allowance for certain hardrock mines, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300042"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2007-11-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1193889600" datetime="2007-11-01"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S13687-13688)</text></action>
		<action date="1193889600" datetime="2007-11-01"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S13688-13689"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/1/2007--Introduced.<br/>Elimination of Double Subsidies for the Hardrock Mining Industry Act of 2007 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to disallow the percentage depletion allowance for hardrock mines located on land currently subject to the general mining laws, or on land patented under such laws.<br/>Establishes in the Treasury the Abandoned Mine Reclamation Trust Fund. Appropriates to such Fund amounts equal to 25% of the additional revenues received due to the disallowance of the depletion allowance for hardrock mines proposed by this Act. Prescribes guidelines under which such Fund shall be available to the Secretary of the Interior for reclamation and restoration of lands and water resources adversely affected by mineral and mineral material mining (excluding coal and fluid minerals). 
	</summary>
</bill>
