<bill session="110" type="s" number="2285" updated="2009-01-09T16:36:56-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1193889600" datetime="2007-11-01" /></status>

	<introduced date="1193889600" datetime="2007-11-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Terrorism Risk Insurance Program Reauthorization Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Terrorism Risk Insurance Program Reauthorization Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">An original bill to reauthorize the Federal terrorism risk insurance program, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300034"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1193889600" datetime="2007-11-01"><text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Dodd. With written report No. 110-215.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1193889600" datetime="2007-11-01" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 461.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/1/2007--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)<br/>Terrorism Risk Insurance Program Reauthorization Act of 2007 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Terrorism Risk Insurance Act to revise the definition of an act of terrorism for terrorism risk insurance purposes to eliminate the requirement that the individual or individuals committing a terrorist act be acting on behalf of any foreign person or foreign interest.<br/>Extends the Terrorism Risk Insurance Program through calendar 2014.<br/>(Sec. 4) States that no insurer may be required to make payment for insured losses in excess of its statutory deductible, combined with its statutory share of insured losses.<br/>Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to: (1) notify Congress within 15 days of an act of terrorism on whether the Secretary estimates that aggregate insured losses will exceed $100 billion; (2) promulgate final regulations for determining the pro rata share of insured losses which exceed $100 billion; and (3) report to Congress on the process used to determine the allocation of pro rata payments when insured losses exceed $100 billion.<br/>Requires insurers to disclose to policyholders the $100 billion cap on liability.<br/>(Sec. 5) Directs the Comptroller General to study and report to certain congressional committees regarding: (1) the availability and affordability of insurance coverage for losses caused by terrorist attacks involving nuclear, biological, chemical, or radiological materials; (2) the outlook for such coverage in the future; (3) the capacity of private insurers and state workers compensation funds to manage risk associated with such events; and (4) whether there are specific markets in the United States with unique capacity constraints on the amount of terrorism risk insurance available.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
