<bill session="110" type="s" number="2292" updated="2009-01-09T16:37:48-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1195016400" datetime="2007-11-14" /></status>

	<introduced date="1193889600" datetime="2007-11-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Bombing Prevention Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">National Bombing Prevention Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002, to establish the Office for Bombing Prevention, to address terrorist explosive threats, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300025"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300029" joined="2008-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300030" joined="2008-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-11-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1193889600" datetime="2007-11-01"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S13692-13693)</text></action>
		<action date="1193889600" datetime="2007-11-01"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1195016400" datetime="2007-11-14" ><text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1222142400" datetime="2008-09-23"><text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 110-481.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="1043" date="1222142400" datetime="2008-09-23" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1043.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/1/2007--Introduced.<br/>National Bombing Prevention Act of 2007 - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish an Office for Bombing Prevention in the Department of Homeland Security's (DHS) Protective Security Coordination Division of the Office of Infrastructure Protection. Assigns the Office primary responsibility for enhancing the ability and coordinating the efforts of the nation to deter, detect, prevent, protect against, and respond to terrorist explosive attacks.<br/>Directs the President to develop and periodically update a national strategy to prevent and prepare for terrorist attacks using explosives or improvised explosive devices in the United States.<br/>Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security, acting through the Under Secretary for Science and Technology, to: (1) coordinate federal nonmilitary research, development, testing, and evaluation activities relating to the detection and prevention of, protection against, and response to explosive attacks within the United States and the development of bomb squad tools and technologies necessary to neutralize and disable explosive devices; (2) coordinate with the Secretary of Defense and the heads of other relevant federal departments to ensure that military information and related activities are applied to nonmilitary uses; (3) establish a technology transfer program to facilitate the identification, modification, and commercialization of technology and equipment for use by governmental agencies, emergency response providers, and the private sector against such attacks; and (4) establish a working group to advise and assist in the identification of military technologies developed by the Department of Defense (DOD) or the private sector to protect against and respond to explosive attacks.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
