<bill session="110" type="s" number="2305" updated="2009-01-09T16:39:32-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1194238800" datetime="2007-11-05"/></status>

	<introduced date="1194238800" datetime="2007-11-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Caging Prohibition Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prevent voter caging.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412247"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412242" joined="2007-11-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="2007-11-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-11-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="2007-11-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-11-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2007-11-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-11-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="2008-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-11-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-11-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300078" joined="2007-11-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-11-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2007-11-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1194238800" datetime="2007-11-05"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S13772-13773)</text></action>
		<action date="1194238800" datetime="2007-11-05"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text></action>
		<action date="1204088400" datetime="2008-02-27"><text>Committee on Rules and Administration. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/5/2007--Introduced.<br/>Caging Prohibition Act of 2007 - Prohibits state or local election officials from preventing an individual from registering or voting in any election for federal office, or permitting a formal challenge under state law to an individual's registration status or eligibility to vote in a federal election, if the sole basis for such decision or challenge is evidence consisting of: (1) a voter caging document or voter caging list; (2) an unverified match list; or (3) any other evidence so designated for purposes of this Act by the Federal Election Commission.<br/>Defines &quot;voter caging document&quot; as: (1) any nonforwardable document that is sent to an individual at the address at which such individual is registered (or seeking to become registered) as a voter in a federal election, and that is returned to the sender or to a third party as undelivered or undeliverable; and (2) any document (other than a notice warning of possible removal from the voting rolls) that is sent to an individual at the address at which such individual is registered.<br/>Defines &quot;unverified match list&quot; as one produced by matching the identity of registered voters or voter registration applicants with the identity of individuals who are ineligible to vote in the registrar's jurisdiction, by virtue of death, conviction, change of address, mental impairment, or otherwise, unless the information establishing the individual's identity contains a signature, photograph, or unique identifying number.<br/>Outlines requirements for challenges to an individual's registration or voting eligibility by persons other than election officials.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
