<bill session="110" type="s" number="2300" updated="2009-01-09T16:38:51-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1194411600" datetime="2007-11-07" /></status>

	<introduced date="1193889600" datetime="2007-11-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Contracting Revitalization Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the Small Business Act, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300060"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="2008-05-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="2007-11-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-11-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1193889600" datetime="2007-11-01"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S13702-13703)</text></action>
		<action date="1193889600" datetime="2007-11-01"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S13703-13710"/></action>
		<calendar date="1194411600" datetime="2007-11-07" ><text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/1/2007--Introduced.<br/>Small Business Contracting Revitalization Act of 2007 - Amends the Small Business Act to provide federal review and oversight of the practice of contract bundling (the consolidation of two or more procurement contracts into a solicitation for a single prime contract that is unlikely, because of its size or complexity, to be suitable for award to a small business). Revises or adds federal provisions or requirements concerning: (1) increased small business participation in federal procurement subcontracts, including a pilot program to provide contractual incentives to prime contractors that exceed their small business subcontracting goals; (2) Small Business Administration (SBA) certification of small businesses owned and controlled by service-disabled veterans, women, and socially and economically disadvantaged individuals; (3) historically underutilized business zones (HUBZones) affected by military base closures; (4) the BusinessLINC program (business-to-business and mentor-protege relationships between large and small businesses); (5) information on contracts involving small businesses that were displaced by bundled or consolidated actions; (6) the reservation of certain prime contract awards to small businesses; (7) a Comptroller General study on federal procurement contracting reporting systems; (8) micropurchase guidelines; (9) reporting on overseas contracts; (10) federal agency accountability with respect to small business procurement contracting and subcontracting goals; (11) certification as a small business for purposes of eligibility for the award of federal contracts and subcontracts (including authority to protest a business as a small business for such purposes); (12) training for federal contracting and contract enforcement personnel; (13) revised size standards for qualification as a small business; and (14) small business size and status for purposes of multiple award contracts.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
