<bill session="110" type="s" number="232" updated="2009-01-09T11:37:30-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31" /></status>

	<introduced date="1168318800" datetime="2007-01-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Watershed Restoration and Enhancement Agreements Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Watershed Restoration and Enhancement Agreements Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to make permanent the authorization for watershed restoration and enhancement agreements.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300100"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1168318800" datetime="2007-01-09"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S300)</text></action>
		<action date="1168318800" datetime="2007-01-09"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S300"/></action>
		<calendar date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. With written report No. 110-8.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="33" date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 33.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/15/2007--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Watershed Restoration and Enhancement Agreements Act of 2007 - Amends the Department of the Interior and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1999 to make permanent the authorization for the Secretary of Agriculture to use Forest Service appropriations for the purpose of entering into cooperative agreements with government, private, and nonprofit entities and landowners for the protection, restoration, and enhancement of fish and wildlife habitat and other resources on public or private land and/or the reduction of risk from natural disaster. Makes provisions regarding executive agency use of procurement contracts, grants, and cooperative agreements inapplicable to: (1) watershed restoration and enhancement agreements entered into under such Act; and (2) cooperative agreements between the Secretary of Agriculture and public or private entities for Forest Service programs, including for cooperative pollution abatement equipment and facilities, cooperative manpower and job training and development, cooperative environmental education and forest history materials, and forestry protection.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
