<bill session="110" type="s" number="235" updated="2009-01-09T11:37:55-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31" /></status>

	<introduced date="1168405200" datetime="2007-01-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Yakima-Tieton Irrigation District Conveyance Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Yakima-Tieton Irrigation District Conveyance Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain buildings and lands of the Yakima Project, Washington, to the Yakima-Tieton Irrigation District.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300018"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1168405200" datetime="2007-01-10"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. With written report No. 110-21.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="47" date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 47.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1213156800" datetime="2008-06-11"><text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S5530"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/16/2007--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.) Yakima-Tieton Irrigation District Conveyance Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain buildings and lands of the Yakima Project, Washington, to the Yakima-Tieton Irrigation District. Shields the United States from liability for damages relating to the conveyed buildings and lands, except for damages caused by negligent acts committed before the conveyance date. Provides that after such conveyance those buildings and lands shall not be considered to be a part of a federal reclamation project and the District shall not be eligible to receive any benefits for them. Directs the Secretary to report to Congress if the Secretary has not completed the conveyance within a year.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
