<bill session="110" type="s" number="2363" updated="2009-01-09T16:46:49-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1195189200" datetime="2007-11-16" /></status>

	<introduced date="1195102800" datetime="2007-11-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Military Construction and Veterans Affairs and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill making appropriations for military construction, the Department of Veterans Affairs, and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2008, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300054"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300029" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300013" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300007" joined="2007-11-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300072" joined="2007-11-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1195102800" datetime="2007-11-15"><text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1195189200" datetime="2007-11-16" ><text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 511.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/15/2007--Introduced.<br/>Military Construction and Veterans Affairs and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2008 - Appropriates funds for FY2008 for the Department of Defense (DOD) for: (1) military construction for the Army, Navy and Marine Corps, and Air Force (military departments), DOD, the Army and Air National Guard, and the Army, Navy, and Air Force reserves; (2) the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) Security Investment Program; (3) family housing construction and related operation and maintenance for the military departments and DOD; (4) the Department of Defense Family Housing Improvement Fund; (5) DOD chemical demilitarization construction; and (6) the Department of Defense Base Closure Accounts of 1990 and 2005. Appropriates funds for the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) for: (1) the Veterans Benefits Administration; (2) readjustment benefits; (3) veterans insurance and indemnities; (4) the Veterans Housing Benefit Program Fund; (5) the Vocational Rehabilitation Loans Program; (6) the Native American Veteran Housing Loan Program; (7) guaranteed transitional housing loans for homeless veterans; (8) the Veterans Health Administration; (9) the National Cemetery Administration; (10) the Office of Inspector General; (11) construction for major and minor projects; and (12) grants for the construction of extended care facilities and veterans cemeteries. Appropriates funds for: (1) the American Battle Monuments Commission; (2) the U.S. Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims; (3) cemeterial expenses, Army; and (4) the Armed Forces Retirement Home. Specifies restrictions and authorities regarding the use of funds appropriated in this Act.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
