<bill session="110" type="s" number="2370" updated="2009-01-09T16:47:42-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1210132800" datetime="2008-05-07" /></status>

	<introduced date="1195102800" datetime="2007-11-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Albuquerque Biological Park Title Clarification Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Albuquerque Biological Park Title Clarification Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to clear title to certain real property in New Mexico associated with the Middle Rio Grande Project, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300009"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300036" joined="2007-11-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1195102800" datetime="2007-11-15"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S14493)</text></action>
		<action date="1195102800" datetime="2007-11-15"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S14493-14494"/></action>
		<action date="1204174800" datetime="2008-02-28"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-376.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1210132800" datetime="2008-05-07" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1213588800" datetime="2008-06-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment. With written report No. 110-366.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="798" date="1213588800" datetime="2008-06-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 798.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/16/2008--Reported to Senate amended. Albuquerque Biological Park Title Clarification Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to issue a quitclaim deed conveying any right, title, and interest the United States may have in and to Tingley Beach, San Gabriel Park, and the BioPark Parcels in Albuquerque, New Mexico, to the City of Albuquerque. Provides that the City shall not be required to pay any additional costs for the value of such Beach, Park, and Parcels. Prohibits this Act from being construed or utilized to affect or otherwise interfere with any position set forth by any party in the lawsuit pending before the U.S. District Court entitled Rio Grande Silvery Minnow v. John W. Keys, III concerning the right to any property associated with the Middle Rio Grande Project.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
