<bill session="110" type="s" number="2387" updated="2009-01-09T16:49:48-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1195189200" datetime="2007-11-16"/></status>

	<introduced date="1195189200" datetime="2007-11-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Managing Arson Through Criminal History (MATCH) Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish guidelines and incentives for States to establish arsonist registries and to require the Attorney General to establish a national arsonist registry and notification program, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300043"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-11-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300062" joined="2007-12-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1195189200" datetime="2007-11-16"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S14628-14630)</text></action>
		<action date="1195189200" datetime="2007-11-16"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/16/2007--Introduced.<br/>Managing Arson Through Criminal History (MATCH) Act of 2007 - Requires jurisdictions (i.e., states, the District of Columbia, U.S. territories and possessions, and federally recognized Indian tribes) to establish and maintain jurisdiction-wide arsonist registries and make such registries available on the Internet.<br/>Requires a criminal arsonist to register in each jurisdiction in which such arsonist resides, is an employee, or is a student. Sets forth other registration requirements and the information required to be provided in a registry by the criminal arsonist and jurisdictions. Allows jurisdictions to exempt from disclosure certain information about an arsonist, including the arsonist's employer and enrollment at an educational institution.<br/>Requires the Attorney General to maintain a national database at the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives (ATF) (to be known as the National Arsonist Registry) and a national arsonist Internet site containing information on each criminal arsonist registered in a jurisdiction's registry or listed on a jurisdiction's Internet site, respectively. Directs the Attorney General to establish a Criminal Arsonist Management Assistance program for awarding grants to jurisdictions to offset the costs of implementing this Act.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
