<bill session="110" type="s" number="24" updated="2009-01-09T11:10:27-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31" /></status>

	<introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Perchlorate Monitoring and Right-to-Know Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Perchlorate Monitoring and Right-to-Know Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Safe Drinking Water Act to require a health advisory and monitoring of drinking water for perchlorate.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300011"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412242" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="2007-04-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2007-01-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2007-01-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S63-64)</text></action>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S64"/></action>
		<action date="1210046400" datetime="2008-05-06"><text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Hearings held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31" ><text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1222228800" datetime="2008-09-24"><text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Boxer with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 110-483. Minority views filed.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="1054" date="1222228800" datetime="2008-09-24" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1054.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/4/2007--Introduced.<br/>Perchlorate Monitoring and Right-to-Know Act of 2007 - Amends the Safe Drinking Water Act to direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to: (1) publish a health advisory for perchlorate that fully protects the health of vulnerable persons (including pregnant women, fetuses, and children) considering body weight, exposure patterns, and all routes of exposure; and (2) promulgate a final regulation requiring monitoring for perchlorate in drinking water. Makes such regulation effective unless and until monitoring for perchlorate is required under a national primary drinking water regulation. Requires consumer confidence reports to disclose the presence and health risks of perchlorate in drinking water.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
