<bill session="110" type="s" number="241" updated="2009-01-09T11:38:43-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31" /></status>

	<introduced date="1168405200" datetime="2007-01-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Natural Resource Protection Cooperative Agreement Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Natural Resource Protection Cooperative Agreement Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to enter into cooperative agreements to protect natural resources of units of the National Park System through collaborative efforts on land inside and outside of units of the National Park System.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300100"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300001" joined="2007-01-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300097" joined="2007-02-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1168405200" datetime="2007-01-10"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S382)</text></action>
		<action date="1168405200" datetime="2007-01-10"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S382"/></action>
		<calendar date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. With written report No. 110-10.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="35" date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 35.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1213156800" datetime="2008-06-11"><text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S5530"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/15/2007--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.) Natural Resource Protection Cooperative Agreement Act - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to enter into cooperative agreements with State, local, or tribal governments, other federal agencies, other public entities, educational institutions, private nonprofit organizations, or willing private landowners to protect natural resources of units of the National Park System (NPS) through collaborative efforts on land inside and outside of NPS units. Sets forth the terms and conditions that such an agreement shall contain, including that the agreement provide for: (1) clear and direct benefits to natural resources in units of the NPS; (2) the preservation, conservation, and restoration of coastal and riparian systems, watersheds, and wetlands; (3) preventing, controlling, or eradicating invasive exotic species that occupy land within a unit of the NPS or adjacent to such a unit; or (4) restoration of natural resources, including native wildlife habitat. Prohibits the Secretary from using any amounts associated with an agreement entered into under the Act for the purposes of land acquisition, regulatory activity, or the development, maintenance, or operation of infrastructure, with the exception of ancillary support facilities that the Secretary determines to be necessary for the completion of projects or activities identified in the agreement. Authorizes appropriations.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
