<bill session="110" type="s" number="2433" updated="2009-01-09T16:55:38-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1202878800" datetime="2008-02-13" /></status>

	<introduced date="1197003600" datetime="2007-12-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Global Poverty Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Global Poverty Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the President to develop and implement a comprehensive strategy to further the United States foreign policy objective of promoting the reduction of global poverty, the elimination of extreme global poverty, and the achievement of the Millennium Development Goal of reducing by one-half the proportion of people worldwide, between 1990 and 2015, who live on less than $1 per day.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400629"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412242" joined="2008-07-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2008-02-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2008-05-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300070" joined="2008-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="2008-07-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-12-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2008-06-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300008" joined="2008-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2008-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="2008-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2008-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2008-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2008-05-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2008-06-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300061" joined="2008-07-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2008-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412249" joined="2008-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="2008-02-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2008-07-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2008-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2008-06-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2008-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300050" joined="2007-12-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2008-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2008-02-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300090" joined="2008-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="2008-06-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2008-07-16"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1197003600" datetime="2007-12-07"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1202878800" datetime="2008-02-13" ><text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1209009600" datetime="2008-04-24"><text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Biden with amendments and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 110-331.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="718" date="1209009600" datetime="2008-04-24" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 718.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/24/2008--Reported to Senate amended. Global Poverty Act of 2007 - Directs the President, through the Secretary of State, to develop and implement a comprehensive strategy to further the U.S. foreign policy objective of promoting the reduction of global poverty, the elimination of extreme global poverty, and the achievement of the United Nations Millennium Development Goal of reducing by one-half the proportion of people, between 1990 and 2015, who live on less than $1 per day. Requires the strategy to contain specific and measurable goals and to consist of specified components, including: (1) continued investment or involvement in existing U.S. initiatives related to international poverty reduction and trade preference programs for developing countries; (2) improving the effectiveness of development assistance and making available additional overall United States assistance levels as appropriate; (3) enhancing and expanding debt relief as appropriate; (4) mobilizing and leveraging the participation of businesses and public-private partnerships; (5) coordinating the goal of poverty reduction with other internationally recognized Millennium Development Goals; and (6) integrating principles of sustainable development and entrepreneurship into policies and programs. Sets forth specified reporting requirements. Directs the Secretary of State to designate a coordinator who will have primary responsibility for overseeing and drafting the reports, as well as responsibility for helping to implement recommendations contained in the reports. Defines specified terms.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
