<bill session="110" type="s" number="2434" updated="2009-01-09T16:55:47-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1197003600" datetime="2007-12-07"/></status>

	<introduced date="1197003600" datetime="2007-12-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Computer Trespass Clarification Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to clarify conditions for the interceptions of computer trespass communications under the USA-PATRIOT Act.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300042"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1197003600" datetime="2007-12-07"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S15032)</text></action>
		<action date="1197003600" datetime="2007-12-07"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S15032-15033"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	12/7/2007--Introduced.<br/>Computer Trespass Clarification Act of 2007 - Amends the federal criminal code to: (1) exclude from the definition of &quot;computer trespasser&quot; for purposes of determining the legality of interceptions of computer communications any person who has any relationship with the owner or operator of a protected computer (currently, only persons who have a contractual relationship with the owner or operator of a protected computer are excluded); (2) require the owner or operator of a protected computer to be attempting to respond to communications activity that threatens the integrity or operation of such computer before authorizing the interception of a computer trespasser's communications by a person acting under color of law (e.g., law enforcement officers); and (3) limit the length of warrantless surveillance of a computer trespasser to the earlier of 96 hours or as soon as communications that are sought are obtained. 
	</summary>
</bill>
