<bill session="110" type="s" number="2435" updated="2009-01-09T16:55:55-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1197003600" datetime="2007-12-07"/></status>

	<introduced date="1197003600" datetime="2007-12-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Reasonable Notice and Search Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to limit authority to delay notice of search warrants.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300042"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1197003600" datetime="2007-12-07"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S15033)</text></action>
		<action date="1197003600" datetime="2007-12-07"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S15033"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	12/7/2007--Introduced.<br/>Reasonable Notice and Search Act - Amends the federal criminal code to revise provisions governing search warrants authorized under the USA PATRIOT ACT to: (1) limit the authority to delay notice of the issuance of such search warrants to cases involving danger to the life or physical safety of an individual, flight from prosecution, destruction of or tampering with evidence sought by such warrants, or intimidation of potential witnesses; (2) require notification of the issuance of such warrants within seven days (currently, within a &quot;reasonable period not to exceed 30 days&quot;) after execution; and (3) allow extensions of the delay in notification for additional periods of up to 21 days if the court finds that the execution of a warrant will endanger the life or physical safety of an individual or result in flight from prosecution, destruction of or tampering with evidence sought by the warrant, or intimidation of potential witnesses.<br/>Terminates the authority to delay notification of USA PATRIOT ACT search warrants on December 31, 2009.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
