<bill session="110" type="s" number="2444" updated="2009-01-09T16:57:02-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1197349200" datetime="2007-12-11"/></status>

	<introduced date="1197349200" datetime="2007-12-11"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Higher Education Sustainability Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Education to provide grants to establish and evaluate sustainability programs, charged with developing and implementing integrated environmental, economic, and social sustainability initiatives, and to direct the Secretary of Education to convene a summit of higher education experts in the area of sustainability.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300076"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2007-12-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2008-02-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-12-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-12-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2008-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-12-11"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1197349200" datetime="2007-12-11"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	12/11/2007--Introduced.<br/>Higher Education Sustainability Act of 2007 - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of Education to make grants to establish sustainability programs at institutions of higher education (IHEs). Directs the Secretary to contract with an IHE, nonprofit organization, or consortium of such institutions for administration of the grant program. Requires such programs to develop and implement: (1) sustainability practices, including in the areas of energy management, green building, waste management, purchasing, transportation, and toxics management; and (2) other aspects of sustainability that integrate campus operations with multidisciplinary educational programs and are applicable to the private and government sectors. Directs the Secretary to convene a summit of higher education experts, federal representatives, and business and industry leaders to encourage cooperative efforts to enhance sustainability programs at IHEs and apply such programs to the community and workplace.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
