<bill session="110" type="s" number="2492" updated="2009-01-09T17:03:06-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1197867600" datetime="2007-12-17"/></status>

	<introduced date="1197867600" datetime="2007-12-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Military Housing Privatization Initiatives Projects Oversight and Accountability Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for improved oversight of and accountability for military housing privatization initiative projects.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300080"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300068" joined="2007-12-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300021" joined="2007-12-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1197867600" datetime="2007-12-17"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	12/17/2007--Introduced.<br/>Military Housing Privatization Initiatives Projects Oversight and Accountability Act of 2007 - Requires each military housing privatization initiative project to be carried out under a guaranteed maximum price contract (to be reviewed by an independent third party) and accompanied by a performance schedule. Requires each Secretary concerned to prescribe regulations for effective oversight and management of projects under the Secretary's jurisdiction.<br/>Establishes requirements for: (1) combining projects in the event of termination of a lease or foreclosure on a project; (2) funding reserves; (3) sequestration and release of funds to be paid under a contract; (4) community meetings to convey project information; (5) certification of construction experience; (6) bonding levels; and (7) communication, review, and the effect of unsatisfactory performance or default (including the selection of a successor contractor).<br/>Requires annual reports on lessons learned regarding the operation of military housing privatization initiative projects.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
