<bill session="110" type="s" number="2513" updated="2009-01-09T17:05:47-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1210132800" datetime="2008-05-07" /></status>

	<introduced date="1197954000" datetime="2007-12-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Minute Man National Historical Park Boundary Revision Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Minute Man National Historical Park Boundary Revision Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to modify the boundary of the Minute Man National Historical Park, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300059"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-12-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1197954000" datetime="2007-12-18"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1208923200" datetime="2008-04-23"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-514.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1210132800" datetime="2008-05-07" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1213588800" datetime="2008-06-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. With written report No. 110-369.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="801" date="1213588800" datetime="2008-06-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 801.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/16/2008--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)<br/>Minute Man National Historical Park Boundary Revision Act - Modifies the boundary of Minute Man National Historical Park in Massachusetts to include a certain area generally depicted on the map entitled &quot;Minute Man National Historical Park Proposed Boundary,&quot; dated July 2007.<br/>Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to acquire the land or an interest in the land within that area by purchase from willing sellers, donation, or exchange.<br/>Authorizes appropriations. 
	</summary>
</bill>
