<bill session="110" type="s" number="2521" updated="2009-01-09T17:06:47-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"/></status>

	<introduced date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Domestic Partnership Benefits and Obligations Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide benefits to domestic partners of Federal employees.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300067"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2008-01-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300001" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2008-12-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300090" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2007-12-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S16008)</text></action>
		<action date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S16008-16009"/></action>
		<action date="1222228800" datetime="2008-09-24"><text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	12/19/2007--Introduced.<br/>Domestic Partnership Benefits and Obligations Act of 2007 - Provides that a federal employee and his or her domestic partner shall be entitled to benefits available to, and shall be subject to obligations imposed upon, a married federal employee and his or her spouse.<br/>Defines &quot;domestic partner&quot; to mean an adult unmarried person living with another adult unmarried person of the same sex in a committed, intimate relationship. Defines &quot;benefits&quot; to include federal health insurance and enhanced dental and vision benefits, retirement and disability benefits, family, medical, and emergency leave, group life insurance, long-term care insurance, compensation for work injuries, and benefits for disability, death, or captivity. Excludes members of the uniformed services from the definition of &quot;employee.&quot;<br/>Sets forth requirements for filing: (1) an affidavit of eligibility as such a domestic partner, which shall include a certification that the employee and the domestic partner are each other's sole domestic partners and intend to remain so indefinitely; and (2) a statement upon dissolution of such a domestic partnership.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
