<bill session="110" type="s" number="2535" updated="2009-01-09T17:08:33-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" /></status>

	<introduced date="1200978000" datetime="2008-01-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Martin Van Buren National Historic Site Boundary Revision Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Martin Van Buren National Historic Site Boundary Revision Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to revise the boundary of the Martin Van Buren National Historic Site, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300022"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1200978000" datetime="2008-01-22"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1217390400" datetime="2008-07-30"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with amendments. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="984" date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 984.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/16/2008--Reported to Senate amended. Martin Van Buren National Historic Site Boundary Revision Act - Adjusts the boundary of the Martin Van Buren National Historic Site in the state of New York to include approximately 261 acres of land identified as the &quot;PROPOSED PARK BOUNDARY&quot; as depicted on the &quot;Boundary Map, Martin Van Buren National Historic Site,&quot; dated January 2005. Authorizes the Secretary to acquire such lands and interests from willing sellers. Requires land acquired for the Site to be administered as part of such site. Authorizes appropriations. 
	</summary>
</bill>
