<bill session="110" type="s" number="2543" updated="2009-01-09T17:09:35-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1200978000" datetime="2008-01-22"/></status>

	<introduced date="1200978000" datetime="2008-01-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Child Custody Protection Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 18, United States Code, to prohibit taking minors across State lines in circumvention of laws requiring the involvement of parents in abortion decisions.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300040"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300002" joined="2008-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300029" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300055" joined="2008-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300047" joined="2008-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300098" joined="2008-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300071" joined="2008-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300052" joined="2008-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2008-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300088" joined="2008-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300013" joined="2008-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300077" joined="2008-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400546" joined="2008-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="2008-01-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400576" joined="2008-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300083" joined="2008-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300035" joined="2008-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400432" joined="2008-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300062" joined="2008-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300054" joined="2008-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400418" joined="2008-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300089" joined="2008-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300014" joined="2008-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300048" joined="2008-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300027" joined="2008-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300050" joined="2008-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300021" joined="2008-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300072" joined="2008-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300090" joined="2008-01-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1200978000" datetime="2008-01-22"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/22/2008--Introduced.<br/>Child Custody Protection Act - Amends the federal criminal code to prohibit transporting a minor child across a state line to obtain an abortion (deems such transporting to be a de facto abridgment of the right of a parent under any law in the minor’s state of residence that requires parental involvement in the minor’s abortion decision). Makes an exception for an abortion necessary to safe the life of the minor. Makes it an affirmative defense to a prosecution or civil action under this Act that a defendant: (1) reasonably believed that before the minor obtained the abortion, the required parental consent or notification or judicial authorization took place; or (2) was presented with documentation showing that a court waived parental notification requirements or authorized the minor's abortion.<br/>Defines &quot;abortion&quot; as the termination of a pregnancy with an intention other than to increase the probability of a live birth, preserve the life or health of the child after live birth, terminate an ectopic pregnancy, or remove a dead unborn child who died as the result of a spontaneous abortion, accidental trauma, or a criminal assault on the pregnant female or her unborn child. Imposes a fine and/or prison term of up to one year on anyone who has committed an act of incest with a minor and knowingly transports such minor across a state line to obtain an abortion. 
	</summary>
</bill>
