<bill session="110" type="s" number="2561" updated="2009-01-09T17:11:52-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" /></status>

	<introduced date="1201496400" datetime="2008-01-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a theme study to identify sites and resources to commemorate and interpret the Cold War.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300082"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2008-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300040" joined="2008-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2008-05-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1201496400" datetime="2008-01-28"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S396-397)</text></action>
		<action date="1201496400" datetime="2008-01-28"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S397"/></action>
		<action date="1217390400" datetime="2008-07-30"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="985" date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 985.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/16/2008--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.) Directs the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a national historic landmark theme study to identify sites and resources in the United States that are significant to the Cold War. Requires such theme study to include recommendations for commemorating and interpreting identified sites and resources, including; (1) sites for which studies for potential inclusion in the National Park System should be authorized; (2) sites for which new national historic landmarks should be nominated; and (3) other appropriate designations. Requires the Secretary to consult with the Secretary of the Air Force, state and local officials, state historic preservation offices, and other interested organizations and individuals in conducting the theme study. Directs the Secretary to establish the Cold War Advisory Committee, which shall assist the Secretary in carrying out this Act. Directs the Secretary to prepare and publish an interpretive handbook on such War and disseminate information gathered through the study. Authorizes appropriations. 
	</summary>
</bill>
