<bill session="110" type="s" number="2569" updated="2009-01-09T17:12:50-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29"/></status>

	<introduced date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Ovarian Cancer Biomarker Research Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Director of the National Cancer Institute to make grants for the discovery and validation of biomarkers for use in risk stratification for, and the early detection and screening of, ovarian cancer.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300011"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2008-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="2008-06-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2008-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2008-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2008-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2008-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300035" joined="2008-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2008-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2008-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300006" joined="2008-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2008-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2008-01-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="412244" joined="2008-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="2008-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2008-06-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S448)</text></action>
		<action date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/29/2008--Introduced.<br/>Ovarian Cancer Biomarker Research Act of 2008 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Director of the National Cancer Institute to enter into cooperative agreements with, or make grants to, public or nonprofit entities to establish and operate centers to conduct research on biomarkers for use in risk stratification for, and the early detection and screening of, ovarian cancer. Designates each center as an Ovarian Cancer Biomarker Center of Excellence.<br/>Allows federal payments under such an agreement or grant to be used for research on: (1) the development and characterization of new biomarkers and the refinement of existing biomarkers; (2) the clinical and laboratory validation of such biomarkers; (3) the development and implementation of clinical and epidemiological research on the utilization of such biomarkers; and (4) the development and implementation of repositories for new tissue, urine, serum, and other biological specimens.<br/>Requires the Director to: (1) make available for research banked serum and tissue specimens from clinical research regarding ovarian cancer that was funded by the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS); (2) establish an Ovarian Cancer Biomarker Clinical Trial Committee, which shall be established and operated in consultation with the Gynecologic Oncology Group, to assist the Director to design and implement national clinical trials to determine the utility of such biomarkers; and (3) establish a national data center to conduct statistical analyses of trial data.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
