<bill session="110" type="s" number="2585" updated="2009-01-09T17:14:49-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1201755600" datetime="2008-01-31"/></status>

	<introduced date="1201755600" datetime="2008-01-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Armed Forces Suicide Prevention Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the enhancement of the suicide prevention programs of the Department of Defense, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300051"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412242" joined="2008-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2008-11-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300005" joined="2008-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2008-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400619" joined="2008-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2008-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300016" joined="2008-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="412249" joined="2008-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2008-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300048" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2008-07-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2008-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="412243" joined="2008-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300050" joined="2008-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2008-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="412244" joined="2008-05-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="2008-02-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1201755600" datetime="2008-01-31"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/31/2008--Introduced.<br/>Armed Forces Suicide Prevention Act of 2008 - Directs the Secretary of Defense to undertake specified actions to enhance the suicide prevention programs of the Department of Defense (DOD), including: (1) suicide prevention training for all members of the Armed Forces and DOD civilian health care community and family support professionals; and (2) a suicide prevention outreach program throughout the Armed Forces and military family communities. Directs the Secretary to provide readjustment assistance to spouses and parents of members returning from deployments, including information on: (1) ways to identify signs and symptoms of risk factors for suicide; and (2) the national suicide prevention hotline and other suicide prevention resources. Authorizes the Secretary to award grants and enter into cooperative agreements to identify and implement within DOD strategies for: (1) the recruitment and retention of qualified military behavioral health professionals to provide mental health services, and substance abuse disorder prevention and treatment services, to members; and (2) reducing the stigma associated with seeking mental health treatment.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
