<bill session="110" type="s" number="2580" updated="2009-01-09T17:14:13-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1201669200" datetime="2008-01-30"/></status>

	<introduced date="1201669200" datetime="2008-01-30"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">College and University Rural Education Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">CURE Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to improve the participation in higher education of, and to increase opportunities in employment for, residents of rural areas.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400050"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300005" joined="2008-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2008-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400546" joined="2008-02-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2008-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300050" joined="2008-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2008-03-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300026" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412244" joined="2008-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2008-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300090" joined="2008-01-30"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1201669200" datetime="2008-01-30"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/30/2008--Introduced.<br/>College and University Rural Education (CURE) Act of 2008 - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to authorize the Secretary of Education to award grants to partnerships between rural institutions of higher education (IHEs) and rural local educational agencies, rural education service agencies, regional employers, or rural education nonprofit organizations for activities to: (1) improve the rural IHE enrollment rates of rural secondary school graduates and former attendees; and (2) encourage nontraditional students' participation in rural IHE degree programs. Authorizes the Secretary to award grants to partnerships between rural IHEs and regional employers to: (1) provide additional training to rural IHE attendees in careers relevant to the regional economy; and (2) encourage regional businesses to employ rural IHE graduates. Authorizes the Secretary to award grants to rural IHEs to create or strengthen academic programs that prepare graduates to enter high-need occupations in the regional and local economies. Requires the Comptroller General to investigate, and make recommendations to Congress regarding the improvement of, rural access to four-year IHEs and degree programs.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
