<bill session="110" type="s" number="2608" updated="2009-01-09T17:17:46-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1202360400" datetime="2008-02-07"/></status>

	<introduced date="1202360400" datetime="2008-02-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Women's Procurement Program Improvement Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to make improvements to the Small Business Act.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300091"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300083" joined="2008-04-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300035" joined="2008-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300054" joined="2008-07-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400194" joined="2008-06-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1202360400" datetime="2008-02-07"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S790-791)</text></action>
		<action date="1202360400" datetime="2008-02-07"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S791"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/7/2008--Introduced.<br/>Small Business Women's Procurement Program Improvement Act - Amends the Small Business Act relating to the women's procurement program (the provision of contracting opportunities for women-owned small businesses) to require the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to wait until five years after the program is implemented before conducting a required study to identify industries in which small businesses owned and controlled by women are underrepresented with respect to federal procurement contracting (and therefore eligible for contracting preferences or set-asides). Presumes as underrepresented by women-owned small businesses the industries identified in industry codes 11 through 81 of the 2007 North American Industry Classification System Code. States that a contracting officer need not make a finding of past gender discrimination by a contracting agency in order to comply with federal contracting requirements under the women's business procurement program.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
