<bill session="110" type="s" number="2616" updated="2009-01-09T17:18:47-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1202706000" datetime="2008-02-11" /></status>

	<introduced date="1202446800" datetime="2008-02-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Forests, Parks, Public Land, and Reclamation Projects Authorization Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize certain programs and activities in the Forest Service, the Department of the Interior, and the Department of Energy, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300009"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1202446800" datetime="2008-02-08"><text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1202706000" datetime="2008-02-11" ><text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 572.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1213156800" datetime="2008-06-11"><text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S5530"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/8/2008--Introduced.<br/>National Forests, Parks, Public Land, and Reclamation Projects Authorization Act of 2008 - Authorizes specified programs and activities in the Department of the Interior, the Forest Service, and the Department of Energy concerning, among other things, land conveyances, boundary adjustments, studies, memorials, commissions, and museums, national park natural resource protection, national trails and rivers, national heritage areas, and advanced energy technology transfer centers. Sets forth provisions concerning the Northern Mariana Islands. Makes amendments to various public laws, including the National Trails System Act, the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act, the National Underground Railroad Network to Freedom Act of 1998, the Omnibus Parks and Public Lands Management Act of 1996, the Oregon Resource Conservation Act of 1996, the Reclamation and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act, the Energy Policy Act of 2005, the Steel and Aluminum Energy Conservation and Technology Competitiveness Act of 1988, the Immigration and Nationality Act, and the Compacts of Free Association Amendments Act of 2003. 
	</summary>
</bill>
