<bill session="110" type="s" number="2611" updated="2009-01-09T17:18:09-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1202360400" datetime="2008-02-07"/></status>

	<introduced date="1202360400" datetime="2008-02-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Trade Agreement Benchmarks and Accountability Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to make bills implementing trade agreements subject to a point of order unless certain conditions are met, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300037"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2008-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2008-02-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1202360400" datetime="2008-02-07"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S792-793)</text></action>
		<action date="1202360400" datetime="2008-02-07"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S793"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/7/2008--Introduced.<br/>Trade Agreement Benchmarks and Accountability Act - Subjects bills implementing trade agreements to a point of order unless certain conditions are met.<br/>Withdraws congressional approval of a bill implementing a trade agreement only if a report by the International Trade Commission (ITC) indicates that certain benchmarks and predictions made with respect to an agreement are not being met and a joint resolution approving such withdrawal is enacted by Congress. Describes the benchmarks as analyses of the following effects of the agreement: (1) resulting job creation and job losses; (2) resulting improvement in wages for U.S. workers; (3) implementation and enforcement of the labor and environmental standards by each country that is a party to the agreement; and (4) the extent to which the agreement will result in an increase in access by U.S. businesses to the market of each country that is a party to the agreement, particularly those sectors identified by the U.S. Trade Representative (USTR) as of special importance.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
