<bill session="110" type="s" number="262" retreived_date="1226083880" updated="2008-11-07T13:51:20-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31" /></status>

	<introduced date="1168491600" datetime="2007-01-11"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Morley Nelson Snake River Birds of Prey National Conservation Area Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Morley Nelson Snake River Birds of Prey National Conservation Area Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to rename the Snake River Birds of Prey National Conservation Area in the State of Idaho as the Morley Nelson Snake River Birds of Prey National Conservation Area in honor of the late Morley Nelson, an international authority on birds of prey, who was instrumental in the establishment of this National Conservation Area, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300029"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300030" joined="2007-01-11"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1168491600" datetime="2007-01-11"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. With written report No. 110-14.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="39" date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 39.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="110" type="h" number="3734" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="110" type="h" number="3734" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Commemorations"/>
		<term name="Congressional tributes"/>
		<term name="Idaho"/>
		<term name="Names"/>
		<term name="Natural areas"/>
		<term name="Natural resources"/>
		<term name="Public lands"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/15/2007--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Morley Nelson Snake River Birds of Prey National Conservation Area Act - Renames the Snake River Birds of Prey National Conservation Area in Idaho as the Morley Nelson Snake River Birds of Prey National Conservation Area in honor of the late Morley Nelson, an international authority on birds of prey, who was instrumental in the establishment of this National Conservation Area. 
	</summary>
</bill>
