<bill session="110" type="s" number="2635" updated="2009-01-09T17:21:07-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1202878800" datetime="2008-02-13"/></status>

	<introduced date="1202878800" datetime="2008-02-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Gulf of the Farallones and Cordell Bank National Marine Sanctuaries Boundary Modification and Protection Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to expand the boundaries of the Gulf of the Farallones National Marine Sanctuary and the Cordell Bank National Marine Sanctuary.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300011"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2008-02-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1202878800" datetime="2008-02-13"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text></action>
		<action date="1203915600" datetime="2008-02-25"><text>Star Print ordered on the bill.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/13/2008--Introduced.<br/>Gulf of the Farallones and Cordell Bank National Marine Sanctuaries Boundary Modification and Protection Act - Declares it is U.S. policy to protect and preserve living and other resources of the Gulf of the Farallones National Marine Sanctuary (Farallones NMS) and Cordell Bank National Marine Sanctuary (Cordell Bank NMS) marine environments. Makes certain adjustments to expand the boundaries of the Farallones NMS and the Cordell NMS. Prohibits within the Farallones NMS and the Cordell Bank NMS: (1) the leasing, exploration, development, production, or transporting by pipeline of minerals or hydrocarbons; (2) the conduct of aquaculture (with exceptions); and (3) subject to limitation, the discharge of materials, substances, or introduced species or a harmful change in the salinity. Prohibits the conduct of aquaculture within Monterey Bay National Marine Sanctuary. Directs the Secretary of Commerce to complete: (1) an interim supplemental management plan for each sanctuary that focuses on protective resource management in the areas added by this Act; and (2) a revised comprehensive management plan for each of the sanctuaries. Requires the Secretary to review the operations of the Farallones NMS to determine whether area added to it by this Act shall be designated as a new and separate NMS.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
