<bill session="110" type="s" number="2630" updated="2009-01-09T17:20:31-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1202878800" datetime="2008-02-13"/></status>

	<introduced date="1202878800" datetime="2008-02-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Commercial Fishing Industry Health Care Coverage Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to establish a Federal grant program to provide increased health care coverage to and access for uninsured and underinsured workers and families in the commercial fishing industry, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300059"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="2008-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2008-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2008-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2008-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300075" joined="2008-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2008-04-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1202878800" datetime="2008-02-13"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S977-978"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/13/2008--Introduced.<br/>Commercial Fishing Industry Health Care Coverage Act of 2008 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services, through the Health Resources and Services Administration, to establish a grant program to assist commercial fishing states in establishing or strengthening programs to expand health care coverage and access for uninsured or underinsured workers in the commercial fishing industry and their families.<br/>Requires the Secretary to provide: (1) program planning grants for commercial fishing states and organizations within such states, including for initial research and planning to develop a qualified health care coverage program; and (2) implementation and administration grants for such states.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
