<bill session="110" type="s" number="2644" updated="2009-01-09T17:22:17-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1202965200" datetime="2008-02-14"/></status>

	<introduced date="1202965200" datetime="2008-02-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to clarify and improve information for members and former members of the Armed Forces on upgrades of discharge, to prohibit personality disorder discharges in cases of post-traumatic stress disorder and traumatic brain injury, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400050"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1202965200" datetime="2008-02-14"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/14/2008--Introduced.<br/>Requires: (1) each member of the Armed Forces being considered for any type of military discharge to receive written notice that an upgrade in the characterization of such discharge will not automatically result from review by a discharge review board; (2) such notice to also advise the member of the right to discuss discharge options with military legal counsel prior to electing a characterization or type of discharge; (3) each member to acknowledge receipt of such notice; and (4) each military department Secretary to annually make public information on discharge reviews. Directs the Secretary of Defense to ensure that each member receives, at the time of discharge, comprehensive information on the effect of the discharge status of the member on benefits and services available through the Department of Defense (DOD), Department of Veterans Affairs (VA), or any other federal department or agency providing benefits to former members. Prohibits the Secretary of a military department from discharging for a personality disorder a member: (1) unless the member has undergone testing by DOD for post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD), traumatic brain injury (TBI), and any related mental health disorder or injury prior to a final action with respect to the discharge; or (2) determined by the Secretary to suffer from PTSD, TBI, or a related mental health disorder or injury. Requires the Secretary to waive the 15-year time limit generally applicable to discharge reviews in the case of reviews of discharges for personality disorder of a former member who has been diagnosed with PTSD, TBI, or a related mental health disorder or injury.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
