<bill session="110" type="s" number="265" updated="2009-01-09T11:41:53-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31" /></status>

	<introduced date="1168491600" datetime="2007-01-11"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Little Butte/Bear Creek Subbasins Water Feasibility Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Little Butte/Bear Creek Subbasins Water Feasibility Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Reclamation, to conduct a water resource feasibility study for the Little Butte/Bear Creek Subbasins in Oregon.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300090"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="2007-01-11"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1168491600" datetime="2007-01-11"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. With written report No. 110-24.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="50" date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 50.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1213156800" datetime="2008-06-11"><text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S5530"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/16/2007--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.) Little Butte/Bear Creek Subbasins Water Feasibility Act - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Reclamation, to participate in the Water for Irrigation, Streams and the Economy Project water management feasibility study and environmental impact statement in accordance with the Memorandum of Agreement Between City of Medford and Bureau of Reclamation for the Water for Irrigation, Streams and the Economy Project, dated July 2, 2004. Authorizes appropriations. Sets the non-federal share at 50% of the Bureau's costs in carrying out this Act. Permits the non-federal share to be in the form of certain in-kind services.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
