<bill session="110" type="s" number="2663" updated="2009-01-09T17:24:28-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1204002000" datetime="2008-02-26" /></status>

	<introduced date="1203915600" datetime="2008-02-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">CPSC Reform Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reform the Consumer Product Safety Commission to provide greater protection for children's products, to improve the screening of noncompliant consumer products, to improve the effectiveness of consumer product recall programs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300080"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="2008-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="2008-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="412242" joined="2008-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2008-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400619" joined="2008-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2008-02-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2008-02-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300068" joined="2008-02-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="2008-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300078" joined="2008-02-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1203915600" datetime="2008-02-25"><text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S1127-1138"/></action>
		<calendar date="1204002000" datetime="2008-02-26" ><text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 582.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1204261200" datetime="2008-02-29"><text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure made in Senate.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S1434"/></action>
		<action date="1204261200" datetime="2008-02-29"><text>Cloture motion on the motion to proceed to the measure presented in Senate.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S1434"/><reference label="text" ref="CR S1434"/></action>
		<action date="1204261200" datetime="2008-02-29"><text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure withdrawn in Senate.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S1434"/></action>
		<action date="1204520400" datetime="2008-03-03"><text>Motion to proceed to measure considered in Senate.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S1451-1457, S1459"/></action>
		<action date="1204520400" datetime="2008-03-03"><text>Cloture on the motion to proceed invoked in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 86 - 1. Record Vote Number: 36.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S1459"/><reference label="text" ref="CR S1459"/></action>
		<action date="1204606800" datetime="2008-03-04"><text>Measure laid before Senate by motion.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S1495-1502, S1502-1518, S1518-1519"/></action>
		<action date="1204693200" datetime="2008-03-05"><text>Considered by Senate.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S1556-1593"/></action>
		<action date="1204693200" datetime="2008-03-05"><text>Cloture motion on the bill presented in Senate.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S1593"/><reference label="text" ref="CR S1593"/></action>
		<action date="1204779600" datetime="2008-03-06"><text>Considered by Senate.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S1669-1697"/></action>
		<action date="1204779600" datetime="2008-03-06"><text>Cloture motion on the bill withdrawn by unanimous consent in Senate.</text></action>
		<action date="1204779600" datetime="2008-03-06"><text>Senate incorporated this measure in H.R.4040 as an amendment.</text></action>
		<action date="1204779600" datetime="2008-03-06"><text>Senate passed companion measure H.R.4040 in lieu of this measure by Yea-Nay Vote. 79 - 13. Record Vote Number: 41.</text></action>
		<action date="1204779600" datetime="2008-03-06"><text>Returned to the Calendar. Calendar No. 582.</text></action>
		<action date="1204779600" datetime="2008-03-06"><text>See also H.R.4040.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/25/2008--Introduced.<br/>CPSC Reform Act - Amends the Consumer Product Safety Act to authorize appropriations to carry out the Act and for other purposes. Creates or modifies provisions relating to personnel and Commissioners of the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC), public disclosure of information, and rulemaking procedures. Requires third party certification of, and provides for tracking and record keeping regarding, children's products. Modifies provisions relating reporting of substantial product hazards and corrective action plans. Requires manufacturers, retailers, distributors, and importers to identify each other. Modifies provisions relating to prohibited acts, penalties, preemption, and sharing of information with federal, state, local, and foreign government agencies. Requires certain manufacturers or distributors to post an escrow or proof of insurance to cover recalls. Allows enforcement by state attorneys general and provides public and private sector whistleblower protections. Bans children's products containing lead and lowers the allowable lead content in paint. Requires a study of preventable injuries and deaths of minority children related to consumer products. Requires a cost-benefit analysis under the Poison Prevention Packaging Act of 1970. Imposes or modifies requirements regarding portable gasoline containers, toy safety, all-terrain vehicles, garage door openers, carbon monoxide, cigarette lighters, and consumer product registration forms. Requires development of a risk assessment methodology regarding imports. Requires publication of a list of product defects that constitute a substantial product hazard. Conditions importation of a consumer product on the manufacturer's compliance with certain inspection and record keeping requirements. Requires a database on violations of consumer product safety rules to be used to determine whether a container being imported contains consumer products that are in violation of a consumer product safety standard and whether action should be taken under imported products provisions.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
