<bill session="110" type="s" number="2672" updated="2009-01-09T17:25:36-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1204088400" datetime="2008-02-27"/></status>

	<introduced date="1204088400" datetime="2008-02-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Conrad State 30 Improvement Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide incentives to physicians to practice in rural and medically underserved communities.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300026"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="2008-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2008-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2008-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300061" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300013" joined="2008-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2008-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300050" joined="2008-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400194" joined="2008-06-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2008-06-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1204088400" datetime="2008-02-27"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1272-1273)</text></action>
		<action date="1204088400" datetime="2008-02-27"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/27/2008--Introduced.<br/>Conrad State 30 Improvement Act - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Technical Corrections Act of 1994 to make the the J-1 visa waiver (Conrad state 30/medical services in underserved areas) program permanent. Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to: (1) revise entry provisions for H-1B visa foreign medical graduates and provide for an increase in the annual per-state cap of 30 foreign doctors; (2) exempt from worldwide immigration numerical limitations alien physicians who have completed service requirements of a state waiver or exemption, including alien physicians who completed such service before the date of the enactment of this Act; and (3) increase Conrad program waiver authority with respect to alien physicians in facilities that treat patients from, but that may not be located in, a medically underserved area.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
