<bill session="110" type="s" number="2702" updated="2009-01-09T17:29:20-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1204606800" datetime="2008-03-04"/></status>

	<introduced date="1204606800" datetime="2008-03-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Fracture Prevention and Osteoporosis Testing Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to improve access to, and increase utilization of, bone mass measurement benefits under the Medicare part B Program.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400619"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2008-09-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2008-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2008-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2008-04-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2008-04-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2008-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2008-07-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2008-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2008-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412244" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2008-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="2008-05-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1204606800" datetime="2008-03-04"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/4/2008--Introduced.<br/>Medicare Fracture Prevention and Osteoporosis Testing Act of 2008 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a national minimum payment amount for CPT code 77080 (relating to dual energy x-ray absorptiometry, or DXA, the most widely accepted method of measuring bone mass to predict fracture risk) and CPT code 77082 (relating to vertebral fracture assessment, or VFA), and any successor to such codes as identified by the Secretary (bone mass scans). Directs the Secretary to arrange with the Institute of Medicine of the National Academies to conduct a study for a report to the Secretary and Congress on: (1) the ramifications of Medicare reimbursement reductions for DXA and VFA on beneficiary access to bone mass measurement benefits; and (2) the methods to increase use of bone mass measurement by Medicare beneficiaries.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
