<bill session="110" type="s" number="2725" updated="2009-01-09T17:32:12-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1207800000" datetime="2008-04-10" /></status>

	<introduced date="1204779600" datetime="2008-03-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 6892 Main Street in Gloucester, Virginia, as the &quot;Congresswoman Jo Ann S. Davis Post Office&quot;.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300099"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412249" joined="2008-03-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1204779600" datetime="2008-03-06"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1705)</text></action>
		<action date="1204779600" datetime="2008-03-06"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1206676800" datetime="2008-03-28"><text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs referred to Subcommittee on Federal Financial Management, Government Information, Federal Services, and International Security.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1207800000" datetime="2008-04-10" ><text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1207800000" datetime="2008-04-10"><text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman without amendment. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="680" date="1207800000" datetime="2008-04-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 680.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1210564800" datetime="2008-05-12"><text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S4046"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/6/2008--Introduced.<br/>Designates the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 6892 Main Street in Gloucester, Virginia, as the &quot;Congresswoman Jo Ann S. Davis Post Office.&quot;<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
