<bill session="110" type="s" number="2723" updated="2009-01-09T17:31:58-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1204779600" datetime="2008-03-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1204779600" datetime="2008-03-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Deamonte Driver Dental Care Access Improvement Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to expand the dental workforce and improve dental access, prevention, and data reporting, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400050"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2008-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2008-04-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2008-04-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2008-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="2008-03-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2008-04-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2008-07-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1204779600" datetime="2008-03-06"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/6/2008--Introduced.<br/>Deamonte Driver Dental Care Access Improvement Act of 2008 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to schools of dentistry and hospitals with accredited training programs in pediatric dentistry. Amends title V (Maternal and Child Health Services) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to require the Secretary to provide for a pilot program to increase access to dental care for underserved populations through the use of new allied dental health professionals. Requires the Secretary to award grants to federally qualified health centers to expand and improve the provision of dental services to medically underserved populations. Authorizes the Secretary to award grants to develop, implement, and evaluate public health and clinical strategies to prevent and manage early childhood caries. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a business tax credit for a portion of compensation received for providing dental services under SSA titles XIX (Medicaid) or XXI (State Children's Health Insurance Program) (SCHIP) or from an uninsured individual. Requires the Secretary, acting through the the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to conduct a public education and awareness campaign on preventing, controlling, and ultimately eliminating early childhood caries. Amends SSA titles XIX and XXI to expand reporting requirements with respect to children's dental services. Requires the Comptroller General to study payment rates for dental services provided to individuals under Medicaid or SCHIP. Requires the Secretary to ensure the inclusion of dental health prevention and promotion activities within existing prenatal and maternal child health programs.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
