<bill session="110" type="s" number="2741" updated="2009-01-09T17:34:14-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1205208000" datetime="2008-03-11"/></status>

	<introduced date="1205208000" datetime="2008-03-11"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Disability Savings Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for disability savings accounts, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300034"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1205208000" datetime="2008-03-11"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1878-1879)</text></action>
		<action date="1205208000" datetime="2008-03-11"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S1879-1882"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/11/2008--Introduced.<br/>Disability Savings Act of 2008 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a tax exemption for disability savings accounts that have a value of $250,000 or less and are established for beneficiaries under the age of 65 who are blind or disabled.<br/>Allows tax-free distributions from such accounts for certain services provided to account beneficiaries, including education services, respite care, clothing, therapy, nutritional management, and funeral and burial expenses.<br/>Allows tax credits for contributions of up to $2,000 made to a disability savings account and for certain entities that maintain disability savings accounts.<br/>Permits disability savings accounts to be disregarded in determining eligibility for Medicaid benefits and certain other means-tested federal programs.<br/>Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a program for marketing, outreach, and education related to disability savings accounts.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
