<bill session="110" type="s" number="276" updated="2009-01-09T11:43:16-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1168491600" datetime="2007-01-11"/></status>

	<introduced date="1168491600" datetime="2007-01-11"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Passport and Visa Security Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to strengthen the consequences of the fraudulent use of United States or foreign passports and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300043"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300088" joined="2007-01-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300062" joined="2007-05-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1168491600" datetime="2007-01-11"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S459-460)</text></action>
		<action date="1168491600" datetime="2007-01-11"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S461-463"/></action>
		<action date="1178078400" datetime="2007-05-02"><text>Committee on the Judiciary Subcommittee on Terrorism, Technology and Homeland Security. Hearings held.</text></action>
		<action date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6519)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/11/2007--Introduced.<br/>Passport and Visa Security Act of 2007 - Amends the federal criminal code to revise provisions relating to the unauthorized issuance of U.S. passports to prohibit any person, during any three-year period, from: (1) producing, issuing, or transferring 10 or more passports without lawful authority; (2) forging, counterfeiting, altering, or falsely making such passports; (3) transacting sales of or distributing such counterfeit passports; or (4) making 10 or more false applications for passports. Imposes a fine and/or prison term of up to 20 years for violations. Revises criminal prohibitions against: (1) making false statements in an application for a passport; (2) forgery and unlawful production of a passport; (3) misuse of a passport; and (4) immigration and visa fraud, including trafficking in counterfeit immigration documents. Makes the punishment for attempts or conspiracies to commit passport or visa fraud the same as for the completed crime. Prohibits in connection with federal immigration laws: (1) any scheme to defraud persons seeking benefits under such laws; and (2) false representation of attorney (or accredited representative) status. Grants extraterritorial jurisdiction for the prosecution of certain passport and visa fraud offenses. Directs the U.S. Sentencing Commission to revise its sentencing guidelines and policies relating to passport and visa fraud offenses. Directs the Attorney General to develop prosecution guidelines for compliance with U.S. treaty obligations relating to asylum seekers entering the United States with fraudulent documents. Expands the investigative authority of State Department special agents relating to passport and document fraud.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
