<bill session="110" type="s" number="2770" updated="2009-01-09T17:38:07-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"/></status>

	<introduced date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Downed Animal Enforcement Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Meat Inspection Act to strengthen the food safety inspection system by imposing stricter penalties for the slaughter of nonambulatory livestock.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300043"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="2008-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2008-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2008-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300001" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="2008-09-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR 3/14/2008 S2151)</text></action>
		<action date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/13/2008--Introduced.<br/>Downed Animal Enforcement Act of 2008 - Amends the Federal Meat Inspection Act to make it a violation of such Act to: (1) slaughter any nonambulatory livestock, or prepare any carcass or carcass part or meat or meat food product from such animal, for human food use; or (2) fail to comply with the Humane Methods of Slaughter Act of 1958. Establishes the following penalties for violations of such prohibitions: (1) gross income-based civil penalty for a first violation; (2) one-year inspection service suspension for a second violation; and (3) permanent withdrawal of inspection service a third violation. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to promulgate final regulations that provide for public disclosure of a comprehensive list of establishments at which recalled meat or poultry is known to be available for public consumption or sale.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
