<bill session="110" type="s" number="2779" updated="2009-01-09T17:39:14-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" /></status>

	<introduced date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 to clarify that uncertified States and Indian tribes have the authority to use certain payments for certain noncoal reclamation projects.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300009"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400619" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300007" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300003" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300036" joined="2008-03-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR 3/14/2008 S2156-2157)</text></action>
		<action date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. (text of measure as introduced: CR 3/14/2008 S2157)</text></action>
		<action date="1215576000" datetime="2008-07-09"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-572.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="986" date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 986.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/16/2008--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)<br/>Amends the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977, with respect to the allocation of surface mining reclamation funds to states and Indian tribes, to modify limitations on such allocations to provide for payments for filling voids and sealing tunnels and entryways (of non-coal mines as well as coal mines).<br/>Requires uncertified states or Indian tribes to use such allocated funds to fill voids and seal tunnels and entryways (of non-coal as well as coal mines). (&quot;Uncertified states and Indian tribes&quot; are those which have not certified to the Secretary of the Interior that all priorities specified under the Act for eligible lands and waters have been achieved.)<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
