<bill session="110" type="s" number="2787" updated="2009-01-09T17:40:15-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1206936000" datetime="2008-03-31"/></status>

	<introduced date="1206936000" datetime="2008-03-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2009</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2009</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2009 for military activities of the Department of Defense, to prescribe military personnel strengths for fiscal year 2009, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300066"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300071" joined="2008-03-31"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1206936000" datetime="2008-03-31"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2234)</text></action>
		<action date="1206936000" datetime="2008-03-31"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/31/2008--Introduced.<br/>National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2009 - Authorizes appropriations for the Department of Defense (DOD) for FY2009. Authorizes appropriations to DOD for: (1) procurement, including aircraft, missiles, weapons and tracked combat vehicles, ammunition, shipbuilding and conversion, and other procurement; (2) the Rapid Acquisition Fund; (3) the Joint Improvised Explosive Device Defeat Fund; (4) Defense Production Act purchases; (5) research, development, test, and evaluation; (6) operation and maintenance, including working capital funds, the Defense Health Program, chemical agents and munitions destruction, drug interdiction and counter-drug activities, and the Defense Inspector General; (6) active and reserve military personnel, including end strengths; (7) the North Atlantic Treaty Organization Security Investment Program; (8) chemical demilitarization construction; and (9) Guard and reserve forces facilities. Sets forth provisions or requirements concerning: (1) active and reserve military personnel, including officer and reserve personnel policy; (2) military education and training; (3) military pay and allowances; (4) retired pay and survivor benefits; (5) military health care; (6) acquisition policy and management; (7) DOD organization and management, including the chemical demilitarization program and intelligence-related matters; (8) financial matters, including counter-drug activities and matters related to homeland security; (9) civilian personnel matters; (10) matters relating to foreign nations; (11) matters relating to building partner capabilities to combat international terrorism; and (12) base closure and realignment activities. Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2009 - Authorizes appropriations for FY2009 for military construction for the Armed Forces and defense agencies.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
