<bill session="110" type="s" number="2799" updated="2009-01-09T17:41:45-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1207108800" datetime="2008-04-02"/></status>

	<introduced date="1207108800" datetime="2008-04-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Women Veterans Health Care Improvement Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to expand and improve health care services available to women veterans, especially those serving in Operation Iraqi Freedom and Operation Enduring Freedom, from the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300076"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2008-06-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2008-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2008-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2008-04-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2008-04-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300068" joined="2008-04-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2008-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300054" joined="2008-04-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2008-05-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2008-06-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2008-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300075" joined="2008-04-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300084" joined="2008-04-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2008-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="2008-04-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2008-07-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1207108800" datetime="2008-04-02"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/2/2008--Introduced.<br/>Women Veterans Health Care Improvement Act of 2008 - Requires the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to: (1) conduct a long-term epidemiological study on the health of women veterans who served on active duty in Operations Iraqi Freedom and Enduring Freedom; (2) assess barriers encountered by women veterans to the provision by the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) of comprehensive health care; (3) assess all health care services and programs provided by the VA for women veterans; (4) study the health consequences on women veterans of active-duty service in Operations Iraqi Freedom and Enduring Freedom; (5) provide training and certification for mental health professionals who provide counseling and care to women veterans suffering from sexual trauma; (6) develop a program of training and certification for VA health care professionals on the effective treatment of women veterans suffering from post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD); (7) carry out a pilot program of child care for certain women veterans receiving health care from VA facilities; (8) carry out a pilot program of reintegration and readjustment services in group retreat settings for women veterans recently separated from service after a prolonged deployment; and (9) ensure that there is at least one full-time women veterans program manager at each VA medical center. Authorizes the Secretary to furnish care to a newborn child of a woman veteran receiving VA maternity care for up to 30 days after the birth of the child. Requires women veterans recently separated from service to be included on the Advisory Committee on Women Veterans and the Advisory Committee on Minority Veterans. 
	</summary>
</bill>
