<bill session="110" type="s" number="2805" updated="2009-01-09T17:42:32-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" /></status>

	<introduced date="1207108800" datetime="2008-04-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Rio Grande Pueblos Irrigation Infrastructure Improvement Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Rio Grande Pueblos Irrigation Infrastructure Improvement Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Commissioner of Reclamation, to assess the irrigation infrastructure of the Rio Grande Pueblos in the State of New Mexico and provide grants to, and enter into cooperative agreements with, the Rio Grande Pueblos to repair, rehabilitate, or reconstruct existing infrastructure, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300009"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1207108800" datetime="2008-04-02"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2359)</text></action>
		<action date="1207108800" datetime="2008-04-02"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S2359-2361"/></action>
		<action date="1209009600" datetime="2008-04-24"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="987" date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 987.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/2/2008--Introduced.<br/>Rio Grande Pueblos Irrigation Infrastructure Improvement Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Commissioner of Reclamation, to: (1) conduct a study of irrigation infrastructure for 18 Rio Grande Pueblos in New Mexico; and (2) develop a list of projects recommended to be implemented over a 10-year period to repair, rehabilitate, or reconstruct such infrastructure. Requires the Secretary to carry out such activity with the consent of each Pueblo that notifies the Secretary of the intention to participate in the study and development of the list.<br/>Directs the Secretary, in developing that list, to: (1) consider specified factors, including the extent of disrepair, economic and cultural impacts, and overall benefits of the project to efficient water operations; and (2) prioritize the recommended projects based on a review of each of the factors and a consideration of the projected benefits. Authorizes the Secretary (subject to specified limitations) to provide grants to the Pueblos to plan, design, construct, or otherwise implement recommended projects to repair, rehabilitate, reconstruct, or replace Pueblo irrigation infrastructure to: (1) increase water use efficiency and agricultural productivity for the benefit of a Pueblo; (2) conserve water; or (3) otherwise enhance water management or help avert water supply conflicts in the Rio Grande Basin.<br/>Sets the federal share of the project's cost at 75%, with an exception based on financial hardship. Provides that nothing in this Act shall affect existing project-specific authority, U.S. responsibilities to any such Pueblo, Pueblo water rights, state water law, or an interstate compact governing water.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
