<bill session="110" type="s" number="2807" updated="2009-01-09T17:42:46-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1207195200" datetime="2008-04-03" /></status>

	<introduced date="1207108800" datetime="2008-04-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Land and Liberty Protection Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Do No Harm Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Government Real Estate Accountability and Transparency Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">No Trespassing Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Americans From Violent Crime Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Taxpayer Property Protection Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect the liberty and property of all Americans.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400576"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1207108800" datetime="2008-04-02"><text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1207195200" datetime="2008-04-03" ><text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 623.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/2/2008--Introduced.<br/>Land and Liberty Protection Act of 2008 - Protecting Americans from Violent Crime Act of 2008 - Bars the promulgation and enforcement of regulations that prohibit individuals from possessing firearms in units of the National Park System and the National Wildlife Refuge System. Government Real Estate Accountability and Transparency Act of 2008 - Requires the submission of annual reports detailing the amount of land that is owned by the federal government and the costs of maintaining that land. No Trespassing Act of 2008 - Bars the Secretary of the Interior from approving a management plan for a National Heritage Area unless the local coordinating entity of the proposed Area notifies the individuals who reside or own property in that Area. Prohibits any National Park Service (NPS) employee or member of the local coordinating entity of a National Heritage Area from entering private property without the owner's consent. Taxpayer Property Protection Act of 2008 - Bars the Department of the Interior, the Department of Energy, and the Forest Service from assuming control of any land in a state unless the citizens of the political subdivisions in which the land is located approve the assumption of control by a referendum. Do No Harm Act of 2008 - Prohibits a National Heritage Area designation from taking effect until the President certifies that it will not cause an adverse impact on specified agriculture, livestock, energy, critical infrastructure, and housing concerns.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
