<bill session="110" type="s" number="2817" updated="2009-01-09T17:43:59-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1207195200" datetime="2008-04-03"/></status>

	<introduced date="1207195200" datetime="2008-04-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Park Centennial Fund Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the National Park Centennial Fund, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400619"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300002" joined="2008-07-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300005" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300062" joined="2008-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300078" joined="2008-09-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="412244" joined="2008-04-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1207195200" datetime="2008-04-03"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2444-2445)</text></action>
		<action date="1207195200" datetime="2008-04-03"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/3/2008--Introduced.<br/>National Park Centennial Fund Act - Establishes a revolving fund in the Treasury to be known as the National Park Centennial Fund, into which, not later than 30 days after enactment of this Act, on October 1, 2008, and each October 1 thereafter through 2016, there shall be transferred, out of any funds in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $100 million to carry out this Act. Requires the annual budget submission of the President for the Department of the Interior to include a list of National Park Centennial proposals. Requires the list to include projects under the following initiatives: (1) an Education in Parks Centennial Initiative; (2) a Diversity in Parks Centennial Initiative; (3) a Supporting Park Professionals Centennial Initiative; (4) an Environmental Leadership Centennial Initiative; (5) a Natural Resource Protection Centennial Initiative; (6) a Cultural Resource Protection Centennial Initiative; and (7) a Visitor Enjoyment and Health Centennial Initiative. Sets forth requirements for: (1) the deposit of revenues in excess of specified amounts received from offshore oil and gas activities in the Gulf of Mexico into the Fund; and (2) the establishment of special rate postage stamps as a means through which the public can contribute to the Fund. Treats the amounts received pursuant to such requirements as offsetting receipts for this Act's purposes. Terminates the authority provided for such offsets on September 30, 2017. 
	</summary>
</bill>
