<bill session="110" type="s" number="2819" updated="2009-01-09T17:44:14-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1207195200" datetime="2008-04-03"/></status>

	<introduced date="1207195200" datetime="2008-04-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Economic Recovery in Health Care Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to preserve access to Medicaid and the State Children's Health Insurance Program during an economic downturn, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300084"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="2008-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2008-04-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="2008-04-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2008-04-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300082" joined="2008-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2008-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2008-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2008-04-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2008-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2008-04-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300061" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300068" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2008-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300081" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412249" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="2008-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2008-04-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2008-04-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300001" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="412243" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300078" joined="2008-04-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2008-04-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2008-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="412244" joined="2008-04-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="2008-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2008-04-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1207195200" datetime="2008-04-03"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2445-2446)</text></action>
		<action date="1207195200" datetime="2008-04-03"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S2446-2448"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/3/2008--Introduced.<br/>Economic Recovery in Health Care Act of 2008 - Prohibits the Secretary of Health and Human Services from finalizing, implementing, enforcing, or otherwise taking any action to give effect prior to April 1, 2009, to the following administrative actions: (1) the proposed and final rule (with certain exceptions) entitled &quot;Medicaid Program; Health-Care Related Taxes,&quot; published, respectively, on March 23, 2007, and on February 22, 2008; (2) the proposed rule entitled &quot;Medicaid Program; Graduate Medical Education,&quot; published on May 23, 2007; (3) the State Health Official Letter 07-001, dated August 17, 2007, issued by the Director of the Center for Medicaid and State Operations in the Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services regarding certain requirements under the State Children's Health Insurance Program (SCHIP) relating to the prevention of the substitution of health benefits coverage for children and the enforcement of medical support orders; (4) the proposed rule entitled &quot;Medicaid Program; Clarification of Outpatient Clinic and Hospital Facility Services definition and Upper Payment Limit,&quot; published on September 28, 2007; (5) the interim final rule entitled &quot;Medicaid Program; Optional State Plan Case Management Services,&quot; published on December 4, 2007; and (6) the proposed rule entitled &quot;Revisions to Procedures for the Departmental Appeals Board and Other Departmental Hearings,&quot; published on December 28, 2007. Amends the U.S. Troop Readiness, Veterans' Care, Katrina Recovery, and Iraq Accountability Appropriations Act of 2007 to extend through April 1, 2009, the moratorium relating to the cost limit for providers operated by units of government and provisions to ensure the integrity of the federal-state financial partnership. Amends the Medicare, Medicaid, and SCHIP Extension Act of 2007 to extend through April 1, 2009, the moratorium relating to rehabilitation services, school-based administration, and school-based transportation. Provides for state fiscal relief through a temporary increase of Medicaid federal medical assistance percentage (FMAP) and targeted grants to Round One (FY2008 and FY2009) and Round Two (FY2009 only) Qualifying States. Makes appropriations for related payments to such states.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
