<bill session="110" type="s" number="2839" updated="2009-01-09T17:46:48-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1207800000" datetime="2008-04-10"/></status>

	<introduced date="1207800000" datetime="2008-04-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Global Competitiveness Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide emergency relief for United States businesses and industries currently employing temporary foreign workers and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300027"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300002" joined="2008-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300030" joined="2008-07-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2008-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300050" joined="2008-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300095" joined="2008-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300049" joined="2008-04-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1207800000" datetime="2008-04-10"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/10/2008--Introduced.<br/>Global Competitiveness Act of 2008 - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to extend the annual cap exemption for returning H-2B aliens (temporary nonagricultural workers). Revises H-1B nonimmigrant visa (specialty occupation) provisions regarding: (1) recapture of unused visas (including a recapture fee); (2) visa increases and increases for exemptions from numerical limitations for aliens with higher education degrees; (3) increased employer petition fees; (4) employer restrictions on outsourcing, advertising, and hiring; and (5) enforcement, information sharing, and labor application penalty increases. Amends the American Competitiveness in the Twenty-first Century Act of 2000 regarding: (1) recapture of unused employment-based immigrant visas and redistribution to specified employment categories, including nurses and physical therapists; and (2) a recapture fee (with an exemption for certain health care facilities). Increases the annual limit for National Science Foundation low-income scholarships. Revises L-visa (intracompany transfer) provisions regarding: (1) Department of Homeland Security (DHS) authority to investigate employer fraud; (2) whistleblower protections; and (3) limitations on approval of start-up company petitions. Authorizes (with a supplemental fee) early status adjustment filing for certain employment-based immigrants. Obligates funds from the H-1B Nonimmigrant Petitioner Account for programs under the Jacob K. Javits Gifted and Talented Students Education Act of 2001. Amends the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1966 to extend the E-Verify program. 
	</summary>
</bill>
