<bill session="110" type="s" number="2834" updated="2009-01-09T17:46:10-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1207713600" datetime="2008-04-09"/></status>

	<introduced date="1207713600" datetime="2008-04-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Washington County Growth and Conservation Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish wilderness areas, promote conservation, and improve public land in Washington County, Utah, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300007"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300052" joined="2008-04-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1207713600" datetime="2008-04-09"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1208836800" datetime="2008-04-22"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-493.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/9/2008--Introduced.<br/>Washington County Growth and Conservation Act of 2008 - Designates specified public lands in Utah as wilderness and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System. Provides for the acquisition of land or interests in any such area designated as wilderness. Releases certain wilderness study areas in Washington County, Utah, from further study for designation as wilderness. Designates specified federal land in Zion National Park in Washington County as a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System, which shall be known as the Zion Wilderness. Establishes the Red Cliffs National Conservation Area and the Beaver Dam Wash National Conservation Area in Utah. Designates specified segments of the Virgin River and its tributaries across federal land within and adjacent to Zion National Park as components of the national wild and scenic rivers system. Requires development of a comprehensive Washington County travel management plan. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to designate a trail which shall be known as the &quot;High Desert Off-Highway Vehicle Trail.&quot; Provides for the conveyance of certain public land in Washington County. Grants the Washington County Water Conservancy District nonexclusive rights-of-way for specified reservoirs. Sets forth provisions regarding the management of priority biological areas in Washington County. Authorizes grants and cooperative agreements for the carrying out of initiatives related to the restoration or conservation of such areas.<br/>Provides for the conveyance of specified federal land in Dixie National Forest in Utah. 
	</summary>
</bill>
