<bill session="110" type="s" number="2858" updated="2009-01-09T17:49:08-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1208232000" datetime="2008-04-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1208232000" datetime="2008-04-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Dorothy I. Height and Whitney M. Young, Jr. Social Work Reinvestment Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Social Work Reinvestment Commission to provide independent counsel to Congress and the Secretary of Health and Human Services on policy issues associated with recruitment, retention, research, and reinvestment in the profession of social work, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300073"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="2008-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2008-06-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="2008-06-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2008-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2008-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="2008-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2008-09-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2008-07-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2008-09-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300084" joined="2008-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2008-06-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300090" joined="2008-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2008-07-31"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1208232000" datetime="2008-04-15"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3028-3029)</text></action>
		<action date="1208232000" datetime="2008-04-15"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/15/2008--Introduced.<br/>Dorothy I. Height and Whitney M. Young, Jr. Social Work Reinvestment Act - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish the Social Work Reinvestment Commission to provide independent counsel to Congress on policy issues associated with the recruitment, retension, research, and reinvestment in the profession of social work.<br/>Directs the Commission to study and report to Congress on issues facing the social work profession, including: (1) fair market compensation, high social work educational debt, social work workforce trends, knowledge development, and social work safety; and (2) state-level social work licensure policies and reciprocity agreements for providing services across state lines.<br/>Authorizes the Secretary to award various grants to eligible entities and individuals to support demonstration programs related to research, workplace improvements, education, training, and programs of excellence.<br/>Directs the Secretary to: (1) contract with a national social work research entity to serve as a coordinating center and clearinghouse for information on activities under the demonstration program; and (2) develop and issue public service announcements that advertise and promote the social work profession. Designates March of 2008, and of each succeeding year, as National Social Work Awareness Month. 
	</summary>
</bill>
