<bill session="110" type="s" number="2852" updated="2009-01-09T17:48:24-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1208145600" datetime="2008-04-14"/></status>

	<introduced date="1208145600" datetime="2008-04-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Spending and Taxpayer Accessibility Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide increased accessibility to information on Federal spending, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300027"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300021" joined="2008-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400194" joined="2008-05-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1208145600" datetime="2008-04-14"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2977-2978)</text></action>
		<action date="1208145600" datetime="2008-04-14"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S2978-2979"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/14/2008--Introduced.<br/>Federal Spending and Taxpayer Accessibility Act - Directs the Congressional Research Service (CRS) to create a free public Internet website that includes data for fiscal years after FY2007 and allows the user to search specified information on each federal earmark, including the intended recipient, total dollar amount, the sponsoring Member of Congress, and the status of the bill to which it is attached. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to provide, upon an eligible individual's request, his or her taxpayer account statement. Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to include the financial outlays exceeding $25,000 of all federal agencies for fiscal years after FY2008 on the Internet website established by the Federal Funding Accountability and Transparency Act of 2006. Declares that nothing in this Act shall require the disclosure of classified information. 
	</summary>
</bill>
