<bill session="110" type="s" number="2860" updated="2009-01-09T17:49:25-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1208232000" datetime="2008-04-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1208232000" datetime="2008-04-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Fair Value and Independent Appraisal Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to diminish predatory lending by enhancing appraisal quality and standards, to improve appraisal oversight, to ensure mortgage appraiser independence, to provide for enhanced remedies and enforcement, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412246"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400621" joined="2008-04-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300078" joined="2008-05-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1208232000" datetime="2008-04-15"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/15/2008--Introduced.<br/>Fair Value and Independent Appraisal Act - Amends the Truth in Lending Act to prohibit a creditor from extending a mortgage to any consumer without first obtaining a written appraisal of the property to be mortgaged, prepared in accordance with specified requirements. Requires a creditor to provide a copy of each such appraisal to the consumer without charge, at least three days prior to the transaction closing date. Declares unfair or deceptive specified property appraisal practices in the provision of: (1) mortgage lending services for a consumer credit transaction secured by the consumer's principal dwelling; or (2) any mortgage brokerage services for such a transaction. Establishes civil monetary penalties for such practices. Directs the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and the Federal Trade Commission to jointly prescribe regulations defining such unfair or deceptive acts or practices.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
