<bill session="110" type="s" number="2872" updated="2009-01-09T17:50:55-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1208318400" datetime="2008-04-16"/></status>

	<introduced date="1208318400" datetime="2008-04-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Benefit Rating Acceleration for Veteran Entitlements Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend titles II and XVI of the Social Security Act to provide for treatment of disability rates and certified as total by reason of unemployability by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs as disability for purposes of such titles, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400050"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2008-04-16"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1208318400" datetime="2008-04-16"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/16/2008--Introduced.<br/>Benefit Rating Acceleration for Veteran Entitlements Act of 2008 - Amends titles II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) and XVI (Supplemental Security Income) (SSI) of the Social Security Act to treat as a disability for OASDI and SSI disability payment purposes any service-connected disability rated and certified by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs as total by reason of unemployability, and expected to last at least one year. Applies the same treatment to related child's insurance and widow's and widower's insurance benefits. Makes medical findings by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs of total service-connected disability by reason of unemployability conclusive evidence of disability for OASDI and SSI purposes. Requires treatment of any determination of a veteran's disability by the Commissioner of Social Security for OASDI and SSI purposes as a disability or a combination of disabilities rated as 100% disabling by reason of individual unemployability for veterans' benefits purposes. Cautions, however, that such requirement shall not be construed to establish a service-connection or presumption of service-connection with respect to any disability of a veteran.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
