<bill session="110" type="s" number="2902" updated="2009-01-09T17:54:37-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1208923200" datetime="2008-04-23"/></status>

	<introduced date="1208923200" datetime="2008-04-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Independent Office of Advocacy and Small Business Regulatory Reform Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure the independent operation of the Office of Advocacy of the Small Business Administration, ensure complete analysis of potential impacts on small entities of rules, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300091"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300080" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400194" joined="2008-06-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1208923200" datetime="2008-04-23"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3307-3308)</text></action>
		<action date="1208923200" datetime="2008-04-23"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S3308-3309"/></action>
		<action date="1209441600" datetime="2008-04-29"><text>Senate Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text></action>
		<action date="1209441600" datetime="2008-04-29"><text>Referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/23/2008--Introduced.<br/>Independent Office of Advocacy and Small Business Regulatory Reform Act of 2008 - Requires the Office of Advocacy (Office) of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to carry out responsibilities concerning the analysis of regulatory functions, including regulatory flexibility analyses. Requires: (1) each federal budget to include a separate statement of the amount requested for the Office, designated in a separate account in the General Fund of the Treasury; and (2) the SBA Administrator to provide the Office with appropriate and adequate office space, together with necessary equipment, operating budget, and communications facilities and services, and to provide necessary maintenance services for such offices and equipment. Requires: (1) each federal agency to notify the SBA's Chief Counsel for Advocacy of any agency draft rules that may have a significant impact on a substantial number of small businesses; (2) each agency's final regulatory analysis of a final rule to include the agency's response to any comments of the Chief Counsel for Advocacy with respect to that rule, as well as changes made as a result of such comments; and (3) agencies to make final regulatory flexibility analyses available to the public, including on a website.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
