<bill session="110" type="s" number="2911" updated="2009-01-09T17:55:46-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1209009600" datetime="2008-04-24"/></status>

	<introduced date="1209009600" datetime="2008-04-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Infant Immunization Improvement Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve vaccination rates among children.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300075"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2008-04-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1209009600" datetime="2008-04-24"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3405)</text></action>
		<action date="1209009600" datetime="2008-04-24"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/24/2008--Introduced.<br/>Infant Immunization Improvement Act of 2008 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize an immunization grantee to use funds from a preventive health services grant to provide, through participating Women, Infants and Children Program clinics: (1) recommended vaccines to eligible children aged 0 to 35 months; (2) for the coordination of care or immunization services; or (3) payment for the salary of an immunization coordinator. Requires: (1) the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) and state administrators of such immunization program to consult with the Food and Nutrition Service in carrying out activities related to screening for appropriate immunization services; and (2) any recipient of such a grant that receives funding for an immunization information system to permit all clinics that participate in preventive health services projects and in the Special Supplemental Food and Nutrition Program to have access to the system.<br/>Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director, to annually conduct an immunization awareness campaign and carry out immunization education and outreach activities to: (1) increase the awareness of parents of the benefits of age appropriate immunizations; (2) inform the general public concerning the efficacy of new vaccines and new vaccine schedules; and (3) disseminate information that emphasizes the benefits of recommended vaccines for the public good.<br/>Requires activities under this Act to target areas with the greatest immunization needs in the 0 to 35 month age group.<br/>Calls for the Secretary and the Director to work to improve the integration of immunization information systems with electronic medical records, other health information systems, and health information exchanges.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
