<bill session="110" type="s" number="2926" updated="2009-01-09T17:57:44-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1209355200" datetime="2008-04-28"/></status>

	<introduced date="1209355200" datetime="2008-04-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Nonprofit Research and Education Corporations Enhancement Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to modify and update provisions of law relating to nonprofit research and education corporations, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300001"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1209355200" datetime="2008-04-28"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3445-3446)</text></action>
		<action date="1209355200" datetime="2008-04-28"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/28/2008--Introduced.<br/>Veterans Nonprofit Research and Education Corporations Enhancement Act of 2008 - Amends federal provisions concerning the establishment at Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) medical facilities of nonprofit research and education corporations (NRECs) to allow an NREC to facilitate the conduct of research or education, or both, at more than one VA medical center. States that such an NREC shall be known as a multi-medical center research corporation (MCRC). Allows an NREC to act as a MCRC if: (1) the NREC board of directors approve a resolution permitting that NREC to act as a MCRC; and (2) the Secretary of Veterans Affairs approves the resolution. Requires each NREC and MCRC to be established in accordance with the nonprofit laws of the state in which the VA medical center which it supports is located. States that either such corporation shall not be considered to be owned by, or an agent or instrumentality of, the United States. Expands the authorized areas of experience or expertise with respect to non-VA members of boards of directors of NRECs and MCRCs. Increases authorized corporate powers of NRECs and MCRCs to include entering into contracts and setting fees for education and training facilitated through such corporation.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
