<bill session="110" type="s" number="2932" updated="2009-01-09T17:58:30-05:00">
	<status><enacted date="1223438400" datetime="2008-10-08" /></status>

	<introduced date="1209441600" datetime="2008-04-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Poison Center Support, Enhancement, and Awareness Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="enacted">Poison Center Support, Enhancement, and Awareness Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to reauthorize the poison center national toll-free number, national media campaign, and grant program to provide assistance for poison prevention, sustain the funding of poison centers, and enhance the public health of people of the United States.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300076"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="2008-07-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300002" joined="2008-07-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2008-06-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300052" joined="2008-07-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2008-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2008-06-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300081" joined="2008-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300077" joined="2008-06-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300083" joined="2008-07-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300035" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400432" joined="2008-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2008-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300010" joined="2008-06-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2008-06-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300014" joined="2008-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300003" joined="2008-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2008-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300078" joined="2008-06-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300075" joined="2008-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300050" joined="2008-07-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2008-06-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400054" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400194" joined="2008-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2008-07-31"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1209441600" datetime="2008-04-29"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
		<action date="1222142400" datetime="2008-09-23"><text>Senate Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text></action>
		<action date="1222142400" datetime="2008-09-23"><text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S9340-9341"/></action>
		<vote date="1222142400" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2008-09-23" where="s" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text></vote>
		<action date="1222261380" datetime="2008-09-24T10:03:00-04:00"><text>Received in the House.</text></action>
		<action date="1222228800" datetime="2008-09-24"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<action date="1222265280" datetime="2008-09-24T11:08:00-04:00"><text>Held at the desk.</text></action>
		<action date="1222372200" datetime="2008-09-25T16:50:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Pallone moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text></action>
		<action date="1222372200" datetime="2008-09-25T16:50:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H9920-9922"/></action>
		<action date="1222372200" datetime="2008-09-25T16:50:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 2932.</text></action>
		<action date="1222372500" datetime="2008-09-25T16:55:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Terry objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text></action>
		<action date="1222446300" datetime="2008-09-26T13:25:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H10049"/></action>
		<vote date="1222446720" how="roll" roll="653" datetime="2008-09-26T13:32:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote2" suspension="1" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by recorded vote (2/3 required): 403 - 6 (Roll no. 653). (text: CR 9/25/2008 H9920-9921)</text></vote>
		<topresident date="1222401600" datetime="2008-09-26" ><text>Cleared for White House.</text></topresident>
		<topresident date="1222660800" datetime="2008-09-29" ><text>Presented to President.</text></topresident>
		<signed date="1223438400" datetime="2008-10-08" ><text>Signed by President.</text></signed>
		<enacted number="110-377" date="1223438400" datetime="2008-10-08" type="public" ><text>Became Public Law No: 110-377.</text></enacted>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/8/2008--Public Law. Poison Center Support, Enhancement, and Awareness Act of 2008 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to provide coordination and assistance for the maintenance of the nationwide toll-free phone number to access poison control centers. Requires the Secretary to carry out and expand upon a national media campaign to educate the public and health care providers about poison prevention and the availability of poison control center resources in local communities. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into contracts with nationally recognized organizations in the field of poison control and national media firms for the development and implementation of a nationwide poison prevention and poison control center awareness campaign. Expands the poison control center grant program to allow the Secretary to award grants for poison control centers to comply with the operational requirements needed to sustain certification. Adds as the purposes for which such grants may be used: (1) to establish and evaluate best practices in the United States for poison prevention, poison control center outreach, and emergency and preparedness programs; (2) to implement standard patient management guidelines for commonly encountered toxic exposures; (3) to develop, support, and enhance technology and capabilities of professional organizations in the field of poison control to collect national poisoning, toxic occurrence, and related public health data; and (4) to develop initiatives to foster the enhanced public health utilization of national poison data. Eliminates matching requirements for such grants.<br/>Authorizes appropriations for FY2009-FY2014.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
