<bill session="110" type="s" number="2948" updated="2009-01-09T18:00:30-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30"/></status>

	<introduced date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Empowerment Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide quality, affordable health insurance for small employers and individuals.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400050"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3599)</text></action>
		<action date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/30/2008--Introduced.<br/>Small Business Empowerment Act - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a national program to make quality, affordable health insurance available to small employers and self-employed individuals in a manner that will spread risk on a national basis, modeled on the federal employees health benefit program.<br/>Requires the Secretary to enter into a contract with an eligible entity for administration of the program. Authorizes such administrator to provide health insurance coverage to employees of participating employers and individuals. Directs such administrator to: (1) establish a pilot program to provide for the offering by carriers of a model health benefits plan; and (2) contract with the Institute of Medicine to assess the impact of the program on health care coverage costs and access.<br/>Sets minimum standards for program health benefits plans. Directs the Secretary to prescribe regulations providing for employer participation.<br/>Establishes the National Health Coverage Commission. Includes among Commission duties: (1) developing a model that ensures adequate coverage for medically necessary services, promotes disease and chronic disease management, and provides incentives for health provider compliance with best practices protocols; and (2) developing model cost sharing mechanisms that do not discriminate and that accommodate lower income individuals.<br/>Directs the Secretary and the program administrator to implement an educational campaign concerning the program.<br/>Requires the Secretary to: (1) establish a program to provide reinsurance to qualified carriers offering plans under this Act; (2) make specified large claim payments (from the Small Business Health Coverage Trust Fund established by this Act) and annual payments to such carriers; and (3) require the payment of monthly assessments by each issuer offering health insurance coverage.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
