<bill session="110" type="s" number="2957" updated="2009-01-09T18:01:37-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1209614400" datetime="2008-05-01"/></status>

	<introduced date="1209614400" datetime="2008-05-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Credit Union Regulatory Improvements Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to modernize credit union net worth standards, advance credit union efforts to promote economic growth, and modify credit union regularity standards and reduce burdens, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300067"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2008-07-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2008-05-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1209614400" datetime="2008-05-01"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3708-3710)</text></action>
		<action date="1209614400" datetime="2008-05-01"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/1/2008--Introduced.<br/>Credit Union Regulatory Improvements Act of 2008 - Amends the Federal Credit Union Act to reduce the minimum net worth ratio requirements of credit unions.<br/>Revises the minimum risk-based net ratio for such capitalizations.<br/>Transfers from the federal banking agencies to the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC) the authority to adjust the net worth levels of credit unions.<br/>Instructs the National Credit Union Administration Board (Board) to design the risk-based net worth requirement to take account of material risks to insured credit unions that are taken account of by comparable standards applicable to FDIC-insured institutions.<br/>Establishes a temporary waiver of the net worth restoration plan requirement for an undercapitalized credit union which attains its status due to a major natural or man-made disaster.<br/>Revamps requirements for limits and restrictions on member business loans.<br/>Authorizes credit unions to lease to any business enterprise separate and clearly distinct space in credit union office buildings in underserved areas.<br/>Authorizes the Board, in specified circumstances, to encompass within credit union membership any person or organization within an underserved local community, neighborhood, or rural district. Permits a credit union to invest in securities for its own account.<br/>Increases the investment and lending limit in credit union service organizations.<br/>Exempts certain voluntary mergers involving multiple common-bond credit unions from the numerical limit for eligibility within the field of membership category of a credit union. Directs the Board to prescribe criteria for continued membership of certain member groups in the case of certain credit union conversions to a community charter.<br/>Includes just cause as grounds for expulsion from membership.<br/>Authorizes term limits for board members of federal credit unions.<br/>Revises voting requirements for credit union conversions to mutual savings banks.<br/>Amends the Clayton Act to exempt from its pre-merger notification and waiting period requirements any mergers of one insured credit union activities with another which require agency approval under the Federal Credit Union Act.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
