<bill session="110" type="s" number="2950" updated="2009-01-09T18:00:44-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30"/></status>

	<introduced date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Helping HANDS for Autism Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Helping Housing, Awareness, and Navigation Demonstration Services for Individuals With Autism Spectrum Disorders Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase housing, awareness, and navigation demonstration services (HANDS) for individuals with autism spectrum disorders.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400272"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2008-07-31"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1209528000" datetime="2008-04-30"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/30/2008--Introduced.<br/>Helping Housing, Awareness, and Navigation Demonstration Services for Individuals With Autism Spectrum Disorders Act of 2008 or the Helping HANDS for Autism Act of 2008 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS Secretary), in coordination with the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD Secretary) and the Secretary of Education, to establish a demonstration program to award grants to eligible entities to develop an autism navigator program to create a more efficient, effective, coordinated use of the health, housing, education, and social service systems for individuals with an autism spectrum disorder. Requires: (1) an eligible entity that receives a grant to develop an autism navigator program that will recruit, employ, train, assign, and supervise autism navigators; and (2) the HHS Secretary to provide for evaluations to determine the effects of navigator services.<br/>Directs the HHS Secretary, in coordination with the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to: (1) develop, demonstrate, and disseminate a standard curriculum for training first responders in assisting individuals with autism and other cognitive behavioral disabilities and their families during emergencies; and (2) award grants to states and local governments to train first responders in providing assistance to such individuals in emergency situations.<br/>Requires the HUD Secretary to convene a task force to establish a housing demonstration grant program to award grants to entities to provide a program aimed at providing individualized housing and services to adults with an autism spectrum disorder.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
