<bill session="110" type="s" number="2979" updated="2009-01-09T18:04:27-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26" /></status>

	<introduced date="1210046400" datetime="2008-05-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to exempt the African National Congress from treatment as a terrorist organization, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300060"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="2008-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300008" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="2008-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2008-06-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="412248" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2008-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300049" joined="2008-06-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1210046400" datetime="2008-05-06"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26" ><text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"><text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Leahy without amendment. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="850" date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 850.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/26/2008--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Amends the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2008 to state that for purposes of alien inadmissibility based upon terrorist-related grounds the African National Congress (ANC) shall not be considered to be a terrorist organization on the basis of any act or event that occurred before the date of enactment of such Act. Authorizes the Secretary of State (after consultation with the Attorney General and the Secretary of Homeland Security) or the Secretary of Homeland Security (after consultation with the Secretary of State and the Attorney General) to determine, in such Secretary's sole unreviewable discretion, that inadmissibility based upon specified criminal convictions or terrorist activities shall not apply to an alien with respect to activities undertaken in opposition to apartheid rule in South Africa. Expresses the sense of Congress that the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Homeland Security should exercise such authority in appropriate instances to exempt the anti-apartheid activities of aliens who are current or former officials of the government of the Republic of South Africa. Directs the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Attorney General, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and the Director of National Intelligence, to ensure that databases used to determine U.S. admissibility are appropriately updated. 
	</summary>
</bill>
