<bill session="110" type="s" number="2988" updated="2009-01-09T18:05:33-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1210132800" datetime="2008-05-07"/></status>

	<introduced date="1210132800" datetime="2008-05-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Accelerating Cures Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to enhance public and private research efforts to develop new tools and therapies that prevent, detect, and cure diseases.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300067"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1210132800" datetime="2008-05-07"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3894)</text></action>
		<action date="1210132800" datetime="2008-05-07"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S3894-3899"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/7/2008--Introduced.<br/>Accelerating Cures Act of 2008 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to define &quot;translational research&quot; to mean research that transforms scientific discoveries arising from laboratory, clinical, or population studies into clinical application to reduce disease incidence, morbidity, and mortality.<br/>Establishes a Pathways to Cures Subcommittee within the Office of Portfolio Analysis and Strategic Initiatives (OPASI) of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to help advise and direct translational research priorities.<br/>Requires the Director of NIH to establish a Federally Funded Research and Development Center (FFRDC) on clinical effectiveness research. Requires the Director of FFRDC to establish an independent Clinical Effectiveness Advisory Board.<br/>Requires the Director of OPASI to appoint a Director of Centralized Institutional Review Boards who shall establish and oversee the functioning and progress of a series of such Boards to serve as human subject safety and well-being custodians for multi-institutional clinical trials that are funded by public research dollars. Requires the Director of NIH to: (1) commission the Institute of Medicine to study the rules that protect patient safety and anonymity; (2) examine informed consent processes; and (3) ensure that each institute and center of NIH has established a translational research training program.<br/>Requires the Director of OPASI to develop a Translational Development Program for New Innovations to guide entities through the translational research development process.<br/>Establishes the Translational Research Fund to consist of amounts appropriated for translational research priorities.<br/>Requires each application for, and summary of, a project, grant, or contract from NIH to include a statement on the possible applications of the research for detecting, treating, or curing a health condition or disease state.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
