<bill session="110" type="s" number="2982" updated="2009-01-09T18:04:49-05:00">
	<status><enacted date="1223438400" datetime="2008-10-08" /></status>

	<introduced date="1210046400" datetime="2008-05-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Runaway and Homeless Youth Protection Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Reconnecting Homeless Youth Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Runaway and Homeless Youth Protection Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">Reconnecting Homeless Youth Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="enacted">Reconnecting Homeless Youth Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Runaway and Homeless Youth Act to authorize appropriations, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300065"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300092" joined="2008-05-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1210046400" datetime="2008-05-06"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3795-3796)</text></action>
		<action date="1210046400" datetime="2008-05-06"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S3796-3798"/></action>
		<calendar date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22" ><text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Leahy with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="751" date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 751.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1222315200" datetime="2008-09-25"><text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S9548-9551"/><reference label="text of measure as reported in Senate" ref="CR S9548-9550"/></action>
		<action date="1222315200" datetime="2008-09-25"><text>The committee substitute as amended agreed to by Unanimous Consent.</text></action>
		<vote date="1222315200" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2008-09-25" where="s" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text></vote>
		<action date="1222434780" datetime="2008-09-26T10:13:00-04:00"><text>Received in the House.</text></action>
		<action date="1222401600" datetime="2008-09-26"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<action date="1222485060" datetime="2008-09-26T12:11:00-04:00"><text>Held at the desk.</text></action>
		<action date="1222471440" datetime="2008-09-26T20:24:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Andrews asked unanimous consent to take from the Speaker's table and consider.</text></action>
		<action date="1222471440" datetime="2008-09-26T20:24:00-04:00"><text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H10113-10115"/></action>
		<vote date="1222471500" how="without objection" datetime="2008-09-26T20:25:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote2" result="pass" ><text>On passage Passed without objection.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H10113-10115"/></vote>
		<topresident date="1222401600" datetime="2008-09-26" ><text>Cleared for White House.</text></topresident>
		<topresident date="1222747200" datetime="2008-09-30" ><text>Presented to President.</text></topresident>
		<signed date="1223438400" datetime="2008-10-08" ><text>Signed by President.</text></signed>
		<enacted number="110-378" date="1223438400" datetime="2008-10-08" type="public" ><text>Became Public Law No: 110-378.</text></enacted>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/8/2008--Public Law. (This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the Senate on September 25, 2008. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Reconnecting Homeless Youth Act of 2008 - (Sec. 3) Amends the Runaway and Homeless Youth Act to revise requirements for services provided under grants from the Secretary of Health and Human Services for centers for runaway and homeless youth and their families. Limits the length of stay in such a center to 21 days. Increases grant minimum allotments from $100,000 to $200,000 for states and from $45,000 to $70,000 for the U.S. Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands. Prohibits the allotted amounts for a state for FY2009-FY2010 from being less than the allotted amount for FY2008. Requires the plan proposed by grant applicants for a runaway and homeless youth center to include an adequate emergency preparedness and management plan. (Sec. 4) Revises requirements for transitional living programs. Specifies that shelter and services may be provided by grant, agreement, or contract (currently, directly or indirectly) to homeless youth. Increases the maximum length of continuous stay in such programs from 540 days to 635 days, if a youth would benefit to an usual extent from additional time in the program. Requires a transitional living program also to develop an adequate emergency preparedness and management plan. (Sec. 5) Requires the Secretary to give priority (currently, special consideration) to grant applicants for specified research, evaluation, demonstration, and service projects regarding runaway youth and homeless youth. Requires the Secretary to give special consideration to proposed projects relating to: (1) behavior (currently, mental) health care for runaway and homeless youth; (2) access to educational and workforce programs to achieve outcomes such as decreasing secondary school dropout rates, increasing rates of attaining a secondary school diploma (or equivalent), or increasing placement and retention in postsecondary education or advanced workforce training programs; and (3) programs, including innovative programs, that assist youth in obtaining and maintaining safe and stable housing (which may include programs with supportive services that continue after the youth completes the remainder of the programs). Requires the Secretary to ensure that selected grant applicants: (1) represent diverse U.S. geographic regions; and (2) carry out projects that serve diverse populations of runaway or homeless youth. (Sec. 6) Requires the Secretary to report periodically to specified congressional committees and the public: (1) estimates of the incidence and prevalence of runaway and homeless individuals between 13 to 26 years of age; and (2) an assessment of such individual's characteristics. (Sec. 7) Requires the Secretary to give priority to public and, as under current law, nonprofit private agencies for sexual abuse prevention programs. (Sec. 8) Requires the Secretary to establish performance standards for grant recipients. (Sec. 9) Directs the Comptroller General to study and report to specified congressional committees on the processes for making grants under the Runaway and Homeless Youth Act. (Sec. 10) Redefines &quot;homeless youth&quot; to cover an individual seeking shelter in a runaway and homeless center who is less than a maximum age higher than 18, if the center is located in a state or locality with a child or youth-serving-facility licensure law or regulation that permits a higher maximum age. Allows a homeless youth to participate in a transitional living program up to age 22, as of the expiration of the maximum stay permitted, if the individual commences such stay before attaining age 22. Defines &quot;runaway youth&quot; as an individual under age 18 who absents himself or herself from home or place of legal residence without the permission of parents or legal guardians. (Sec. 13) Authorizes appropriations for FY2009-FY2013.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
