<bill session="110" type="s" number="3004" updated="2009-01-09T18:07:39-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1221624000" datetime="2008-09-17" where="s" result="pass" how="by Unanimous Consent" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1210564800" datetime="2008-05-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Energy National Security Act for Fiscal Year 2009</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Department of Energy National Security Act for Fiscal Year 2009</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">Department of Energy National Security Act for Fiscal Year 2009</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">An original bill to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2009 for defense activities of the Department of Energy, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300066"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1210564800" datetime="2008-05-12"><text>Committee on Armed Services. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Levin. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1210564800" datetime="2008-05-12" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 735.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1221624000" datetime="2008-09-17"><text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S8933-8934"/></action>
		<action date="1221624000" datetime="2008-09-17"><text>Senate struck all after the Enacting Clause and substituted the language of S.3001 amended (Division C only).</text></action>
		<vote date="1221624000" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2008-09-17" where="s" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent. (text: CR 9/18/2008 S9163-9164)</text></vote>
		<action date="1221760560" datetime="2008-09-18T14:56:00-04:00"><text>Received in the House.</text></action>
		<action date="1221710400" datetime="2008-09-18"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<action date="1221761160" datetime="2008-09-18T15:06:00-04:00"><text>Held at the desk.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/17/2008--Passed Senate amended. Department of Energy National Security Act for Fiscal Year 2009 - Division C: Department of Energy National Security Authorizations and Other Authorizations - Title XXXI [sic]: Department of Energy National Security Programs - Subtitle A: National Security Programs Authorizations - (Sec. 3101) Authorizes appropriations for the Department of Energy (DOE) for FY2008 for: (1) activities of the National Nuclear Security Administration in carrying out programs necessary for national security, with specified allocations for weapons activities, defense nuclear nonproliferation activities, naval reactors, and the Office of the Administrator for Nuclear Security; and (2) new plant projects and environmental restoration and waste management activities in carrying out national security programs, with specified allocations for defense environmental cleanup, other defense activities, and defense nuclear waste disposal. Subtitle B: Program Authorizations, Restrictions, and Limitations - (Sec. 3111) Includes as a responsibility of the Administrator for Nuclear Security (Administrator) the elimination of inventories of surplus fissile materials usable for nuclear weapons. (Sec. 3112) Directs the Secretary of Energy to report to the congressional defense and appropriations committees on the status of compliance of DOE sites with the Design Basis Threat issued by the Department of Defense in November 2005. (Sec. 3113) Amends the Atomic Energy Defense Act to require the Secretary, in each even-numbered year beginning in 2010, to report to the defense committees and the Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs identifying any inadvertent releases of restricted data or formerly restricted data (in conjunction with the release of declassified information) discovered in the prior two-year period. (Sec. 3114) Directs the Administrator to carry out a program to provide scholarships and fellowships for enabling individuals to qualify for employment in DOE nonproliferation programs. Requires participants to enter into an agreement to receive educational assistance for up to a five-year period, and afterward to serve in a DOE nonproliferation position for the same number of years that the assistance was provided. Requires repayment for failure to complete the educational program or to serve the required period. Allows the Administrator to waive such repayment when seeking recovery would be against equity and good conscience or contrary to the best interests of the United States. Allows a preference for individuals enrolled or accepted for enrollment in an institution of higher education that has a cooperative program with DOE. Requires a program activities report from the Administrator to the defense and appropriations committees. Provides funding.<br/>(Sec. 3115) Requires the Administrator to: (1) conduct a review of the Global Initiatives for Proliferation Prevention program; (2) report review results to the defense and appropriations committees; and (3) report to such committees on funding for projects under the program. Prohibits FY2009 funding until 30 days after the latter report is submitted. Prohibits the use of FY2009 program funds for projects related to energy security that could promote the Global Nuclear Energy Partnership.<br/>Title XXXII: Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board - (Sec. 3201) Authorizes appropriations for FY2009 for the Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
