<bill session="110" type="s" number="3011" updated="2009-01-09T18:08:32-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" /></status>

	<introduced date="1210651200" datetime="2008-05-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Palo Alto Battlefield National Historic Site Boundary Expansion Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Palo Alto Battlefield National Historical Park Boundary Expansion and Redesignation Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Palo Alto Battlefield National Historic Site Act of 1991 to expand the boundaries of the historic site, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300027"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1210651200" datetime="2008-05-13"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1217390400" datetime="2008-07-30"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="993" date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 993.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/16/2008--Reported to Senate amended. Palo Alto Battlefield National Historical Park Boundary Expansion and Redesignation Act of 2008 - Redesignates the Palo Alto Battlefield National Historic Site (located in Brownsville, Texas, and dedicated to the preservation and interpretation of the Mexican-American War) as the &quot;Palo Alto Battlefield National Historical Park.&quot; Amends the Palo Alto Battlefield National Historic Site Act of 1991 to expand the boundaries of the Park to include certain land. 
	</summary>
</bill>
