<bill session="110" type="s" number="3010" updated="2009-01-09T18:08:24-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" /></status>

	<introduced date="1210651200" datetime="2008-05-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Route 66 Corridor Preservation Program Reauthorization Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Route 66 Corridor Preservation Program Reauthorization Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reauthorize the Route 66 Corridor Preservation Program.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300036"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2008-06-02"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1210651200" datetime="2008-05-13"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4108)</text></action>
		<action date="1210651200" datetime="2008-05-13"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S4108"/></action>
		<action date="1213675200" datetime="2008-06-17"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-539.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="992" date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 992.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/16/2008--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)<br/>Route 66 Corridor Preservation Program Reauthorization Act - Authorizes appropriations through FY2019 to carry out the purposes of Public Law 106-45 (relating to the preservation of the cultural resources of the Route 66 Corridor and authorizing the Secretary of the Interior to provide assistance for the preservation of the Corridor). 
	</summary>
</bill>
