<bill session="110" type="s" number="3024" updated="2009-01-09T18:10:10-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1211256000" datetime="2008-05-20" /></status>

	<introduced date="1210824000" datetime="2008-05-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Eurasia Foundation Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Eurasia Foundation Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize grants to the Eurasia Foundation, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300008"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300070" joined="2008-05-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1210824000" datetime="2008-05-15"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1211256000" datetime="2008-05-20" ><text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1212379200" datetime="2008-06-02"><text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Biden without amendment. With written report No. 110-342.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="754" date="1212379200" datetime="2008-06-02" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 754.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/2/2008--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.) Eurasia Foundation Act - Directs the Secretary of State to make an annual grant to the Eurasia Foundation to: (1) promote civil society, private enterprise, and public administration and policy in the countries of Eurasia; (2) strengthen indigenous institutions that foster national development, social change, economic growth, and cooperative international relationships consistent with U.S. interests in Eurasia; and (3) conduct programs in the countries of Eurasia that would be difficult or impossible for an official U.S. entity. Sets forth provisions respecting: (1) grant eligibility; (2) audits; (3) recordkeeping; and (4) reports. Directs the Foundation and any successor or related entity to the U.S. Russia Investment Fund to enter into a memorandum of understanding to: (1) coordinate activities carried out by the Foundation and the successor or related entity; and (2) ensure that the activities of one entity do not duplicate the activities of the other entity. Authorizes FY2009-FY2010 appropriations.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
