<bill session="110" type="s" number="3027" updated="2009-01-09T18:10:33-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1210824000" datetime="2008-05-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1210824000" datetime="2008-05-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">COACH Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Coaching Our Adolescents for College Heights Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the National and Community Service Act of 1990 to establish a program to provide college coaches to low- and middle-income high-achieving high school students.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300022"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1210824000" datetime="2008-05-15"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4284-4285)</text></action>
		<action date="1210824000" datetime="2008-05-15"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/15/2008--Introduced.<br/>Coaching Our Adolescents for College Heights Act or the COACH Act - Amends the National and Community Service Act of 1990 to direct the Corporation for National and Community Service to award a contract to a nonprofit organization to establish a seven-year pilot program under which recent college graduates commit to two terms of service as coaches to high-achieving, low- or middle-income high school students in exchange for national service awards for each term of service. Requires such coaches, which are to total 100 and operate in no more than five school districts, to: (1) build a strong college-going culture for all students in high schools with historically low college attendance rates; and (2) provide limited cohorts of high-achieving, low- or middle-income students with guidance in studies suited to college-bound students, and support during the college search and application processes. Requires the nonprofit organization to raise $3 of nonfederal funds for every $1 of federal funds provided under the contract. Directs the Corporation to contract with an independent agency to study the effects of the pilot program on the achievement of participating students and students in participating high schools. Requires the Corporation to plan an expansion of such program if it is shown to be effective in improving student achievement.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
