<bill session="110" type="s" number="3037" updated="2009-01-09T18:11:50-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1211256000" datetime="2008-05-20"/></status>

	<introduced date="1211256000" datetime="2008-05-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">ACTION Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">AmeriCorps: Together Improving Our Nation Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the National and Community Service Act of 1990 to improve the educational awards provided for national service, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300034"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="2008-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2008-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="2008-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2008-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2008-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300068" joined="2008-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2008-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="2008-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2008-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2008-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300006" joined="2008-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300084" joined="2008-05-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300090" joined="2008-05-20"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1211256000" datetime="2008-05-20"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4488-4489)</text></action>
		<action date="1211256000" datetime="2008-05-20"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/20/2008--Introduced.<br/>AmeriCorps: Together Improving Our Nation Act or the ACTION Act - Amends the National and Community Service Act of 1990 to alter the formula for determining the amount of the national service educational award to base the award on the average cost of attending a four-year institution of higher education, rather than a portion of a veteran's basic educational assistance allowance. Excludes the national service educational award from an individual's gross income for tax purposes. Permits the Corporation for National and Community Service to support a national service program that is carried out by another federal agency and implements the priorities of such agency. Makes Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation a Cabinet position. Raises the Officer's compensation to Level I of the Executive Schedule.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
