<bill session="110" type="s" number="3047" updated="2009-01-09T18:13:07-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1211342400" datetime="2008-05-21"/></status>

	<introduced date="1211342400" datetime="2008-05-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Enhancing Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics Education Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the coordination of the Nation's science, technology, engineering, and mathematics education initiatives.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400629"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300070" joined="2008-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2008-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2008-07-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2008-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2008-09-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2008-05-21"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1211342400" datetime="2008-05-21"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/21/2008--Introduced.<br/>Enhancing Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics Education Act of 2008 - Requires the President to establish, in the Office of Science and Technology Policy, a Committee on Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics Education (STEM education) within the National Science and Technology Council.<br/>Establishes an Office of Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics Education in the Department of Education, to be administered by an Assistant Secretary. Requires the Assistant Secretary to conduct an annual evaluation of the STEM education programs administered by the department.<br/>Requires the Secretary of Education to award a grant to establish a voluntary State Consortium on STEM Education and a grant to the National Science Digital Library to establish a National STEM Education Research Repository.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
