<bill session="110" type="s" number="3045" updated="2009-01-09T18:12:51-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" /></status>

	<introduced date="1211342400" datetime="2008-05-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Kenai Mountains-Turnagain Arm National Forest Heritage Area Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Kenai Mountains-Turnagain Arm National Heritage Area Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Kenai Mountains-Turnagain Arm National Forest Heritage Area in the State of Alaska, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300075"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1211342400" datetime="2008-05-21"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4623)</text></action>
		<action date="1211342400" datetime="2008-05-21"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S4623-4625"/></action>
		<action date="1213675200" datetime="2008-06-17"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-539.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="995" date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 995.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/16/2008--Reported to Senate amended. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)<br/>Kenai Mountains-Turnagain Arm Area National Forest Heritage Area Act - Establishes the Kenai Mountains-Turnagain Arm National Forest Heritage Area in Alaska. Designates the Kenai Mountains-Turnagain Arm National Forest Heritage Corridor Communities Association as the Area's local coordinating entity. Requires the Association to prepare and submit a management plan for the Area. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to evaluate the accomplishments of the Area and to prepare and submit a report that includes recommendations for the future role of the National Park Service (NPS), if any, respecting the Area. Authorizes Appropriations. Sets a limit on the total amounts that may be made available to carry out this Act. Limits the federal share of the total cost of any activity carried out under this Act to 50%.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
