<bill session="110" type="s" number="3051" updated="2009-01-09T18:13:37-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" /></status>

	<introduced date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Battle of Camden Study Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">National Park Service Special Resource Studies and Technical Corrections Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to study the suitability and feasibility of designating the site of the Battle of Camden in South Carolina, as a unit of the National Park System, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300047"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="996" date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 996.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/16/2008--Reported to Senate amended. National Park Service Special Resource Studies and Technical Corrections Act of 2008 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a special resource study to determine the suitability and feasibility of: (1) designating the site of the Battle of Camden, South Carolina, and of Historic Camden, South Carolina, as a unit or units of the National Park System; and (2) including Fort San Geronimo and other related resources in the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico as part of the San Juan National Historic Site. Makes technical corrections and conforming amendments to various acts concerning specified areas, forests, trails, and other matters.<br/>Renames the Gaylord A. Nelson Wilderness as the Gaylord Nelson Wilderness. Provides for the House Committee on Natural Resources (under current law, the Committee on House Administration) to be notified of a recommendation that a commemorative work in the District of Columbia and its environs should be located in Area I. 
	</summary>
</bill>
