<bill session="110" type="s" number="3052" updated="2009-01-09T18:13:44-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1217304000" datetime="2008-07-29" /></status>

	<introduced date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Naval Vessel Transfer Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Naval Vessel Transfer Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the transfer of naval vessels to certain foreign recipients.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300008"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300070" joined="2008-05-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4795)</text></action>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S4795-4796"/></action>
		<calendar date="1217304000" datetime="2008-07-29" ><text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1221019200" datetime="2008-09-10"><text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Dodd without amendment. With written report No. 110-451.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="949" date="1221019200" datetime="2008-09-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 949.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/10/2008--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Naval Vessel Transfer Act of 2008 - Authorizes the President to transfer on a grant basis to: (1) Pakistan, the OLIVER HAZARD PERRY class guided missile frigate MCINERNEY; (2) Greece, the OSPREY class minehunter coastal ships OSPREY and ROBIN; (3) Chile, the KAISER class oiler ANDREW J. HIGGINS; and (4) Peru, the NEWPORT class amphibious tank landing ships FRESNO and RACINE. States that: (1) the value of such vessels transferred on a grant basis shall not be counted against the aggregate value of excess defense articles transferred to countries in any fiscal year under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961; (2) transfer costs shall be charged to the recipient; and (3) to the maximum extent practicable, the country to which a vessel is transferred shall have necessary vessel repair and refurbishment carried out at U.S. shipyards (including U.S. Navy shipyards). Terminates transfer authority two years after enactment of this Act.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
