<bill session="110" type="s" number="3061" updated="2009-01-09T18:14:49-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31" /></status>

	<introduced date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">William Wilberforce Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Child Soldiers Prevention and Accountability Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">William Wilberforce Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Child Soldiers Prevention and Accountability Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize appropriations for fiscal years 2008 through 2011 for the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000, to enhance measures to combat trafficking in persons, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300008"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="2008-06-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300052" joined="2008-06-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2008-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300092" joined="2008-06-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300013" joined="2008-05-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2008-07-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4798-4799)</text></action>
		<action date="1211428800" datetime="2008-05-22"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31" ><text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1220846400" datetime="2008-09-08"><text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Leahy with amendments. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="946" date="1220846400" datetime="2008-09-08" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 946.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/22/2008--Introduced.<br/>William Wilberforce Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2008 - Amends the the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 to direct the Secretary of State to establish within the Department of State an Office to Monitor and Combat Trafficking. (Current law authorizes such Office's establishment.)<br/>Directs the President to implement an anti-trafficking program monitoring system.<br/>Authorizes the President to establish the Paul D. Wellstone Presidential Award for Extraordinary Efforts to Combat Trafficking in Persons.<br/>Sets forth protections for aliens who: (1) may be trafficking victims or who may testify against traffickers (including parole entry for certain family members); (2) are work-based nonimmigrants; (3) are domestic workers; or (4) are employees of foreign diplomatic or other government personnel, or employees of international organization personnel.<br/>Sets forth provisions respecting: (1) assistance for trafficking victims, including child victims and U.S. citizens; (2) offenses of trafficking, forced labor, enticement into slavery, sex trafficking of children, and sex tourism. Directs the Secretary to develop: (1) policies and procedures to ensure that unaccompanied alien children in the United States are safely repatriated to their country of nationality or of last habitual residence; and (2) a safe repatriation pilot program for alien children.<br/>States, with specified exceptions, that the care and custody of unaccompanied alien children in the United States shall be the responsibility of the Secretary of Health and Human Services. Sets forth related provisions and authorizations of appropriations.<br/>Child Soldiers Prevention Act of 2008 - Prohibits, with a national interest waiver, funds for specified military and related areas from being made available to the government of a country identified by the Department as having governmental armed forces or government supported armed groups that recruit and use child soldiers. Authorizes the President to reinstate assistance upon certifying to Congress that a government is implementing: (1) compliance measures; and (2) mechanisms to prohibit future use of child soldiers.<br/>Authorizes the President to provide assistance to a country for international military education and training otherwise prohibited under this Act upon certifying to Congress that such assistance is for implementation of measures to demobilize child soldiers and for programs to support professionalization of the military.<br/>Makes it a federal crime to recruit or use child soldiers. Makes such recruitment or use a grounds for an alien's removal from the United States. 
	</summary>
</bill>
