<bill session="110" type="s" number="3085" updated="2009-01-09T18:17:51-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" /></status>

	<introduced date="1212638400" datetime="2008-06-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Cooperative Watershed Management Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Cooperative Watershed Management Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of the Interior to establish a cooperative watershed management program, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412244"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300029" joined="2008-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300005" joined="2008-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300030" joined="2008-06-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1212638400" datetime="2008-06-05"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5206)</text></action>
		<action date="1212638400" datetime="2008-06-05"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S5206-5208"/></action>
		<action date="1216180800" datetime="2008-07-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-603.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="999" date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 999.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/5/2008--Introduced.<br/>Cooperative Watershed Management Act of 2008 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to establish a cooperative watershed management program under which the Secretary shall provide grants to eligible management entities to: (1) form a self-sustaining, cooperative watershed-wide management group; (2) enlarge a management group; or (3) conduct projects in accordance with the goals of a management group.<br/>Requires an eligible management entity to be comprised of each affected stakeholder of the watershed that is the subject of the entity, including: (1) representatives of private interests; (2) any federal agency that has authority regarding the watershed; (3) any state or local agency that has such authority; and (4) any Indian tribe member who owns land within the watershed or land held in trust.<br/>Directs the Secretary, during the first phase, to provide to a recipient a grant of not greater than $100,000 each year for not more than three years. Requires a recipient to use the funds to establish or enlarge a management group, develop a mission statement, and develop project concepts.<br/>Directs the Secretary, for each year of the first phase, to determine whether the recipient has made sufficient progress during the year to justify additional funding. Sets conditions to receive funds for each phase. Prohibits a management group from using grant funds for any group initiative unless it reaches a consensus decision. Sets federal cost share requirements. 
	</summary>
</bill>
