<bill session="110" type="s" number="3083" updated="2009-01-09T18:17:35-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1212552000" datetime="2008-06-04"/></status>

	<introduced date="1212552000" datetime="2008-06-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">TRADE Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Trade Reform, Accountability, Development, and Employment Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require a review of existing trade agreements and renegotiation of existing trade agreements based on the review, to set terms for future trade agreements, to express the sense of the Senate that the role of Congress in trade policymaking should be strengthened, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400050"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300016" joined="2008-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300037" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2008-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2008-07-16"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1212552000" datetime="2008-06-04"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5043-5044)</text></action>
		<action date="1212552000" datetime="2008-06-04"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S5044-5047"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/4/2008--Introduced.<br/>Trade Reform, Accountability, Development, and Employment Act of 2008, or the TRADE Act of 2008 - Directs the Comptroller General of the United States to: (1) review certain free trade agreements (including Uruguay Round Agreements) between the United States and foreign countries; and (2) report to the Congressional Trade Agreement Review Committee regarding such agreements, including analyses of specified subjects and of each agreement, as well as whether the country has a democratic form of government that respects certain core labor rights and fundamental human rights, protects intellectual property rights, and enforces environmental laws.<br/>Declares that implementing bills of new trade agreements shall be subject to a point of order in the Senate unless such agreements include certain standards with respect to: (1) labor; (2) environment and public safety; (3) food and product health and safety; (4) provision of services; (5) investment; (6) procurement; (7) intellectual property; (8) agriculture; (9) trade remedies and safeguards; (10) rules of origin; (11) dispute resolution and enforcement; (12) technical assistance; and (13) national security.<br/>Requires the President to submit to Congress a plan to bring existing trade agreements into compliance with such standards.<br/>Establishes a Congressional Trade Agreement Review Committee.<br/>Expresses the sense of Congress that a certain process for U.S. trade negotiations should be followed when Congress considers legislation providing special procedures for implementing bills of trade agreements.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
