<bill session="110" type="s" number="3093" updated="2009-01-09T18:18:52-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1212638400" datetime="2008-06-05"/></status>

	<introduced date="1212638400" datetime="2008-06-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Electronic Employment Verification Reauthorization Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to extend and improve the effectiveness of the employment eligibility confirmation program.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300048"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="2008-06-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300035" joined="2008-06-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300040" joined="2008-07-11"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1212638400" datetime="2008-06-05"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5214-5215)</text></action>
		<action date="1212638400" datetime="2008-06-05"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/5/2008--Introduced.<br/>Electronic Employment Verification Reauthorization Act of 2008 - Amends the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 to make the employment eligibility confirmation pilot programs permanent. Redesignates the basic pilot program as the E-verify program (program). Requires that any person or employer that enters into a federal contract participate in the program. Requires that an employer electing to verify the employment eligibility of existing employees do so not later than 10 days after notifying the Secretary of Homeland Security of such election. Authorizes the Secretary to require an employer or class of employers to participate in the program if the Secretary has reasonable cause to believe that the employer has engaged in material employment violations under the Immigration and Nationality Act. Requires that an employer participating in the program use the confirmation system to reverify an individual's work authorization not later than three days after the date on which such individual's employment authorization is scheduled to expire. Requires that the Director of United States Citizenship and Immigration Services establish in a rural setting or in an area with fewer than 10,000 residents a demonstration program to assist small businesses verify the employment eligibility of newly hired employees.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
