<bill session="110" type="s" number="3096" updated="2009-01-09T18:19:15-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" /></status>

	<introduced date="1212724800" datetime="2008-06-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the National Cave and Karst Research Institute Act of 1998 to authorize appropriations for the National Cave and Karst Research Institute.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300009"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300036" joined="2008-06-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1212724800" datetime="2008-06-06"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1213675200" datetime="2008-06-17"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-539.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="1002" date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1002.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/16/2008--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.) Amends the National Cave and Karst Research Institute Act of 1998 to remove a provision limiting federal spending by the Department of the Interior for the National Cave and Karst Research Institute, in New Mexico, to the amount of nonfederal funding received. Authorizes appropriations. 
	</summary>
</bill>
