<bill session="110" type="s" number="3090" updated="2009-01-09T18:18:28-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1212638400" datetime="2008-06-05"/></status>

	<introduced date="1212638400" datetime="2008-06-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">SAFE AIR Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Safe Aviation Facilities Ensure Aircraft Integrity and Reliability Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for adequate oversight and inspection by the Federal Aviation Administration of facilities outside the United States that perform maintenance and repair work on United States commercial aircraft, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412243"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300092" joined="2008-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2008-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2008-06-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1212638400" datetime="2008-06-05"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/5/2008--Introduced.<br/>Safe Aviation Facilities Ensure Aircraft Integrity and Reliability Act of 2008 or the SAFE AIR Act of 2008 - Requires the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to: (1) prescribe regulations requiring maintenance work on passenger aircraft to be performed by certain authorized individuals; (2) certify to Congress that the FAA has inspected each foreign repair station that has performed work on U.S. air carrier aircraft or components at least twice in the preceding year and tested persons who perform safety-sensitive functions at such stations for use of alcohol or controlled substances; and (3) develop a plan to identify all noncertified maintenance providers that have performed maintenance work on such aircraft. Prohibits the Administrator from certifying a foreign repair station unless it complies with certain final security regulations.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
