<bill session="110" type="s" number="3106" updated="2009-01-09T18:20:32-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1213070400" datetime="2008-06-10"/></status>

	<introduced date="1213070400" datetime="2008-06-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Vessel Hull Design Protection Amendments of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend chapter 13 of title 17, United States Code (relating to the vessel hull design protection), to clarify the definitions of a hull and a deck.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300065"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300061" joined="2008-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2008-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300027" joined="2008-06-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1213070400" datetime="2008-06-10"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5449)</text></action>
		<action date="1213070400" datetime="2008-06-10"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S5449"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/10/2008--Introduced.<br/>Vessel Hull Design Protection Amendments of 2008 - Amends federal copyright law to specify that the design of a vessel's hull, deck, or combination of a hull and deck, including a plug or mold are protected (currently, only the design of the vessel hull is protected, including a plug or mold and the definition of hull includes the deck). Requires that Department of Defense rights in a registered design, including the right to build to such a design, be determined solely by provisions of federal Armed Forces law relating to rights in technical data or by the instrument under which the design was developed for the U.S. government. Redefines &quot;useful article&quot; and &quot;hull.&quot; Defines &quot;deck&quot; as the horizontal surface of the vessel that covers the hull, including exterior cabin and cockpit surfaces, and exclusive of masts, sails, yards, rigging, hardware, fixtures, and other attachments. 
	</summary>
</bill>
