<bill session="110" type="s" number="3116" updated="2009-01-09T18:21:49-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1213156800" datetime="2008-06-11"/></status>

	<introduced date="1213156800" datetime="2008-06-11"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Outpatient Mental Health Modernization Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to stabilize and modernize the provision of partial hospitalization services under the Medicare program, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400418"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2008-07-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1213156800" datetime="2008-06-11"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/11/2008--Introduced.<br/>Outpatient Mental Health Modernization Act of 2008 - Establishes a moratorium between January 1, 2009, and January 1, 2010, on changes in the Medicare outpatient department (OPD) fee schedule amount established for partial hospital (episode and visit) services. Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to: (1) establish an accreditation program for community mental health centers providing partial hospitalization services; (2) require a specified reduction in the OPD fee schedule increase factor for any such center that fails to submit required data on its partial hospitalization services; and (3) establish a minimum number of four units of items and services as a requirement for coverage of such services. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to require fiscal intermediaries under the Medicare program to file the cost reports of providers of partial hospitalization services into the Healthcare Provider Cost Reporting Information System (HCRIS) maintained by the Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services. 
	</summary>
</bill>
