<bill session="110" type="s" number="3133" updated="2009-01-09T18:24:03-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1213243200" datetime="2008-06-12"/></status>

	<introduced date="1213243200" datetime="2008-06-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Responsible Ownership of Public Land Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of the Interior to establish an annual production incentive fee with respect to Federal onshore and offshore land that is subject to a lease for production of oil or natural gas under which production is not occurring, to authorize use of the fee for energy efficiency and renewable energy projects, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300034"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2008-06-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="2008-07-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2008-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2008-06-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2008-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2008-06-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1213243200" datetime="2008-06-12"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5631)</text></action>
		<action date="1213243200" datetime="2008-06-12"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/12/2008--Introduced.<br/>Responsible Ownership of Public Land Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to establish an annual production incentive fee for federal onshore and offshore lands subject to a lease for production of oil or natural gas under which production is not occurring. Prescribes the fee amount for each acre of land from which oil or natural gas is produced for less than 90 days in a calendar year.<br/>Establishes the Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy Fund to serve as depository for fees received under this Act.<br/>Describes energy programs to be funded with such fees, including: (1) solar energy research and development; (2) next-generation wind turbines; (3) weatherization assistance low-income housing; (4) new technologies to improve the energy efficiency of and reduce greenhouse gas emissions from buildings; (5) energy storage systems to support electric drive vehicles, stationary applications, and electricity transmission and distribution; (6) advanced vehicles research, development, and demonstration; and (7) low-income home energy assistance.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
