<bill session="110" type="s" number="3142" updated="2009-01-09T18:25:13-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1213675200" datetime="2008-06-17"/></status>

	<introduced date="1213675200" datetime="2008-06-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Preventing Stillbirth and SUID Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to enhance public health activities related to stillbirth and sudden unexpected infant death.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400629"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2008-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300077" joined="2008-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300050" joined="2008-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300006" joined="2008-07-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2008-07-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1213675200" datetime="2008-06-17"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/17/2008--Introduced.<br/>Preventing Stillbirth and SUID Act of 2008 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to develop: (1) a standard definition of stillbirth; and (2) a standard protocol for stillbirth data collection and surveillance, including enhancing the National Vital Statistics System for the reporting of stillbirths. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA), the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), and the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH), to establish: (1) a national registry that can facilitate the understanding of root causes, rates, and trends of stillbirth; (2) public education and prevention programs aimed at reducing the occurrence of stillbirth; and (3) a population-based sudden, unexpected infant deaths (SUID) case registry that can facilitate the understanding of the root causes, rates, and trends of SUID.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
