<bill session="110" type="s" number="3143" updated="2009-01-09T18:25:20-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1213675200" datetime="2008-06-17"/></status>

	<introduced date="1213675200" datetime="2008-06-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Capture Arrest and Transport Charged Fugitives Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to assist law enforcement agencies in locating, arresting, and prosecuting fugitives from justice.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300038"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300035" joined="2008-06-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400418" joined="2008-06-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2008-06-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1213675200" datetime="2008-06-17"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5821-5822)</text></action>
		<action date="1213675200" datetime="2008-06-17"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/17/2008--Introduced.<br/>Capture Arrest and Transport Charged Fugitives Act of 2008 - Amends the Presidential Threat Protection Act of 2000 to authorize appropriations through FY2015 for establishing new Regional Fugitive Task Forces and for hiring criminal investigators and providing training for such Task Forces. Requires the Attorney General to: (1) provide transportation services to state and local governments for the extradition of fugitives through the U.S. Marshal Service Justice Prisoner and Alien Transportation Service; (2) make grants to states for the extradition of fugitives to other states for prosecution; and (3) make grants to states for establishing or upgrading information and identification technologies for serious misdemeanor and felony warrants. Makes state compliance with felony and serious misdemeanor warrant reporting requirements a condition for receiving grants under this Act. Requires states to make electronically available to the National Crime Information Center (NCIC) all serious misdemeanor and felony warrants issued by such states and their local jurisdictions.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
