<bill session="110" type="s" number="3148" updated="2009-01-09T18:26:00-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1213761600" datetime="2008-06-18"/></status>

	<introduced date="1213761600" datetime="2008-06-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Oregon Caves National Monument Boundary Adjustment Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to modify the boundary of the Oregon Caves National Monument, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300100"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1213761600" datetime="2008-06-18"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5756-5757)</text></action>
		<action date="1213761600" datetime="2008-06-18"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S5757-5758"/></action>
		<action date="1217390400" datetime="2008-07-30"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/18/2008--Introduced.<br/>Oregon Caves National Monument Boundary Adjustment Act of 2008 - Adjusts the boundary of the Oregon Caves National Monument (Monument). Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to: (1) transfer certain acreage in the Monument to the Secretary of the Interior; and (2) adjust the boundary of the Rogue River-Siskiyou National Forest to exclude certain lands in the Monument transferred by the Secretary.<br/>Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate certain additional segments of the Monument as components of the national wild and scenic rivers system.<br/>Requires the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) administer the Monument in accordance with this Act and other legal authorities; and (2) carry out forest restoration activities within the boundaries of the Monument.<br/>Directs the Secretary of Agriculture or the Interior to accept any grazing lease or permit that is donated by a livestock operator that holds a valid existing grazing lease or permit for a grazing allotment.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
