<bill session="110" type="s" number="3157" updated="2009-01-09T18:27:08-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1213761600" datetime="2008-06-18"/></status>

	<introduced date="1213761600" datetime="2008-06-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Southeast Arizona Land Exchange and Conservation Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the exchange and conveyance of certain National Forest System land and other land in southeast Arizona, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300062"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1213761600" datetime="2008-06-18"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1215576000" datetime="2008-07-09"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-572.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/18/2008--Introduced.<br/>Southeast Arizona Land Exchange and Conservation Act of 2008 - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to: (1) accept a conveyance of non-federal land in Gila, Yavapai, Maricopa, Pinal, and Coconino Counties, Arizona, from Resolution Copper Mining, LLC (Resolution Copper); (2) convey to Resolution Copper certain federal land located in Pinal County, Arizona; (3) convey specified land in Pinal County to the town of Superior, Arizona; and (4) appraise lands exchanged or conveyed under this Act.<br/>Instructs Resolution Copper to deliver to the Secretary an executed document granting a permanent conservation easement for the easement area (the surface estate of the Apache Leap Conservation Easement Area, Arizona) to an entity that is: (1) a qualified unit of government or Indian tribe; or (2) a land trust or other qualified organization. Requires Resolution Copper to determine whether the area covered by the easement should be managed to establish: (1) additional cultural and historical resource protections or measures; or (2) additional or alternative public access routes, trails, and trailheads to Apache Leap. Makes lands acquired by the Secretary under this Act part of the National Forest within which the land is located.<br/>Directs the Secretary to construct in the Global Ranger District of the Tonto National Forest, Arizona, one or more replacement campgrounds for the Oak Flat Campground.<br/>Requires Resolution Copper to make value adjustment payments to the United States based upon locatable minerals produced from federal lands in Pinal County, Arizona.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
