<bill session="110" type="s" number="3165" updated="2009-01-09T18:28:08-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1213848000" datetime="2008-06-19"/></status>

	<introduced date="1213848000" datetime="2008-06-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Summer Travel Delay Prevention Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to develop a plan to share military and special use airspace along the eastern seaboard with commercial air traffic, to provide adequate resources for the FAA New York Integration Office, to establish an Aviation Traveler Task Force, and to design a notification system to alert passengers of potential service disruptions.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300087"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1213848000" datetime="2008-06-19"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/19/2008--Introduced.<br/>Summer Travel Delay Prevention Act - Directs the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to develop: (1) a plan for opening up to commercial flights special use airspace for additional lanes of air traffic at specific choke points; and (2) a permanent plan for sharing military airspace off the eastern U.S. coast by such flights. Authorizes the Director of the New York Integration Office of the FAA to transfer appropriated amounts for Office operations to flight delay reduction projects in airspace over the New York-New Jersey region. Requires the FAA Administrator to establish an Aviation Traveler Task Force to: (1) clarify interpretations of FAA safety directives with which air carriers will soon need to comply; (2) develop contingency plans in the event that additional aircraft do not comply with such safety directives and need to be grounded; and (3) design a notification system to alert passengers of potential service disruptions.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
