<bill session="110" type="s" number="3176" updated="2009-01-09T18:29:30-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1214193600" datetime="2008-06-23"/></status>

	<introduced date="1214193600" datetime="2008-06-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Disaster Recovery Substance Abuse Mental Health Treatment Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to authorize the President to provide mental health and substance abuse services.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300063"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1214193600" datetime="2008-06-23"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/23/2008--Introduced.<br/>Disaster Recovery Substance Abuse Mental Health Treatment Act of 2008 - Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to authorize the President to provide mental health and substance abuse services to individuals affected by a major disaster to relieve or prevent mental health or substance abuse problems caused or aggravated by that disaster or its aftermath.<br/>Allows such assistance to include financial assistance to government agencies, mental health or substance abuse organizations, or mental health providers to provide, or train individuals to provide, mental health or substance abuse services. Restricts assistance to an 18-month period, which in limited circumstances may be extended if the President determines it to be in the public interest. Makes this applicable to any major disaster declared by the President on or after August 29, 2005.<br/>Requires the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration and the head of any other federal agency that provides mental health or substance abuse services, in coordination with the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) and state and local officials with responsibilities for such services, to: (1) conduct a survey of such services; and (2) develop a strategy for the adequate provision of such services to individuals affected by major disasters and to emergency response providers responding to major disasters.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
