<bill session="110" type="s" number="3174" updated="2009-01-09T18:29:15-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1213934400" datetime="2008-06-20"/></status>

	<introduced date="1213934400" datetime="2008-06-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Port Authority of New York/New Jersey Port Security Task Force Implementation Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve port and intermodal supply chain security.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300064"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2008-06-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2008-06-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2008-06-20"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1213934400" datetime="2008-06-20"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/20/2008--Introduced.<br/>Port Authority of New York/New Jersey Port Security Task Force Implementation Act of 2008 - Amends federal port security law to revise mandatory elements of the secure system of transportation program. Directs the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, acting through the Commissioner of Customs and Border Protection, to establish minimum program standards and procedures for verifying, at the point goods are placed in a cargo container for shipping, that such container is free of unauthorized contents, including hazardous chemical, biological, radiological, or nuclear material, and is securely sealed after verification of its contents. Prohibits the entry of any container that has not complied with such standards and procedures. Requires Area Maritime Transportation Security Plans to establish regional response and recovery protocols for transportation security incidents. Amends the SAFE Port Act to require the Secretary of Homeland Security to ensure that the Port Security Exercise Program utilizes Area Maritime Transportation Security Plans in conducting port security exercises. Requires the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating to develop and utilize a national standard for prioritizing and assessing security risks at U.S. ports, such as the Maritime Assessment Strategy Tool. Sets forth requirements regarding: (1) use of the U.S. Coast Guard's Maritime Security Risk Assessment Model tool to conduct vessel and port facility security risk assessments; (2) establishment of maritime and cargo security integrated project teams; (3) sharing of port facility vulnerability assessments and integration of port security plans and systems with local port authority and law enforcement agencies; (4) policy for advanced notice of Coast Guard boarding of vessels for security or Port State Control inspections; (5) confiscation of fraudulent transportation worker identification cards (TWICs); (6) Federal Maritime Commission training and licensing of steamship agents; (7) designation of a U.S. person to be responsible for notifying emergency response entities in the event of a transportation security incident involving a U.S. or foreign vessel; (8) minimum incident command system training and performance standards for maritime security guards; (9) consideration of regional strategic risk management priorities for tier 1 and tier 2 ports in grant awards; and (10) the submission of security plans for supply, bunker, and fuel deliver and launch vessels conducting activities or providing services to other vessels at anchorage. 
	</summary>
</bill>
