<bill session="110" type="s" number="3175" updated="2009-01-09T18:29:23-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1214366400" datetime="2008-06-25" /></status>

	<introduced date="1213934400" datetime="2008-06-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Predisaster Hazard Mitigation Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Predisaster Hazard Mitigation Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to reauthorize the predisaster hazard mitigation program, to make technical corrections to that Act, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300067"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2008-06-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300001" joined="2008-06-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1213934400" datetime="2008-06-20"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1214366400" datetime="2008-06-25" ><text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1222056000" datetime="2008-09-22"><text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman with amendments. With written report No. 110-479.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="1040" date="1222056000" datetime="2008-09-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1040.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/22/2008--Reported to Senate amended. Predisaster Hazard Mitigation Act of 2008 - Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to require the President to: (1) award financial assistance under the pre-disaster hazard mitigation program on a competitive basis; and (2) ensure that the amount of assistance made available to each state is not less than the lesser of $575,000 or the amount that is equal to 1% of the total funds appropriated to carry out such program for the fiscal year, and is not more than 15% of such appropriated funds.<br/>Authorize appropriations for the program for FY2009-FY2013. Repeals the program termination date. Prohibits a state from using more than 25% of the financial assistance made available to the state under the program in a fiscal year for flood control projects.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
