<bill session="110" type="s" number="3189" updated="2009-01-09T18:31:17-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" /></status>

	<introduced date="1214366400" datetime="2008-06-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Endangered Fish Recovery Programs Improvement Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Endangered Fish Recovery Programs Improvement Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend Public Law 106-392 to require the Administrator of the Western Area Power Administration and the Commissioner of Reclamation to maintain sufficient revenues in the Upper Colorado River Basin Fund, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300009"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400619" joined="2008-07-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300036" joined="2008-06-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1214366400" datetime="2008-06-25"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1215489600" datetime="2008-07-08"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-571.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="1005" date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1005.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/16/2008--Reported to Senate amended. Endangered Fish Recovery Programs Improvement Act of 2008 - Amends federal law providing funding to continue endangered fish recovery implementation programs for the Upper Colorado and San Juan River Basins by: (1) modifying the definition of &quot;capital projects&quot; to include rehabilitation and repair of facilities; (2) modifying the definition of &quot;facilities&quot; to include facilities for protection of critical habitat and for preventing entrainment of fish in water diversions; (3) increasing funding; and (4) extending the authorization period to fund recovery programs.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
