<bill session="110" type="s" number="3203" updated="2009-01-09T18:33:05-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"/></status>

	<introduced date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">KC-Tanker Recompete Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit the use of funds by the Department of Defense on the KC-X tanker contract, and for other purposes related to that contract.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300083"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300013" joined="2008-06-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/26/2008--Introduced.<br/>KC-Tanker Recompete Act - Prohibits funds from being used by the Department of Defense (DOD) on the KC-X (aerial refueling) tanker contract. Defines such contract as the contract awarded by the Department of the Air Force on February 29, 2008, for such aircraft. Outlines requirements and conditions as part of the acquisition process for the award of a contract for a replacement for the KC-135 tanker, including: (1) an independent cost estimate; (2) an increase in the proposal cost or price by the amount of any illegal subsidization by a subsidized person; (3) ensuring an evaluation of the cost borne by a supplier and the cost borne by a foreign government; (4) the consideration of national security impacts; (5) defense industrial base considerations; (6) consideration of the loss of U.S. employee and corporate tax revenue when awarding contracts to foreign entities; and (7) the impact of U.S. regulatory burdens. Directs the Secretary of Defense and the contract source selection authority to require any prospective defense contractor or subcontractor not already covered by the Foreign Corrupt Practices Act to comply with such Act's requirements as a contract award condition. Allows a waiver of such requirement for national security purposes.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
