<bill session="110" type="s" number="3214" updated="2009-01-09T18:34:32-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"/></status>

	<introduced date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">America's Beautiful National Parks Quarter Dollar Coin Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for a program for circulating quarter dollar coins that are emblematic of a national park or other national site in each State, the District of Columbia, and each territory of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412251"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300041" joined="2008-07-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1214452800" datetime="2008-06-26"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/26/2008--Introduced.<br/>America's Beautiful National Parks Quarter Dollar Coin Act of 2008 - Requires quarter dollars, issued beginning in 2010, to have designs on the reverse emblematic of one national site in each state, the District of Columbia and territory of the United States. Instructs the Secretary of the Treasury to select in each state a national park or other national site to be honored with a coin. Requires Yellowstone National Park, established on March 1, 1872, as the nation's first national park, to be depicted on the first quarter dollar issued and to be designated to the state of Wyoming. Requires five coin designs in each year of the period of issuance. Instructs the Secretary to strike and make available for sale silver bullion coins that are exact duplicates of such quarter dollars.<br/>Authorizes the Director of the National Park Service to purchase for resale or distribution numismatic items issued under this Act. Requires the Secretary to take such actions as are necessary to ensure that minting and issuing coins under this Act will not result in any net cost to the federal government. 
	</summary>
</bill>
