<bill session="110" type="s" number="322" updated="2009-01-09T11:49:11-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1170910800" datetime="2007-02-08" /></status>

	<introduced date="1169010000" datetime="2007-01-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Indian Youth Telemental Health Demonstration Project Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Indian Youth Telemental Health Demonstration Project Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish an Indian youth telemental health demonstration project.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300037"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="2007-01-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300005" joined="2007-01-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2007-01-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300071" joined="2007-01-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300097" joined="2007-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300075" joined="2007-01-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300026" joined="2007-01-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300090" joined="2007-01-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1169010000" datetime="2007-01-17"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S693-694)</text></action>
		<action date="1169010000" datetime="2007-01-17"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S694-695"/></action>
		<calendar date="1170910800" datetime="2007-02-08" ><text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1176177600" datetime="2007-04-10"><text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Dorgan with an amendment. With written report No. 110-43.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="108" date="1176177600" datetime="2007-04-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 108.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/10/2007--Reported to Senate amended. Indian Youth Telemental Health Demonstration Project Act of 2007 - Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services to carry out a demonstration project to award up to five grants, of up to four years each, for the provision of telemental health services to Indian youth who have expressed suicidal ideas, have attempted suicide, or have mental health conditions that increase or could increase the risk of suicide. Makes eligible for such grants any Indian tribes and tribal organizations that operate one or more facilities: (1) located in Alaska and part of the Alaska Federal Health Care Access Network; (2) reporting active clinical telehealth capabilities; or (3) offering school-based telemental health services relating to psychiatry to Indian youth.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
