<bill session="110" type="s" number="3248" updated="2009-01-09T18:39:44-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1215662400" datetime="2008-07-10"/></status>

	<introduced date="1215662400" datetime="2008-07-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Commodity Speculation Reform Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Commodity Exchange Act to clarify the treatment of purchases of certain commodity futures contracts and financial instruments with respect to limits established by the Commodity Futures Trading Commission relating to excessive speculation, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300067"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2008-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2008-07-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300010" joined="2008-07-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1215662400" datetime="2008-07-10"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6567-6568, S6569-6570)</text></action>
		<action date="1215662400" datetime="2008-07-10"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S6568-6569"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/10/2008--Introduced.<br/>Commodity Speculation Reform Act of 2008 - Amends the Commodity Exchange Act to prohibit the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC) from issuing a no action letter to any foreign board of trade that lists a contract whose price settles on the price of a contract traded on an exchange regulated by the CFTC, unless the foreign board provides the CFTC with information and data accessibility comparable to those provided the CFTC by entities under its jurisdiction. Directs the CFTC to: (1) promulgate regulations to establish and enforce speculative position limits for qualifying commodities, a methodology for aggregating specified positions, and information reporting rules to facilitate monitoring and enforcement of speculative position limits and over-the-counter commodity derivatives; and (2) appoint at least 100 additional full-time employees to assist in carrying out such requirements. Prohibits a person from holding or controlling a position, separately or in combination, net long or net short, for the purchase or sale of a commodity for future delivery or, on a futures-equivalent basis, any option, or an over-the-counter commodity derivative that exceeds CFTC speculative position limits. Instructs the CFTC to study and report to certain congressional committees regarding: (1) trends in speculative activity relating to metals; and (2) possible extension of CFTC authority to cover trading of metals.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
