<bill session="110" type="s" number="325" updated="2009-01-09T11:49:34-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1169010000" datetime="2007-01-17"/></status>

	<introduced date="1169010000" datetime="2007-01-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Health Partnership Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for innovation in health care through State initiatives that expand coverage and access and improve quality and efficiency in the health care system.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300009"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300098" joined="2007-01-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-11-16"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1169010000" datetime="2007-01-17"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S696-698)</text></action>
		<action date="1169010000" datetime="2007-01-17"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S698-701"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/17/2007--Introduced.<br/>Health Partnership Act - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a State Health Innovation Commission. Requires the Commission to: (1) provide states with reform options for state health care expansion and improvement programs; (2) establish minimum performance measures and goals with respect to coverage, quality, and cost of state programs; (3) review state applications and determine whether to submit a state proposal to Congress; and (4) submit to Congress a list of state applications that the Commission recommends for approval. Deems such proposals to be approved unless a joint resolution has been enacted disapproving such proposal. Sets forth rules for congressional consideration of such proposals. Requires the Secretary to: (1) provide a grant to a state that has an application approved to enable such state to carry out an innovative state health program; (2) give priority to those state programs that the Commission determines have the greatest opportunity to succeed in providing expanded health insurance coverage and improving health access; and (3) link state allocations to the meeting of the goals and performance measures established under this Act. Prohibits states from: (1) failing to maintain the same level of expenditures for health care coverage; (2) changing eligibility criteria for state medical assistance programs; or (3) permitting the imposition of any preexisting condition exclusion for covered benefits, with exceptions.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
