<bill session="110" type="s" number="3276" updated="2009-01-09T18:43:31-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1216180800" datetime="2008-07-16"/></status>

	<introduced date="1216180800" datetime="2008-07-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Open and Transparent Smithsonian Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the application of sections 552, 552a, and 552b of title 5, United States Code, (commonly referred to as the Freedom of Information Act and the Privacy Act) and the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) to the Smithsonian Institution, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300048"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300092" joined="2008-07-16"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1216180800" datetime="2008-07-16"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6873-6875)</text></action>
		<action date="1216180800" datetime="2008-07-16"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/16/2008--Introduced.<br/>Open and Transparent Smithsonian Act of 2008 - Makes the Freedom of Information Act, the Privacy Act, federal law relating to open meetings of federal agencies, and the Federal Advisory Committee Act applicable to the Smithsonian Institution. Makes this Act applicable to: (1) all actions taken by the Board of Regents of the Smithsonian Institution or any other officer or employee of the Smithsonian Institution before, on, or after the enactment date of this Act; (2) any record created before, on, or after that date; and (3) any meeting held before, on, or after that date. Amends the Privacy Act to allow a federal agency, upon request by the chairperson or ranking member of a committee, subcommittee, or joint committee of Congress, to make a disclosure of any record which is contained in a system of records to that chairperson or ranking member. 
	</summary>
</bill>
