<bill session="110" type="s" number="328" updated="2009-01-09T11:49:56-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1169010000" datetime="2007-01-17"/></status>

	<introduced date="1169010000" datetime="2007-01-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Ensuring Implementation of the 9/11 Commission Report Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">9/11 Commission Civil Liberties Board Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Faster and Smarter Funding for First Responders Act of 2005</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">HERO Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Homeland Emergency Response Operations Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Omnibus Nonproliferation and Anti-Nuclear Terrorism Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure the implementation of the recommendations of the National Commission on Terrorist Attacks Upon the United States.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400272"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2007-01-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1169010000" datetime="2007-01-17"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/17/2007--Introduced.<br/>Ensuring Implementation of the 9/11 Commission Report Act - Homeland Emergency Response Operations Act or the HERO Act - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to require the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to complete assignment of the electromagnetic spectrum for public safety services to permit operation by December 31, 2007. Requires reports respecting: (1) a unified incident command system; (2) a national critical infrastructure risk and vulnerabilities assessment; and (3) private sector preparedness. Faster and Smarter Funding for First Responders Act of 2005 - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish a Department of Homeland Security (DHS) grant program to assist state and local governments in achieving essential capabilities for terrorism preparedness. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (Secretary) to: (1) establish an Office of the Comptroller within the Office for Domestic Preparedness, a First Responder Grants Board, and a Task Force on Terrorism Preparedness for First Responders; and (2) promulgate national voluntary standards for first responder equipment. Requires reports by: (1) DHS on a unified incident command system, a national critical infrastructure risk and vulnerabilities assessment, the comprehensive screening system, a biometric entry and exit data system, international collaboration on border and document security, and standardization of secure identification; (2) the Comptroller General on private sector preparedness, federal first responder training programs, and terrorist watch list consolidation; (3) the Secretary of Transportation on a national strategy for transportation security on airline passenger screening, on explosives detection at airline screening checkpoints, and on the comprehensive screening program; (4) the Director of the National Counterterrorism Center on collection and analysis of intelligence on terrorist travel; (5) the Commissioner of Social Security on social security card security enhancements; (6) the Director of National Intelligence on implementation of goals, and establishment of a National Counterterrorism Center; (7) the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) on the creation of an FBI national security workforce; (8) the Central Intelligence Agency (CIA); (9) the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) on information sharing incentives and on the leadership of the President of national security institutions in the information revolution; (10) the Secretary of Defense on Northern Command plans for homeland defense; and (11) the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) on security clearance standardization. Directs the Secretary and the Secretary of Defense to each report on homeland airspace defense. Directs the Attorney General to report on specified areas of civil liberties and security and executive power, including government sharing of personal information. 9/11 Commission Civil Liberties Board Act - Revises provisions concerning the Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board. Provides for the designation of privacy and civil liberties officers. Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to require fingerprints in passports. Requires specified reports on the recommendations of the 9/11 Commission and the policy goals of the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004. Revises provisions concerning the House and Senate intelligence committees. Requires public disclosure by the President of certain intelligence funding. Expresses the sense of Congress respecting: (1) Afghanistan; (2) Pakistan; (3) Saudi Arabia; (4) coalition strategy against Islamic terrorism; (5) the Middle East Partnership Initiative (MEPI); (6) the Proliferation Security Initiative; and (7) nuclear weapons and materials security standards. Sets forth provisions respecting: (1) terrorist sanctuary elimination; (2) standards for detention and humane treatment of captured terrorists; (3) economic policies to combat terrorism; (4) terrorist financing; and (5) public diplomacy, scholarship, exchange, and library programs in the Islamic world, and international broadcasting. Omnibus Nonproliferation and Anti-Nuclear Terrorism Act of 2007 - Establishes the Office of Nonproliferation Programs in the Executive Office of the President. Sets forth provisions concerning: (1) removal of certain restrictions on cooperative threat reduction and energy nonproliferation programs, and modification of such programs' fund use outside the former Soviet Union; (2) the Global Threat Reduction Initiative; (3) Russia's tactical and non-strategic nuclear weapons; (4) research and development of alternative use of weapons of mass destruction expertise; (5) nonproliferation activities; and (6) strengthening the Nuclear Nonproliferation Treaty.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
