<bill session="110" type="s" number="331" updated="2009-01-09T11:50:23-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1169096400" datetime="2007-01-18"/></status>

	<introduced date="1169096400" datetime="2007-01-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide grants from moneys collected from violations of the corporate average fuel economy program to be used to expand infrastructure necessary to increase the availability of alternative fuels.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400546"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412242" joined="2007-03-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400619" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-05-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300050" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300026" joined="2007-02-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1169096400" datetime="2007-01-18"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S756-757)</text></action>
		<action date="1169096400" datetime="2007-01-18"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/18/2007--Introduced.<br/>Establishes the Energy Security Fund, to be funded by proceeds deposited in the general fund of the Treasury from fines, penalties, and other funds obtained through enforcement actions for violations of automobile fuel economy standards. Directs the Secretary of Energy, acting through the Clean Cities Program of the Department of Energy, to establish a program of grants to expand the availability of alternative fuels to consumers. Makes amounts in the Fund available to the Secretary for such grants. Declares eligible for assistance any entity that is eligible for assistance under the Clean Cities Program. Bars from such assistance: (1) large, vertically-integrated oil companies; and (2) any entity that receives other federal funds for the construction or expansion of the same alternative refueling infrastructure. Sets forth a maximum ceiling for grants and for stations. Limits the use of such funds to construction or expansion of alternative fueling infrastructure.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
