<bill session="110" type="s" number="3344" updated="2009-01-09T18:52:17-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1217217600" datetime="2008-07-28" /></status>

	<introduced date="1217044800" datetime="2008-07-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Children from Pornography and Internet Exploitation Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Enhancing the Effective Prosecution of Child Pornography Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">PROTECT Our Children Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Providing Resources, Officers, and Technology To Eradicate Cyber Threats to Our Children Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to defend against child exploitation and child pornography through improved Internet Crimes Against Children task forces and enhanced tools to block illegal images, and to eliminate the unwarranted release of convicted sex offenders.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400576"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300055" joined="2008-09-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300030" joined="2008-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300088" joined="2008-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400621" joined="2008-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300013" joined="2008-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300041" joined="2008-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400546" joined="2008-09-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300062" joined="2008-09-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400418" joined="2008-09-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300014" joined="2008-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400054" joined="2008-09-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1217044800" datetime="2008-07-26"><text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1217217600" datetime="2008-07-28" ><text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 906.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/26/2008--Introduced.<br/>Protecting Children from Pornography and Internet Exploitation Act of 2008 - Providing Resources, Officers, and Technology to Eradicate Cyber Threats to Our Children Act of 2008 or the PROTECT Our Children Act of 2008 - Directs the Attorney General to create and implement a National Strategy for Child Exploitation Prevention and Interdiction and to submit such Strategy to Congress by February 1 of each year.<br/>Establishes within the Department of Justice (DOJ) a National Internet Crimes Against Children (ICAC) Task Force Program consisting of state and local law enforcement task forces (including at least one ICAC Task Force for each state) to address online enticement of children, child exploitation, and child obscenity and pornography. Directs the Attorney General to conduct periodic reviews of the effectiveness of ICAC task forces and provide training programs to support such task forces.<br/>Directs the Attorney General to establish: (1) a National Internet Crimes Against Children Data System (System) to assist the National ICAC Task Force Program and federal, state, local, and tribal agencies in investigating and prosecuting child exploitation; (2) a steering committee to provide guidance to the System on training and technology and the development of strategic plans; and (3) additional computer forensic capacity to address the current backlog for computer forensics, including for child exploitation investigations.<br/>Authorizes the Attorney General to award grants to state and local ICAC task forces. Requires the National Institute of Justice to prepare a report on investigative factors that indicate whether a subject of an online child exploitation investigation poses a higher risk of harm to children.<br/>Enhancing the Effective Prosecution of Child Pornography Act of 2007 [sic] - Amends the federal criminal code to enhance prohibitions against child sexual exploitation and child pornography. Imposes additional requirements on electronic communication or remote computing service providers for reporting suspected violations of child pornography laws.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
