<bill session="110" type="s" number="334" updated="2009-01-09T11:50:46-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1169096400" datetime="2007-01-18"/></status>

	<introduced date="1169096400" datetime="2007-01-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Healthy Americans Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide affordable, guaranteed private health coverage that will make Americans healthier and can never be taken away.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300100"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300002" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2008-07-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300030" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300092" joined="2008-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300019" joined="2007-12-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300007" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300048" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300078" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412248" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300069" joined="2007-12-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300049" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300090" joined="2008-06-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1169096400" datetime="2007-01-18"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S757-763)</text></action>
		<action date="1169096400" datetime="2007-01-18"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
		<action date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1363-1364)</text></action>
		<action date="1174536000" datetime="2007-03-22"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3556)</text></action>
		<action date="1178596800" datetime="2007-05-08"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5676-5677)</text></action>
		<action date="1189137600" datetime="2007-09-07"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S11264-11267)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/18/2007--Introduced.<br/>Healthy Americans Act - Requires each adult individual to have the opportunity to purchase a Healthy Americans Private Insurance Plan (HAPI). Makes individuals who are not enrolled in another specified health plan and who are not opposed to coverage for religious reasons responsible for enrolling themselves and their dependent children in a HAPI plan offered through their state of residence. Sets forth penalties for failure to enroll. Establishes standardized coverage and state options for HAPI plans. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to promulgate guidelines concerning the benefits, items, and services to be covered. Sets forth requirements for setting premiums. Requires the Secretary to establish the Healthy America Advisory Committee to provide annual recommendations concerning modifications to the benefits, items, and services required. Provides for school-based health centers. Authorizes states to establish and operate a State Choices for Long-Term Care Program. Requires the Secretary to establish Chronic Care Education Centers. Requires states to establish or designate a state Health Help Agency to carry out the administration of HAPI plans and to promote prevention and wellness for residents. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to require employers and individuals to each make shared responsibility payments for HAPI plan premiums. Sets forth requirements for health insurance issuers offering a HAPI plan. Establishes the Healthy Americans Public Health Trust Fund for the payment of: (1) premium subsidies; and (2) bonuses to states for implementing medical malpractice reform. Terminates federal health benefits coverage, including coverage provided under the Federal Employees Health Benefits (FEHB) program and the State Children's Health Insurance program (SCHIP).<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
