<bill session="110" type="s" number="3385" updated="2009-01-09T18:57:23-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"/></status>

	<introduced date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">FDA Food Safety Modernization Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act with respect to the safety of the food supply.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300038"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300002" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400054" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300049" joined="2008-07-31"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S7933-7934)</text></action>
		<action date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S7934-7941"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/31/2008--Introduced.<br/>FDA Food Safety Modernization Act - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to expand the authority of the Secretary of Health and Human Services (the Secretary) to regulate food, including by authorizing the Secretary to: (1) suspend the registration of a food facility; and (2) order a cessation on distribution or recall of food.<br/>Directs the Secretary to allocate resources based on the risk profile of food facilities or food.<br/>Requires the Secretary and the Secretary of Agriculture to prepare a National Agriculture and Food Defense Strategy.<br/>Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to assist state, local, and tribal governments in preparing for, assessing, decontaminating, and recovering from an agriculture or food emergency. Requires the Secretary to: (1) assess fees on domestic food facilities and food importers; (2) promulgate regulations on sanitary transportation practices for food; and (3) develop a policy to manage the risk of food allergy and anaphylaxis in schools and early childhood education programs.<br/>Directs the Secretary to: (1) recognize accreditation bodies that accredit food testing laboratories; and (2) improve the capabilities to track and trace raw agricultural commodities.<br/>Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to enhance foodborne illness surveillance systems.<br/>Provides for: (1) foreign supplier verification programs; (2) a voluntary qualified importer program; and (3) the inspection of foreign facilities registered to import food.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
