<bill session="110" type="s" number="3380" updated="2009-01-09T18:56:47-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"/></status>

	<introduced date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Saving Energy Through Public Transportation Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote increased public transportation use, to promote increased use of alternative fuels in providing public transportation, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300022"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2008-09-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="2008-09-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2008-09-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2008-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2008-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300081" joined="2008-09-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2008-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2008-09-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/31/2008--Introduced.<br/>Saving Energy Through Public Transportation Act of 2008 - Authorizes appropriations for FY2008-FY2009 for public transportation formula grants. Authorizes the Secretary of Transportation to make such grants for: (1) operating costs of equipment and facilities being used to provide the public transportation the grant recipient is no longer able to pay as a result of reducing fares; (2) operating and capital costs of equipment and facilities being used to provide transportation services that the recipient incurs as a result of expanding such services; (3) the avoidance of increased fares or decreased services; (4) the costs of acquiring clean or alternative fuel vehicle-related equipment or facilities; and (5) administrative costs in establishing or expanding services to provide commuters with information about alternatives to single occupancy vehicle use. Requires a grant that involves acquiring clean or alternative fuel vehicle-related equipment or facilities for complying with the Clean Air Act to be for 100% of the net project cost unless the grant recipient requests a lower percentage.<br/>Amends the Safe, Accountable, Flexible, Efficient Transportation Equity Act: A Legacy for Users to require federal employees in urbanized areas served by fixed route public transportation to be offered transit pass transportation fringe benefits. Requires: (1) the Secretary to issue guidance on nationwide implementation of a transportation fringe benefit program; and (2) agencies to report on program implementation.<br/>Requires the Secretary to establish a pilot program to carry out vanpool demonstration projects in not more than three urbanized areas and two other areas. Requires a grant for a capital project during FY2008-FY2009 that involves additional parking facilities at an end-of-line fixed guideway station or at a park-and-ride lot that serves a fixed route commuter bus route that is more than 20 miles in length to be for 100% of the net capital cost of the project unless the grant recipient requests a lower percentage.<br/>Requires the Secretary of Transportation to carry out a national consumer awareness program on the environmental, energy, and economic benefits of public transportation alternatives to the use of single occupancy vehicles<br/>Amends the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 to allow a federal agency to enter into a contract to purchase a generally available fuel that is not an alternative or synthetic fuel or a fuel predominantly produced from a nonconventional petroleum source if: (1) the contract does not specifically require the contractor to provide such an alternative, synthetic, or nonconventional fuel; (2) the purpose of the contract is not to obtain such a fuel; and (3) the contract does not provide incentives for a refinery upgrade or expansion to allow a refinery to use or increase its use of fuel from a nonconventional petroleum source.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
