<bill session="110" type="s" number="3403" updated="2009-01-09T18:59:36-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"/></status>

	<introduced date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Accuracy in Fuel Economy Standards Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 49, United States Code, to require determination of the maximum feasible fuel economy level achievable for cars and light trucks for a year based on a projected fuel gasoline price that is not less than the applicable high gasoline price projection issued by the Energy Information Administration.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300018"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2008-11-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2008-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400619" joined="2008-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2008-09-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/31/2008--Introduced.<br/>Accuracy in Fuel Economy Standards Act - Requires the Secretary of Transportation to calculate maximum feasible fuel economy standards for passenger automobiles and non-passenger automobiles based on the most recent high gasoline price projection issued by the Energy Information Administration (EIA).<br/>Defines the &quot;applicable high gasoline price projection&quot; as the greatest of a range of estimated gasoline prices that the EIA issues as part of its annual energy outlook, short-term energy outlook, or similar analyses for: (1) the year (or years) corresponding to the model year (or model years) for which the Secretary is prescribing an average fuel economy standard; and (2) the range of years considered by the Secretary in determining the costs and benefits associated with such standard.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
