<bill session="110" type="s" number="3414" updated="2009-01-09T19:00:55-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"/></status>

	<introduced date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Visa Efficiency and E-Verify Extension Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to recapture family-sponsored and employment-based immigrant visas lost to bureaucratic delays and to prevent losses of family-sponsored and employment-based immigrant visas in the future, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400272"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2008-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2008-07-31"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/31/2008--Introduced.<br/>Visa Efficiency and E-Verify Extension Act of 2008 - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to establish the fiscal year worldwide level of employment-based immigrants at 140,000 plus: (1) the previous year's unused visas; and (2) the number of unused visas from FY2002-FY2007. Establishes the fiscal year worldwide level of family-sponsored immigrants at 480,000 minus the number of certain aliens not subject to direct numerical limitations plus: (1) the previous year's unused visas; and (2) the number of unused visas from FY2002-FY2007. (States that such annual level shall not be less than 226,000.) Amends the Immigration and Nationality Technical Corrections Act of 1994 to extend the J-1 visa waiver (Conrad state 30/medical services in underserved areas) program through June 1, 2013. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to issue final regulations to eliminate or reduce fraud in the special immigrant non-minister religious worker program by no later than December 31, 2008. Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to extend the special immigrant program for non-minister religious workers until October 1, 2011. Amends the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 to extend the employment eligibility confirmation pilot programs (which includes the E-Verify basic pilot program) for five years. Directs the Commissioner of Social Security and the Secretary, for fiscal years beginning on or after October 1, 2008, to enter into a fiscal year agreement which shall: (1) provide funds to the Commissioner for such programs' full costs in quarterly advances; and (2) require an annual accounting and reconciliation of costs incurred and funds provided. Provides for interim funding continuation (based upon the latest agreement) if an agreement has not been reached by October 1 of a fiscal year. Requires that the Government Accountability Office (GAO) conduct studies regarding: (1) erroneous tentative nonconfirmations under the E-Verify program; and (2) such program's effects on small entities. 
	</summary>
</bill>
