<bill session="110" type="s" number="3413" updated="2009-01-09T19:00:47-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"/></status>

	<introduced date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Access for All America Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to achieve access to comprehensive primary health care services for all Americans and to improve primary care delivery through an expansion of the community health center and National Health Service Corps programs.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400357"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2008-07-31"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S7971-7973)</text></action>
		<action date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/31/2008--Introduced.<br/>Access for All America Act - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, to award grants to public or nonprofit entities certified as federally qualified health centers to operate community health centers and provide basic health and support services to medically underserved populations. Provides for the conversion of existing family medical practices to federally qualified health centers. Sets forth requirements for grant applicants relating to accessibility of services to underserved populations, quality assurance, standard fee and discount schedules, nondenial of services, and cultural awareness.<br/>Amends the Public Health Service Act to extend through FY2015 the authorization of appropriations for the National Health Service Corps scholarship and loan repayment program.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
