<bill session="110" type="s" number="342" updated="2009-01-09T11:51:51-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1169442000" datetime="2007-01-22"/></status>

	<introduced date="1169442000" datetime="2007-01-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Secure Travel and Counterterrorism Partnership Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to expand visa waiver program to countries on a probationary basis and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300098"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="2007-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300070" joined="2007-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2007-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300001" joined="2007-01-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1169442000" datetime="2007-01-22"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S828-829)</text></action>
		<action date="1169442000" datetime="2007-01-22"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S829-830"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/22/2007--Introduced.<br/>Secure Travel and Counterterrorism Partnership Act - Expresses the sense of Congress that the United States should expand the visa waiver program to nationals of foreign countries that are allies in the war on terrorism. Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish a pilot program to expand the visa waiver program for up to five new countries that are are cooperating with the United States on security and counterterrorism matters. Requires a country, prior to participation, to conclude a counterterrorism and security information sharing agreement with the United States. Authorizes: (1) a country to participate for an initial three-year period, with an additional two-year extension; and (2) the Secretary to terminate a country's participation for program noncompliance. Directs the Secretary to develop and implement procedures to improve the manner of calculating visa overstay rates.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
