<bill session="110" type="s" number="3437" updated="2009-01-09T19:03:40-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"/></status>

	<introduced date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Restoring America's Integrity Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to limit the use of certain interrogation techniques, to require notification of the International Committee of the Red Cross of detainees, to prohibit interrogation by contractors, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300043"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2008-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300050" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300084" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="2008-08-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S8044-8045)</text></action>
		<action date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"><text>Read twice and referred to the Select Committee on Intelligence.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduce" ref="CR S8045"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	8/1/2008--Introduced.<br/>Restoring America's Integrity Act - Prohibits any individual in the custody or control of personnel of the intelligence community (IC) or element or instrumentality thereof, regardless of nationality or physical location, from being subject to any treatment or technique of interrogation not authorized by the U.S. Army Field Manual on Human Intelligence Collector Operations. Requires the head of an IC element or instrumentality who detains or has control of such an individual to notify the International Committee of the Red Cross and provide access to such individual in a manner consistent with practices of the Armed Forces. Prohibits the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency (CIA) from permitting a CIA contractor or subcontractor to carry out an interrogation (instead requiring a CIA employee to do so).<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
