<bill session="110" type="s" number="347" updated="2009-01-09T11:52:28-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1169442000" datetime="2007-01-22"/></status>

	<introduced date="1169442000" datetime="2007-01-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="popular" as="">Minimum Wage bill</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Minimum Wage Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to provide for an increase in the Federal minimum wage, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300098"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300099" joined="2007-01-22" withdrawn="2007-01-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1169442000" datetime="2007-01-22"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/22/2007--Introduced.<br/>Minimum Wage Act of 2007 - Amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to increase the federal minimum wage to: (1) $5.85 an hour, beginning on the 60th day after enactment of this Act; (2) $6.55 an hour, beginning 12 months after that 60th day; and (3) $7.25 an hour, beginning 24 months after that 60th day.<br/>Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) make permanent accelerated cost recovery provisions for qualified leasehold improvement and restaurant property; (2) permit certain small businesses with gross receipts of not more than $10 million to use cash accounting methods and be exempt from the requirement of using inventories; (3) allow employers the work opportunity tax credit for hiring certain restaurant workers between the ages of 16 and 20; (4) set forth a definition and rules for evaluating the economic substance of financial transactions with tax consequences (economic substance doctrine); (5) impose an enhanced penalty for understatements of tax liability due to transactions lacking economic substance; (6) apply inverted corporation tax rules to certain transactions occurring after March 20, 2002; and (7) eliminate the requirement for a pre-levy collection due process hearing for taxpayers with employment tax liabilities.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
