<bill session="110" type="s" number="3519" updated="2009-01-09T19:13:38-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1221710400" datetime="2008-09-18"/></status>

	<introduced date="1221710400" datetime="2008-09-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Puppy Uniform Protection and Safety Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Animal Welfare Act to provide further protection for puppies.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300038"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412243" joined="2008-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2008-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="2008-09-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1221710400" datetime="2008-09-18"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S9031-9032)</text></action>
		<action date="1221710400" datetime="2008-09-18"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S9032"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/18/2008--Introduced.<br/>Puppy Uniform Protection and Safety Act - Amends the Animal Welfare Act to define &quot;retail pet store&quot; as a person that: (1) sells an animal directly to the public for use as a pet; and (2) does not breed or raise more than 50 dogs for use as pets during any one-year period.<br/>Exempts from requirements to obtain a license as an animal dealer or exhibitor under such Act any retail pet store or other person who: (1) does not breed or raise more than 50 dogs for use as pets during any one-year period; and (2) derives less than a substantial portion of their income from the breeding and raising of dogs or cats on their own premises and sells such dogs or cats to a dealer or research facility.<br/>Requires: (1) a dealer to provide each dog it holds that is 12 weeks or older with a minimum of two exercise periods during each day for a total of no less than one hour of exercise; (2) such exercise to include removing the dog from the dog's primary enclosure and allowing the dog to walk for the entire exercise period; and (3) such exercise to not include use of a treadmill, catmill, jenny mill, slat mill, or similar device, unless prescribed by a doctor of veterinary medicine. 
	</summary>
</bill>
