<bill session="110" type="s" number="3525" updated="2009-01-09T19:14:20-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1221710400" datetime="2008-09-18"/></status>

	<introduced date="1221710400" datetime="2008-09-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Star-Spangled Banner Bicentennial Commemorative Coin Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of the Treasury to mint coins in commemoration of the bicentennial of the writing of the &quot;Star-Spangled Banner&quot;, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400064"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300029" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2008-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300081" joined="2008-09-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="2008-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400576" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300080" joined="2008-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300036" joined="2008-09-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400194" joined="2008-10-02"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1221710400" datetime="2008-09-18"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S9036-9037)</text></action>
		<action date="1221710400" datetime="2008-09-18"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S9037"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/18/2008--Introduced.<br/>Star-Spangled Banner Bicentennial Commemorative Coin Act - Instructs the Secretary of the Treasury to mint and issue $1 coins in commemoration of the bicentennial of the writing of the Star-Spangled Banner.<br/>Requires a coin design emblematic of the battle for Baltimore that formed the basis for the Star-Spangled Banner.<br/>Authorizes the Secretary to issue the coins only during the calendar year beginning on January 1, 2012.<br/>Requires specified surcharges in sales of the coin, which shall be paid to the Maryland War of 1812 Bicentennial Commission for the purpose of supporting bicentennial activities, educational outreach activities, and preservation and improvement activities pertaining to the sites and structures relating to the War of 1812.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
