<bill session="110" type="s" number="3522" updated="2009-01-09T19:14:00-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1221710400" datetime="2008-09-18"/></status>

	<introduced date="1221710400" datetime="2008-09-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Board of Certification Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a Federal Board of Certification to enhance the transparency, credibility, and stability of financial markets, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300091"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1221710400" datetime="2008-09-18"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S9032-9033)</text></action>
		<action date="1221710400" datetime="2008-09-18"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S9033-9034"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/18/2008--Introduced.<br/>Federal Board of Certification Act of 2008 - Establishes a Federal Board of Certification to certify that the mortgages within a security instrument meet the underlying standards they claim to meet with regards to such mortgage characteristics as: (1) documentation; (2) loan to value ratios; (3) debt service to income ratios; and (4) borrower credit standards and geographic concentration. States that the purpose of this certification process is to increase the transparency, predictability, and reliability of securitized mortgage products.<br/>Authorizes market participants, including firms that package mortgage loans into mortgage securities, to elect to have their mortgage securities evaluated by the Board.<br/>Authorizes the Board to: (1) promulgate regulations establishing enumerated security standards to use in certifying mortgage securities; (2) establish uniform principles and standards and report forms for the regular examination of such securities; and (3) develop uniform reporting systems for ascertaining mortgage security risk.<br/>Grants the Board access to all books, accounts, records, reports, files, memorandums, papers, things, and property belonging to or in use by federal financial institutions regulatory agencies.<br/>Requires any publication, transmission, or webpage containing an advertisement for or invitation to buy a mortgage security to carry a disclaimer that certification by the Federal Board of Certification can in no way be considered a guarantee of the mortgage security, but is merely a judgment of the degree of risk offered by the security in question.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
