<bill session="110" type="s" number="3539" updated="2009-01-09T19:16:02-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1222142400" datetime="2008-09-23"/></status>

	<introduced date="1222142400" datetime="2008-09-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Girl Scouts USA Centennial Commemorative Coin Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of the Treasury to mint coins in commemoration of the centennial of the establishment of the Girl Scouts of the United States of America.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300025"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2008-09-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="412251" joined="2008-09-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2008-09-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2008-09-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300068" joined="2008-09-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300054" joined="2008-09-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2008-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300075" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2008-09-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="412248" joined="2008-11-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400194" joined="2008-10-02"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1222142400" datetime="2008-09-23"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/23/2008--Introduced.<br/>Girl Scouts USA Centennial Commemorative Coin Act - Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to mint and issue up to 350,000 $1 coins in commemoration of the centennial of the Girl Scouts of the United States of America.<br/>Requires the coin design to be emblematic of such centennial.<br/>Requires such coins to be issued in uncirculated and proof qualities, from only one U.S. Mint facility.<br/>Declares the sense of Congress that such facility should be the U.S. Mint at West Point, New York, to the greatest extent possible.<br/>Authorizes the Secretary to issue such coins only during calendar 2011.<br/>Applies a $10 per coin surcharge to all coin sales. Requires all surcharges received to be paid to the Girl Scouts of the United States of America for efforts involved in marking it centennial, which may include efforts to preserve the birthplace of founder Juliette Gordon Low.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
