<bill session="110" type="s" number="3560" updated="2009-01-09T19:18:38-05:00">
	<status><enacted date="1223438400" datetime="2008-10-08" /></status>

	<introduced date="1222228800" datetime="2008-09-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">QI Program Supplemental Funding Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">QI Program Supplemental Funding Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">QI Program Supplemental Funding Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="enacted">QI Program Supplemental Funding Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to provide additional funds for the qualifying individual (QI) program, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300005"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300048" joined="2008-09-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1222228800" datetime="2008-09-24"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
		<action date="1222315200" datetime="2008-09-25"><text>Senate Committee on Finance discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S9459-9461"/></action>
		<vote date="1222315200" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2008-09-25" where="s" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR S9460-9461"/></vote>
		<action date="1222376460" datetime="2008-09-25T18:01:00-04:00"><text>Received in the House.</text></action>
		<action date="1222315200" datetime="2008-09-25"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<action date="1222315200" datetime="2008-09-25"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
		<action date="1222531800" datetime="2008-09-27T13:10:00-04:00"><text>RE-REFERRAL OF S. 3560 - Mr. Pallone asked unanimous consent that the bill, S. 3560, be re-referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition, to the Committee on Ways and Means. Agreed to without objection.</text></action>
		<action date="1222488000" datetime="2008-09-27"><text>Rereferred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1222532160" datetime="2008-09-27T13:16:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Pallone moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text></action>
		<action date="1222532160" datetime="2008-09-27T13:16:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H10170-10176"/></action>
		<action date="1222532160" datetime="2008-09-27T13:16:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 3560.</text></action>
		<vote date="1222533900" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-09-27T13:45:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote2" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H10170-10171"/></vote>
		<topresident date="1222488000" datetime="2008-09-27" ><text>Cleared for White House.</text></topresident>
		<topresident date="1222660800" datetime="2008-09-29" ><text>Presented to President.</text></topresident>
		<signed date="1223438400" datetime="2008-10-08" ><text>Signed by President.</text></signed>
		<enacted number="110-379" date="1223438400" datetime="2008-10-08" type="public" ><text>Became Public Law No: 110-379.</text></enacted>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/8/2008--Public Law. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) QI Program Supplemental Funding Act of 2008 - Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act, as amended by the Medicare Improvements for Patients and Providers Act of 2008, to provide supplemental funding for the qualifying individual (QI) program. Requires a state to have in operation, in mechanized Medicaid claims processing and information retrieval systems, an eligibility determination system which provides for data matching through the Public Assistance Reporting Information System (PARIS) facilitated by the Secretary of Health and Human Services, including matching with medical assistance programs operated by other states. Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to make sponsors of certain antibiotic drugs eligible for a three-year or a five-year market exclusivity if a marketing application is submitted for an antibiotic drug that: (1) was approved by the Secretary of Health and Human Services before November 21, 1997; or (2) was the subject of one or more applications received by the Secretary before November 21, 1997, none of which was approved. Authorizes the use of Medicaid integrity program funds for transportation and travel expenses for attendees at education, training, or consultative activities. Increases FY2014 funding for the Medicare Improvement Fund.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
