<bill session="110" type="s" number="3579" updated="2009-01-09T19:20:55-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1222315200" datetime="2008-09-25"/></status>

	<introduced date="1222315200" datetime="2008-09-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Silver Alert Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Kristen's Act Reauthorization of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to encourage, enhance, and integrate Silver Alert plans throughout the United States, to authorize grants for the assistance of organizations to find missing adults, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400621"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300061" joined="2008-09-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1222315200" datetime="2008-09-25"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/25/2008--Introduced.<br/>National Silver Alert Act - Directs the Attorney General to: (1) establish a national Silver Alert communications network within the Department of Justice (DOJ) to assist regional and local search efforts for missing seniors; (2) assign a DOJ officer to serve as the Silver Alert Coordinator to coordinate the network with states; and (3) award grants to states for support of Silver Alert plans and the network. Defines &quot;missing senior&quot; as any individual who is reported as missing to or by a law enforcement agency and who meets state requirements for designation as a missing senior. Directs the Coordinator to: (1) establish minimum standards for the issuance and dissemination of alerts issued through the network; and (2) make available to states, local governments, law enforcement agencies, and other concerned entities network training and information.<br/>Authorizes the Attorney General to award grants to states and local governments to provide voluntary electronic monitoring services to elderly individuals (Sammy Kirk Voluntary Electronic Monitoring Program).<br/>Kristen's Act Reauthorization of 2008 - Directs the Attorney General to make competitive grants to public agencies and/or nonprofit private organizations to: (1) maintain a national resource center and database for tracking missing adults; and (2) provide assistance and to law enforcement agencies, families, and victim advocates in locating and recovering missing adults.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
