<bill session="110" type="s" number="3598" updated="2009-01-09T19:23:11-05:00">
	<status><enacted date="1223870400" datetime="2008-10-13" /></status>

	<introduced date="1222315200" datetime="2008-09-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Drug Trafficking Vessel Interdiction Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Drug Trafficking Vessel Interdiction Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed senate">Drug Trafficking Vessel Interdiction Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="enacted">Drug Trafficking Vessel Interdiction Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend titles 46 and 18, United States Code, with respect to the operation of submersible vessels and semi-submersible vessels without nationality.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300056"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300008" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300047" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400621" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300080" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300048" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300078" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300090" joined="2008-09-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2008-09-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<vote date="1222315200" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2008-09-25" where="s" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>Introduced in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S9553-9554"/><reference label="text as passed Senate" ref="CR S9553-9554"/></vote>
		<action date="1222434780" datetime="2008-09-26T10:13:00-04:00"><text>Received in the House.</text></action>
		<action date="1222401600" datetime="2008-09-26"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<action date="1222401600" datetime="2008-09-26"><text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1222401600" datetime="2008-09-26"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1222401600" datetime="2008-09-26"><text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text></action>
		<action date="1222549140" datetime="2008-09-27T17:59:00-04:00"><text>Mr. Conyers moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text></action>
		<action date="1222549140" datetime="2008-09-27T17:59:00-04:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H10251-10254"/></action>
		<action date="1222549140" datetime="2008-09-27T17:59:00-04:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 3598.</text></action>
		<action date="1222549800" datetime="2008-09-27T18:10:00-04:00"><text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Smith (TX) objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text></action>
		<action date="1222711080" datetime="2008-09-29T14:58:00-04:00"><text>Considered as unfinished business.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H10631"/></action>
		<vote date="1222711140" how="by voice vote" datetime="2008-09-29T14:59:00-04:00" where="h" type="vote2" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote. (text: CR 9/27/2008 H10251-10252)</text></vote>
		<topresident date="1222660800" datetime="2008-09-29" ><text>Cleared for White House.</text></topresident>
		<topresident date="1223006400" datetime="2008-10-03" ><text>Presented to President.</text></topresident>
		<signed date="1223870400" datetime="2008-10-13" ><text>Signed by President.</text></signed>
		<enacted number="110-407" date="1223870400" datetime="2008-10-13" type="public" ><text>Became Public Law No: 110-407.</text></enacted>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/13/2008--Public Law. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the Senate passed version is repeated here.) Drug Trafficking Vessel Interdiction Act of 2008 - Title I: Criminal Prohibition - Amends the federal criminal code to impose a fine and/or prison term of up to 15 years for knowingly operating, attempting or conspiring to operate, or embarking in any submersible or semi-submersible vessel that is without nationality in, through, or from waters beyond the outer limit of the territorial sea of a single country or a lateral limit of that country's territorial sea with an adjacent country, with the intent to avoid detection. Grants extraterritorial federal jurisdiction over an offense under this Act. Specifies that a claim of nationality or registry under this Act includes only: (1) possession on board the vessel and production of documents evidencing the vessel's nationality as provided in the 1958 Convention on the High Seas; (2) flying its nation's ensign or flag; or (3) a verbal claim of nationality or registry by the person in charge of the vessel. Makes it an affirmative defense to a prosecution under this Act that a vessel operated at the time of a violation was: (1) a vessel of the Untied States or lawfully registered in a foreign nation; (2) classed by and designated in accordance with the rules of a classification society; (3) lawfully operated in a government regulated or licensed activity; or (4) equipped with and using an operable automatic identification system, vessel monitoring system, or a long range identification and tracking system. Specifies the documents required to conclusively prove an affirmative defense.<br/>Directs the U.S. Sentencing Commission to promulgate or amend sentencing guidelines to provide adequate penalties for violating the criminal prohibition imposed by this Act.<br/>Title II: Civil Prohibition - Imposes a civil penalty of up to $1 million for a violation of this Act. Allows the same defenses to a civil enforcement proceeding as for a criminal prosecution under this Act.<br/>Defines a &quot;semi-submersible vessel&quot; as any manned or unmanned watercraft constructed or adapted to operate with most of its hull and bulk under the surface of the water. Defines a &quot;submersible vessel&quot; as a manned or unmanned vessel capable of operating completely below the surface of the water.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
