<bill session="110" type="s" number="367" updated="2009-01-09T11:54:55-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1169528400" datetime="2007-01-23"/></status>

	<introduced date="1169528400" datetime="2007-01-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Decent Working Conditions and Fair Competition Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Tariff Act of 1930 to prohibit the import, export, and sale of goods made with sweatshop labor, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300037"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="2008-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="2007-10-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2008-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300008" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300047" joined="2007-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="2007-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-12-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="2008-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2008-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300016" joined="2007-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2008-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300081" joined="2008-04-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="412249" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="2007-10-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-09-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300006" joined="2007-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2008-02-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300084" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2008-01-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1169528400" datetime="2007-01-23"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
		<action date="1169787600" datetime="2007-01-26"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1235-1236)</text></action>
		<action date="1170046800" datetime="2007-01-29"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1265)</text></action>
		<action date="1188964800" datetime="2007-09-05"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S11089)</text></action>
		<action date="1193284800" datetime="2007-10-25"><text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation Subcommittee on Interstate Commerce, Trade, and Tourism. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/23/2007--Introduced.<br/>Decent Working Conditions and Fair Competition Act - Amends the Tariff Act of 1930 to revise the prohibition on importing convict-made goods into the United States to make it unlawful to: (1) import into, or export from, the United States any sweatshop good; or (2) introduce into commerce, sell, trade, or advertise in commerce, offer to sell, or transport or distribute in U.S. commerce, any sweatshop good. Grants the President, for reasons of national interest, authority to recommend waiver of the applications set forth in this Act in connection with the goods of any country with respect to one or more of the principles and rights defined in this Act as a core labor standard. Sets forth procedures for consideration of such a waiver. Makes it unlawful for persons to introduce into commerce, sell, trade, or advertise in commerce, offer to sell or transport or distribute in commerce any sweatshop good. Requires the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to enforce this prohibition as if it were an unfair or deceptive act or practice proscribed under the Federal Trade Commission Act. Allows specified persons with standing to bring a civil action in U.S. district courts against sellers of goods, wares, articles, or merchandise on grounds of a violation of such prohibition. Prohibits executive agencies and the Armed Forces from entering into procurement contracts for sweatshop goods. Prohibits anything in this Act from being construed to preempt a state from regulating labor standards required in the mining, production, or manufacture of merchandise purchased by the state.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
