<bill session="110" type="s" number="368" updated="2009-01-09T11:55:03-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1173931200" datetime="2007-03-15" /></status>

	<introduced date="1169528400" datetime="2007-01-23"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">COPS Improvements Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">COPS Improvements Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to enhance the COPS ON THE BEAT grant program, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300008"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412242" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="2007-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300005" joined="2007-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2007-10-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="2007-03-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-03-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300082" joined="2007-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2007-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-05-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400619" joined="2007-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="2007-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2007-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2007-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300061" joined="2007-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300092" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300016" joined="2007-01-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300081" joined="2007-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="2007-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-01-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="300080" joined="2007-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="412243" joined="2007-02-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300078" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300075" joined="2008-06-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300006" joined="2007-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-03-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2007-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300084" joined="2007-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2007-11-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300090" joined="2007-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="2008-09-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2007-01-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1169528400" datetime="2007-01-23"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S921-922)</text></action>
		<action date="1169528400" datetime="2007-01-23"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S922-923"/></action>
		<calendar date="1173931200" datetime="2007-03-15" ><text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23"><text>Committee on the Judiciary Senate Subcommittee on Crime and Drugs. Hearings held.</text></action>
		<action date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24"><text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Leahy without amendment. With written report No. 110-73.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="175" date="1179979200" datetime="2007-05-24" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 175.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1182312000" datetime="2007-06-20"><text>Committee on the Judiciary. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/24/2007--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)<br/>COPS Improvements Act of 2007 - Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to expand the authority of the Attorney General to make grants for public safety and community policing programs (COPS ON THE BEAT or COPS program). Revises grant purposes to provide for: (1) the hiring or training of law enforcement officers for intelligence, antiterror, and homeland security duties; (2) the hiring of school resource officers; (3) school-based partnerships between local law enforcement agencies and local school systems to combat crime, gangs, drug activities, and other problems facing elementary and secondary schools; (4) innovative programs to reduce and prevent illegal drug (including methamphetamine) manufacturing, distribution, and use; and (5) enhanced community policing and crime prevention grants that meet emerging law enforcement needs.<br/>Allows COPS program grants to be used to hire former members of the Armed Forces to serve as career law enforcement officers for community-oriented policing, particularly in communities adversely affected by a recent military base closing.<br/>Authorizes the Attorney General to make grants to: (1) assign community prosecutors to handle cases from specific geographic areas and address counterterrorism problems, specific violent crime problems, and localized violent and other crime problems; and (2) develop new technologies to assist state and local law enforcement agencies in crime prevention.<br/>Grants the Office of Community Oriented Policing Services exclusive authority to perform functions and activities under the COPS program.<br/>Requires grant recipients to retain additional law enforcement officers for a 12-month period after the end of the grant period.<br/>Authorizes the Attorney General to renew COPS program grants if grant recipients can demonstrate significant progress in achieving the objectives of the initial grant application.<br/>Increases: (1) the authorization of appropriation for the COPS program; and (2) the amount of funds available for technical assistance from 3 to 5%. Specifies amounts to be made available for hiring officers and prosecutors and for technology grants.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
