<bill session="110" type="s" number="3682" updated="2009-01-09T19:33:01-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1222920000" datetime="2008-10-02"/></status>

	<introduced date="1222920000" datetime="2008-10-02"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Energy Innovation Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide incentives to small business concerns for innovative energy-efficient technologies and products, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300091"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="2008-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2008-10-02"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1222920000" datetime="2008-10-02"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S10489)</text></action>
		<action date="1222920000" datetime="2008-10-02"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/2/2008--Introduced.<br/>Small Business Energy Innovation Act of 2008 - Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to direct the Secretary of Energy, in consultation with the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA), to make grants and loan guarantees to small business concerns for the development of innovative energy-efficient technologies and products. Amends the Small Business Act to establish in the SBA the position of Director of Energy Innovation to coordinate SBA energy innovation activities and technical assistance programs. Establishes an energy innovation grant program to provide grants, on a competitive basis, to private, nonprofit organizations, including institutions of higher education, that are capable to providing technical assistance relating to renewable and advanced energy efficiency systems, advanced transportation fuels, carbon capture and sequestration practices and technologies, and other energy efficiency technologies. 
	</summary>
</bill>
