<bill session="110" type="s" number="3695" updated="2009-01-09T19:34:41-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1227070800" datetime="2008-11-19"/></status>

	<introduced date="1227070800" datetime="2008-11-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">POWER Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Prisoner Opportunity, Work, and Education Requirement Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require a 50-hour workweek for Federal prison inmates, to reform inmate work programs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300040"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1227070800" datetime="2008-11-19"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/19/2008--Introduced.<br/>Prisoner Opportunity, Work, and Education Requirement Act or the POWER Act - Amends the Crime Control Act of 1990 to require federal prison inmates to: (1) work for not less than 50 hours weekly; and (2) engage in job training and educational and life skills preparation study. Requires Federal Prison Industries (a government corporation) to employ inmates in manufacturing activities by subcontracting with private sector contractors. Requires inmate wages earned in a 50-hour work week program to be used for the costs of incarceration, victim restitution, inmate expenses, and related state and local prisoner programs.<br/>Repeals certain provisions restricting the funding of, and purchase of products from, Federal Prison Industries and prohibiting a public private competition for work performed by employees of the Bureau of Prisons and Federal Prison Industries.<br/>Directs the Attorney General to establish the Foreign Labor Substitute Panel to review pilot projects by U.S. companies for the manufacture of goods by federal convicts that would otherwise be manufactured by foreign labor.<br/>Revises federal criminal code provisions to restate the mission, operating objectives, performance standards, and other requirements for Federal Prison Industries.<br/>Requires the Comptroller General to provide for annual independent evaluations of the operations of Federal Prison Industries and to report to Congress on such evaluations (currently, the Board of Directors of Federal Prison Industries is required to report to Congress). 
	</summary>
</bill>
