<bill session="110" type="s" number="3691" updated="2009-01-09T19:34:11-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1227070800" datetime="2008-11-19"/></status>

	<introduced date="1227070800" datetime="2008-11-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Financial Regulation Reform Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Commodity Exchange Act to require reporting and recordkeeping for positions involving credit-default swaps, to grant the Federal Reserve Board authority over investment-bank holding companies, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300025"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1227070800" datetime="2008-11-19"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR 11/17/2008 S10549-10550)</text></action>
		<action date="1227070800" datetime="2008-11-19"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/19/2008--Introduced.<br/>Financial Regulation Reform Act of 2008 - Amends the Commodity Exchange Act to: (1) subject credit-default swap trading clearinghouses to regulation by the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC); and (2) direct the CFTC to set reporting and recordkeeping requirements for positions involving credit-default swaps. Grants the Federal Reserve Board authority over investment-bank holding companies. Directs the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to issue final rules to: (1) designate clearinghouses for credit-default swaps; and (2) prohibit fraudulent, deceptive, or manipulative acts or practices in connection with such swaps. Establishes a temporary Commission on Financial Regulatory Reform to review the financial regulatory structure and propose a comprehensive framework for fundamental reform of financial regulation in the United States.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
