<bill session="110" type="s" number="374" updated="2009-01-09T11:55:50-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1169614800" datetime="2007-01-24"/></status>

	<introduced date="1169614800" datetime="2007-01-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Art and Collectibles Capital Gains Tax Treatment Parity Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide the same capital gains treatment for art and collectibles as for other investment property and to provide that a deduction equal to fair market value shall be allowed for charitable contributions of literary, musical, artistic, or scholarly compositions created by the donor.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300036"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300029" joined="2007-01-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300030" joined="2007-01-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2007-01-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="2007-01-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-01-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300003" joined="2007-01-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300099" joined="2007-02-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1169614800" datetime="2007-01-24"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1059-1060)</text></action>
		<action date="1169614800" datetime="2007-01-24"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S1060-1061"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/24/2007--Introduced.<br/>Art and Collectibles Capital Gains Tax Treatment Parity Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) eliminate the 28-percent capital gains tax rate for collectibles, thus allowing gain from the sale of collectibles (including art works) to be taxed at the 15-percent tax rate applicable to other investment property; (2) allow the creator of a literary, musical, artistic, or scholarly property a fair market value tax deduction for the donation of such property to a tax-exempt organization, if properly appraised and donated no sooner than 18 months after its creation. 
	</summary>
</bill>
