<bill session="110" type="s" number="382" updated="2009-01-09T11:56:50-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1169614800" datetime="2007-01-24"/></status>

	<introduced date="1169614800" datetime="2007-01-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Keeping Families Together Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to establish a State family support grant program to end the practice of parents giving legal custody of their seriously emotionally disturbed children to State agencies for the purpose of obtaining mental health services for those children.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300025"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412242" joined="2007-12-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2007-01-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-01-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-01-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300047" joined="2007-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-01-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-01-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300088" joined="2007-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-01-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2007-01-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-03-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300068" joined="2008-09-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="2007-01-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300080" joined="2007-01-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-01-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300084" joined="2007-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2007-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2007-01-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1169614800" datetime="2007-01-24"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1067-1069)</text></action>
		<action date="1169614800" datetime="2007-01-24"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/24/2007--Introduced.<br/>Keeping Families Together Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to allow the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, to award competitive matching grants to states to establish systems of care to treat and provide services to all children who are in the custody of the state or at-risk of entering into the custody of the state for the purpose of receiving mental health services. Requires states to use grant funds for certain activities, including to: (1) expand public health insurance programs to cover community-based mental health and family support services for such children and their families that will be sustainable after the grant has expired; (2) provide outreach and public education concerning available programs and activities; and (3) provide training and professional development for personnel who work with such children. Requires the Administrator to establish a task force to examine: (1) problems of mental health in the child welfare and juvenile justice systems; (2) issues with respect to access by children and youth to mental health services; and (3) the role of federal agencies in promoting access by children and youth to mental health services. 
	</summary>
</bill>
