<bill session="110" type="s" number="390" updated="2009-01-09T11:57:49-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" /></status>

	<introduced date="1169701200" datetime="2007-01-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Utah Recreational Land Exchange Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Utah Recreational Land Exchange Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the exchange of certain land in Grand, San Juan, and Uintah Counties, Utah, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300007"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300052" joined="2007-01-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1169701200" datetime="2007-01-25"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1191-1192)</text></action>
		<action date="1169701200" datetime="2007-01-25"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1178164800" datetime="2007-05-03"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-91.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1221105600" datetime="2008-09-11" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="973" date="1221537600" datetime="2008-09-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 973.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/16/2008--Reported to Senate amended. Utah Recreational Land Exchange Act of 2008 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to convey specified federal land in Grand, San Juan, and Uintah Counties, Utah, to the state of Utah in exchange for specified non-federal land in such counties. Requires the conveyance to be in three phases.<br/>Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) land valuation, appraisal, and equalization; and (2) land administration, including water rights, hazardous materials, oil shale resources, mineral leasing, and revenues.<br/>Requires the conveyance of certain federal land to be subject to a 1,000 foot wide scenic easement and a 200 foot wide road of right-of-way previously granted to the National Park Service (NPS) for the Dinosaur National Monument.<br/>Authorizes appropriations.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
