<bill session="110" type="s" number="409" updated="2009-01-09T12:01:24-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1169787600" datetime="2007-01-26"/></status>

	<introduced date="1169787600" datetime="2007-01-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Water Infrastructure Revitalization Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide environmental assistance to non-Federal interests in the State of North Dakota.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300026"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300037" joined="2007-01-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1169787600" datetime="2007-01-26"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1242)</text></action>
		<action date="1169787600" datetime="2007-01-26"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/26/2007--Introduced.<br/>Water Infrastructure Revitalization Act - Directs the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, to establish a program to provide environmental assistance to non-federal interests in North Dakota, which may be provided in the form of design and construction assistance for water-related environmental infrastructure and resource protection and development projects. Requires projects to be publicly owned as a prerequisite for assistance. Directs the Secretary to enter into local cooperation agreements with non-federal interests for project design and construction. Sets the federal share of project costs under local cooperation agreements at 75%. Requires a reduction in the non-federal share of the cost of constructing projects under this Act, using a federal formula for water rate affordability, where the rate for affordability relating to the project area exceeds the average state-wide rate by a specified percentage. Sets the non-federal share of operation and maintenance costs for projects constructed with assistance under this Act at 100%.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
