<bill session="110" type="s" number="41" updated="2009-01-09T11:12:38-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/></status>

	<introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Research Competitiveness Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide incentives to improve America's research competitiveness, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300005"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2007-01-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-07-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="400619" joined="2007-07-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2008-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300069" joined="2007-06-22" withdrawn="2007-06-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="2008-04-21"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S70-72)</text></action>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/4/2007--Introduced.<br/>Research Competitiveness Act of 2007 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) modify the tax credit for increasing research expenses to establish a standard 20% credit rate for research expenses exceeding 50% of average expenses over the preceding three year period; (2) establish a uniform 80% reimbursement rate for all contract research expenses (100% for basic research payments); (3) make such tax credit permanent; (4) allow a tax credit for equity investments in small business innovation companies; and (5) allow the issuance of tax exempt facility bonds for research park facilities used in connection with research and experimentation.<br/>Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to: (1) study and report to Congress on taxpayer compliance with the substantiation requirements for claiming the tax credit for increasing research activities; and (2) issue regulations on the application of private activity bond rules to the funding of federal research agreements.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
