<bill session="110" type="s" number="426" updated="2009-01-09T12:03:33-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1170046800" datetime="2007-01-29"/></status>

	<introduced date="1170046800" datetime="2007-01-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Biofuels Investment Trust Fund Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide that all funds collected from the tariff on imports of ethanol be invested in the research, development, and deployment of biofuels, especially cellulosic ethanol produced from biomass feedstocks.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300077"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170046800" datetime="2007-01-29"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1292-1293)</text></action>
		<action date="1170046800" datetime="2007-01-29"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S1293"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/29/2007--Introduced.<br/>Biofuels Investment Trust Fund Act - Establishes a Biofuels Investment Trust Fund consisting of transferred amounts received in the U.S. Treasury from duties collected on imports of ethyl alcohol or any mixture containing ethyl alcohol that is to be used as a fuel or in producing a mixture of gasoline and alcohol, a mixture of a special fuel and alcohol, or any other mixture to be used as a fuel (including motor fuel). Directs the Secretary of Energy to use amounts in the Trust Fund to: (1) provide assistance to farmers, producers, biorefiners, researchers, universities, and other persons or entities involved in the research, development, and deployment, or production of biofuels, especially for cellulosic ethanol production; or (2) advance research, development, and deployment of biofuels, especially cellulosic ethanol produced from biomass feedstocks.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
