<bill session="110" type="s" number="427" updated="2009-01-09T12:03:40-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1170133200" datetime="2007-01-30"/></status>

	<introduced date="1170133200" datetime="2007-01-30"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Affordable Housing Expansion and Public Safety Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for additional section 8 vouchers, to reauthorize the Public and Assisted Housing Drug Elimination Program, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300042"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170133200" datetime="2007-01-30"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1328-1331)</text></action>
		<action date="1170133200" datetime="2007-01-30"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S1331-1332"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/30/2007--Introduced.<br/>Affordable Housing Expansion and Public Safety Act - Instructs the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (Secretary) to provide an additional 100,000 incremental vouchers for tenant-based rental housing assistance under the Section 8 Housing Choice Voucher Program in FY2008. Amends the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act to direct: (1) each participating jurisdiction to use Home Investments Partnership (HOME) grant funds to provide affordable housing to individuals or families whose income is 30% or lower than the area median income (extremely low-income); and (2) direct the Secretary to allocate HOME funds to such jurisdictions on a specified pro-rata basis. Amends the Anti-Drug Abuse Act of 1988 to: (1) extend to FY2012 the authorization of appropriations for the Public and Assisted Housing Crime and Drug Elimination Program (PHDEP); (2) set aside specified amounts for the Office of Policy Development and Research; (3) identify activities eligible for grant funds; and (4) require the Office to review research to assess strategies likely to be effective in preventing and reducing violent and drug-related crimes in public and federally assisted low-income housing. Expresses the sense of the Senate that Congress shall create a national affordable housing trust fund to supply 1.5 million additional affordable housing units over the next 10 years, especially for extremely low-income and very low-income families. Repeals multiyear procurement authority for the F-22A Raptor Fighter Aircraft. Prohibits the Secretary of Energy from implementing the advanced research program for fossil fuels.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
