<bill session="110" type="s" number="433" updated="2009-01-09T12:04:29-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1170133200" datetime="2007-01-30"/></status>

	<introduced date="1170133200" datetime="2007-01-30"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="popular" as="">Iraq War Policy bill</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Iraq War De-Escalation Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to state United States policy for Iraq, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400629"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="2007-02-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-02-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170133200" datetime="2007-01-30"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1322, S1343-1344)</text></action>
		<action date="1170133200" datetime="2007-01-30"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/30/2007--Introduced.<br/>Iraq War De-Escalation Act of 2007 - States that: (1) U.S. Armed Forces levels in Iraq after the date of enactment of this Act shall not exceed January 10, 2007, levels without specific statutory authority enacted by Congress after the date of the enactment of this Act; and (2) except as otherwise provided, the phased redeployment of U.S. Armed Forces from Iraq shall begin by May 1, 2007. Authorizes the President to temporarily suspend such redeployment upon certification to Congress that: (1) such action is in the U.S. national interest; and (2) the government of Iraq is taking specified actions. Resumes redeployment if Congress enacts a joint resolution disapproving such suspension or suspension renewal. Authorizes, upon certification by the President to Congress, post-deployment retention of certain forces in Iraq to: (1) protect U.S. personnel and facilities; (2) conduct targeted counter-terrorism operations; (3) provide training for Iraqi security forces; and (4) conduct Office of Defense Attache functions. Terminates retention if Congress enacts a joint resolution disapproving such retention. Reaffirms provisions prohibiting the establishment of bases or installations providing for the permanent stationing of U.S. forces in Iraq. States that it shall be U.S. policy to: (1) implement a plan to intensify training of Iraqi security forces; and (2) undertake diplomatic initiatives to restore peace in Iraq and prevent a regional conflict. Conditions continued economic assistance (with exceptions for humanitarian, employment, and security assistance) to the government of Iraq after May 1, 2007, upon the President certifying to Congress that the government of Iraq is taking specified actions with respect to economic improvements and reducing sectarian violence.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
