<bill session="110" type="s" number="442" updated="2009-01-09T12:05:41-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01" /></status>

	<introduced date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">John R. Justice Prosecutors and Defenders Incentive Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">John R. Justice Prosecutors and Defenders Incentive Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for loan repayment for prosecutors and public defenders.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300038"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="2007-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300005" joined="2007-06-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-02-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300008" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="2007-02-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-02-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400619" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400621" joined="2007-05-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2007-02-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300061" joined="2007-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300092" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2007-02-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="2007-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300080" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300001" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="412243" joined="2007-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300078" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2007-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300036" joined="2007-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2007-02-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2007-12-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300090" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="2007-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2007-05-02"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1413-1415)</text></action>
		<action date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S1415"/></action>
		<action date="1172552400" datetime="2007-02-27"><text>Committee on the Judiciary. Hearings held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01" ><text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1176177600" datetime="2007-04-10"><text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Leahy with amendments. With written report No. 110-51. Additional views filed.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="113" date="1176177600" datetime="2007-04-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 113.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/10/2007--Reported to Senate amended. John R. Justice Prosecutors and Defenders Incentive Act of 2007 - Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to add a program for student loan repayment for prosecutors and public defenders. Defines &quot;prosecutor&quot; and &quot;public defenders&quot; to include individuals engaged in the supervision, education, or training of other prosecutors and public defenders. Includes within the definition of &quot;public defender&quot; full-time employees of nonprofit organizations who devote substantially all their time providing indigent criminal defense services and federal public defenders. Requires prosecutors and public defenders to prosecute or provide representation for juvenile delinquency cases.<br/>Directs the Attorney General to establish a program to assume the obligation to repay the student loans of any borrowers who are employed as prosecutors or public defenders and are not in default on their loans. Sets forth requirements for such program, including that: (1) the borrower will remain employed as a prosecutor or public defender for not less than three years; and (2) the borrower will repay to the Attorney General any repayment benefits received if the borrower is fired from employment for misconduct or voluntarily separates from employment.<br/>Limits the amount payable under such program to $10,000 per year for any borrower and to an aggregate total of $60,000 for any borrower.<br/>Authorizes the Attorney General to enter into subsequent agreements with a borrower for another three-year period or a lesser period.<br/>Requires the Attorney General to give priority in granting repayment benefits to borrowers who have the least ability to repay their loans.<br/>Authorizes the Attorney General to issue regulations to carry out this Act.<br/>Directs the Government Accountability Office to study and report to Congress on the impact of law school accreditation requirements and other factors on law school costs and access, including the impact of such requirements on racial and ethnic minorities.<br/>Authorizes appropriations. 
	</summary>
</bill>
