<bill session="110" type="s" number="451" updated="2009-01-09T12:07:00-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"/></status>

	<introduced date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Foreign Language Coordination Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a National Foreign Language Coordination Council.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300001"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="2007-01-31"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1425-1426)</text></action>
		<action date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S1426-1427"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/31/2007--Introduced.<br/>National Foreign Language Coordination Act of 2007 - Establishes, in the Executive Office of the President, a National Foreign Language Coordination Council to: (1) oversee and implement the National Security Language Initiative (NSLI); and (2) develop and implement a national foreign language strategy. Includes heads of certain federal agencies as members of the Council. Establishes a National Language Director, to be appointed by the President, to: (1) chair the Council; (2) develop and monitor implementation of the strategy, built upon the efforts of the NSLI; (3) establish formal relationships among major stakeholders, including federal, state, and local government agencies, academia, industry, labor, and heritage communities; and (4) coordinate and lead a public information campaign. Requires the Council to consult with states to provide for designation of state contact persons. Encourages formation of state interagency councils, or designation of state lead agencies, to coordinate with the Council and state and local agencies.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
