<bill session="110" type="s" number="459" updated="2009-01-09T12:08:06-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"/></status>

	<introduced date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Breast Cancer Patient Protection Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require that health plans provide coverage for a minimum hospital stay for mastectomies, lumpectomies, and lymph node dissection for the treatment of breast cancer and coverage for secondary consultations.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300091"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412242" joined="2007-03-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2008-09-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2007-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2007-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2007-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2007-01-31"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170219600" datetime="2007-01-31"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/31/2007--Introduced.<br/>Breast Cancer Patient Protect Action of 2007 - Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA), the Public Health Service Act, and the Internal Revenue Code to require a group health plan or a health issuer offering group health insurance coverage that provides medical and surgical benefits to ensure that inpatient (and in the case of a lumpectomy, outpatient) coverage and radiation therapy are provided for breast cancer treatment. Prohibits such a plan or issuer from: (1) restricting benefits for any hospital length of stay to less than 48 hours in connection with a mastectomy or breast conserving surgery or 24 hours in connection with a lymph node dissection; or (2) requiring that a provider obtain authorization from the plan or issuer for prescribing any such length of stay. Requires such a plan or issuer to: (1) provide notice to each participant and beneficiary regarding the coverage required under this Act; and (2) ensure that full coverage is provided for secondary consultations by specialists in the appropriate medical fields to confirm or refute a diagnosis of cancer. Applies such requirements to health insurance issuers offering coverage in the individual market.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
