<bill session="110" type="s" number="47" updated="2009-01-09T11:13:23-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/></status>

	<introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Law Enforcement Assistance Force Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">LEAF Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a Law Enforcement Assistance Force in the Department of Homeland Security to facilitate the contributions of retired law enforcement officers during major disasters.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300040"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400194" joined="2007-01-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1169096400" datetime="2007-01-18"><text>Star Print ordered on the bill.</text></action>
		<action date="1175227200" datetime="2007-03-30"><text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs referred to Subcommittee on State, Local, and Private Sector Preparedness and Integration.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/4/2007--Introduced.<br/>Law Enforcement Assistance Force Act of 2007 or the LEAF Act - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish a Law Enforcement Assistance Force (Force) to facilitate the contributions of retired law enforcement officers and agents during major disasters. Outlines Force eligibility requirements. Authorizes the Secretary to request eligible participants to assist efforts of federal, state, or local government law enforcement agencies in responding to such disasters.<br/>Requires a participant to remain in an assignment for the lesser of: (1) the period during which the law enforcement agency needs such services; or (2) 30 days.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
