<bill session="110" type="s" number="489" updated="2009-01-09T12:11:59-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1170651600" datetime="2007-02-05"/></status>

	<introduced date="1170651600" datetime="2007-02-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Green Buildings Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve efficiency in the Federal Government through the use of green buildings, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300099"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170651600" datetime="2007-02-05"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1577-1578)</text></action>
		<action date="1170651600" datetime="2007-02-05"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/5/2007--Introduced.<br/>Green Buildings Act of 2007 - Directs the Administrator of General Services to establish a position of, and appoint, a Director who shall: (1) establish an Office of Green Buildings (2) establish a Green Building Advisory Committee; (2) carry out public outreach; (3) develop and recommend a green building research plan; (4) analyze current budget and contracting practices that affect achievement of green buildings; and (5) develop and implement a comprehensive indoor air quality program for federal facilities. Defines a &quot;green building&quot; as one that, during its life-cycle: (1) reduces energy, water, and material resource use and the generation of waste; (2) improves indoor environmental quality; (3) improves impacts of the building on human health and the environment; (4) increases the use of environmentally preferable products; (5) increases reuse and recycling opportunities; and (6) integrates systems in the building.<br/>Authorizes the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to provide grants to state educational agencies for use in: (1) providing technical assistance for EPA's programs (including the Tools for Schools Program and the Healthy School Environmental Assessment Tool) to schools for use in addressing environmental issues; and (2) developing state school environmental quality plans. Authorizes the EPA to provide grants to nonprofit organizations to assist in community and public education on healthy school environments.<br/>Requires the EPA to develop voluntary school site acquisition guidelines that account for: (1) efficient use of energy; (2) the special vulnerability of children to hazardous substances or pollution exposure where the potential for site contamination exists; (3) available modes of transportation; and (4) potential use of the school as an emergency shelter.<br/>Requires the Director to: (1) identify incentives to encourage the use of green buildings and related technology in federal government operations; and (2) consult with the Committee to assist in the implementation of the Environmental Stewardship Scorecard.<br/>Requires the Office to carry out specified demonstration projects at federal buildings and universities to contribute to its research goals.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
