<bill session="110" type="s" number="492" updated="2009-01-09T12:12:22-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1170738000" datetime="2007-02-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1170738000" datetime="2007-02-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Somalia Stabilization and Reconstruction Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote stabilization and reconstruction efforts in Somalia, to establish a Special Envoy for Somalia to strengthen United States support to the people of Somalia in their efforts to establish a lasting peace and form a democratically elected and stable central government, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300042"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412242" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-02-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300050" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300095" joined="2007-03-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170738000" datetime="2007-02-06"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/6/2007--Introduced.<br/>Somalia Stabilization and Reconstruction Act of 2007 - States that it is U.S. policy to support efforts by the people of Somalia to achieve peace, economic growth, and democracy, and to eradicate extremism and terrorism from their country and region. Directs the President to: (1) appoint a Special Envoy for Somalia to coordinate U.S. involvement in the region and to ensure that the U.S. government remains informed of and engaged in efforts to resolve the instability in Somalia; and (2) instruct the U.S. Permanent Representative to the United Nations to work with the appropriate U.N. agencies, regional organizations, nongovernmental organizations, and the international community to establish an International Donor Trust Fund for Somalia. Authorizes the President to: (1) support a regional or international peacekeeping force for Somalia; and (2) provide assistance to support efforts for a peaceful resolution of the conflict in Somalia as well as the establishment of a representative government in Somalia. Directs the Secretary of State to convene one or more donor conferences for Somalia. Restricts foreign assistance to countries identified as providing assistance to individuals or entities seeking to prevent the formation of a government of national unity in Somalia or harm U.S. interests.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
