<bill session="110" type="s" number="51" updated="2009-01-09T11:13:56-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/></status>

	<introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="popular" as="">Stem Cell Research bill</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Pluripotent Stem Cell Therapy Enhancement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to derive human pluripotent stem cell lines using techniques that do not knowingly harm embryos.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400194"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/4/2007--Introduced.<br/>Pluripotent Stem Cell Therapy Enhancement Act of 2007 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to develop techniques for the isolation, derivation, production, or testing of pluripotent stem cells that have the flexibility of embryonic stem cells (whether or not they have an embryonic source) and that may result in improved understanding of, or treatments for, diseases and other adverse health conditions, provided that such techniques do not involve: (1) the creation of a viable human embryo for research purposes; or (2) the destruction or discarding of a human embryo or embryos; or (3) knowingly subjecting a human embryo or embryos to risk of injury or death greater than that allowed for federal research on fetuses in utero under current law. Requires the Secretary to: (1) provide guidance concerning the next steps required for additional research; (2) prioritize research with the greatest potential for near-term clinical benefit; and (3) take into account techniques outlined by the President's Council on Bioethics and any other appropriate techniques and research.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
