<bill session="110" type="s" number="522" updated="2009-01-09T12:16:21-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"/></status>

	<introduced date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Intellectual Property Rights Enforcement Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to safeguard the economic health of the United States and the health and safety of the United States citizens by improving the management, coordination, and effectiveness of domestic and international intellectual property rights enforcement, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300006"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300008" joined="2007-12-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2007-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300098" joined="2007-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="2007-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2007-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="300037" joined="2007-07-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="2007-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300054" joined="2008-03-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-03-29" withdrawn="2007-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300049" joined="2007-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2007-05-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170824400" datetime="2007-02-07"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1194411600" datetime="2007-11-07"><text>Committee on the Judiciary. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/7/2007--Introduced.<br/>Intellectual Property Rights Enforcement Act - Amends the Treasury and General Government Appropriations Act, 2000 to repeal provisions establishing the National Intellectual Property Law Enforcement Coordination Council.<br/>Establishes the Intellectual Property Enforcement Network (IPEN), consisting of specified representatives of various government agencies, to: (1) establish policies, objectives, and priorities concerning international intellectual property protection and law enforcement; (2) coordinate and facilitate implementation of such policies, objectives, and priorities; and (3) protect U.S. intellectual property rights overseas, including by creating an international task force.<br/>Requires the agencies in IPEN to: (1) share the information they collect; (2) coordinate civil and criminal actions related to intellectual property rights; (3) establish formal processes for consulting and working with state and local government agencies and consulting with companies, writers, artists, labor unions, and other interested persons and groups; and (4) consult with the Register of Copyrights on law enforcement matters.<br/>Urges the President and relevant agency officers, when meeting with certain foreign countries, to stress the importance of establishing and participating in the international task force.<br/>Requires the Director of the Office of Mangement and Budget and the Coordinator of IPEN to submit to the President and the relevant congressional committees a strategic plan, which includes the goals, objectives, and priorities of IPEN.<br/>Calls for other government intellectual property initiatives to be consolidated into the work of IPEN to prevent duplication.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
