<bill session="110" type="s" number="542" updated="2009-01-09T12:18:56-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23" /></status>

	<introduced date="1170910800" datetime="2007-02-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to conduct feasibility studies to address certain water shortages within the Snake, Boise, and Payette River systems in the State of Idaho, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300029"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170910800" datetime="2007-02-08"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1808)</text></action>
		<action date="1170910800" datetime="2007-02-08"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S1808"/></action>
		<action date="1177473600" datetime="2007-04-25"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-86.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. With written report No. 110-113.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="246" date="1183003200" datetime="2007-06-28" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 246.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/28/2007--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.) Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Reclamation, to conduct feasibility studies to on projects that address water shortages within the Snake, Boise, and Payette River systems in Idaho and that are considered appropriate for further study by the Bureau of Reclamation water storage assessment report issued during 2006. Requires that such study comply with Bureau of Reclamation policy standards and guidelines for studies. Authorizes appropriations. Terminates the authority provided by this Act ten years after the enactment of this Act. 
	</summary>
</bill>
