<bill session="110" type="s" number="559" updated="2009-01-09T12:21:10-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"/></status>

	<introduced date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Vote Integrity and Verification Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to require a voter-verified permanent paper ballot under title III of such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300078"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1903-1904)</text></action>
		<action date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/13/2007--Introduced.<br/>Vote Integrity and Verification Act of 2007 - Amends the Help America Vote Act of 2002 (HAVA) with respect to: (1) ballot verification and mandatory paper record audit capacity; and (2) accessibility and ballot verification of results for individuals with disabilities.<br/>Requires the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology to study, test, and develop best practices to enhance the accessibility of ballot verification mechanisms for individuals with disabilities, voters whose primary language is not English, and voters with difficulties in literacy.<br/>Requires laboratories to meet standards prohibiting conflicts of interest as a condition of accreditation for the testing of voting system hardware and software.<br/>Outlines additional voting system requirements and prohibitions.<br/>Extends the authorization of the Election Assistance Commission (EAC).<br/>Provides for complaints to the Attorney General by persons aggrieved by violations of HAVA.<br/>Makes available additional funding to enable states to meet the costs of the requirements imposed by this Act. Directs the chief auditor of each state to appoint an Election Audit Board to administer, without advance notice to the precincts selected, random hand counts of the voter-verified paper ballots required to be produced and preserved for each such election held in the state. Makes it unlawful for a chief state election administration official to take an active part in political management or in a political campaign with respect to any federal election over which such official has supervisory authority. Repeals the exemption of the EAC from certain government contracting requirements.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
