<bill session="110" type="s" number="565" updated="2009-01-09T12:21:56-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"/></status>

	<introduced date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Next Generation Hispanic-Serving Institutions Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to expand and enhance postbaccalaureate opportunities at Hispanic-serving institutions, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300009"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400619" joined="2007-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400621" joined="2007-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300054" joined="2007-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300027" joined="2007-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300078" joined="2007-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2007-02-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1910-1911)</text></action>
		<action date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S1911"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/13/2007--Introduced.<br/>Next Generation Hispanic-Serving Institutions Act - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to revise requirements for Hispanic-serving institutions (HSIs) under title V (Developing Institutions). Establishes a program of competitive grants to eligible HSIs that offer postbaccalaureate certifications or degrees (part B grants). Limits a part B grant award's duration to not more than five years. Prohibits the Secretary of Education from awarding more than one part B grant to an HSI in any one fiscal year. Authorizes appropriations for: (1) the current part A program of grants to HSIs that offer baccalaureate degrees or are junior or community colleges; and (2) the new part B program of grants to HSIs that offer postbaccalaureate certifications or degrees.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
