<bill session="110" type="s" number="567" updated="2009-01-09T12:22:12-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"/></status>

	<introduced date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="popular" as="">Authorization bill FY2008, Defense</title>
		<title type="popular" as="">Defense Department FY2008 Authorization bill</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2008 for military activities of the Department of Defense, to prescribe military personnel strengths for fiscal year 2008, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300066"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300071" joined="2007-02-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1911-1912)</text></action>
		<action date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/13/2007--Introduced.<br/>National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008 - Authorizes appropriations for the Department of Defense (DOD) for FY2008 for military operations and military construction. Authorizes appropriations to DOD for: (1) procurement, including aircraft, missiles, weapons and tracked combat vehicles, ammunition, shipbuilding and conversion, and other procurement; (2) the Rapid Acquisition Fund and the Joint Improvised Explosive Device Defeat Fund; (3) research, development, test, and evaluation, including ballistic missile defense; (4) operation and maintenance, including defense working capital funds, the defense health program, chemical agents and munitions destruction, and environmental restoration; (5) active and reserve military personnel, including end strengths; and (6) increased costs due to the Global War on Terror for military activities and military construction. Sets forth provisions or requirements concerning: (1) active and reserve military personnel, including officer personnel policy; (2) military education and training, including military justice and defense dependents' education; (3) military pay and allowances; (4) retired pay and survivor benefits, including Survivor Benefit Plan (SBP) matters; (5) military health care; (6) acquisition policy and management; (7) DOD organization and management, including intelligence-related matters; (8) financial, counterdrug, and homeland security matters; (9) civilian personnel matters; and (10) matters relating to other nations, including nonproliferation. Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2007[sic] - (Text to be submitted at a later date.)<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
