<bill session="110" type="s" number="569" updated="2009-01-09T12:22:28-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"/></status>

	<introduced date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Vaccines for the Future Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to accelerate efforts to develop vaccines for diseases primarily affecting developing countries and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300070"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="2007-05-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1912)</text></action>
		<action date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S1912-1913"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/13/2007--Introduced.<br/>Vaccines for the Future Act of 2007 - Directs the President to establish a comprehensive strategy to accelerate efforts to develop vaccines and microbicides for neglected diseases such as HIV/AIDS, malaria, and tuberculosis. States that such strategy shall: (1) expand public-private partnerships and seek to leverage foreign country and private sector resources; (2) include the negotiation of advance market commitments and other economic incentives for the research, development, and manufacturing of vaccines and microbicides for HIV/AIDS, tuberculosis, malaria, and other neglected diseases; (3) address related intellectual property and regulatory issues; (4) maximize U.S. capabilities to support clinical trials of vaccines and microbicides in developing countries; and (5) expand the purchase and delivery of existing vaccines. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to enter into negotiations with the World Bank, the International Development Association, the GAVI Alliance, such entities' member nations, and other interested parties to establish advance market commitments to purchase vaccines and microbicides to combat neglected diseases. (Defines &quot;GAVI Alliance&quot; as the public-private partnership launched in 2000 for the purpose of saving children and protecting all people through the widespread use of vaccines.)<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
