<bill session="110" type="s" number="570" updated="2009-01-09T12:22:36-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1210132800" datetime="2008-05-07" /></status>

	<introduced date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Virginia Ridge and Valley Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Virginia Ridge and Valley Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to designate additional National Forest System lands in the State of Virginia as wilderness or a wilderness study area, to designate the Kimberling Creek Potential Wilderness Area for eventual incorporation in the Kimberling Creek Wilderness, to establish the Seng Mountain and Bear Creek Scenic Areas, to provide for the development of trail plans for the wilderness areas and scenic areas, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300099"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412249" joined="2007-02-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1913-1914)</text></action>
		<action date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1208232000" datetime="2008-04-15"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-485.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1210132800" datetime="2008-05-07" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1213588800" datetime="2008-06-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 110-349.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="781" date="1213588800" datetime="2008-06-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 781.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/16/2008--Reported to Senate amended. Virginia Ridge and Valley Act of 2008 - Designates certain lands in the Jefferson National Forest, Virginia (Brush Mountain and Brush Mountain East, Seng Mountain and Raccoon Branch, Stone Mountain, Hunting Camp Creek and Garden Mountain, Mountain Lake Additions, Lewis Fork Addition and Little Wilson Creek Additions, Shawvers Run Additions, Peters Mountain Addition, and Kimberling Creek Additions) as wilderness. Designates certain lands in the Jefferson National Forest as: (1) the &quot;Lynn Camp Creek Wilderness Study Area&quot;; and (2) the &quot;Kimberling Creek Potential Wilderness Area&quot; for incorporation in the Kimberling Creek Wilderness. Sets forth requirements regarding ecological restoration in the Kimberling Creek Potential Wilderness Area. Specifies that the potential wilderness area be designated as wilderness and included in Kimberling Creek Wilderness on the earlier of: (1) the date on which the Secretary of Agriculture publishes in the Federal Register notice that the conditions in such Area that are incompatible with the Wilderness Act have been removed; or (2) five years after enactment of this Act. Designates Seng Mountain and Raccoon Branch, and Bear Creek, as National Scenic Areas (Scenic Areas). States that the purposes of such Areas are to: (1) ensure the protection and preservation of scenic quality, water quality, natural characteristics, and water resources; (2) protect wildlife and fish habitat; (3) protect areas that may develop characteristics of old-growth forests; and (4) provide a variety of recreation opportunities. Authorizes the Secretary to only allow such uses of the Scenic Areas as will further such purposes. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to develop a management plan for the Scenic Areas. Sets forth provisions regarding roads, timber harvesting, insect and disease outbreaks, vegetation management, motorized vehicles, wildfire suppression, and water quality. Withdraws all federal land in the Scenic Areas from: (1) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and (2) operation of the mineral leasing and geothermal leasing laws. Directs the Secretary to establish a trail plan to develop hiking and equestrian trails on the lands in Jefferson National Forest designated as wilderness by this Act and non-motorized recreation trails within the Scenic Areas. Instructs the Secretary to establish the trail plan in consultation with interested parties. Requires the Secretary to report on the implementation of such plan, including the identification of priority trails for development. Directs the Secretary to develop a specified sustainable trail along the southern boundary of the Raccoon Branch Wilderness connecting to forest development road 49352 in Smyth County. 
	</summary>
</bill>
