<bill session="110" type="s" number="572" updated="2009-01-09T12:22:52-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"/></status>

	<introduced date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Student Aid Reward Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure that Federal student loans are delivered as efficiently as possible in order to provide more grant aid to students.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300059"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300090" joined="2007-02-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1914-1915)</text></action>
		<action date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S1915"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/13/2007--Introduced.<br/>Student Aid Reward Act of 2007 - Amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of Education to carry out a Student Aid Reward (SAR) Program of payments to encourage institutions of higher education (IHEs) to participate in the student loan program under title IV that is most cost-effective for taxpayers. Requires that a SAR payment to an IHE equal at least 50% of the savings to the federal government generated by the IHE's participation in the most cost-effective student loan program, rather than one not cost-effective for taxpayers. Requires IHEs receiving SAR payments to: (1) provide student loans under that most cost-effective program for five years after the payment date; and (2) use payment funds, where appropriate, to supplement student Pell Grants. Allows such funds to be used also to award need-based grants to lower and middle income graduate students.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
