<bill session="110" type="s" number="575" updated="2009-01-09T12:23:16-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"/></status>

	<introduced date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Border Infrastructure and Technology Modernization Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize appropriations for border and transportation security personnel and technology, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300036"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300037" joined="2007-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300062" joined="2007-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300054" joined="2007-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300027" joined="2007-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-02-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1916)</text></action>
		<action date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S1916-1918"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/13/2007--Introduced.<br/>Border Infrastructure and Technology Modernization Act of 2007 - Directs the Under Secretary for Border and Transportation Security (Under Secretary) of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to: (1) increase, during FY2008-FY2012, the number of agents and inspectors in the Bureau of Immigration and Customs Enforcement of the DHS; and (2) provide such agents and inspectors new technology training to a level of proficiency acceptable to protect U.S. borders. Directs the Administrator of the General Services Administration (GSA) to update, and submit to Congress, the Port of Entry Infrastructure Assessment Study. Directs the Under Secretary to prepare annually, and submit to Congress, a National Land Border Security Plan that includes a vulnerability assessment of each port of entry located on the U.S. northern and southern borders. Authorizes the Under Secretary to establish one or more port security coordinators at such ports of entry. Directs the Commissioner of the United States Customs and Border Protection of the DHS to: (1) develop a plan to expand Customs-Trade Partnership Against Terrorism programs along the U.S. northern and southern borders; and (2) establish a demonstration program to develop a cooperative trade security system to improve supply chain security. Directs the Under Secretary to carry out a technology demonstration program to test and evaluate new port of entry technologies that enhance port of entry inspections and the detection of weapons of mass destruction, and to train personnel in its use.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
