<bill session="110" type="s" number="576" updated="2009-01-09T12:23:23-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"/></status>

	<introduced date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Restoring the Constitution Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the effective prosecution of terrorists and guarantee due process rights.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300034"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="2007-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2007-03-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-02-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-02-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="2007-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2007-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="2007-03-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-03-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="2007-06-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2007-02-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1918-1919)</text></action>
		<action date="1171342800" datetime="2007-02-13"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
		<action date="1190001600" datetime="2007-09-17"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S11563)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/13/2007--Introduced.<br/>Restoring the Constitution Act of 2007 - Amends federal provisions concerning the prosecution of unlawful enemy combatants by U.S. military commissions to, among other things: (1) repeal the authority for civilian trial (prosecution) counsel in a commission proceeding, but authorize civilian military defense counsel; (2) exclude statements made by coercion; (3) authorize the Secretary of Defense to make exceptions to commission procedures and rules of evidence as required by unique circumstances of military or intelligence operations during hostilities; (4) provide for self-representation by the accused, while requiring assistance by military defense counsel; (5) authorize the military judge to order trial counsel to disclose to defense counsel the sources, methods, or activities in which witnesses or evidence against the accused was obtained; (6) require commission decision review by the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Armed Forces rather than by the Court of Military Commission Review; (7) provide the scope of review of detention-related decisions; (8) repeal a provision of the Military Commissions Act of 2006 prohibiting invoking the Geneva Conventions (Conventions) or similar protocols in any habeas corpus or other action to which the United States is a party; (9) require the President to notify other parties to the Conventions that the United States expects members of U.S. Armed Forces and other U.S. citizens detained in a conflict not of an international character to be treated in a manner consistent with the Conventions; (10) include as War Crime offenses the denial of trial rights and the imposition of cruel, inhuman, or degrading treatment or punishment; (11) restore habeas corpus for individuals detained by the United States; and (12) provide for expedited judicial review of civil actions that challenges any provision of the Military Commissions Act of 2006.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
