<bill session="110" type="s" number="580" updated="2009-01-09T12:23:54-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23" /></status>

	<introduced date="1171429200" datetime="2007-02-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the National Trails System Act to require the Secretary of the Interior to update the feasibility and suitability studies of four national historic trails, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300052"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300007" joined="2007-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300083" joined="2007-08-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1171429200" datetime="2007-02-14"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1962)</text></action>
		<action date="1171429200" datetime="2007-02-14"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S1962-1963"/></action>
		<action date="1177560000" datetime="2007-04-26"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-88.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. With written report No. 110-95.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="225" date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 225.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/26/2007--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Amends the National Trails System Act to direct the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) revise the feasibility and suitability studies for certain existing National Historic Trails for consideration of possible additions to such trails; and (2) study the feasibility and suitability of designating certain routes and cutoffs as components of the Oregon, Pony Express, California, and Mormon Pioneer National Historic Trails and as shared components of the California and Oregon National Historic Trails. 
	</summary>
</bill>
