<bill session="110" type="s" number="586" updated="2009-01-09T12:26:38-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1171429200" datetime="2007-02-14"/></status>

	<introduced date="1171429200" datetime="2007-02-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Community Health Workers Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to provide grants to promote positive health behaviors in women and children.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300009"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-08-02"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1171429200" datetime="2007-02-14"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1966-1967)</text></action>
		<action date="1171429200" datetime="2007-02-14"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S1967-1968"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/14/2007--Introduced.<br/>Community Health Workers Act of 2007 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to award grants to promote positive health behaviors for women and children in target populations, especially racial and ethnic minority women and children in medically underserved communities. Permits such funds to be used to support community health workers to: (1) educate, guide, and provide outreach regarding health problems among women and children, especially among racial and ethnic minority women and children; (2) educate, guide, and provide experiential learning opportunities that target behavioral risk factors, including poor nutrition and tobacco use; (3) educate and guide regarding effective strategies to promote positive health behaviors within the family; (4) educate and provide outreach regarding enrollment in health insurance; (5) promote community wellness and awareness; and (6) educate and refer target populations to appropriate health care agencies and community based programs and organizations. Requires the Secretary to give priority to experienced applicants who propose to target geographic areas: (1) with a high percentage of uninsured or underinsured residents who are eligible for health insurance; (2) with a high percentage of families for whom English is not their primary language; and (3) that encompass the United States-Mexico border region. Requires the Secretary to: (1) encourage community health worker programs to collaborate with academic institutions; and (2) establish guidelines for assuring the quality of the training and supervision of community health workers under programs funded under this Act and for assuring the cost-effectiveness of such programs.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
