<bill session="110" type="s" number="60" updated="2009-01-09T11:15:02-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/></status>

	<introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Wakefield Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to provide a means for continued improvement in emergency medical services for children.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300056"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-05-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-11-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300052" joined="2007-05-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300037" joined="2007-05-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-09-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300001" joined="2007-05-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2008-07-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2008-01-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2008-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300026" joined="2007-05-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S78-79)</text></action>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S79"/></action>
		<action date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23"><text>Star Print ordered on the bill.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/4/2007--Introduced.<br/>Wakefield Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to extend by one year the length of time for which a grant may be awarded under the emergency medical services for children grant program, which allows the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to states or schools of medicine to support projects to expand and improve emergency medical services for children who need treatment for trauma or critical care. Sets forth as the purpose of the program the reduction of child and youth morbidity and mortality by supporting improvements in the quality of all emergency medical care children receive. Requires the Secretary to support emergency medical services for children by supporting projects that: (1) develop and present scientific evidence; (2) promote existing innovative technologies appropriate for the care of children; and (3) provide information on health outcomes and effectiveness and cost-effectiveness. Directs that such program: (1) strive to enhance the pediatric capability of emergency medical service systems; and (2) be coordinated with all research, evaluations, and awards undertaken by the federal government related to emergency medical services for children.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
