<bill session="110" type="s" number="606" updated="2009-01-09T12:29:14-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Honest Leadership and Accountability in Contracting Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve Federal contracting and procurement by eliminating fraud and abuse and improving competition in contracting and procurement and by enhancing administration of Federal contracting personnel, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300037"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300082" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300080" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300078" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300006" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300026" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2007-02-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S6330-6331"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/15/2007--Introduced.<br/>Honest Leadership and Accountability in Contracting Act of 2007 - Amends the federal criminal code to impose fines and penalties on war profiteering and fraud. Requires revision of the Federal Acquisition Regulation (FAR) to provide that no prospective contractor shall be considered to have a satisfactory record of integrity and ethics if it has a pattern of either overcharging the government or failing to comply with the law. Provides for the disclosure to Congress of audit reports issued by executive agencies. Requires the Federal Procurement Data System to be modified to include publication of information on specified federal contractor penalties and violations. Amends the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949 to prohibit awarding of certain monopoly federal contracts. Requires revision of the FAR to require competition for certain multiple award contracts. Denies protest rights for certain awards. Prohibits an agency from contracting for the performance of: (1) any inherently governmental function; or (2) acquisition functions closely associated with inherently governmental functions. Prescribes minimum requirements for political appointees holding public contracting and safety positions. Includes as a protected disclosure by a federal employee: (1) any lawful disclosure an employee or applicant reasonably believes is credible evidence of waste, abuse, or gross mismanagement, without restriction as to time, place, form, motive, context, or prior disclosure; and (2) the disclosure of information required to be kept secret in the interest of national defense or the conduct of foreign affairs that the employee or applicant reasonably believes is direct evidence of waste, abuse, or gross mismanagement if such disclosure is made to a Member or employee of Congress who is authorized to receive information of the type disclosed. Sets forth provisions concerning review and appeal of actions concerning such disclosures. Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to provide that, for purposes of provisions regarding the protection of voluntarily shared critical infrastructure information, a permissible use of independently obtained critical infrastructure information includes any lawful disclosure an employee or applicant reasonably believes is credible evidence of waste, fraud, abuse, or gross mismanagement, without restriction as to time, place, form, motive, context, or prior disclosure. Requires agencies to inform employees on how to make a lawful disclosure of information. 
	</summary>
</bill>
