<bill session="110" type="s" number="613" updated="2009-01-09T12:30:08-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1175054400" datetime="2007-03-28" /></status>

	<introduced date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Reconstruction and Stabilization Civilian Management Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Reconstruction and Stabilization Civilian Management Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enhance the overseas stabilization and reconstruction capabilities of the United States Government, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300070"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300008" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400621" joined="2008-04-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2008-03-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300050" joined="2007-03-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300095" joined="2008-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300099" joined="2007-03-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2039-2040)</text></action>
		<action date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S2040-2042"/></action>
		<calendar date="1175054400" datetime="2007-03-28" ><text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1176177600" datetime="2007-04-10"><text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Biden without amendment. With written report No. 110-50.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="112" date="1176177600" datetime="2007-04-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 112.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/10/2007--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.) Reconstruction and Stabilization Civilian Management Act of 2007 - (Sec. 2) States that the purpose of this Act is to provide for the development, as a core mission of the Department of State and the United States Agency for International Development (USAID), of an expert civilian response capability to carry out stabilization and reconstruction activities in a country or region that is in, or is in transition from, conflict or civil strife. (Sec. 5) Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to authorize the President to furnish assistance to help stabilize and reconstruct a country or region that is in, or is in transition from, conflict or civil strife. Authorizes funds to be transferred or reprogrammed for expenses related to the development, training, and operations of the Response Readiness Corps. Authorizes appropriations for: (1) assistance; and (2) replenishment of funds. (Sec. 6) Amends the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 to establish within the Department an Office of the Coordinator for Reconstruction and Stabilization. Sets forth Office functions. (Sec. 7) Authorizes the Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator of USAID, to establish a Response Readiness Corps to provide stabilization and reconstruction activities in foreign countries or regions that are at risk of, in, or are in transition from, conflict or civil strife. Provides that the Corps shall have: (1) an active federal component of up to 250 personnel and a standby federal component of up to 2000 personnel; and (2) a non-federal Civilian Reserve of at least 500 personnel (which may include federal retirees). Directs the Secretary to report to the appropriate congressional committees on the status of efforts to establish the Corps. (Sec. 8) Amend the Foreign Service Act to authorize the Secretary, in cooperation with the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of the Army, to establish a stabilization and reconstruction curriculum for use in programs of the Foreign Service Institute, the National Defense University, and the United States Army War College. Sets forth curriculum content. (Sec. 9) Sets forth training and promotion provisions. (Sec. 10) Sets forth personnel provisions. (Sec. 11) Authorizes appropriations.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
