<bill session="110" type="s" number="615" updated="2009-01-09T12:30:23-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">September 11 Family Humanitarian Relief and Patriotism Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide the nonimmigrant spouses and children of nonimmigrant aliens who perished in the September 11, 2001, terrorist attacks an opportunity to adjust their status to that of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300064"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300082" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2007-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300013" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2007-03-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S2043"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/15/2007--Introduced.<br/>September 11 Family Humanitarian Relief and Patriotism Act - Provides permanent resident status adjustment for a requesting alien who was on September 10, 2001, the wife, child, or dependent son or daughter of a lawful nonimmigrant alien who died as a result of the September 11, 2001, terrorist attacks against the United States. Authorizes an alien who has been ordered excluded, deported, removed, or ordered to depart voluntarily from the United States to apply for such status adjustment. Provides for cancellation of removal and permanent resident status adjustment for a requesting alien who was: (1) on September 10, 2001, the wife, child, or dependent son or daughter of an alien who died as a result of the September 11, 2001, terrorist attacks against the United States; and (2) deemed to be a beneficiary of the September 11th Victim Compensation Fund of 2001. Makes the provisions of this Act inapplicable to an alien who is: (1) inadmissible or deportable under criminal or security grounds, including September 11, 2001, terrorist activity; or (2) a family member of such an alien.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
