<bill session="110" type="s" number="617" updated="2009-01-09T12:30:38-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1210132800" datetime="2008-05-07" /></status>

	<introduced date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Eagle Parks Pass Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Public Land Military Pass Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to make the National Parks and Federal Recreational Lands Pass available at a discount to certain veterans.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300090"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300029" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2007-10-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400619" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-03-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300054" joined="2007-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2008-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300075" joined="2007-12-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2007-05-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300036" joined="2007-05-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300021" joined="2008-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400054" joined="2008-05-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400194" joined="2007-03-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="2007-07-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2044)</text></action>
		<action date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1184212800" datetime="2007-07-12"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-158.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1210132800" datetime="2008-05-07" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1213588800" datetime="2008-06-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 110-350.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="782" date="1213588800" datetime="2008-06-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 782.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/16/2008--Reported to Senate amended. Public Land Military Pass Act - Makes the National Parks and Federal Recreational Lands Pass, as provided in this Act, available at a discount (subject to the same rate of increase as the regular cost of the Pass) to any veterans and active duty and reserve members of the U.S. Armed Forces determined to be eligible for such a discount. Requires the Secretary of the Interior (with respect to federal land management agencies) and the Secretary of Agriculture (with respect to the Forest Service), after consultation with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs and the Secretary of Defense, to determine the appropriate documentation that a veteran or an active duty or reserve member shall provide as proof that the veteran or member is eligible for the discount. Makes a National Parks and Federal Recreational Lands Pass issued under this Act valid for one year after the date of issuance. 
	</summary>
</bill>
