<bill session="110" type="s" number="627" updated="2009-01-09T12:32:04-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1173931200" datetime="2007-03-15" /></status>

	<introduced date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Safe Babies Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Safe Babies Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 to improve the health and well-being of maltreated infants and toddlers through the creation of a National Court Teams Resource Center, to assist local Court Teams, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300051"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="2007-07-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300008" joined="2007-07-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400621" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2007-03-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300092" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-10-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400418" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300048" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2008-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400194" joined="2007-03-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300090" joined="2007-02-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2076-2077)</text></action>
		<action date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1173931200" datetime="2007-03-15" ><text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1174881600" datetime="2007-03-26"><text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Leahy without amendment. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="88" date="1174881600" datetime="2007-03-26" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 88.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/26/2007--Reported to Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)<br/>Safe Babies Act of 2007 - Amends the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 to require the Administrator of the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention to award a grant to a national early childhood development organization to establish a National Court Teams Resource Center to: (1) promote the well-being of maltreated infants and toddlers and their families; (2) help prevent the recurrence of abuse and neglect of children; (3) promote timely reunification of families or other successful permanency outcomes for maltreated infants and toddlers in foster care; and (4) select, and provide assistance to, local Court Teams created to achieve those goals.<br/>Sets forth organization selection criteria and application requirements, including assurance that at least one qualified judge will serve as Judicial Leader of each Court Team receiving assistance.<br/>Requires the Center to: (1) develop materials to guide judges in the decision-making process regarding, and to train Court Teams in the appropriate care for, maltreated infants and toddlers; (2) develop a database to track the progress of and to evaluate such Teams; and (3) provide information to communities and courts seeking to adopt the Court Teams approach.<br/>Requires Center assistance to each Team to include: (1) direction, coordination, oversight, training, and technical assistance; and (2) providing a Local Community Coordinator to serve as a resource of child development expertise.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
