<bill session="110" type="s" number="642" updated="2009-01-09T12:33:59-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31" /></status>

	<introduced date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Environmental Justice Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Environmental Justice Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to codify Executive Order 12898, relating to environmental justice, to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to fully implement the recommendations of the Inspector General of the Agency and the Comptroller General of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300038"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-06-11"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2086-2087)</text></action>
		<action date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S2087"/></action>
		<calendar date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31" ><text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1222228800" datetime="2008-09-24"><text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Boxer without amendment. With written report No. 110-485. Minority views filed.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="1056" date="1222228800" datetime="2008-09-24" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1056.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/15/2007--Introduced.<br/>Environmental Justice Act of 2007 - Authorizes and directs the President to execute, administer, and enforce as a matter of federal law the provisions of Executive Order 12898, dated February 11, 1994, (Federal Actions To Address Environmental Justice In Minority Populations and Low-Income Populations) with modifications: (1) defining &quot;environmental justice&quot; and &quot;fair treatment&quot;; and (2) providing that the provisions concerning judicial review shall not apply.<br/>Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to carry out specified recommendations set forth in the following reports: (1) the EPA Inspector General's report number 2006-P-00034 entitled &quot;EPA needs to conduct environmental justice reviews of its programs, policies and activities&quot;; (2) the Government Accountability Office (GAO) report numbered GAO-05-289 entitled &quot;EPA Should Devote More Attention to Environmental Justice when Developing Clean Air Rules&quot;; and (3) the Inspector General's report number 2004-P-00007 entitled &quot;EPA Needs to Consistently Implement the Intent of the Executive Order on Environmental Justice.&quot;<br/>Requires the Administrator to report semiannually to Congress on the implementation of such recommendations as well as progress on modifying emergency management procedures to incorporate environmental justice in the agency's Incident Command Structure in accordance with the December 18, 2006, letter from the Deputy Administrator to the Acting Inspector General.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
