<bill session="110" type="s" number="644" updated="2009-01-09T12:34:19-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Total Force Educational Assistance Enhancement and Integration Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to recodify as part of that title certain educational assistance programs for members of the reserve components of the Armed Forces, to improve such programs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300068"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412242" joined="2007-02-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-05-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300030" joined="2007-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-06-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300088" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-03-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2007-02-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300037" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="2007-02-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300080" joined="2007-07-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-10-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412243" joined="2007-05-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2007-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300090" joined="2008-02-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/15/2007--Introduced.<br/>Total Force Educational Assistance Enhancement and Integration Act of 2007 - Recodifies under federal veterans' benefits law (currently codified under federal armed forces law) provisions relating to educational assistance for members of the reserves. Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (Secretary) (currently, the Secretary of each military department) to carry out such assistance. Makes eligible for such assistance under this Act those who, after October 1, 2008: (1) enlist or extend an enlistment in the Selected Reserve for not less than six years; or (1) are appointed or agree to serve in the Selected Reserve for at least six years. Includes under this Act those eligible for such assistance as of October 1, 2008. Increases monthly amounts of authorized assistance. Removes restrictions on the use of such assistance for apprenticeships and on-job training, flight training, licensing and certification tests, and individualized tutorial assistance. Requires the Secretary (currently, the military department Secretaries) to provide educational assistance to reserve personnel ordered to active duty in response to a war or national emergency. Makes eligible for such assistance under this Act those who, on or after October 1, 2008: (1) serve on active duty in support of a contingency operation for 90 days or more; or (2) perform full-time National Guard duty for 90 days or more in response to a national emergency. Includes under this Act those eligible for such assistance as of October 1, 2008. Revises provisions concerning assistance amounts. Requires funding for benefits accruing under this Act: (1) on or after October 1, 2008, to be made from funds available to the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) for the payment of readjustment benefits; and (2) before such date from the Department of Defense Education Benefits Fund.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
