<bill session="110" type="s" number="653" updated="2009-01-09T12:35:42-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Secure Travel and Counterterrorism Partnership Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to expand visa waiver program to countries on a probationary basis and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300098"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300070" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2007-02-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300001" joined="2007-02-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1171515600" datetime="2007-02-15"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/15/2007--Introduced.<br/>Secure Travel and Counterterrorism Partnership Act - Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the United States should modernize the visa waiver program by enhancing program security requirements and extending visa-free travel privileges to nationals of foreign countries that are allies in the war on terrorism; and (2) such expansion will have positive security, economic, and bilateral effects.<br/>Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act with respect to the visa waiver program to authorize waiver of low visa refusal rate requirements for a country that meets security and counterterrorism cooperation requirements and has a sustained reduction in visa refusal rates.<br/>Authorizes the Secretary of Homeland Security to consider: (1) specified security-related issues in determining whether to waive low visa refusal requirements; and (2) visa overstay rates in determining program eligibility.<br/>Provides for the following program security enhancements: (1) implementation of an electronic travel authorization system which shall provide biographical information; (2) participant country reporting of lost and stolen passports to the U.S. government; (3) participant country acceptance of its citizens or nationals removed from the United States; and (4) security-related information exchange about a country's citizens or nationals traveling to the United States.<br/>Requires the Secretary to establish an exit system that records the departure on a flight leaving the United States of every alien program participant. Requires that such system: (1) match an alien's biometric information against watch lists and immigration information; and (2) compare such biometric information against air carrier manifests to confirm departures.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
