<bill session="110" type="s" number="667" updated="2009-01-09T12:38:49-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"/></status>

	<introduced date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Education Begins at Home Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to expand programs of early childhood home visitation that increase school readiness, child abuse and neglect prevention, and early identification of developmental and health delays, including potential mental health concerns, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300010"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2007-03-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="2007-03-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300008" joined="2007-07-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2007-06-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-03-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400619" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="2008-04-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2007-10-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300068" joined="2007-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2007-06-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300081" joined="2007-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="2007-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300083" joined="2007-03-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-09-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412243" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300006" joined="2007-03-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-11-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300084" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300090" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="2008-06-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2007-04-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S2173-2178"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/16/2007--Introduced.<br/>Education Begins at Home Act - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), in collaboration with the Secretary of Education, to make: (1) grants to states for programs of early childhood home visitation; and (2) competitive grants to local educational agencies and other eligible applicants for early home visitation for families with English language learners. Directs the Secretary of Defense, in collaboration with the Secretary of Education, to make competitive grants to eligible applicants for early home visitation for military families. Amends the Head Start Act to direct the Secretary of HHS to establish standards for home visitor staff in Early Head Start programs with respect to their training, qualifications, and conduct of home visits. Revises Early Head Start programs to provide for: (1) training in parenting skills and child development; (2) certain home-based and family support services; (3) procedures for transition into Head Start or other local early childhood education programs; (4) staff communication and program coordination; and (5) professional development and personnel enhancement. Directs the Secretary of HHS to develop and implement a public information and educational campaign to inform the public and new parents about the importance of proper care for infants and children under five years of age. 
	</summary>
</bill>
