<bill session="110" type="s" number="675" updated="2009-01-09T12:40:16-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1177473600" datetime="2007-04-25" /></status>

	<introduced date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Training for Realtime Writers Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide competitive grants for training court reporters and closed captioners to meet requirements for realtime writers under the Telecommunications Act of 1996, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300051"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300070" joined="2007-03-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-03-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300047" joined="2007-03-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="2008-05-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300061" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300068" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300048" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300078" joined="2007-03-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="412244" joined="2008-05-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300084" joined="2007-02-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2007-05-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2180)</text></action>
		<action date="1171602000" datetime="2007-02-16"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1177473600" datetime="2007-04-25" ><text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1185854400" datetime="2007-07-31"><text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Inouye with amendments. With written report No. 110-138.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="291" date="1185854400" datetime="2007-07-31" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 291.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/31/2007--Reported to Senate amended. Training for Realtime Writers Act of 2007 - (Sec. 3) Directs the Secretary of Commerce to make competitive grants to court reporting systems meeting certain requirements to promote recruitment, training, and placement of individuals, including individuals who have completed a court reporting training program, as realtime writers providing closed captioning in video programming. Sets forth priorities in making grants. Limits each grant to$1.5 million for a two-year period. (Sec. 4) Sets forth grant application requirements. (Sec. 5) Allows grant funds to be used for recruitment, scholarships, distance learning, developing and implementing both English and Spanish curricula, mentoring, encouraging individuals with disabilities to pursue a career in realtime writing, and employment of personnel for all those purposes. (Sec. 6) Sets forth reporting requirements. (Sec. 7) Authorizes appropriations.(Sec. 8) Repeals this Act five years after enactment. 
	</summary>
</bill>
