<bill session="110" type="s" number="694" updated="2009-01-09T12:44:57-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1179288000" datetime="2007-05-16" /></status>

	<introduced date="1172552400" datetime="2007-02-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Cameron Gulbransen Kids and Cars Safety Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Cameron Gulbransen Kids Transportation Safety Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">K.T. Safety Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Transportation to issue regulations to reduce the incidence of child injury and death occurring inside or outside of light motor vehicles, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300022"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="2007-02-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="412242" joined="2007-02-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300005" joined="2007-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-10-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-09-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-02-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="2007-02-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300071" joined="2007-03-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2007-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2007-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300092" joined="2008-02-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300013" joined="2007-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2007-03-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300081" joined="2007-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300037" joined="2007-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300083" joined="2007-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300054" joined="2007-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300080" joined="2007-05-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300040" joined="2007-03-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412243" joined="2007-12-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300078" joined="2007-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300095" joined="2007-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-05-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2007-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300026" joined="2007-10-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="412244" joined="2007-03-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400194" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300084" joined="2007-03-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="2007-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2007-02-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1172552400" datetime="2007-02-27"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2278-2279)</text></action>
		<action date="1172552400" datetime="2007-02-27"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text></action>
		<action date="1178769600" datetime="2007-05-10"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5925-5926)</text></action>
		<calendar date="1179288000" datetime="2007-05-16" ><text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"><text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Inouye with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 110-275.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="619" date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 619.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/13/2008--Reported to Senate amended. Cameron Gulbransen Kids Transportation Safety Act of 2007, or the K.T. Safety Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of Transportation to initiate a rulemaking for motor vehicles to require: (1) automatic reversal of direction by power windows and panels when they detect an obstruction; (2) an expanded rearward field of view to prevent backing incidents; and (3) automatic transmissions to have an anti-rollaway system that requires the service brake to be depressed before the transmission can be shifted out of park, which shall function in any starting system key position in which the transmission can be shifted out of park. Requires the Secretary, if it is determined that no additional safety standards are reasonable and appropriate, to: (1) report to Congress the reason such standards were not prescribed; and (2) make available to the public information on which vehicles are or are not equipped with automatic reversal of direction by power windows and panels when they detect an obstruction. Provides a phase-in period for the power window and rearward visibility provisions. Requires: (1) motor vehicle manufacturers for each year through 2010 to transmit to the Secretary the make and model of motor vehicles with automatic transmissions that do not have an anti-rollaway system; and (2) the Secretary to make such information available to the public. Requires the Secretary to: (1) establish and maintain a database of injuries and deaths in nontraffic, noncrash motor vehicle events; (2) supplement an existing consumer information program on child safety or create a new program with information about hazards to children in nontraffic, noncrash incident situations; and (3) make such information available to the public.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
