<bill session="110" type="s" number="696" updated="2009-01-09T12:45:33-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1172552400" datetime="2007-02-27"/></status>

	<introduced date="1172552400" datetime="2007-02-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Energy Research Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish an Advanced Research Projects Administration-Energy to initiate high risk, innovative energy research to improve the energy security of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300005"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2007-06-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1172552400" datetime="2007-02-27"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2279-2280)</text></action>
		<action date="1172552400" datetime="2007-02-27"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S2280-2281"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/27/2007--Introduced.<br/>Energy Research Act of 2007 - Establishes the Advanced Research Projects Administration - Energy (ARPA-E) to reduce foreign energy imports and to improve the competitiveness of the U.S. economy by: (1) promoting revolutionary changes in the critical technologies that would promote energy competitiveness; (2) turning cutting-edge science and engineering into technologies for energy and environmental application; and (3) accelerating innovation in energy and the environment for both traditional and alternative energy sources and in energy efficiency mechanisms to reduce energy use.<br/>Requires the ARPA-E Director to award competitive grants, cooperative agreements, or contracts to institutions of higher education, companies, or consortia of such entities (which may include federally funded research and development centers).<br/>Requires the Director to implement such programs in a manner similar to the Small Business Innovation Research Program in order to ensure that small-business concerns are fully able to participate in the programs.<br/>Authorizes the Director to carry out a program to award cash prizes in recognition of outstanding achievements with potential application to the mission of ARPA-E.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
