<bill session="110" type="s" number="705" updated="2009-01-09T12:49:20-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1172638800" datetime="2007-02-28"/></status>

	<introduced date="1172638800" datetime="2007-02-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Office of Federal Procurement Policy Act to establish a governmentwide policy requiring competition in certain executive agency procurements, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300066"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2007-02-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="2007-02-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300048" joined="2007-02-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300097" joined="2007-02-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1172638800" datetime="2007-02-28"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2362)</text></action>
		<action date="1172638800" datetime="2007-02-28"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/28/2007--Introduced.<br/>Amends the Office of Federal Procurement Policy Act to require an executive agency, when procuring Federal Prison Industries (FPI) products to: (1) use competitive procedures; or (2) make an individual purchase under a multiple award contract in accordance with applicable competition requirements. Requires an agency to: (1) timely notify FPI of procurements; and (2) consider a timely offer from FPI in the same manner as other offers. Requires agency heads to ensure that: (1) agencies do not purchase a FPI product or service unless an agency's contracting officer determines that the product or service is comparable to products or services available from the private sector that best meet the agencies' needs; and (2) FPI performs its contractual obligations to agencies to the same extent as any other contractor. Outlines exceptions to the competitive procedures requirement. Prohibits requiring a contractor to use FPI as a subcontractor or supplier. Prohibits agencies from entering into contracts with FPI under which inmate workers would have access to classified and sensitive information. Restricts the interstate and foreign commerce of services resulting from convict labor in a prisoner work program operated by a prison or jail of a state or local jurisdiction. Subjects knowing violators of such restrictions to fine or imprisonment, or both. Requires state and local prison work programs to meet specified requirements. Provides for exemptions for services performed as part of an inmate work program conducted by a state or local government to disassemble, scrap, and recycle products, other than electronic products, that would otherwise be disposed of in a landfill. Authorizes recovered scrap from such program to be sold. 
	</summary>
</bill>
