<bill session="110" type="s" number="717" updated="2009-01-09T12:52:56-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1172638800" datetime="2007-02-28"/></status>

	<introduced date="1172638800" datetime="2007-02-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Identification Security Enhancement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to repeal title II of the REAL ID Act of 2005, to restore section 7212 of the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004, which provides States additional regulatory flexibility and funding authorization to more rapidly produce tamper- and counterfeit-resistant driver's licenses, and to protect privacy and civil liberties by providing interested stakeholders on a negotiated rulemaking with guidance to achieve improved 21st century licenses to improve national security.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300001"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="2007-02-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300002" joined="2007-06-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300005" joined="2007-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2008-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412243" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300095" joined="2007-02-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="412244" joined="2007-02-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1172638800" datetime="2007-02-28"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2368-2369)</text></action>
		<action date="1172638800" datetime="2007-02-28"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S2369"/></action>
		<action date="1209441600" datetime="2008-04-29"><text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/28/2007--Introduced.<br/>Identification Security Enhancement Act of 2007 - Repeals title II of the Real ID Act of 2005. Prohibits federal agencies from accepting state-issued driver's licenses and personal identification cards after specified deadlines unless such identification conforms to the minimum standards promulgated under this Act. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to: (1) establish by regulation minimum standards for acceptance of state-issued driver's licenses and personal identification cards by federal agencies; (2) establish a negotiated rulemaking process before publishing such standards; and (3) award grants to states to assist them in conforming to such standards. 
	</summary>
</bill>
