<bill session="110" type="s" number="727" updated="2009-01-09T12:56:08-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"/></status>

	<introduced date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Teaching Geography is Fundamental Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve and expand geographic literacy among kindergarten through grade 12 students in the United States by improving professional development programs for kindergarten through grade 12 teachers offered through institutions of higher education.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300023"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="2007-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="2008-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="2007-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300002" joined="2007-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2007-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2007-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-07-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300088" joined="2007-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400619" joined="2008-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300068" joined="2007-05-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2007-03-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300001" joined="2007-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2008-09-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300075" joined="2007-10-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300050" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300069" joined="2007-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300026" joined="2007-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300084" joined="2007-10-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300099" joined="2007-03-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300090" joined="2007-03-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2493-2494)</text></action>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/1/2007--Introduced.<br/>Teaching Geography is Fundamental Act - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to establish a geography education grant program under title II, Teacher Quality Enhancement. Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award a grant to a national nonprofit educational organization or consortium, with 75% to be used for subgrants to institutions of higher education associated with state geographic alliances, nonprofit educational organizations, or state or local educational agencies. Requires various grantee and subgrantee activities designed to expand geographic literacy among kindergarten through grade 12 students by improving their teachers' professional development programs offered through institutions of higher education. Includes among such activities state-based conferences to assess geographic literacy and identify improvement strategies.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
