<bill session="110" type="s" number="732" updated="2009-01-09T12:58:06-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"/></status>

	<introduced date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Peace Corps Volunteer Empowerment Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to empower Peace Corps volunteers, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300034"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300078" joined="2008-09-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2498-2499)</text></action>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
		<action date="1185336000" datetime="2007-07-25"><text>Committee on Foreign Relations Subcommittee on Western Hemisphere, Peace Corps and Narcotics Affairs. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-551.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/1/2007--Introduced.<br/>Peace Corps Volunteer Empowerment Act - Authorizes appropriations for seed funding for Peace Corps volunteers to carry out approved demonstration projects. Authorizes charitable fundraising by Peace Corps volunteers. Requires the Director of the Peace Corps to: (1) award grants to private nonprofit corporations and returned Peace Corps volunteers to enable such volunteers to to develop programs and projects in the United States to promote Peace Corps goals; (2) increase the number of Peace Corps volunteers with at least five years of relevant work experience, and establish FY2008-FY2010 experienced volunteer demonstration programs in at least 20 countries; (3) establish a electronic system for promoting improved communication among Peace Corps volunteers and staff; (4) provide for volunteer input in senior staff and program reviews; (5) review the Peace Corps medical screening process; (6) seek to secure the right of volunteers to suspend enrollment in retiree health plans and to resume such enrollment upon service completion; and (7) provide whistleblower and administrative separation protection. Provides for a Volunteer Advisory Committee for each country in which volunteers serve. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to provide tax deduction guidance for volunteers or volunteer leaders enrolled under the Peace Corps Act. Requires the Peace Corps to publish a financial guide for applicants and volunteers.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
