<bill session="110" type="s" number="735" updated="2009-01-09T12:59:06-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1177473600" datetime="2007-04-25" /></status>

	<introduced date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Terrorist Hoax Improvements Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Terrorist Hoax Improvements Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 18, United States Code, to improve the terrorist hoax statute.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300059"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2007-03-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300062" joined="2007-03-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300048" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300027" joined="2007-04-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2501-2502)</text></action>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1176350400" datetime="2007-04-12"><text>Committee on the Judiciary. Committee consideration and Mark Up Session held.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1177473600" datetime="2007-04-25" ><text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1178251200" datetime="2007-05-04"><text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Leahy with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 110-61.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="134" date="1178251200" datetime="2007-05-04" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 134.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/4/2007--Reported to Senate amended. Terrorist Hoax Improvements Act of 2007 - Amends the federal criminal code to: (1) expand the prohibition against conveying false information and hoaxes to include false information and hoaxes about any federal crime of terrorism; (2) increase maximum prison terms for hoaxes involving a member of the Armed Forces during war; (3) revise civil liability provisions to allow emergency personnel to seek reimbursement of expenses from the perpetrator of a hoax who receives actual notice that such personnel are taking emergency or investigative actions in response to the hoax and who fails to inform one or more parties of the hoax; and (4) expand the prohibition against mailing threatening communications in the United States or to a foreign country to include threats against corporations and governmental entities (as well as individuals).<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
