<bill session="110" type="s" number="737" updated="2009-01-09T12:59:52-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"/></status>

	<introduced date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Voter Advocate and Democracy Index Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 in order to measure, compare, and improve the quality of voter access to polls and voter services in the administration of Federal elections in the States.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400629"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="2007-07-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2503)</text></action>
		<action date="1172725200" datetime="2007-03-01"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/1/2007--Introduced.<br/>Voter Advocate and Democracy Index Act of 2007 - Amends the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to establish within the Election Assistance Commission an Office of the Voter Advocate to develop and administer a program to: (1) collect specified voter data from states with respect to each election for federal office; (2) develop, refine, and publish a Democracy Index; (3) make grants to eligible entities; and (4) make recommendations to states to improve their performance in the administration of federal elections (as determined based on a state-by-state comparison of the voter data collected under this Act.) Directs the Office to establish a Democracy Index Pilot Program for calendar year 2008 to make grants to eligible entities for the purpose of creating a Democracy Index. Requires each state to submit to the Office of the Voter Advocate specified voter data with respect to each election for federal office.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
