<bill session="110" type="s" number="759" updated="2009-01-09T13:07:50-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1173070800" datetime="2007-03-05"/></status>

	<introduced date="1173070800" datetime="2007-03-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit the use of funds for military operations in Iran.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412249"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-11-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2007-10-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-10-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1173070800" datetime="2007-03-05"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2601-2603)</text></action>
		<action date="1173070800" datetime="2007-03-05"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
		<action date="1174968000" datetime="2007-03-27"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3803)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/5/2007--Introduced.<br/>Prohibits funds from being obligated or expended for military operations or activities within or above Iran's territory or within Iran's territorial waters except pursuant to a specific congressional authorization enacted after the date of the enactment of this Act. Exempts from such prohibition military operations or activities: (1) to directly repel an attack launched from within Iran's territory; (2) to directly thwart an imminent attack to be launched from within Iran's territory; (3) in hot pursuit of forces engaged outside the territory of Iran who thereafter enter into Iran; and (4) connected with U.S. government intelligence or intelligence-related activities. Requires the President within 24 hours after determining to use funds for such a military purpose to report to the Senate Committees on Armed Services and Foreign Relations and the Select Committee on Intelligence, and the House Committees on Armed Services and Foreign Affairs and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence. 
	</summary>
</bill>
