<bill session="110" type="s" number="783" updated="2009-01-09T13:16:10-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1210132800" datetime="2008-05-07" /></status>

	<introduced date="1173157200" datetime="2007-03-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Jean Lafitte National Historical Park and Preserve Boundary Adjustment Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Jean Lafitte National Historical Park and Preserve Boundary Adjustment Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to adjust the boundary of the Barataria Preserve Unit of the Jean Lafitte National Historical Park and Preserve in the State of Louisiana, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300063"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1173157200" datetime="2007-03-06"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2718-2719)</text></action>
		<action date="1173157200" datetime="2007-03-06"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S2719"/></action>
		<action date="1177560000" datetime="2007-04-26"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-88.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1210132800" datetime="2008-05-07" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1213588800" datetime="2008-06-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 110-352.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="784" date="1213588800" datetime="2008-06-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 784.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/16/2008--Reported to Senate amended. Jean Lafitte National Historical Park and Preserve Boundary Adjustment Act of 2008 - Amends the National Parks and Recreation Act of 1978 to: (1) adjust the boundary of the Barataria Preserve Unit of Jean Lafitte National Historical Park and Preserve in Louisiana; and (2) authorize the Secretary of the Interior (the Secretary) to acquire any additional land, water, and interests in land and water within the Unit by donation, purchase, transfer from any other federal agency, or exchange. Allows any non-federal land specified on the map entitled &quot;Boundary Map, Barataria Preserve Unit. Jean Lafitte National Historical Park and Preserve, dated December 2007, as &quot;Lands Proposed for Addition,&quot; to be acquired only with the owner's consent and requires the boundary of the Unit to be adjusted to reflect the acquisition. Requires: (1) administrative jurisdiction over any federal land within the areas on the Map specified as &quot;Lands Proposed for Addition&quot; to be transferred without consideration, to the administrative jurisdiction of the National Park Service (NPS), to be administered as part of the Unit; and (2) any land specified on the Map that is acquired or transferred, to be subject to any easements that have been agreed to by the Secretary and the Secretary of the Army. Modifies and/or eliminates certain provisions related to the acquisition of property within the Unit. Authorizes the Secretary, with the consent of the owner and the parish governing authority, to: (1) acquire land, water, and interests in land and water by any of the methods described above with respect to the acquisition of additional land, water, and interests within the Unit (including use of appropriations from the Land and Water Conservation Fund); and (2) revise the boundaries of the Unit to include adjacent land and water. Permits hunting, fishing, and trapping within the Unit, but only as to land, water, or interests in land and water managed by the Secretary. Continues to provide for the designation of zones where, and established periods when, no hunting, fishing, or trapping shall be permitted for public safety reasons. 
	</summary>
</bill>
