<bill session="110" type="s" number="799" updated="2009-01-09T13:21:51-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1173243600" datetime="2007-03-07"/></status>

	<introduced date="1173243600" datetime="2007-03-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Community Choice Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to provide individuals with disabilities and older Americans with equal access to community-based attendant services and supports, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300051"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="2007-03-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-03-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="300008" joined="2007-03-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400619" joined="2007-03-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2007-03-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300092" joined="2007-03-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-03-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300083" joined="2008-05-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-03-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-03-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-09-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-07-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412244" joined="2007-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2008-02-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2007-05-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1173243600" datetime="2007-03-07"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2807)</text></action>
		<action date="1173243600" datetime="2007-03-07"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S2807-2811"/></action>
		<action date="1184040000" datetime="2007-07-10"><text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Hearings held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/7/2007--Introduced.<br/>Community Choice Act of 2007 - Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to require state Medicaid plan coverage of community-based attendant services and supports for certain Medicaid-eligible individuals. Outlines requirements for: (1) an enhanced federal medical assistance percentage (FMAP) for ongoing activities of early coverage states that enhance and promote the use of community-based attendant services and supports; and (2) increased federal financial participation for certain expenditures incurred by the state for the provision of such services and supports. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) award grants to eligible states which have established a Consumer Task Force to assist the state in its development of real choice systems change initiatives; and (2) conduct a demonstration project for the purpose of evaluating service coordination and cost-sharing approaches with respect to the provision of community-based services and supports to dually eligible individuals.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
