<bill session="110" type="s" number="81" updated="2009-01-09T11:17:46-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/></status>

	<introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">West Valley Remediation Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the United States Department of Energy to remediate the Western New York Nuclear Service Center in the Town of Ashford, New York, and to dispose of nuclear waste.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300087"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-01-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/4/2007--Introduced.<br/>West Valley Remediation Act of 2007 - Directs the Secretary of Energy to remediate the Western New York Nuclear Service Center in West Valley, New York. Requires the Secretary to decontaminate and decommission: (1) Center facilities in which certain solidified high level radioactive waste was stored; (2) facilities used in waste solidification; and (3) material and hardware used in connection with the West Valley Demonstration Project. Makes the Secretary responsible for all remediation costs. Instructs the Secretary to: (1) transport high level radioactive waste at the Center to a federal repository for permanent disposal; (2) safeguard and ensure safe storage of such waste; and (3) dispose of low level radioactive waste and transuranic waste located at the Center, including future radioactive waste generated as a result of remediation. Directs the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) to regulate the remediation of radioactive waste and nuclear materials at the Center. Requires the Secretary to develop and submit a specified decommissioning plan for NRC approval. Requires the Secretary to: (1) enter into a consultation agreement with New York State regarding remediation of the Center; (2) prepare an environmental impact statement for decommissioning or long-term stewardship of the Center; and (3) assume exclusive use and possession of the Center after execution of a Cooperative Agreement with the New York State Energy Research and Development Authority. Requires the Secretary to take title to any land or facilities at the Center that have not been approved by the NRC for release for unrestricted use, and title to all radioactive and nonradioactive wastes and materials located at the Center. Repeals the West Valley Demonstration Project Act upon assumption of exclusive use and possession of the Center by the Secretary.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
