<bill session="110" type="s" number="823" updated="2009-01-09T13:27:16-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1173330000" datetime="2007-03-08"/></status>

	<introduced date="1173330000" datetime="2007-03-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Microbicide Development Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act with respect to facilitating the development of microbicides for preventing transmission of HIV/AIDS and other diseases, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400629"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2007-03-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-05-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2007-03-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2007-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-03-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-04-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300090" joined="2007-03-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2007-06-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1173330000" datetime="2007-03-08"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2919-2920)</text></action>
		<action date="1173330000" datetime="2007-03-08"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/8/2007--Introduced.<br/>Microbicide Development Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Director of the Office of AIDS Research to: (1) expedite the implementation of the federal strategic plan for the conduct and support of microbicide research and development; and (2) expand, intensify, and coordinate all activities with respect to research and development of microbicides to prevent the transmission of HIV and other sexually transmitted diseases. Requires the Director of the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Diseases to: (1) establish within the Division of AIDS an organizational branch to carry out microbicide research and development; and (2) assign priority to ensuring adequate funding and support for the Microbicide Trials Network and other programs for supporting microbicides clinical trials. Requires the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to fully implement the CDC's microbicide agenda to support microbicide research and development. Directs the head of the Office of HIV/AIDS of the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) to develop and implement a program to support the development of microbicides products for the prevention of the transmission of HIV/AIDS and other diseases, and facilitate wide-scale availability of such products. Requires the Secretary of State to report to Congress on advance market commitments of microbicides to prevent HIV infection as a means of creating private sector investment incentives.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
