<bill session="110" type="s" number="83" updated="2009-01-09T11:18:00-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/></status>

	<introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Rail Security Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide increased rail transportation security.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300071"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300008" joined="2007-01-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-01-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-01-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S91-92)</text></action>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/4/2007--Introduced.<br/>Rail Security Act of 2007 - Directs the Assistant Secretary of Homeland Security for the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) to conduct a vulnerability assessment of freight and passenger rail transportation, and develop specific prioritized recommendations for improving rail security. Directs the Assistant Secretary to conduct a study on requiring security screening for passengers, baggage, and cargo on passenger trains. Authorizes the Secretary of Transportation to make grants to Amtrak for fire and life-safety improvements and infrastructure upgrades to tunnels on the Northeast Corridor. Directs Amtrak to submit to the National Transportation Safety Board (NTSB) a plan to address the needs of families of passengers involved in rail passenger accidents. Authorizes the Assistant Secretary to award grants to Amtrak for certain system-wide Amtrak, freight, hazardous materials transportation, and passenger rail security upgrades. Directs the Administrator of the Federal Railroad Administration to set forth certain standards for welded rail and tank car safety improvements. Sets forth certain whistleblower protections for rail employees or other persons providing information about perceived security threats.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
