<bill session="110" type="s" number="832" updated="2009-01-09T13:28:30-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1210132800" datetime="2008-05-07" /></status>

	<introduced date="1173416400" datetime="2007-03-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the sale of approximately 25 acres of public land to the Turnabout Ranch, Escalante, Utah, at fair market value.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300052"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300007" joined="2007-03-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1173416400" datetime="2007-03-09"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2970)</text></action>
		<action date="1173416400" datetime="2007-03-09"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1204088400" datetime="2008-02-27"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-364.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1210132800" datetime="2008-05-07" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1213588800" datetime="2008-06-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with amendments. With written report No. 110-354.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="786" date="1213588800" datetime="2008-06-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 786.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/16/2008--Reported to Senate amended. Directs the Secretary of the Interior, if Turnabout Ranch of Escalante, Utah, submits an offer to the Secretary to acquire specified federal land for the appraised value, to convey to the Ranch all right, title, and interest to such land. Requires the Secretary to complete an appraisal of the federal land, as specified in this Act. Requires Turnabout Ranch to pay: (1) to the Secretary an amount equal to the appraised value of the federal land; and (2) any costs of the conveyance.<br/>Requires the Secretary to deposit the proceeds from the conveyance of the federal land in the Federal Land Deposit Account established by the Federal Land Transaction Facilitation Act, to be spent in accordance with such Act. Modifies the boundaries of the Grand Staircase-Escalante National Monument in Utah to exclude the federal land conveyed to Turnabout Ranch when the conveyance is completed. 
	</summary>
</bill>
