<bill session="110" type="s" number="833" updated="2009-01-09T13:28:39-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1173416400" datetime="2007-03-09"/></status>

	<introduced date="1173416400" datetime="2007-03-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">COMPETE Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Competitiveness through Education, Technology, and Enterprise Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to make the United States competitive in a global economy.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300024"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300080" joined="2007-03-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1173416400" datetime="2007-03-09"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2970-2971)</text></action>
		<action date="1173416400" datetime="2007-03-09"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S2971-2973"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/9/2007--Introduced.<br/>Competitiveness through Education, Technology, and Enterprise Act of 2007 or the COMPETE Act of 2007 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide tax incentives for research and education by: (1) making permanent the credit for increasing research activities; (2) providing a credit for information and communications technology education; and (3) setting an alternative percentage limitation for corporate charitable contributions to the mathematics and science partnership program. Directs the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to establish an SBIR-STEM Workforce Development Grant Pilot program awarding bonus grants to grantees under the Small Business Innovation Research program to provide workforce development opportunities to college students in the science, technology, engineering, and mathematics fields. Expresses the sense of the Senate that the maximum Pell Grant should be increased from $4,600 for academic year 2008-2009 to $5,400 for academic year 2012-2013. Authorizes the Secretary of Energy to award matching grants to institutions of higher education to: (1) provide stipends or other financial assistance for students enrolled in graduate programs in the sciences, technology, engineering, or mathematics; and (2) support outreach and mentoring activities to increase the participation of underrepresented groups in the sciences, technology, engineering, or mathematics at all or any level of education, including elementary, secondary and postsecondary education. Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of Education to make partnership bonus grants annually to a certain number of elementary and of secondary schools in each state that show the most improvement in mathematics and in science, respectively.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
