<bill session="110" type="s" number="850" updated="2009-01-09T13:30:50-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1173758400" datetime="2007-03-13"/></status>

	<introduced date="1173758400" datetime="2007-03-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Scott Gardner Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve sharing of immigration information among Federal, State, and local law enforcement officials, to improve State and local enforcement of immigration laws, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400054"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300035" joined="2007-03-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1173758400" datetime="2007-03-13"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/13/2007--Introduced.<br/>Scott Gardner Act - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to share immigration information with the Attorney General. Requires a joint report from such officials to Congress on improving the performance of federal immigration databases to ensure the prompt entry of immigration information. Requires: (1) the director of each state and local law enforcement agency receiving federal incarceration funds under the Immigration and Nationality Act (INA) to collect and report to the Secretary all immigration and DWI (driving while intoxicated) information collected in the course of normal duties; (2) such information to appear in the wanted person file of the National Criminal Information Center (NCIC) database; and (3) state or local detention of an arrested flagged alien pending federal transfer. Amends INA to: (1) require the Secretary to reimburse the costs of training state and local law enforcement employees on federal immigration laws; and (2) authorize the apprehension and detention of an alien for DWI or a similar violation, as long as the alien is deportable on any other grounds or is an illegal alien. Requires each state motor vehicle administrator to share with the Secretary all information concerning aliens with records of DWI convictions or refusals to take sobriety tests. Directs the Secretary to submit to Congress a formula for the allocation of federal detention facilities for aliens.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
