<bill session="110" type="s" number="86" updated="2009-01-09T11:18:25-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1201669200" datetime="2008-01-30" /></status>

	<introduced date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Fossil Creek Wild and Scenic River Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to designate segments of Fossil Creek, a tributary to the Verde River in the State of Arizona, as wild and scenic rivers.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300071"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300062" joined="2007-01-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S93-94)</text></action>
		<action date="1167886800" datetime="2007-01-04"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1194498000" datetime="2007-11-08"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-282.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1201669200" datetime="2008-01-30" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1207800000" datetime="2008-04-10"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 110-283.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="635" date="1207800000" datetime="2008-04-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 635.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/4/2007--Introduced.<br/>Fossil Creek Wild and Scenic River Act of 2007 - Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate specified segments of Fossil Creek, a tributary to the Verde River in Arizona, as components of the national wild and scenic rivers system. Requires the Secretary of Agriculture to submit a river management plan for the designated segments. 
	</summary>
</bill>
