<bill session="110" type="s" number="868" updated="2009-01-09T13:33:10-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1210132800" datetime="2008-05-07" /></status>

	<introduced date="1173758400" datetime="2007-03-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate segments of the Taunton River in the Commonwealth of Massachusetts as a component of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300059"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-03-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1173758400" datetime="2007-03-13"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1189483200" datetime="2007-09-11"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-213.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1210132800" datetime="2008-05-07" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1213588800" datetime="2008-06-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 110-355.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="787" date="1213588800" datetime="2008-06-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 787.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/16/2008--Reported to Senate amended. Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (the Act) to designate specified segments of the Taunton River in Massachusetts as a component of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System. Requires the river segments to be managed in accordance with the Taunton River Stewardship Plan, dated July 2005, including any amendment to such Plan, that the Secretary of the Interior determines to be consistent with this Act. Authorizes the Secretary, in order to provide for the protection, preservation, and enhancement of each river segment, to enter into cooperative agreements, which may include provisions for financial and other assistance, with: (1) the Commonwealth of Massachusetts (including the political subdivisions of Massachussetts); (2) the Taunton River Stewardship Council; and (3) any appropriate nonprofit, as determined by the Secretary. Bars the river segments from being: (1) administered as a unit of the National Park System; or (2) subject to the laws (including regulations) that govern the administration of such System. Considers the zoning ordinances adopted by specified towns and cities, including any provision of the zoning ordinances related to the conservation of floodplains, wetlands, and watercourses associated with any river segment designated by this Act, to satisfy each standard and requirement under the Act regarding the prohibition on the federal acquisition of certain lands by condemnation for inclusion in any national, wild, scenic, or recreational river area. Authorizes the Secretary, respecting each river segment, to only acquire parcels of land by donation or with the owner's consent. Prohibits the acquisition of any parcel by condemnation. 
	</summary>
</bill>
