<bill session="110" type="s" number="875" updated="2009-01-09T13:34:06-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1173844800" datetime="2007-03-14"/></status>

	<introduced date="1173844800" datetime="2007-03-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">SAFE Energy Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Security and Fuel Efficiency Energy Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve energy security of the United States through a 50 percent reduction in the oil intensity of the economy of the United States by 2030 and the prudent expansion of secure oil supplies, to be achieved by raising the fuel efficiency of the vehicular transportation fleet, increasing the availability of alternative fuel sources, fostering responsible oil exploration and production, and improving international arrangements to secure the global oil supply, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300037"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300029" joined="2007-03-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300030" joined="2007-04-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300001" joined="2007-04-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1173844800" datetime="2007-03-14"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3112-3113, S3127)</text></action>
		<action date="1173844800" datetime="2007-03-14"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S3127-3133"/></action>
		<action date="1178596800" datetime="2007-05-08"><text>Committee on Appropriations Senate Subcommittee on Energy and Water Development. Hearings held.</text></action>
		<action date="1181620800" datetime="2007-06-12"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S7508-7511)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/14/2007--Introduced.<br/>Security and Fuel Efficiency Energy Act of 2007 or the SAFE Energy Act of 2007 - Amends corporate average fuel economy (CAFE) provisions to revise the definition of: (1) &quot;automobile&quot; to mean any vehicle that is propelled by fuel, or by alternative fuel, and is manufactured primarily for use on public streets, roads, and highways (currently, four-wheeled vehicles that are so propelled and manufactured for such use and that are up to 6,000 pounds and certain vehicles between 6,000 and 10,000 pounds); and (2) &quot;passenger automobile&quot; to eliminate the exception for 4-wheel drive automobiles and vehicles weighing more than 6,000 pounds. Requires the Secretary of Transportation to: (1) prescribe separate increased minimum CAFE standards for different classes of automobiles manufactured beginning for model year 2012, but adds an increase of 4% per year in such standard for model years 2013 through 2030; and (2) establish CAFE standards for medium-duty trucks that are consistent with hybridization beginning for model year 2012. Revises the calculation of fuel economy standards for dual fueled automobiles and gaseous fuel dual fueled automobiles manufactured in model year 2012 and beyond to require using the same calculation provisions as used for gas or diesel fueled vehicles. Repeals provisions allowing the Department of Transportation (DOT) to extend manufacturing credits for such automobiles.<br/>Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) repeal the limitation on the number of new qualified hybrid and advanced lean burn technology vehicles eligible for the alternative motor vehicle credit; (2) extend, through 2011, the alternative vehicle credit for certain new qualified hybrid motor vehicles; and (3) allow a new qualified fuel-efficient motor vehicle credit and an advanced technology motor vehicles manufacturing credit.<br/>Sets forth a special rule setting the maximum allowable gross weight for vehicles with a supplementary sixth axle using the National System of Interstate and Defense Highways at 97,000 pounds, provided highway safety is not negatively impacted.<br/>Amends the Clean Air Act to prescribe the volume of renewable fuel and cellulosic biomass ethanol that gasoline sold in the United States must contain in calendar years 2008 through 2020. Increases the alternative fuel vehicle refueling property credit, with an additional increase for qualified alternative fuel vehicle refueling property that is a blender pump. Defines blender pump. Expands the types of allowable fuels. Sets forth requirements regarding: (1) installation of ethanol-blend fuel pumps at covered gas stations; (2) increase in the percentage of duel-fueled automobiles manufactured in model years 2012 through 2022; and (3) establishment of biofuels incentives.<br/>Permits: (1) the exploration for and extraction of hydrocarbon resources from any portion of any foreign exclusive economic zone contiguous to the exclusive economic zone of the United States; and (2) export without license authority all equipment necessary for the exploration for or extraction of such hydrocarbon resources.<br/>Establishes within the National Security Council a Bureau of International Energy.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
