<bill session="110" type="s" number="890" updated="2009-01-09T13:36:09-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23" /></status>

	<introduced date="1173931200" datetime="2007-03-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for certain administrative and support services for the Dwight D. Eisenhower Memorial Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300056"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300013" joined="2007-03-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300081" joined="2007-03-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300083" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300050" joined="2007-03-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1173931200" datetime="2007-03-15"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3202)</text></action>
		<action date="1173931200" datetime="2007-03-15"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S3202-3203"/></action>
		<action date="1177560000" datetime="2007-04-26"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-88.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1179892800" datetime="2007-05-23" ><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with amendments. With written report No. 110-97.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="227" date="1182830400" datetime="2007-06-26" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 227.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1213156800" datetime="2008-06-11"><text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S5530"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/26/2007--Reported to Senate amended. Amends the Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 2000 to expand the powers of the Dwight D. Eisenhower Memorial Commission. Authorizes the Commission to: (1) enter into contracts for specialized or professional services and hire staff without regard to civil service requirements; (2) appoint an architect; (3) enter into cooperative agreements with federal agencies, state, local, tribal, and international governments, and private organizations; and (4) obtain temporary, intermittent, and part-time services and accept volunteer services. Authorizes the head of a federal agency, at the Commission's request, to provide information or assistance to and detail personnel to the Commission. Requires the Commission to: (1) appoint an Executive Director; and (2) obtain administrative and support services from the General Services Administration (GSA) on a reimbursable basis. Authorizes appropriations.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
