<bill session="110" type="s" number="893" updated="2009-01-09T13:36:35-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1173931200" datetime="2007-03-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1173931200" datetime="2007-03-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">A PLUS Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Academic Partnerships Lead Us to Success Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to allow a State to combine certain funds and enter into a performance agreement with the Secretary of Education to improve the academic achievement of students.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400105"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300029" joined="2007-03-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400621" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300013" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400576" joined="2007-03-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300062" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400418" joined="2008-12-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300048" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300027" joined="2007-03-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1173931200" datetime="2007-03-15"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/15/2007--Introduced.<br/>Academic Partnerships Lead Us to Success Act or the A PLUS Act - Allows each state to enter into a five-year performance agreement with the Secretary of Education permitting it to receive federal funds on a consolidated basis that would otherwise be directed toward specific programs furthering the stated purpose of title I (Improving the Academic Achievement of the Disadvantaged) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965. Requires each agreement to be approved by a combination of specified state parties, and list the programs for which consolidated funding is requested. Allows states to use such funds for any educational purpose permitted by state law, but requires states to make certain assurances that they will use fiscal control and fund accounting procedures, abide by federal civil rights laws, and advance educational opportunities for the disadvantaged. Allows amendments to the scope of performance agreements. Requires each agreement state to: (1) maintain an accountability system measuring annual student progress toward state proficiency standards; (2) annually disseminate student performance data disaggregated by specified student groups; and (3) keep aggregate spending on elementary and secondary education at no less than 90% of such spending for the school year coinciding with this Act's enactment. Limits administrative expenses. Requires the inclusion of private schools and teachers in activites funded on a consolidated basis. Directs the Secretary to evaluate each performance agreement midway through its execution. Allows the Secretary to terminate an agreement whose terms are not met for three consecutive school years.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
