<bill session="110" type="s" number="904" updated="2009-01-09T13:38:10-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1173931200" datetime="2007-03-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1173931200" datetime="2007-03-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Small Business Opportunity Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide additional relief for small business owners ordered to active duty as members of reserve components of the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300091"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300029" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300080" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300069" joined="2007-04-16"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1173931200" datetime="2007-03-15"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3211-3212)</text></action>
		<action date="1173931200" datetime="2007-03-15"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/15/2007--Introduced.<br/>Veterans Small Business Opportunity Act of 2007 - Amends the Small Business Act to extend certain small business loan time limits with respect to a small business owned and controlled by: (1) a veteran called to active duty on or after September 11, 2001; or (2) a service-disabled veteran who became disabled due to an injury or illness incurred or aggravated during a period of active duty on or after such date. Extends such time limits by the period that the veteran was on active duty. Directs the Secretary of Defense to conduct a study for promoting positive working relations between employers and their reserve component employees. Increases: (1) certain Small Business Administration (SBA) loan limits for small business owners who are members of the National Guard or reserves; and (2) SBA funding for the Office of Veterans Business Development. Directs the President to establish an interagency task force to coordinate federal efforts to increase capital and business development opportunities for, and increase the award of federal contracting and subcontracting opportunities to, small businesses owned and controlled by disabled veterans and other veterans (businesses). Requires the SBA Administrator and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to ensure one-stop online registration for such small businesses. Authorizes the Secretary to develop business development assistance for such small businesses.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
