<bill session="110" type="s" number="910" updated="2009-01-09T13:38:56-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1173931200" datetime="2007-03-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1173931200" datetime="2007-03-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Healthy Families Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for paid sick leave to ensure that Americans can address their own health needs and the health needs of their families.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300059"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412242" joined="2007-12-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300008" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300001" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300084" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2007-09-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2007-03-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1173931200" datetime="2007-03-15"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3220)</text></action>
		<action date="1173931200" datetime="2007-03-15"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S3220-3224"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/15/2007--Introduced.<br/>Healthy Families Act - Requires certain employers, who employ 15 or more employees for each working day during 20 or more workweeks a year, to provide a minimum paid sick leave and employment benefits of: (1) seven days annually for those who work at least 30 hours per week; and (2) a prorated annual amount for those who work less than 30 but at least 20 hours a week, or less than 1,500 but at least 1,000 hours per year. Allows employees to use such leave to meet their own medical needs or to care for the medical needs of certain family members. Directs the Secretary of Labor to exercise certain investigative and enforcement authority with respect to this Act's provisions for employees covered by title I of the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 or the Government Employee Rights Act of 1991. Provides that, for employees under their jurisdiction, such authority shall be exercised by the Librarian of Congress, the Comptroller General, the Board of Directors of the congressional Office of Compliance, or the Merit Systems Protection Board. Declares that the requirements under this Act are minimum requirements, and are not to be construed to discourage employers from adopting or retaining more generous leave policies.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
