<bill session="110" type="s" number="911" updated="2009-01-09T13:39:05-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1195016400" datetime="2007-11-14" /></status>

	<introduced date="1174276800" datetime="2007-03-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Conquer Childhood Cancer Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Conquer Childhood Cancer Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to advance medical research and treatments into pediatric cancers, ensure patients and families have access to the current treatments and information regarding pediatric cancers, establish a population-based national childhood cancer database, and promote public awareness of pediatric cancers.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300081"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="2008-06-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="2007-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="412242" joined="2007-09-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="2007-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-07-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2007-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300070" joined="2007-03-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="2007-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2008-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300082" joined="2007-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300008" joined="2007-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300047" joined="2007-05-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2007-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-03-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300088" joined="2008-05-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400619" joined="2008-03-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="2008-02-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2007-09-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2007-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300092" joined="2008-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300013" joined="2008-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-10-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300019" joined="2007-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300068" joined="2007-10-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2007-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="412249" joined="2008-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300037" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300077" joined="2008-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300023" joined="2007-06-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300035" joined="2008-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400432" joined="2008-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400418" joined="2008-04-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300080" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300014" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300003" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300027" joined="2007-06-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300001" joined="2007-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-06-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2008-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="412243" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-11-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300050" joined="2007-03-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2007-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300036" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300021" joined="2007-03-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300006" joined="2007-06-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-12-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-06-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400054" joined="2007-09-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2007-06-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300026" joined="2008-07-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400194" joined="2007-04-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300072" joined="2007-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2007-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300099" joined="2008-04-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="2007-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2007-06-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1174276800" datetime="2007-03-19"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3274-3275)</text></action>
		<action date="1174276800" datetime="2007-03-19"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S3275"/></action>
		<calendar date="1195016400" datetime="2007-11-14" ><text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1197435600" datetime="2007-12-12"><text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Reported by Senator Kennedy with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="535" date="1197435600" datetime="2007-12-12" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 535.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	12/12/2007--Reported to Senate amended. Conquer Childhood Cancer Act of 2007 - (Sec. 3) Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH), to enhance, expand, and intensify pediatric cancer research, including therapeutically applicable research to generate effective treatments, pediatric preclinical testing, and pediatric clinical trials through National Cancer Institute-supported pediatric cancer clinical trials groups and their member institutions.<br/>Directs the Secretary, acting through the Director of NIH, to award grants to enhance and expand cancer research fellowships to train and develop clinical investigators focused on pediatric cancer research.<br/>Authorizes the Secretary to award grants to childhood cancer professional and direct service organizations for the expansion and widespread implementation of: (1) activities that provide information on treatment protocols to ensure early access to the best available therapies and clinical trials for pediatric cancers; (2) activities that provide available information on the late effects of pediatric cancer treatment to ensure access to necessary long-term medical and psychological care; and (3) direct resource services such as educational outreach for parents, information on school reentry and postsecondary education, and resource directories or referral services for financial assistance, psychological counseling, and other support services. Requires the Secretary to develop and implement metrics-based performance measures to assess the effectiveness of activities funded under such grants.<br/>Authorizes appropriations for FY2008-FY2012 to carry out activities related to the National Childhood Cancer Registry. Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to award a grant to enhance and expand infrastructure to track the epidemiology of pediatric cancer into a comprehensive nationwide registry of actual occurrences of pediatric cancer. Requires such registry to be updated to include an actual occurrence within weeks of the date of such occurrence. Subjects such registry to federal laws regarding records maintained on individuals, health information privacy regulations, informed consent regulations, and any other federal laws relating to the privacy of patient information.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
