<bill session="110" type="s" number="941" updated="2009-01-09T13:43:17-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"/></status>

	<introduced date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Community Health Centers Investment Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase Federal support for Community Health Centers and the National Health Service Corps in order to ensure access to health care for millions of Americans living in medically-underserved areas.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400357"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="2007-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="2007-09-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-07-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2007-06-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300075" joined="2007-03-20"/>
		<cosponsor id="412244" joined="2008-04-02"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3512-3513)</text></action>
		<action date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
		<action date="1185768000" datetime="2007-07-30"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S10304)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/20/2007--Introduced.<br/>Community Health Centers Investment Act - Authorizes appropriations for FY2008-FY2015 for: (1) primary health care centers for underserved populations; and (2) the National Health Service Corps. Establishes priorities for the use of such funds and the assignment of Corps personnel.<br/>Amends the Public Health Service Act to increase amounts available for the National Health Corps Scholarship program (including scholarships to individuals from disadvantaged backgrounds).<br/>Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to prohibit limitations on the per visit payment amount, or a component of such amount, for federally qualified health centers.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
