<bill session="110" type="s" number="945" updated="2009-01-09T13:43:46-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"/></status>

	<introduced date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">College Textbook Affordability Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure that college textbooks and supplemental materials are available and affordable.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300038"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-03-20"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3393-3394)</text></action>
		<action date="1174363200" datetime="2007-03-20"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S3394"/></action>
		<action date="1184817600" datetime="2007-07-19"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S9552)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/20/2007--Introduced.<br/>College Textbook Affordability Act of 2007 - Requires publishers informing teachers at institutions of higher education about textbooks or supplements in their subject areas to include written information concerning: (1) the price the publisher would charge the bookstore associated with such institution for such items; (2) any history of revisions for such items; and (3) whether such items are available in other formats, including paperback and unbound, and the price the publisher would charge the bookstore for items in those formats. Requires a publisher that sells a textbook and any accompanying supplement as a single bundled item also to sell them separately and unbundled. Directs federally-assisted institutions of higher education to include on printed or internet course schedules the International Standard Book Number (ISBN) and retail price for each required or recommended textbook or supplement for listed courses. Requires such institutions to provide sellers of textbooks (other than publishers) that meet their requirements with: (1) their course schedules for the subsequent academic period; (2) the ISBN for each textbook or supplement required or recommended for each course; and (3) the number of students enrolled, and the maximum enrollment, in each course.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
