<bill session="110" type="s" number="948" updated="2009-01-09T13:44:10-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1174449600" datetime="2007-03-21"/></status>

	<introduced date="1174449600" datetime="2007-03-21"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">CAMRA Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Children and Media Research Advancement Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize funding for the establishment of a program on children and the media within the National Institute of Child Health and Human Development to study the role and impact of electronic media in the development of children.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300067"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-03-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300013" joined="2007-03-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-03-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-03-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300006" joined="2007-04-23"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1174449600" datetime="2007-03-21"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3519-3521)</text></action>
		<action date="1174449600" datetime="2007-03-21"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S3521"/></action>
		<action date="1175054400" datetime="2007-03-28"><text>Star Print ordered on S. 948.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/21/2007--Introduced.<br/>Children and Media Research Advancement Act or the CAMRA Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the National Institute of Child Health and Human Development, to enter into a contract with the National Academy of Science or another appropriate entity to: (1) review, synthesize, and report on research regarding the roles and impact of electronic media (including television, motion pictures, DVD's, interactive video games, digital music, the Internet, and cell phones) and exposures to such media on youth in core areas of development; and (2) establish research priorities regarding such issues.<br/>Directs the Secretary, acting through the Director, to award grants for research concerning the role and impact of electronic media on the cognitive, physical, and socio-behavioral development of youth. Requires such research to: (1) focus on the impact of factors such as media content, format, length of exposure, age of youth, venue, and nature of parental involvement; and (2) include as electronic media television, motion pictures, DVDs, interactive video games, digital music, the Internet, and cell phones.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
