<bill session="110" type="s" number="962" updated="2009-01-09T13:45:57-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1174536000" datetime="2007-03-22"/></status>

	<introduced date="1174536000" datetime="2007-03-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Energy Carbon Capture and Storage Research, Development, and Demonstration Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to reauthorize and improve the carbon capture and storage research, development, and demonstration program of the Department of Energy and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300009"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300029" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="412251" joined="2007-09-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400619" joined="2007-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-03-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300013" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="412249" joined="2007-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300037" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300077" joined="2007-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300014" joined="2007-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300097" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300036" joined="2007-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412248" joined="2007-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="412244" joined="2007-03-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1174536000" datetime="2007-03-22"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3612)</text></action>
		<action date="1174536000" datetime="2007-03-22"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S3612-3613"/></action>
		<action date="1176696000" datetime="2007-04-16"><text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 110-83.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/22/2007--Introduced.<br/>Department of Energy Carbon Capture and Storage Research, Development, and Demonstration Act of 2007 - Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to direct the Secretary of Energy to: (1) carry out fundamental science and engineering research to develop and document new approaches to capture and store carbon dioxide; (2) ensure that fundamental research is appropriately applied to energy technology development activities and the field testing of carbon sequestration activities; (3) promote regional carbon sequestration partnerships to conduct geologic sequestration tests involving carbon dioxide in a variety of geological settings; and (4) conduct at least seven initial large-volume sequestration tests for geological containment of carbon dioxide. Directs the Secretary, in making competitive awards, to give preference to proposals from partnerships among industrial, academic, and government entities.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
