<bill session="110" type="s" number="973" updated="2009-01-09T13:47:28-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1174536000" datetime="2007-03-22"/></status>

	<introduced date="1174536000" datetime="2007-03-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Restitution for Victims of Crime Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Collection of Restitution Improvement Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Environmental Crimes Restitution Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Preservation of Assets for Restitution Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Mandatory Victims' Restitution Act to improve restitution for victims of crime, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300037"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2007-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300008" joined="2007-05-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300048" joined="2007-03-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412243" joined="2007-04-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1174536000" datetime="2007-03-22"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3626-3628)</text></action>
		<action date="1174536000" datetime="2007-03-22"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1174622400" datetime="2007-03-23"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3703-3704)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/22/2007--Introduced.<br/>Restitution for Victims of Crime Act of 2007 - Collection of Restitution Improvement Act of 2007 - Amends the federal criminal code relating to restitution for victims of crime to: (1) require courts to enter an order for immediate restitution at the sentencing of a convict; (2) allow prosecutors to obtain from the U.S. Probation Office, without a court order, financial information about a convict who owes restitution; (3) require identifying information about convicts to be included in restitution orders of more than $100; and (4) allow crime victims reimbursement of attorney fees incurred in seeking restitution.<br/>Preservation of Assets for Restitution Act of 2007 - Requires courts to issue protective orders for preservation of assets available to satisfy restitution claims. Provides for prejudgment remedies to protect assets available to satisfy restitution claims.<br/>Environmental Crimes Restitution Act of 2007 - Provides for orders of restitution for victims of certain environmental crimes at the sentencing of a convict.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
