<bill session="110" type="s" number="990" updated="2009-01-09T13:49:39-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1174881600" datetime="2007-03-26"/></status>

	<introduced date="1174881600" datetime="2007-03-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Fighting Gangs and Empowering Youth Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Public and Assisted Housing Gang Elimination Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to fight criminal gangs.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400272"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2007-03-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1174881600" datetime="2007-03-26"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3757-3758)</text></action>
		<action date="1174881600" datetime="2007-03-26"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/26/2007--Introduced.<br/>Fighting Gangs and Empowering Youth Act of 2007 - Reauthorizes programs for combating criminal gangs, including after-school programs, programs for safe and drug-free schools and communities, gang resistance education and training programs, and adult and juvenile offender state and local reentry demonstration projects.<br/>Establishes or increases funding for criminal gang-related programs, including: (1) demonstration grants to public and private entities for innovative approaches to combat gang activity; (2) programs that target certain at-risk youth and juvenile offenders ages 11 to 19; (3) state studies of parole or post-incarceration supervision violations and revocations; (4) substance abuse treatment; (5) mentoring grants to nonprofit organizations; (6) transition training for incarcerated youth offenders; (7) gang activity policing grants; (8) grants to prosecutors and law enforcement officials to combat violent crime and protect witnesses; and (9) the National Youth Gang Survey.<br/>Public and Assisted Housing Gang Elimination Act of 2007 - Authorizes the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to make grants to public housing agencies and private, for-profit and nonprofit owners of federally assisted low-income housing for use in eliminating gang-related crime.<br/>Authorizes the Attorney General to: (1) designate and provide assistance to high-intensity gang activity areas; and (2) expand the Project Safe Neighborhoods program to require U.S. attorneys to identify and prosecute criminal street gangs in their respective districts.<br/>Amends the federal criminal code to: (1) expand the definition of &quot;criminal street gang&quot;; (2) prohibit the recruitment or solicitation of persons to participate in a criminal street gang; (3) impose enhanced penalties for committing violent crimes in furtherance or in aid of a criminal street gang and for use of firearms by felons with multiple felony convictions for violent crimes and drug offenses; (4) increase penalties for use of interstate commerce facilities in the commission of murder-for-hire or other felony crimes of violence; and (5) increase penalties for violent crimes in aid of racketeering activities.<br/>Extends the limitation period for prosecuting certain noncapital violent crimes. Requires the U.S. Sentencing Commission to review and revise guidelines relating to violent gang-related crimes.<br/>Provides for certain studies and reports relating to criminal gangs, including reports distinguishing criminal offenses committed by juveniles.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
