<bill session="110" type="s" number="999" updated="2009-01-09T13:50:50-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13" /></status>

	<introduced date="1174968000" datetime="2007-03-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Stroke Treatment and Ongoing Prevention Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Stroke Treatment and Ongoing Prevention Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to improve stroke prevention, diagnosis, treatment, and rehabilitation.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300023"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412242" joined="2007-12-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-04-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2007-06-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2007-03-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="2007-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-03-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-03-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-05-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="300052" joined="2007-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-03-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300088" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2008-04-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-10-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300019" joined="2007-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300068" joined="2008-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2007-09-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300081" joined="2007-03-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300037" joined="2007-03-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300007" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300035" joined="2007-04-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400418" joined="2007-06-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300014" joined="2007-09-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300001" joined="2007-04-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-06-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-10-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-03-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300075" joined="2007-06-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300036" joined="2007-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300021" joined="2007-04-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-04-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400054" joined="2007-03-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300069" joined="2007-06-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300026" joined="2007-06-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412244" joined="2008-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400194" joined="2007-04-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2007-05-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300099" joined="2007-03-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2007-05-11"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1174968000" datetime="2007-03-27"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13" ><text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1208318400" datetime="2008-04-16"><text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Reported by Senator Kennedy with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="699" date="1208318400" datetime="2008-04-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 699.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/16/2008--Reported to Senate amended. Stroke Treatment and Ongoing Prevention Act of 2008 - (Sec. 3) Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) establish and evaluate a grant program to enable states or consortia of states to develop stroke care systems; (2) foster the development of systems of stroke care through total quality improvement of health systems providing primary stroke prevention and identification, treatment, and rehabilitation of individuals who experience a stroke; (3) provide a state, consortia of states, and local agencies technical assistance; and (4) collaborate with appropriate medical and health professional associations to disseminate evidence-based practices on stroke systems of care. Authorizes the Secretary to award matching grants to states or consortia of states to develop and implement stroke care systems that provide high-quality prevention, diagnosis, treatment, and rehabilitation. Sets forth requirements for each state or consortium, including to: (1) establish, enhance, or expand a statewide stroke care system to promote the total quality improvement of stroke care consistent with evidence-based practices; (2) establish, enhance, or expand stroke care centers; (3) enhance, develop, and implement effective methods for training emergency medical services personnel in the identification, assessment, stabilization, and prehospital treatment of stroke patients; and (4) establish, enhance, or improve a support network to provide assistance to facilities with smaller populations of stroke patients or less advanced on-site stroke treatment resources. Allows each state or consortium to use grant funds to: (1) improve existing stroke prevention programs; (2) conduct a stroke education and information campaign; (3) make grants to public and nonprofit private entities for medical professional development; and (4) develop and implement education programs for appropriate medical personnel and health professionals in the use of evidence-based diagnostic approaches, technologies, and therapies for the prevention and treatment of stroke.<br/>Prohibits the Secretary from making payments to a state or consortium unless the state or consortium agrees that the payments will not be expended: (1) to make cash payments to intended recipients of services; (2) to satisfy any federal matching requirements; (3) to provide financial assistance to any entity other than a public or nonprofit private entity; or (4) for construction, alteration, or improvement of any building or facility.<br/>Authorizes the Secretary to give special consideration in awarding grants to any state or consortium: (1) in geographic areas in which there is an elevated incidence or prevalence of stroke or disability resulting from stroke or in an area that is underserved by medical specialists; (2) that demonstrates a significant need for assistance in establishing a comprehensive stroke care system; or (3) that will enhance regional cooperation.<br/>Authorizes appropriations for FY2008-FY2012.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
