<bill session="110" type="sc" number="106" updated="2009-01-09T19:53:06-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1227157200" datetime="2008-11-20"/></status>

	<introduced date="1227157200" datetime="2008-11-20"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A concurrent resolution commending the Government of Switzerland for ongoing assistance in the case of Robert Levinson, urging the Government of the Islamic Republic of Iran to intensify cooperation with the Government of Switzerland and the Federal Bureau of Investigation on the case of Robert Levinson, and expressing sympathy to the family of Robert Levinson.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300078"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1227157200" datetime="2008-11-20"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S10756-10757)</text></action>
		<action date="1227157200" datetime="2008-11-20"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S10756"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/20/2008--Introduced.<br/>Commends the Embassy of Switzerland in Tehran and the government of Switzerland for the ongoing assistance to the U.S. government and to the family of Robert Levinson. Expresses appreciation for efforts by Iranian officials to ensure the safety of Robert Levinson's family during their December 2007 visit to Iran, as well as for the promise of continued assistance. Urges: (1) the government of Iran to intensify its cooperation on the Levinson investigation with the Embassy of Switzerland in Tehran and to share the results of its investigation with the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI); and (2) the President and U.S. allies to engage with Iranian government officials to raise the Levinson case at every opportunity. Expresses sympathy to the family of Robert Levinson during this trying period.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
