<bill session="110" type="sc" number="55" updated="2009-01-09T19:46:57-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1195189200" datetime="2007-11-16" where="s" result="pass" how="by Unanimous Consent" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1195189200" datetime="2007-11-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A concurrent resolution commemorating the centennial anniversary of the sailing of the Navy's &quot;Great White Fleet&quot;, launched by President Theodore Roosevelt on December 16, 1907, from Hampton Roads, Virginia, and returning there on February 22, 1909.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300099"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412249" joined="2007-11-16"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<vote date="1195189200" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2007-11-16" where="s" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S14659-14660"/><reference label="text as passed Senate" ref="CR S14660"/><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S14645"/></vote>
		<action date="1195189200" datetime="2007-11-16"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<action date="1196791920" datetime="2007-12-04T14:12:00-05:00"><text>Received in the House.</text></action>
		<action date="1196744400" datetime="2007-12-04"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/16/2007--Passed Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Commemorates the wisdom of President Theodore Roosevelt in developing and launching the Great White Fleet. Supports a one-time designation of a day to celebrate the 100th centennial of the Great White Fleet and the special role it played in building enduring friendships with important allies and partner nations. Commends efforts by the Department of the Navy to: (1) maintain and strengthen our cooperative partnerships with foreign nations; (2) safeguard our Nation's interests in the maritime domain; and (3) lead the development of a Cooperative Strategy for 21st Century Seapower. Honors the sacrifices made and services rendered by the servicemembers of the Navy, Marine Corps, and the Coast Guard, and the civilians who constitute our maritime services.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
