<bill session="110" type="sc" number="63" updated="2009-01-09T19:47:55-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1200978000" datetime="2008-01-22" where="s" result="pass" how="by Unanimous Consent" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A concurrent resolution expressing the sense of the Congress regarding the need for additional research into the chronic neurological condition hydrocephalus, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300022"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300092" joined="2008-01-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1198040400" datetime="2007-12-19"><text>Referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S16018"/></action>
		<action date="1200978000" datetime="2008-01-22"><text>Senate Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S155-156"/></action>
		<vote date="1200978000" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2008-01-22" where="s" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>Resolution agreed to in Senate without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="text as passed Senate" ref="CR S155-156"/></vote>
		<action date="1201150800" datetime="2008-01-24"><text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text></action>
		<action date="1201543200" datetime="2008-01-28T14:00:00-05:00"><text>Received in the House.</text></action>
		<action date="1201548300" datetime="2008-01-28T15:25:00-05:00"><text>Held at the desk.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/22/2008--Passed Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)<br/>Commends the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) for working with leading scientists and researchers to organize the first-ever NIH conference on hydrocephalus (a neurological condition characterized by the abnormal buildup of cerebrospinal fluids in the ventricles of the brain).<br/>Urges the Director to continue the current collaboration with respect to hydrocephalus among national research institutes.<br/>Calls for: (1) further research into the epidemiology, pathophysiology, disease burden, and improved treatment of hydrocephalus; and (2) increased public awareness and professional education regarding hydrocephalus through partnerships between the federal government and patient advocacy organizations.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
