<bill session="110" type="sj" number="15" updated="2009-01-09T19:55:00-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1180065600" datetime="2007-05-25"/></status>

	<introduced date="1180065600" datetime="2007-05-25"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">United States Policy in Iraq Resolution of 2007</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A joint resolution to revise United States policy on Iraq.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300008"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1180065600" datetime="2007-05-25"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S6962-6963"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/25/2007--Introduced.<br/>United States Policy in Iraq Resolution of 2007 - Repeals the Authorization for Use of Military Force Against Iraq Resolution of 2002 (P.L. 107-243). Authorizes the President to continue participation by U.S. Armed Forces in Multi-National Force--Iraq, or as part of a successor force, for the purposes of: (1) protecting U.S. and coalition personnel and infrastructure; (2) training, equipping, and providing logistical support to Iraqi security forces; (3) conducting targeted counter-terrorism operations; and (4) assisting the government of Iraq maintain border security. States that such authorization shall expire 12 months after the date of enactment of this joint resolution unless extended by Congress. Directs the President to: (1) promptly transition the mission of U.S. forces in Iraq to such purposes; and (2) begin the phased redeployment of U.S. forces from Iraq not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this joint resolution, with the goal of redeploying by March 31, 2008, all U.S. combat forces from Iraq except for those essential for such purposes. Prohibits anything in this joint resolution from being construed to: (1) limit measures to provide for the security of the MultiNational Force-Iraq, including U.S. Armed Forces; and (2) authorize offensive combat activities by U.S. Armed Forces in Iran, Syria, or any other state in the Middle East.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
