<bill session="110" type="sr" number="141" updated="2009-01-09T20:16:02-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1177992000" datetime="2007-05-01" where="s" result="pass" how="by Unanimous Consent" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1176177600" datetime="2007-04-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution urging all member countries of the International Commission of the International Tracing Service who have yet to ratify the May 2006 amendments to the 1955 Bonn Accords to expedite the ratification process to allow for open access to the Holocaust archives located at Bad Arolsen, Germany.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300022"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2007-04-16"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2007-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2007-04-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300078" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300090" joined="2007-04-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2007-04-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1176177600" datetime="2007-04-10"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S4311-4312"/></action>
		<action date="1177992000" datetime="2007-05-01"><text>Senate Committee on Foreign Relations discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S5435"/></action>
		<vote date="1177992000" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2007-05-01" where="s" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>Resolution agreed to in Senate without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR S5435"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/1/2007--Passed Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Commends the countries that have: (1) ratified the amendments to the Agreement Constituting an International Commission for the International Tracing Service (&quot;Bonn Accords&quot;) to allow for open access to the Holocaust archives of the International Tracing Service (ITS) located at Bad Arolsen, Germany; and (2) committed to expedite the archives' release. Urges: (1) countries that have not ratified the amendments to abide by the May 2006 treaty obligations and expedite such ratification; and (2) member countries of the International Commission of the ITS to consider the short time left to Holocaust survivors and unanimously consent to open the ITS archives should all countries not ratify the amendments by May 2007. States that the Senate refuses to forget the Holocaust murder of 6 million Jews and more than 5 million other victims by Nazi perpetrators and their collaborators. 
	</summary>
</bill>
