<bill session="110" type="sr" number="142" updated="2009-01-09T20:16:09-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1176264000" datetime="2007-04-11" where="s" result="pass" how="by Unanimous Consent" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1176177600" datetime="2007-04-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution observing Yom Hashoah, Holocaust Memorial Day, and calling on the remaining member countries of the International Commission of the International Tracing Service to ratify the May 2006 amendments to the 1955 Bonn Accords immediately to allow open access to the Bad Arolsen archives.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300008"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412242" joined="2007-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-04-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300005" joined="2007-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="2007-04-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="2007-04-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-04-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400619" joined="2007-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-04-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="2007-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2007-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2007-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300061" joined="2007-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300078" joined="2007-04-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2007-04-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300099" joined="2007-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="2007-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2007-04-11"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1176177600" datetime="2007-04-10"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4312)</text></action>
		<action date="1176177600" datetime="2007-04-10"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S4312"/></action>
		<action date="1176264000" datetime="2007-04-11"><text>Senate Committee on Foreign Relations discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S4391"/></action>
		<vote date="1176264000" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2007-04-11" where="s" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>Resolution agreed to in Senate without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="text as passed Senate" ref="CR S4391"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/11/2007--Passed Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Joins people around the world in observing Yom Hashoah, Holocaust Memorial Day, and mourning the millions who were lost during the Holocaust. Commends the United States, the United Kingdom, Israel, Poland, and the Netherlands as the member countries of the International Commission of the International Tracing Service that have ratified the May 2006 amendments to the Agreement Constituting an International Commission for the International Tracing Service (Bonn Accords). Calls on: (1) Belgium, France, Germany, Greece, Italy, and Luxembourg, the member countries of the International Commission that have not yet ratified the May 2006 amendments to the Bonn Accords, to do so; and (2) the International Commission to approve the immediate distribution of copies of the documents from the Bad Arolsen archives that have already been digitized when the International Commission meets in Amsterdam in May 2007. Requests the Secretary of the Senate to transmit copies of this resolution to the Secretary of State and to the ambassadors of the member countries of the International Commission in the United States. 
	</summary>
</bill>
