<bill session="110" type="sr" number="178" updated="2009-01-09T20:20:32-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1205121600" datetime="2008-03-10" where="s" result="pass" how="by Unanimous Consent" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1177992000" datetime="2007-05-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sympathy of the Senate to the families of women and girls murdered in Guatemala, and encouraging the United States to work with Guatemala to bring an end to these crimes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300009"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="2007-06-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-09-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-10-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="2007-09-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-07-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-08-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="300068" joined="2007-12-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-12-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-09-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2007-08-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2007-07-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="300090" joined="2008-01-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2007-09-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1177992000" datetime="2007-05-01"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5399-5400)</text></action>
		<action date="1177992000" datetime="2007-05-01"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S5398-5399"/></action>
		<action date="1205121600" datetime="2008-03-10"><text>Senate Committee on Foreign Relations discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text></action>
		<action date="1205121600" datetime="2008-03-10"><text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S1823"/></action>
		<vote date="1205121600" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2008-03-10" where="s" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>Resolution agreed to in Senate with amendments and an amended preamble by Unanimous Consent. (text: CR 3/11/2008 S1890-1891)</text></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/10/2008--Passed Senate amended. Expresses condolences to the families of women and girls murdered in Guatemala and recognizes the families' courage in seeking justice. Expresses the solidarity of the people of the United States with the people of Guatemala in the face of these tragic acts. Condemns the ongoing abductions and murders of women and girls in Guatemala. Urges the government of Guatemala to: (1) strengthen laws with respect to domestic violence and sexual harassment, improve the integrity of the prosecutorial and judicial systems, and provide the resources to enforce justice for crimes against women; and (2) hold accountable law enforcement and judicial officials who have failed to investigate and prosecute the murders. Encourages the Secretary of State and the Attorney General to provide assistance in establishing a comprehensive missing persons system and a state protection program for witnesses, victims' relatives, and human rights defenders. Encourages the Secretary to support efforts to identify perpetrators and unknown victims through forensic analysis, including assisting the government of Guatemala in adequately funding the National Institute for Forensic Science (INACIF) and training lab personnel in investigatory and evidence gathering protocols. Recommends that the Secretary develop a comprehensive plan to combat the growing problem of violence against women in Latin America.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
