<bill session="110" type="sr" number="174" updated="2009-01-09T20:20:02-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1177560000" datetime="2007-04-26" where="s" result="pass" how="by Unanimous Consent" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1177560000" datetime="2007-04-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution honoring the entrepreneurial spirit of small business concerns in the United States during National Small Business Week, beginning April 22, 2007.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300060"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="2007-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400418" joined="2007-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2007-04-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300006" joined="2007-04-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<vote date="1177560000" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2007-04-26" where="s" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S5255-5257"/><reference label="text as passed Senate" ref="CR S5256-5257"/><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S5222"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/26/2007--Passed Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Honors the entrepreneurial spirit of small businesses during National Small Business Week beginning April 22, 2007. Applauds the efforts and achievements of small business owners and their employees. Recognizes the work of the Small Business Administration (SBA) and its resource partners in providing assistance to entrepreneurs and small businesses. Urges the President to ensure that: (1) applicable small business procurement goals are reached by federal agencies; (2) SBA guaranteed loans and venture capital are made available to all qualified small businesses; (3) SBA management assistance programs are provided with the federal resources necessary to do their jobs; and (4) reforms to the SBA disaster loan program are made as quickly as possible. Urges that the SBA continue to be designated as a major agency in the President's annual budget and that the SBA Administrator have an active role as a member of the President's Cabinet.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
