<bill session="110" type="sr" number="193" updated="2009-01-09T20:22:18-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1178769600" datetime="2007-05-10" where="s" result="pass" how="by Unanimous Consent" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1178769600" datetime="2007-05-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution designating the week of May 6 through May 12, 2007, as &quot;North American Occupational Safety and Health Week&quot; and May 9, 2007, as &quot;Occupational Safety and Health Professional Day&quot;.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300038"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-05-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-05-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400194" joined="2007-05-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<vote date="1178769600" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2007-05-10" where="s" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S6001, "/><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S5950"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/10/2007--Passed Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)<br/>Designates the week of May 6 through May 12, 2007, as North American Occupational Safety and Health (NAOSH) Week and May 9, 2007, as Occupational Safety and Health Professional Day.<br/>Commends: (1) occupational safety, health, and environmental practitioners for their ongoing commitment to protecting people, property, and the environment; and (2) businesses that encourage a strong safety culture and incorporate occupational safety and health into their business strategies.<br/>Encourages all industries, organizations, community leaders, employers, and employees to join with the American Society of Safety Engineers to support activities aimed at increasing awareness of the importance of preventing illness, injury, and death in the workplace during NAOSH Week and throughout the year.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
