<bill session="110" type="sr" number="209" updated="2009-01-09T20:24:16-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1179374400" datetime="2007-05-17" where="s" result="pass" how="by Unanimous Consent" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1179374400" datetime="2007-05-17"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing support for the new power-sharing government in Northern Ireland.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300059"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300008" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300071" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-05-17"/>
		<cosponsor id="300090" joined="2007-05-17"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<vote date="1179374400" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2007-05-17" where="s" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S6359-6360"/><reference label="text as passed Senate" ref="CR S6360"/><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S6311-6312"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/17/2007--Passed Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) the United States strongly supports the new power-sharing government in Northern Ireland; (2) political leaders of Northern Ireland, Prime Minister Tony Blair, and Taoiseach Bertie Ahern should be commended for acting in the best interest of the people of Northern Ireland by forming this government; (3) May 8, 2007, will be remembered as an historic day and an important milestone in cementing peace and unity for Northern Ireland and an example for nations around the world plagued by internal conflict; and (4) the United States stands ready to support this new government and to work with the people of Northern Ireland as they achieve their goal of lasting peace. 
	</summary>
</bill>
