<bill session="110" type="sr" number="223" updated="2009-01-09T20:26:01-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1181188800" datetime="2007-06-07" where="s" result="pass" how="by Unanimous Consent" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1181102400" datetime="2007-06-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution recognizing the efforts and contributions of the members of the Monuments, Fine Arts, and Archives program under the Civil Affairs and Military Government Sections of the United States Armed Forces during and following World War II who were responsible for the preservation, protection, and restitution of artistic and cultural treasures in countries occupied by the Allied armies.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300055"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300094" joined="2007-06-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-06-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-06-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-06-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300054" joined="2007-06-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300001" joined="2007-06-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-06-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-06-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300100" joined="2007-06-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2007-06-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1181188800" datetime="2007-06-07"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S7195-7196)</text></action>
		<vote date="1181188800" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2007-06-07" where="s" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S7269-7270"/><reference label="text as passed Senate" ref="CR S7269-7270"/><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S7195"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/7/2007--Passed Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Recognizes the men and women who served in the Monuments, Fine Arts, and Archives program under the Civil Affairs and Military Government Sections of the U.S. Armed Forces for their heroic role in the preservation, protection, and restitution of monuments, works of art, and other artifacts of inestimable cultural importance in Europe and Asia during and following World War II. 
	</summary>
</bill>
