<bill session="110" type="sr" number="258" updated="2009-01-09T20:30:17-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1192680000" datetime="2007-10-18" where="s" result="pass" how="by Unanimous Consent" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1182916800" datetime="2007-06-27"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution recognizing the historical and educational significance of the Atlantic Freedom Tour of the Freedom Schooner Amistad, and expressing the sense of the Senate that preserving the legacy of the Amistad story is important in promoting multicultural dialogue, education, and cooperation.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300034"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-06-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1182916800" datetime="2007-06-27"><text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S8621"/></action>
		<calendar date="1190865600" datetime="2007-09-27" ><text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1190865600" datetime="2007-09-27"><text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Leahy without amendment and with a preamble. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="399" date="1190865600" datetime="2007-09-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 399.</text></calendar>
		<vote date="1192680000" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2007-10-18" where="s" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>Resolution agreed to in Senate without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S13134"/><reference label="text as passed Senate" ref="CR S13134"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/18/2007--Passed Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.) Recognizes the historical and educational significance of the Freedom Schooner Amistad's Atlantic Freedom Tour. Encourages the people of the United States to learn about U.S. history and better understand the experiences that have shaped this nation. Declares that it is the sense of the Senate that preserving the legacy of the Amistad should be regarded as a means of fostering multicultural dialogue, education, and cooperation.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
