<bill session="110" type="sr" number="276" updated="2009-01-09T20:32:31-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1185854400" datetime="2007-07-31" where="s" result="pass" how="by Unanimous Consent" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1184817600" datetime="2007-07-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution calling for the urgent deployment of a robust and effective multinational peacekeeping mission with sufficient size, resources, leadership, and mandate to protect civilians in Darfur, Sudan, and for efforts to strengthen the renewal of a just and inclusive peace process.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300008"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="2007-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2007-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300070" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2007-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300082" joined="2007-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="300098" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300052" joined="2007-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2007-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="2007-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300092" joined="2007-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="300013" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300016" joined="2007-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300068" joined="2007-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300035" joined="2007-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2007-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300080" joined="2007-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300078" joined="2007-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300050" joined="2007-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300021" joined="2007-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300006" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300095" joined="2007-07-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400054" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2007-07-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="400194" joined="2007-07-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="300099" joined="2007-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="300090" joined="2007-07-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2007-07-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1184817600" datetime="2007-07-19"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S9625)</text></action>
		<action date="1184817600" datetime="2007-07-19"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S9624-9625"/></action>
		<action date="1185854400" datetime="2007-07-31"><text>Senate Committee on Foreign Relations discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text></action>
		<action date="1185854400" datetime="2007-07-31"><text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S10525"/></action>
		<vote date="1185854400" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2007-07-31" where="s" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>Resolution agreed to in Senate with amendments and an amended preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/31/2007--Passed Senate amended. Urges the President of the United States to: (1) work with members of the U.N. Security Council and the African Union (AU) to ensure deployment of the United Nations-African Union peacekeeping force to protect civilians in Darfur, Sudan; (2) work bilaterally and with member states of the North Atlantic Trade Organization (NATO), the United Nations, the European Union (EU), the AU, and other partners to assist such force; and (3) work with Congress to ensure funding for such force. Urges: (1) the Secretary-General of the United Nations and the Chairperson of the AU to expedite such force's deployment; and (2) President al-Bashir and the government of Sudan to facilitate such deployment without condition; and (3) the President's Special Envoy to Sudan to continue his legislative outreach to bring peace to Darfur through an inclusive political process. Urges all participants in the Darfur conflict, including rebel movements that were not signatories to the Darfur Peace Agreement, to participate in a U.N.-AU political process in order to return peace to Darfur. Regards failure to participate in such process as a political obstruction that may be worthy of international sanctions. Urges President Bush, the Security Council, the AU, the EU, the League of Arab States, regional nations, and individual nations with economic or political influence over Sudan to: (1) hold President al-Bashir and the government of Sudan accountable for any failure to facilitate such force's deployment; and (2) be prepared to implement meaningful measures, including sanctions, an arms embargo, and a no fly zone for Sudanese military flights over Darfur if the government of Sudan obstructs the peacekeeping mission's deployment.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
