<bill session="110" type="sr" number="320" updated="2009-01-09T20:37:57-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1190347200" datetime="2007-09-21" where="s" result="pass" how="by Unanimous Consent" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1190088000" datetime="2007-09-18"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution recognizing the achievements of the people of Ukraine in pursuit of freedom and democracy, and expressing the hope that the parliamentary elections on September 30, 2007, preserve and extend these gains and provide for a stable and representative government.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300008"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300070" joined="2007-09-18"/>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="2007-09-18"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1190088000" datetime="2007-09-18"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S11667"/></action>
		<action date="1190347200" datetime="2007-09-21"><text>Senate Committee on Foreign Relations discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S11954"/></action>
		<vote date="1190347200" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2007-09-21" where="s" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>Resolution agreed to in Senate without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="text as passed Senate" ref="CR S11954"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/21/2007--Passed Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Acknowledges the cooperation and friendship between the people of the United States and the people of Ukraine since the restoration of Ukraine's independence in 1991. Expresses the admiration of the American people for the ongoing success of the Ukranian people at removing violence from politics, in particular the 2004 presidential elections and the 2006 parliamentary elections. Encourages the people of Ukraine to maintain the democratic successes of the Orange Revolution of 2004. Pledges continued U.S. assistance to the further development of a free and representative democratic government in Ukraine based on the rule of law and the principle of human rights.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
