<bill session="110" type="sr" number="339" updated="2009-01-09T20:40:18-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1191211200" datetime="2007-10-01" where="s" result="pass" how="by Unanimous Consent" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1191211200" datetime="2007-10-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate on the situation in Burma.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300060"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300070" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300082" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300008" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300071" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300013" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300054" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-10-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300050" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300095" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2007-10-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300072" joined="2007-10-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<vote date="1191211200" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2007-10-01" where="s" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S12386-12388"/><reference label="text as passed Senate" ref="CR S12387-12388"/><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S12383"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	10/1/2007--Passed Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Expresses the sense of the Senate: (1) condemning the use of violence against peaceful protesters in Burma; (2) calling on the government of Burma to refrain from further violence, release arrested demonstrators, cease attacks against ethnic minorities, release Aung Sang Suu Kyi and other political prisoners, and begin tripartite political dialogue with Suu Kyi, the National League for Democracy, and the ethnic minorities; (3) calling on the People's Republic of China (PRC) to remove objections to U.N. Security Council efforts to condemn actions taken by the government of Burma against the protesters; (4) calling on the PRC and other nations to suspend military assistance to Burma until civilian democratic rule is restored; (5) recognizing the many constructive statements issued by various nations, and particularly the statement issued by the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) on September 27, 2007; (6) that the United States and the United Nations should strongly encourage the PRC, India, and Russia to modify their position on Burma and use their influence to convince the government of Burma to engage in dialogue with opposition leaders and ethnic minorities; (7) supporting the U.N. mission to Burma led by Ibrahim Gambari; and (8) that the United States should work with the international community to pressure the government of Burma to lift restrictions on humanitarian aid delivery.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
