<bill session="110" type="sr" number="372" updated="2009-01-09T20:44:24-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1194498000" datetime="2007-11-08"/></status>

	<introduced date="1194498000" datetime="2007-11-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate on the declaration of a state of emergency in Pakistan.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300060"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300008" joined="2007-11-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2007-11-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2007-11-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2007-11-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1194498000" datetime="2007-11-08"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S14201-14202"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	11/8/2007--Introduced.<br/>Expresses the sense of the Senate: (1) condemning the decision by President Pervez Musharraf of Pakistan to declare a state of emergency in Pakistan and calling on President Musharraf to revoke the state of emergency; (2) calling upon President Musharraf to honor his commitment to relinquish his position as Chief of Army Staff of Pakistan and allow free parliamentary elections in accordance with the Constitution of Pakistan; (3) that the U.S. government should provide assistance to facilitate such elections; (4) calling upon the government of Pakistan to conduct a full investigation into the attempted assassination of former Prime Minister of Pakistan Benazir Bhutto; and (5) that U.S. military assistance to Pakistan should be subjected to careful review, and that assistance for certain weapons systems not directly related to the fight against Al Qaeda and the Taliban should be suspended if President Musharraf does not revoke the state of emergency and restore the Constitution of Pakistan, relinquish his position as Chief of Army Staff of Pakistan, and allow for free elections. 
	</summary>
</bill>
