<bill session="110" type="sr" number="376" updated="2009-01-09T20:44:54-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1196744400" datetime="2007-12-04" where="s" result="pass" how="by Unanimous Consent" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1194930000" datetime="2007-11-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution providing the sense of the Senate that the Secretary of Commerce should declare a commercial fishery failure for the groundfish fishery for Massachusetts, Maine, New Hampshire, and Rhode Island and immediately propose regulations to implement section 312(a) of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300060"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2007-11-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300081" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300095" joined="2007-11-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300049" joined="2007-11-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1194930000" datetime="2007-11-13"><text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S14300-14301"/></action>
		<action date="1196744400" datetime="2007-12-04"><text>Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text></action>
		<vote date="1196744400" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2007-12-04" where="s" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>Resolution agreed to in Senate without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S14746-14747"/><reference label="text" ref="CR S14746-14747"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	12/4/2007--Passed Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.) Declares that the Secretary of Commerce should reconsider a decision to deny the requests of the Commonwealth of Massachusetts and the states of Maine and Rhode Island for a groundfish fishery failure declaration, look favorably on the request of the state of New Hampshire for such a declaration, and immediately propose regulations implementing related fisheries disaster relief provisions of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
