<bill session="110" type="sr" number="399" updated="2009-01-09T20:48:09-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1197262800" datetime="2007-12-10"/></status>

	<introduced date="1197262800" datetime="2007-12-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate that certain benchmarks must be met before certain restrictions against the Government of North Korea are lifted, and that the United States Government should not provide any financial assistance to North Korea until the Secretary of State makes certain certifications regarding the submission of applications for refugee status.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300013"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300029" joined="2007-12-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300062" joined="2007-12-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300014" joined="2007-12-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300048" joined="2007-12-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2007-12-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1197262800" datetime="2007-12-10"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S15077-15078"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	12/10/2007--Introduced.<br/>States that restrictions imposed on the government of North Korea as a result of its being determined to be a government that has repeatedly supported acts of international terrorism should not be lifted until benchmarks have been met respecting: (1) missile or nuclear technology transfers; (2) cessation of terrorist activities and support of terrorist groups and terrorist activities; (3) counterfeiting of U.S. currency; (4) release of South Korean POWs, Japanese nationals, and Kim Donk-Shik; and (5) Bureau 39's closure. States that the U.S. government should not provide financial assistance (other than humanitarian assistance) to North Korea until the Secretary of State makes certain certifications regarding refugee status applications. 
	</summary>
</bill>
