<bill session="110" type="sr" number="439" updated="2009-01-09T20:53:09-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1202965200" datetime="2008-02-14" where="s" result="pass" how="by Unanimous Consent" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1201755600" datetime="2008-01-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the strong support of the Senate for the North Atlantic Treaty Organization to enter into a Membership Action Plan with Georgia and Ukraine.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300070"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300008" joined="2008-01-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400105" joined="2008-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300047" joined="2008-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300098" joined="2008-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300071" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2008-02-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2008-02-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="300021" joined="2008-02-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2008-02-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1201755600" datetime="2008-01-31"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S550-551)</text></action>
		<action date="1201755600" datetime="2008-01-31"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S550"/></action>
		<calendar date="1202878800" datetime="2008-02-13" ><text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1202878800" datetime="2008-02-13"><text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Biden without amendment and with a preamble. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="574" date="1202878800" datetime="2008-02-13" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 574.</text></calendar>
		<vote date="1202965200" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2008-02-14" where="s" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>Resolution agreed to in Senate without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S1083-1084"/><reference label="text as passed Senate" ref="CR S1084"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/14/2008--Passed Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the Senate reported version is repeated here.) Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives: (1) reaffirming support for enlargement of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) to include democratic governments that are able to meet the membership responsibilities; (2) that NATO's expansion contributes to its relevance; (3) that Georgia and Ukraine are strong allies that have made important progress in the areas of defense and democratic and human rights reform; (4) that a stronger relationship among Georgia, Ukraine, and NATO will benefit those countries and NATO member states; and (5) that the United States should take the lead in supporting the awarding of a Membership Action Plan to Georgia and Ukraine. 
	</summary>
</bill>
