<bill session="110" type="sr" number="433" updated="2009-01-09T20:52:24-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29" where="s" result="pass" how="by Unanimous Consent" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1201582800" datetime="2008-01-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution honoring the brave men and women of the United States Coast Guard whose tireless work, dedication, and selfless service to the United States have led to more than 1 million lives saved over the course of its long and storied 217-year history.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300094"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300075" joined="2008-01-29"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<vote date="1201582800" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2008-01-29" where="s" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S454-455"/><reference label="text as passed Senate" ref="CR S455"/><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S449"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/29/2008--Passed Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Honors the heroic accomplishments of Petty Officer Willard Milam, who represented the finest traditions of the United States Coast Guard during the rescue of four survivors from the Bering Sea. Honors the U.S. Coast Guard, America's lifesavers and guardians of the sea, for its unflinching determination and proud 217-year history of maritime search and rescue, resulting in over 1 million lives saved, and recognizes the tireless work, dedication, and commitment of Coast Guard men and women who commit themselves to executing this noble mission with honor, respect, and devotion to duty.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
