<bill session="110" type="sr" number="445" updated="2009-01-09T20:53:52-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1202360400" datetime="2008-02-07"/></status>

	<introduced date="1202360400" datetime="2008-02-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate on the assassination of former Prime Minister of Pakistan Benazir Bhutto, and the political crisis in Pakistan.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300008"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2008-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300005" joined="2008-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300025" joined="2008-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300082" joined="2008-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2008-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300051" joined="2008-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2008-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2008-02-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2008-02-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1202360400" datetime="2008-02-07"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S795-796)</text></action>
		<action date="1202360400" datetime="2008-02-07"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S794-795"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/7/2008--Introduced.<br/>Conveys the condolences of the people of the United States to the people of Pakistan on the tragic loss of former Prime Minister Benazir Bhutto. Condemns the December 2007 murder of Benazir Bhutto and the slaughter of at least 165 other Pakistani citizens in this attack and the prior attempt on Benazir Bhutto's life. Calls upon the government of Pakistan to: (1) bring the perpetrators to justice and to support an independent inquiry into the assassination of Benazir Bhutto; (2) ensure that free elections are held on February 18, 2008, as scheduled; (3) end the harassment of judges, opposition party activists, and lawyers; and (4) end restrictions on the media and freedom of speech. Calls upon the President to: (1) review U.S. aid to Pakistan to ensure that all assistance furthers the common goals shared by the people of Pakistan and the United States, with specific reference to combating violent radicalism and promoting a free and democratic Pakistan; and (2) suspend weapons transfers to Pakistan if such conditions are not met.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
