<bill session="110" type="sr" number="470" updated="2009-01-09T20:56:51-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1208145600" datetime="2008-04-14" where="s" result="pass" how="by Unanimous Consent" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1204606800" datetime="2008-03-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution calling on the relevant governments, multilateral bodies, and non-state actors in Chad, the Central African Republic, and Sudan to devote ample political commitment and material resources towards the achievement and implementation of a negotiated resolution to the national and regional conflicts in Chad, the Central African Republic, and Darfur, Sudan.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300042"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412242" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="2008-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300070" joined="2008-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="2008-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2008-04-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300008" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300098" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2008-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400621" joined="2008-04-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="2008-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300013" joined="2008-04-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2008-03-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300078" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300050" joined="2008-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2008-04-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400194" joined="2008-04-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1204606800" datetime="2008-03-04"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S1530"/></action>
		<action date="1208145600" datetime="2008-04-14"><text>Senate Committee on Foreign Relations discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S2982-2983"/></action>
		<vote date="1208145600" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2008-04-14" where="s" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>Resolution agreed to in Senate without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR S2982-2983"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/14/2008--Passed Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.) Expresses the concern and compassion of the citizens of the United States for the citizens of Sudan, Chad, and the Central African Republic who have been gravely affected by interrelated violence and instability in these countries. Calls upon all parties to these conflicts to cease hostilities and uphold basic human rights. Urges the governments of Chad and Sudan, with support from regional and international stakeholders, including France, Libya, and China, to commit to another round of negotiations towards a sustainable political solution for national and regional stability. Urges the government of Chad to strengthen democratic institutions, respect human rights, and uphold its commitment to protect its own citizens. Encourages the U.S. government and the international community to support the multilateral peacekeeping missions in Darfur, eastern Chad, and the northern Central African Republic, along with assistance to meet the continuing humanitarian and security needs in these areas.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
