<bill session="110" type="sr" number="486" updated="2009-01-09T20:58:57-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1205467200" datetime="2008-03-14" where="s" result="pass" how="by Unanimous Consent" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1205380800" datetime="2008-03-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution to congratulate the X PRIZE Foundation for their efforts to inspire a new generation of viable, super-efficient vehicles that could help break the addiction of the United States to oil and stem the effects of climate change through the Automotive X PRIZE competition.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300009"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300070" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300068" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300040" joined="2008-03-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300036" joined="2008-03-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<vote date="1205467200" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2008-03-14" where="s" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S2165-2166"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/14/2008--Passed Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)<br/>Commends the X PRIZE Foundation's leadership for their efforts to inspire a new generation of viable, super-efficient vehicles through the Automotive X PRIZE competition. Congratulates the Foundation on its innovation and vision in bringing together some of the finest minds in government, higher education, and industry to participate in the competition and applauds its commitment for encouraging solutions to some of the greatest challenges facing humanity.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
