<bill session="110" type="sr" number="524" updated="2009-01-09T21:03:46-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1209355200" datetime="2008-04-28" where="s" result="pass" how="by Unanimous Consent" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1208836800" datetime="2008-04-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution honoring the entrepreneurial spirit of the owners of small business concerns in the United States during National Small Business Week, beginning April 21, 2008.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300060"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2008-04-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300041" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400546" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300035" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400418" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300080" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="300006" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412244" joined="2008-04-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="400194" joined="2008-04-22"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1208836800" datetime="2008-04-22"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3260-3261)</text></action>
		<action date="1208836800" datetime="2008-04-22"><text>Referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S3260"/></action>
		<action date="1209355200" datetime="2008-04-28"><text>Senate Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text></action>
		<vote date="1209355200" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2008-04-28" where="s" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>Resolution agreed to in Senate without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S3452"/><reference label="text as passed Senate" ref="CR S3452"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	4/28/2008--Passed Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Honors the entrepreneurial spirit of small business owners during National Small Business Week beginning April 21, 2008. Honors the efforts and achievements of small business owners and their employees. Recognizes that small businesses are essential to restoring the country's economic health. Recognizes the vital role of Small Business Administration (SBA) programs, employees, and resource partners in providing assistance to entrepreneurs and small business owners. Urges the President to ensure that: (1) reasonable rules relating to the federal contract procurement program for women-owned small businesses are expeditiously implemented; (2) small businesses have access to quality, affordable health insurance; (3) the needs of veterans and reservists who own, work for, or wish to start a business are met during deployment and upon their return from duty; (4) measures are enacted to provide a stimulus for business lending during the current economic downturn; (5) small business tax burdens and regulatory and bureaucratic barriers are reduced; (6) all federal agencies adhere to contracting goals for small businesses; (7) venture capital and small business loans are available to all qualified small businesses; and (8) necessary federal resources are provided to management assistance programs delivered by SBA resource partners. Urges that the SBA Administrator have an active role as a member of the President's Cabinet.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
