<bill session="110" type="sr" number="541" updated="2009-01-09T21:05:57-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1211342400" datetime="2008-05-21" where="s" result="pass" how="by Unanimous Consent" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1209441600" datetime="2008-04-29"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution supporting humanitarian assistance, protection of civilians, accountability for abuses in Somalia, and urging concrete progress in line with the Transitional Federal Charter of Somalia toward the establishment of a viable government of national unity.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300042"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412242" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2008-05-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2008-05-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300050" joined="2008-04-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2008-05-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1209441600" datetime="2008-04-29"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3516)</text></action>
		<action date="1209441600" datetime="2008-04-29"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S3515-3516"/></action>
		<action date="1211342400" datetime="2008-05-21"><text>Senate Committee on Foreign Relations discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S4705-4706"/></action>
		<vote date="1211342400" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2008-05-21" where="s" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>Resolution agreed to in Senate without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR S4705-4706"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/21/2008--Passed Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.) Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) the United States remains committed to the people of Somalia and to helping build the institutions necessary for a stable and peaceful nation; and (2) the President, in partnership with the African Union, the United Nations, and the international community, should provide humanitarian assistance, ensure accountability for parties responsible for violations of human rights and international humanitarian law in Somalia, and call on all parties to recommit to an inclusive dialogue to promote peace and security in Somalia and across the Horn of Africa. Urges the governments of Ethiopia and of Eritrea to assist in helping to bring about stability to Somalia. States that the Transitional Federal government should: (1) take necessary steps to protect civilians from dangers related to military operations; (2) recommit to the Transitional Federal Charter; and (3) agree to participate in an inclusive political process towards the formation of a government of national unity based on the principles of democracy, accountability, and the rule of law. 
	</summary>
</bill>
