<bill session="110" type="sr" number="570" updated="2009-01-09T21:09:33-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1211169600" datetime="2008-05-19" where="s" result="pass" how="by Unanimous Consent" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1211169600" datetime="2008-05-19"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution congratulating Albania and Croatia on being invited to begin accession talks with the North Atlantic Treaty Organization and expressing support for continuing to enlarge the alliance.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300098"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300070" joined="2008-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300008" joined="2008-05-19"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2008-05-19"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<vote date="1211169600" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2008-05-19" where="s" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S4424"/><reference label="text as passed Senate" ref="CR S4424"/><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S4378"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	5/19/2008--Passed Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Congratulates Albania and Croatia on being invited by the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) to begin accession talks. Supports: (1) the invitations to initiate an Intensified Dialogue between NATO and Bosnia and Herzegovina, Montenegro, and Serbia; (2) the aspirations of Ukraine and Georgia to become integrated into the Euro-Atlantic community; and (3) the enlargement of NATO, and the NATO declaration at the Bucharest Summit that NATO should remain open to European democracies able to assume membership responsibilities. Affirms that any decision about NATO membership will be made through member consensus and that no country outside of NATO has a vote or veto with respect to such decisions.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
