<bill session="110" type="sr" number="600" updated="2009-01-09T21:13:25-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1214280000" datetime="2008-06-24" where="s" result="pass" how="by Unanimous Consent" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1214280000" datetime="2008-06-24"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution commemorating the 44th anniversary of the deaths of civil rights workers Andrew Goodman, James Chaney, and Michael Schwerner in Philadelphia, Mississippi, while working in the name of American democracy to register voters and secure civil rights during the summer of 1964, which has become known as &quot;Freedom Summer&quot;.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400629"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="2008-06-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2008-06-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="300092" joined="2008-06-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<vote date="1214280000" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2008-06-24" where="s" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S6095-6096"/><reference label="text as passed Senate" ref="CR S6095-6096"/><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S6025-6026"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	6/24/2008--Passed Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Encourages all Americans to pause and remember Andrew Goodman, James Chaney, and Michael Schwerner and the 44th anniversary of their deaths. Commemorates their lives and work, and those of all other brave Americans who made the ultimate sacrifice in the name of civil rights and voting rights for all Americans. Commemorates and acknowledges the legacy of the brave Americans who participated in the civil rights movement and the role that they played in changing the hearts and minds of Americans, and creating the political climate necessary to pass legislation to expand such rights.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
