<bill session="110" type="sr" number="612" updated="2009-01-09T21:14:54-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1216008000" datetime="2008-07-14" where="s" result="pass" how="by Unanimous Consent" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1216008000" datetime="2008-07-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate that President George W. Bush, President Dmitry Medvedev of the Russian Federation, and other participants in the 2008 Group of Eight (G8) Summit in Toyako, Hokkaido, Japan should work together to foster a more constructive relationship, and that the Government of the Russian Federation should eschew behaviors that are inconsistent with the Group's objectives of protecting global security, economic stability, and democracy.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300008"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2008-07-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2008-07-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<vote date="1216008000" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2008-07-14" where="s" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S6670-6671"/><reference label="text as passed Senate" ref="CR S6670-6671"/><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S6653-6654"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/14/2008--Passed Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) the United States and the G8 nations should pursue a broad agenda of cooperation with the Russian Federation; (2) the Russian Federation should respect the rights of governments in neighboring countries and their prerogative to seek membership in Euro-Atlantic institutions; (3) the United States and the Russian Federation should work to ensure the continued success of Nunn-Lugar initiatives and nonproliferation and counterterrorism programs; (4) the Russian Federation should adopt foreign and domestic policies that are consistent with freedom and the right to private property; and (5) the United States should welcome the emergence of the Russian Federation as a partner in addressing global challenges. 
	</summary>
</bill>
