<bill session="110" type="sr" number="632" updated="2009-01-09T21:17:23-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1217390400" datetime="2008-07-30"/></status>

	<introduced date="1217390400" datetime="2008-07-30"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution calling on the Governments of the People's Republic of China and the international community to use the upcoming Olympic Games as an opportunity to push for the parties to the conflicts in Sudan, Chad, and the Central African Republic to cease hostilities and revive efforts toward a peaceful resolution of their national and regional conflicts.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300042"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412242" joined="2008-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2008-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="400064" joined="2008-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2008-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2008-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300013" joined="2008-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2008-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2008-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="300091" joined="2008-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2008-07-30"/>
		<cosponsor id="300058" joined="2008-07-30"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1217390400" datetime="2008-07-30"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S7789-7790"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/30/2008--Introduced.<br/>Expresses continued support and sympathy for the hundreds of thousands of civilians of Sudan, Chad, and the Central African Republic who have been affected by the ongoing violence and regional instability. Urges: (1) the United Nations, the African Union, and other international leaders to use the unique opportunity presented by the Olympics to promote peace, dialogue, and reconciliation in areas of conflict; (2) the government of China to press the Sudanese government to commit to a cessation of hostilities, allow the full deployment of UNAMID peacekeeping forces, and engage in good faith in efforts to rejuvenate peace talks; (3) the government of Sudan and other armed actors in the region to cease hostilities; (3) the President and the international community to ensure that mediation efforts are supported and backed by credible leverage through targeted pressure and an enforced arms embargo; and (4) the United Nations and the African Union to use the opportunity presented by a cessation of hostilities to fully deploy and equip UNAMID as well as strengthen the UN Mission in Sudan to better monitor the Abyei region. Welcomes the efforts of the new joint African Union-United Nations mediator, Mr. Djibril Bassole, to revive a comprehensive peace process, demobilize militias, and promote voluntary return of internally displaced persons and refugees. Encourages the UN Secretary-General and other international leaders to publicly promote the principles reflected in the Olympic Truce among all the warring parties in Sudan, Chad, the Central African Republic, and other conflict areas around the world.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
