<bill session="110" type="sr" number="638" updated="2009-01-09T21:18:08-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"/></status>

	<introduced date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution supporting legislation promoting improved health care and access to health care for women.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300093"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412242" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300059" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300018" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300073" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="412243" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="400629" joined="2008-07-31"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2008-07-31"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S7975-7976)</text></action>
		<action date="1217476800" datetime="2008-07-31"><text>Referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S7975"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	7/31/2008--Introduced.<br/>Declares that the Senate commits to pass, and urges the President sign, within 18 months, legislation that guarantees health care for all people of the United States and that: (1) recognizes the role of women as health care consumers, caregivers, and providers; (2) guarantees inclusion of benefits essential to achieving and maintaining good health; (3) promotes primary and preventive care; (4) provides a choice of public and private plans and direct access to a choice of doctors and health providers that ensures continuity of coverage and a delivery system that meets the needs of women; (5) eliminates disparities on the basis of gender, culture, race, ethnicity, socioeconomic status, health status, or sexual orientation; (6) shares financing responsibility among employers, individuals, and the government while taking into account small business needs; (7) ensures affordable access to health care; (8) enhances quality and patient safety; (9) ensures a sufficient supply of qualified providers through expanded medical and public health education and adequate reimbursement; and (10) promotes administrative efficiency and is easy to utilize.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
