<bill session="110" type="sr" number="643" updated="2009-01-09T21:18:46-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1221624000" datetime="2008-09-17" where="s" result="pass" how="by Unanimous Consent" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution calling for greater dialogue between the Dalai Lama and the Government of China regarding rights for the people of Tibet, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300090"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300042" joined="2008-08-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S8048)</text></action>
		<action date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S8048"/></action>
		<action date="1221624000" datetime="2008-09-17"><text>Senate Committee on Foreign Relations discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S8960-8961"/></action>
		<action date="1221624000" datetime="2008-09-17"><text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text></action>
		<vote date="1221624000" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2008-09-17" where="s" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>Resolution agreed to in Senate without amendment and an amended preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR S8960-8961"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/17/2008--Passed Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Urges the Dalai Lama or his representatives and the government of the People's Republic of China (PRC) to begin negotiations for a solution that addresses the legitimate grievances of, and provides genuine autonomy for, the Tibetan people. Affirms that the human rights of Tibetans and their right to practice religion free of government regulation is not an internal matter of any one country. Calls on the U.S. government to press the PRC to: (1) respect freedom of speech and freedom of association and to release those who have committed no crime other than peaceful protest; and (2) allow Tibetans to practice their religion freely.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
