<bill session="110" type="sr" number="648" updated="2009-01-09T21:19:22-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1222056000" datetime="2008-09-22" where="s" result="pass" how="by Unanimous Consent" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution recognizing the 50th anniversary of the crossing of the North Pole by the USS Nautilus (SSN 571) and its significance in the history of both our Nation and the world.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300034"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300081" joined="2008-08-01"/>
		<cosponsor id="300067" joined="2008-08-01"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1217563200" datetime="2008-08-01"><text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S8050"/></action>
		<action date="1222056000" datetime="2008-09-22"><text>Senate Committee on Armed Services discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR S9179-9185"/></action>
		<vote date="1222056000" how="by Unanimous Consent" datetime="2008-09-22" where="s" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>Resolution agreed to in Senate without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR S9181-9182"/></vote>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	9/22/2008--Passed Senate without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.) Recognizes the historic significance of the journey to, and successful crossing of, the North Pole by the USS Nautilus. Commends its officers and crew on the 50th anniversary of such achievement. Recognizes the Nautilus's journey as not only a military and scientific accomplishment, but also in confirming America's long-standing interest in that vital region. Commends the role of the Nautilus and the U.S. submarine force in protecting the interests of the free world during the Cold War. Supports the continuing role of the U.S. submarine force in defending our country in the 21st century.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
