<bill session="110" type="sr" number="65" updated="2009-01-09T20:06:36-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1175054400" datetime="2007-03-28" /></status>

	<introduced date="1170306000" datetime="2007-02-01"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution condemning the murder of Turkish-Armenian journalist and human rights advocate Hrant Dink and urging the people of Turkey to honor his legacy of tolerance.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300008"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412242" joined="2007-04-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2007-03-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2007-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="300024" joined="2007-03-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400619" joined="2007-03-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300034" joined="2007-03-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2007-03-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="300081" joined="2007-03-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2007-02-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1170306000" datetime="2007-02-01"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S1537-1538"/></action>
		<calendar date="1175054400" datetime="2007-03-28" ><text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text></calendar>
		<action date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29"><text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Biden with an amendment and with a preamble. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar under="General Orders" number="102" date="1175140800" datetime="2007-03-29" calendar="Senate Legislative" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 102.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>

	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/29/2007--Reported to Senate amended. Condemns the murder of Hrant Dink. Supports the government of Turkey's pledge to conduct an exhaustive investigation into Mr. Dink's assassination and acknowledges the prompt arrest of individuals allegedly responsible for the killing. Urges the government of Turkey to repeal Article 301 of the Turkish Penal Code and work to foster a more open intellectual environment. Recognizes the government of Turkey's decision to invite senior Armenian religious and political figures to participate in memorial services for Mr. Dink. Calls on the governments of Turkey and Armenia to reestablish full diplomatic, political, and economic relations. Supports Mr. Dink's wish that Turkey pursue further integration into Euro-Atlantic institutions and encourages the government of Turkey to enact reforms conducive to such ends. Urges the people of Turkey to honor Mr. Dink's legacy of tolerance. 
	</summary>
</bill>
