<bill session="111" type="h" number="1052" updated="2009-03-07T11:52:27-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1234414800" datetime="2009-02-12"/></status>

	<introduced date="1234414800" datetime="2009-02-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Ensuring Military Readiness Through Stability and Predictability Deployment Policy Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To mandate minimum periods of rest and recuperation for units and members of the regular and reserve components of the Armed Forces between deployments for Operation Iraqi Freedom or Operation Enduring Freedom.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400396"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400041" joined="2009-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400356" joined="2009-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412209" joined="2009-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412193" joined="2009-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412199" joined="2009-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400001" joined="2009-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2009-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400166" joined="2009-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2009-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400209" joined="2009-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412222" joined="2009-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2009-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2009-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400623" joined="2009-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400638" joined="2009-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412254" joined="2009-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400379" joined="2009-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2009-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2009-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2009-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412299" joined="2009-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412214" joined="2009-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412219" joined="2009-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400184" joined="2009-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="412188" joined="2009-02-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1234414800" datetime="2009-02-12"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/12/2009--Introduced.<br/>Ensuring Military Readiness Through Stability and Predictability Deployment Policy Act - Prohibits any unit of the regular Armed Forces from being deployed for Operations Iraqi Freedom or Enduring Freedom unless the period between the most recent previous deployment and a subsequent deployment is equal to or longer than the period of the most recent previous deployment. Expresses the sense of Congress that the optimal minimum period between such deployments should be equal to or longer than twice the period of the most recent previous deployment. Prohibits any unit of the reserves from being deployed for such Operations unless the period between the most recent previous deployment and a subsequent deployment is at least three times longer than the period of the most recent previous deployment. Expresses the sense of Congress that units of the reserves should not be mobilized continuously for more than one year, and that the optimal minimum period between such deployments should be five years. Provides exceptions from deployment requirements. Authorizes the President or chief of staff of the military department concerned to waive such requirements, under certain circumstances.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
