<bill session="111" type="h" number="1062" updated="2009-03-07T11:53:36-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1234501200" datetime="2009-02-13"/></status>

	<introduced date="1234501200" datetime="2009-02-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">United States Foreign Assistance Partner Vetting System Act of 2009</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to provide for the establishment and implementation of a system to verify that persons who receive United States foreign assistance funds are not affiliated with or do not support foreign terrorist organizations or do not otherwise commit or support acts of international terrorism, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400344"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400279" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400144" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400206" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400343" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412294" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400643" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400154" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412230" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400649" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400260" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400040" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400652" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400433" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412250" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400288" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400055" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412191" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400622" joined="2009-02-13"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1234501200" datetime="2009-02-13"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/13/2009--Introduced.<br/>United States Foreign Assistance Partner Vetting System Act of 2009 - States that it is U.S. policy to protect the people, property, and territory of the United States against acts of international terrorism through the implementation of a system to verify that persons who receive U.S. foreign assistance funds do not commit or support acts of international terrorism. Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to direct the Secretary of State to: (1) establish a system to verify that persons receiving U.S. foreign assistance funds are not affiliated with or supporting foreign terrorist organizations, or otherwise commiting or supporting acts of international terrorism; and (2) ensure that persons denied assistance pursuant to such vetting system are provided specified information and afforded specified procedural safeguards. Sets forth system elements. Prohibits providing foreign assistance funds to persons determined, pursuant to such system, to be affiliated with or supporting such organizations or commit or support international terrorism.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
