<bill session="111" type="h" number="1086" updated="2009-03-07T11:56:25-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1234501200" datetime="2009-02-13"/></status>

	<introduced date="1234501200" datetime="2009-02-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Help Efficient, Accessible, Low-cost, Timely Healthcare (HEALTH) Act of 2009</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To improve patient access to health care services and provide improved medical care by reducing the excessive burden the liability system places on the health care delivery system.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400151"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400627" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400061" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400144" joined="2009-02-24"/>
		<cosponsor id="400206" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400648" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400017" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400147" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412218" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400367" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400659" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400099" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400381" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400142" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400027" joined="2009-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="412216" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400626" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400330" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400242" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400320" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400175" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400385" joined="2009-02-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400255" joined="2009-03-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="412010" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412230" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412196" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400005" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400165" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400077" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400032" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="409888" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400029" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400055" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412261" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400141" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400435" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400622" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412202" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412255" joined="2009-02-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1234501200" datetime="2009-02-13"><text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1234501200" datetime="2009-02-13"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1234501200" datetime="2009-02-13"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/13/2009--Introduced.<br/>Help Efficient, Accessible, Low Cost, Timely Healthcare (HEALTH) Act of 2009 - Sets conditions for lawsuits arising from health care liability claims regarding health care goods or services or any medical product affecting interstate commerce. Sets a statute of limitations of three years after the date of manifestation of injury or one year after the claimant discovers the injury, with certain exceptions. Provides that nothing in this Act limits recovery of the full amount of available economic damages. Limits noneconomic damages to $250,000. Makes each party liable only for the amount of damages directly proportional to such party's percentage of responsibility. Allows the court to restrict the payment of attorney contingency fees. Limits the fees to a decreasing percentage based on the increasing value of the amount awarded. Allows the introduction of collateral source benefits and the amount paid to secure such benefits as evidence. Prohibits a provider of such benefits from recovering any amount from an award in a health care lawsuit involving injury or wrongful death. Authorizes the award of punitive damages only where: (1) it is proven by clear and convincing evidence that a person acted with malicious intent to injure the claimant or deliberately failed to avoid unnecessary injury the claimant was substantially certain to suffer; and (2) compensatory damages are awarded. Limits punitive damages to the greater of two times the amount of economic damages or $250,000. Denies punitive damages in the case of products approved, cleared, or licensed by the Food and Drug Administration (FDA), or otherwise considered in compliance with FDA standards. Provides for periodic payments of future damages.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
