<bill session="111" type="h" number="158" updated="2009-03-07T10:06:28-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Let the People Decide Clean Campaign Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to provide for expenditure limitations and public financing for House of Representatives general elections, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400300"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="2009-01-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2009-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400103" joined="2009-01-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2009-02-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="2009-01-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400195" joined="2009-01-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400378" joined="2009-01-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"><text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"><text>Referred to House House Administration</text></action>
		<action date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"><text>Referred to House Rules</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Congress"/>
		<term name="Congressional elections"/>
		<term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
		<term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
		<term name="Government information and archives"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="House of Representatives"/>
		<term name="Income tax rates"/>
		<term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="Political advertising"/>
		<term name="Political parties and affiliation"/>
		<term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/6/2009--Introduced.<br/>Let the People Decide Clean Campaign Act - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (FECA) to set forth specified expenditure limitations for House of Representatives general elections. Permits additional expenditures by eligible major party, third party, and independent candidates. Establishes in the Treasury the Grassroots Good Citizenship Fund, which shall provide public funding for House candidates' expenditures. Authorizes certain additional amounts from state and national party committees. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) authorize taxpayers to designate specified overpayments and contributions for the Fund; and (2) increase corporate tax rates on taxable income above $10 million, and require payment of the amounts received by reason of such increase to the Fund. Amends FECA to: (1) ban independent expenditures in House elections; (2) ban the use of nonfederal funds for certain disbursements; and (3) set forth specified House limitations for expenditures for elections other than general elections.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
