<bill session="111" type="h" number="192" updated="2009-03-07T10:10:23-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Central Idaho National Forest and Public Land Management Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize various land conveyances involving National Forest System lands and Bureau of Land Management lands in central Idaho to promote economic development and recreational activities in the area, to add certain National Forest System lands and Bureau of Land Management lands in central Idaho to the National Wilderness Preservation System, to provide special management requirements for certain National Forest System lands and Bureau of Land Management lands in central Idaho, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400376"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412300" joined="2009-01-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1233723600" datetime="2009-02-04"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Forests"/>
		<term name="Horticulture and plants"/>
		<term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
		<term name="Idaho"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="Land use and conservation"/>
		<term name="Livestock"/>
		<term name="Mining"/>
		<term name="Motor vehicles"/>
		<term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
		<term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
		<term name="Pedestrians and bicycling"/>
		<term name="Roads and highways"/>
		<term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
		<term name="Water use and supply"/>
		<term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/6/2009--Introduced.<br/>Central Idaho National Forest and Public Land Management Act Act - Requires the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service, and the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Land Management (BLM), to convey specified parcels of federal land to certain counties and cities in central Idaho. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to convey, to the state of Idaho a specified parcel or parcels of BLM land, including roads thereon, for a motorized recreation park. Designates specified parcels of federal land in central Idaho as wilderness areas to be managed as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System (NWPS). Repeals existing law requiring review of portions of the Sawtooth National Recreation Area (SNRA) for possible inclusion in the NWPS. Sets forth provisions concerning the management of federal lands in the Challis National Forest, the Sawtooth National Forest, SNRA, and the Challis District of the BLM that are not designated as wilderness areas under this Act or previous laws. Requires the Secretary of Agriculture to complete a study for establishing the Big Wood Backcountry Trail system for mechanized and nonmotorized recreation on a portion of the Rip and Tear Trail inside the SNRA. 
	</summary>
</bill>
