<bill session="111" type="h" number="193" updated="2009-03-07T10:10:30-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">AmeriCare Health Care Act of 2009</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Social Security Act and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for an AmeriCare that assures the provision of health insurance coverage to all residents, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400387"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2009-02-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2009-02-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2009-02-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E22-23)</text></action>
		<action date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
		<term name="Child health"/>
		<term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
		<term name="Consumer affairs"/>
		<term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
		<term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
		<term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
		<term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
		<term name="Family planning and birth control"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
		<term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
		<term name="Health information and medical records"/>
		<term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
		<term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
		<term name="Hearing, speech, and vision care"/>
		<term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
		<term name="Medicare"/>
		<term name="Mental health"/>
		<term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
		<term name="Prescription drugs"/>
		<term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Women's health"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/6/2009--Introduced.<br/>AmeriCare Health Care Act of 2009 - Adds a new title XXII to the Social Security Act (SSA) entitled &quot;AmeriCare Health Benefits.&quot; Makes all U.S. residents eligible for AmeriCare benefits, including prescription drugs and biologicals. Requires the development of an AmeriCare enrollment mechanism that includes automatic enrollment at birth and the issuance of AmeriCare cards for identification and claims processing purposes.<br/>Provides that an individual may elect not to be enrolled for benefits under AmeriCare if the individual has health benefits coverage under a group health plan at least equivalent to AmeriCare coverage.<br/>Provides the same benefits under AmeriCare as are provided under parts A (Hospital Insurance) and B (Supplementary Medical Insurance) of SSA title XVIII (Medicare).<br/>Provides additional AmeriCare coverage to children under age 24, pregnant women, and low-income individuals. Establishes the AmeriCare Trust Fund.<br/>Requires the modification of Medicaid (SSA title XIX), SCHIP (SSA title XXI [State Children's Health Insurance Program]), and other federal health programs to avoid their duplication of AmeriCare coverage. Provides for the regulation of AmeriCare supplemental policies.<br/>Establishes the general obligations for individuals and employers for the cost of health insurance coverage provided under this Act. Provides for additional premium subsidies.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
