<bill session="111" type="h" number="20" updated="2009-03-07T09:49:50-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Melanie Blocker Stokes Mom's Opportunity to Access Health, Education, Research, and Support for Postpartum Depression Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Melanie Blocker Stokes MOTHERS Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for research on, and services for individuals with, postpartum depression and psychosis.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400350"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400290" joined="2009-01-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400253" joined="2009-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2009-01-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412223" joined="2009-01-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412263" joined="2009-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2009-01-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2009-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400129" joined="2009-01-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400638" joined="2009-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="412200" joined="2009-01-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400009" joined="2009-01-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412228" joined="2009-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400215" joined="2009-01-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400062" joined="2009-01-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412194" joined="2009-01-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="324" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Abortion"/>
		<term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
		<term name="Health information and medical records"/>
		<term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
		<term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
		<term name="Medical research"/>
		<term name="Mental health"/>
		<term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
		<term name="Women's health"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/6/2009--Introduced.<br/>Melanie Blocker Stokes Mom's Opportunity to Access Health, Education, Research, and Support for Postpartum Depression Act or the Melanie Blocker Stokes MOTHERS Act - Encourages the Secretary of Health and Human Services to continue: (1) activities on postpartum depression; and (2) research to expand the understanding of the causes of, and treatments for, postpartum conditions. Expresses the sense of Congress that the Director of the National Institute of Mental Health may conduct a nationally representative longitudinal study of the relative mental health consequences for women of resolving a pregnancy in various ways.<br/>Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Secretary to make grants for projects for the establishment, operation, and coordination of effective and cost-efficient systems for the delivery of essential services to individuals with a postpartum condition and their families. Directs the Secretary to ensure that such projects provide education and services with respect to the diagnosis and management of postpartum conditions. Authorizes such projects to include: (1) delivering or enhancing outpatient home-based health and support services; and (2) providing education to new mothers and their families about postpartum conditions to promote earlier diagnosis and treatment. Sets forth grant requirements. Directs the Secretary to study the benefits of screening for postpartum conditions.<br/>Prohibits the Secretary from utilizing amounts appropriated under this Act to carry out activities or programs that are duplicative of activities or programs that are already being carried out through the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS).<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
