<bill session="111" type="h" number="218" updated="2009-03-07T10:13:25-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Living Organ Donor Tax Credit Act of 2009</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a nonrefundable personal credit to individuals who donate certain life-saving organs.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400433"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"><text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
		<term name="Income tax credits"/>
		<term name="Organ and tissue donation and transplantation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/6/2009--Introduced.<br/>Living Organ Donor Tax Credit Act of 2009 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a nonrefundable tax credit for a donation of a qualified life-saving organ for transplantation by a living individual into another individual. Defines &quot;qualified life-saving organ&quot; as a kidney, liver, lung, pancreas, intestine, bone marrow, or any part thereof. Limits the annual amount of such credit to $5,000 of the unreimbursed costs and lost wages incurred by an organ donor in connection with an organ transplant.<br/>Amends: (1) the Public Health Service Act to reduce federal living organ donation grants by any tax credit for organ donation received under this Act; and (2) the National Organ Transplant Act to provide that any such tax credit shall not be deemed valuable consideration for purposes of the ban against organ purchases.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
