<bill session="111" type="h" number="228" updated="2009-03-13T12:15:36-04:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231304400" datetime="2009-01-07"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231304400" datetime="2009-01-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish a scholarship program for students seeking a degree or certificate in the areas of visual impairment and orientation and mobility.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400199"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231304400" datetime="2009-01-07"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1231304400" datetime="2009-01-07"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text></action>
		<action date="1236142800" datetime="2009-03-04"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
		<term name="Education programs funding"/>
		<term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
		<term name="Health personnel"/>
		<term name="Hearing, speech, and vision care"/>
		<term name="Higher education"/>
		<term name="Medical education"/>
		<term name="Minority education"/>
		<term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
		<term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
		<term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/7/2009--Introduced.<br/>Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish and carry out a scholarship program of financial assistance for individuals who: (1) are accepted for, or currently enrolled in, a program of study leading to a degree or certificate in visual impairment or orientation and mobility, or both; and (2) enter into an agreement to serve, after program completion, as a full-time Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) employee for three years within the first six years after program completion. Sets maximum assistance amounts of $15,000 per academic year and $45,000 total. Requires pro rate repayment for failure to satisfy education or service requirements, while allowing the Secretary to waive or suspend such repayment whenever noncompliance is due to circumstances beyond the control of the participant, or when waiver or suspension is in the best interests of the United States.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
