<bill session="111" type="h" number="239" updated="2009-03-07T10:15:56-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231304400" datetime="2009-01-07"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231304400" datetime="2009-01-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Securing our Borders and our Data Act of 2009</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To impose requirements with regard to border searches of digital electronic devices and digital storage media, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400122"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400311" joined="2009-01-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231304400" datetime="2009-01-07"><text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1231304400" datetime="2009-01-07"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1231304400" datetime="2009-01-07"><text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text></action>
		<action date="1233810000" datetime="2009-02-05"><committee name="House Homeland Security"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border, Maritime, and Global Counterterrorism.</text></action>
		<action date="1234155600" datetime="2009-02-09"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law" activity="Referral" />
		<committee name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Border, Maritime, and Global Counterterrorism" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
		<term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
		<term name="Computers and information technology"/>
		<term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
		<term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
		<term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
		<term name="Government information and archives"/>
		<term name="Government investigations"/>
		<term name="Investigation, prosecution, interrogation methods"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
		<term name="Right of privacy"/>
		<term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/7/2009--Introduced.<br/>Securing Our Borders and Our Data Act of 2009 - Sets forth rules for the search or seizure at a U.S. border of digital electronic devices or digital storage media. Prohibits a search of the digital contents of such devices or media unless such search is based on: (1) a reasonable suspicion regarding the owner of such devices or media; and (2) an independent constitutional authority to make a seizure (other than the authority for border searches). Requires officers at U.S. borders to receive appropriate training to make searches of digital devices or media to minimize the possibility of irreparable damage to such devices or media. Allows the owners of such devices and media to request that searches be conducted out of public view. Requires the Secretary of Homeland Security to: (1) make rules regarding border searches of digital devices and storage media, including rules to protect the integrity of digital data, for the retrieval of seized devices or media by owners, and for sharing such data with other governmental agencies; and (2) publish such rules on the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) website. Requires the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection to conduct an annual study of searches and seizures of digital devices and storage media at U.S. borders and report to Congress on such study.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
