<bill session="111" type="h" number="250" updated="2009-03-07T10:17:07-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231304400" datetime="2009-01-07"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231304400" datetime="2009-01-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Neighborhood Rail Accountability Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Surface Transportation Board to consider certain issues when deciding whether to authorize the construction of a railroad line.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400160"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231304400" datetime="2009-01-07"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text></action>
		<action date="1231304400" datetime="2009-01-07"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Transportation and public works"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Department of Transportation"/>
		<term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
		<term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
		<term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
		<term name="Railroads"/>
		<term name="Surface Transportation Board"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/7/2009--Introduced.<br/>Neighborhood Rail Accountability Act - Requires the Surface Transportation Board, in determining whether to issue a certificate authorizing the construction of an additional railroad line or of an extension to any railroad line, to: (1) give greater weight to local official statements and public comments in opposition to the proposed construction (especially construction in a residential area) if there is an unusually high level of public opposition; and (2) identify any disproportionate negative impacts on any socioeconomic population, including a discussion of alternatives that were considered that would have avoided such impacts. Prescribes procedural requirements for dealing with any false or incorrect information provided by an applicant for a certificate for construction.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
