<bill session="111" type="h" number="26" updated="2009-03-07T09:50:44-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Eating Disorders Awareness, Prevention, and Education Act of 2009</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title V of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to raise awareness of eating disorders and to create educational programs concerning the same, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400027"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"><text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
		<term name="Child health"/>
		<term name="Education programs funding"/>
		<term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
		<term name="Government information and archives"/>
		<term name="Government investigations"/>
		<term name="Health information and medical records"/>
		<term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
		<term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
		<term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/6/2009--Introduced.<br/>Eating Disorders Awareness, Prevention, and Education Act of 2009 - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to authorize the use of innovative assistance funds for programs to: (1) improve identification of students with eating disorders; (2) increase awareness of such disorders among parents and students; and (3) train educators with respect to effective eating disorder prevention and assistance methods. Directs the Secretary of Education to carry out a program to broadcast public service announcements to improve public awareness, and to promote the identification and prevention, of eating disorders. Requires the National Center for Education Statistics and the National Center for Health Statistics to: (1) study the impact eating disorders have on educational advancement and achievement; (2) report on current state and local programs to educate youth on the dangers of eating disorders; and (3) recommend federal, state, and local measures that could be undertaken.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
