<bill session="111" type="h" number="262" updated="2009-03-07T10:18:28-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231304400" datetime="2009-01-07"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231304400" datetime="2009-01-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">David Ray Ritcheson Hate Crime Prevention Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To prevent hate crimes, to provide support services for victims of hate crimes, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400199"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231304400" datetime="2009-01-07"><text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, Energy and Commerce, Education and Labor, Oversight and Government Reform, House Administration, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1231304400" datetime="2009-01-07"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1231304400" datetime="2009-01-07"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1231304400" datetime="2009-01-07"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1231304400" datetime="2009-01-07"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1231304400" datetime="2009-01-07"><text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text></action>
		<action date="1231304400" datetime="2009-01-07"><text>Referred to House House Administration</text></action>
		<action date="1231304400" datetime="2009-01-07"><text>Referred to House Financial Services</text></action>
		<action date="1234155600" datetime="2009-02-09"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" activity="Referral" />
		<committee name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Census and government statistics"/>
		<term name="Crime prevention"/>
		<term name="Crime victims"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
		<term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
		<term name="Education programs funding"/>
		<term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
		<term name="Employee leave"/>
		<term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
		<term name="Government information and archives"/>
		<term name="Hate crimes"/>
		<term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
		<term name="Higher education"/>
		<term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
		<term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
		<term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
		<term name="Unemployment"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/7/2009--Introduced.<br/>David Ray Ritcheson Hate Crime Prevention Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow victims of hate crimes to claim unemployment insurance for loss of employment directly resulting from their experience as victims of such crimes.<br/>Prohibits health care insurers from taking into account whether a person is or has been a victim of a hate crime when making a determination as to eligibility for insurance coverage, the rate or premium of an insurance plan or policy, and the amount of insurance coverage provided. Amends the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 to allow a victim of a hate crime to take family and medical leave.<br/>Authorizes the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to award grants to provide housing to victims of a hate crime, homeless individuals who require housing assistance as a result of being a victim of a hate crime, and individuals for whom emergency shelter services are unavailable or insufficient. Authorizes the Attorney General to award grants to: (1) provide counseling and related assistance to victims of hate crimes and their dependents; (2) establish and operate a national clearinghouse and resource center for information and statistics relating to the incidence and prevention of hate crimes; and (3) establish and operate a national, toll-free telephone hotline and a website to provide information and assistance to victims of hate crimes.<br/>Requires the head of each federal agency to establish prevention, treatment, and rehabilitation programs and services relating to hate crimes for employees.<br/>Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award grants to local educational agencies and institutions of high education to improve and provide programs relating to hate crimes. 
	</summary>
</bill>
