<bill session="111" type="h" number="281" updated="2009-03-07T10:20:40-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231304400" datetime="2009-01-07"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231304400" datetime="2009-01-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Transparency in Corporate Filings Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Securities and Exchange Commission to permit or require persons filing or furnishing information under the securities laws to make such information available on internet websites, in addition to or instead of including such information in filings with or submissions to the Commission, under such conditions as the Commission may specify by rule.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412202"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231304400" datetime="2009-01-07"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
		<term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
		<term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital media"/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
		<term name="Financial services and investments"/>
		<term name="Government information and archives"/>
		<term name="Internet and video services"/>
		<term name="Securities"/>
		<term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/7/2009--Introduced.<br/>Transparency in Corporate Filings Act - Amends the Securities Act of 1933, the Securities Exchange Act of 1934, and the Investment Company Act of 1940, with respect to mandatory public disclosures in either registration statements, prospectuses, reports, or broadcasts, to authorize the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to provide that a disclosure form, periodic report, or document need not be filed if the SEC has otherwise prescribed another means for public disclosure of such information (such as on a website).<br/>Amends the Investment Company Act of 1940 to authorize the SEC to: (1) permit or require one or more alternative means of public disclosure (such as on a website) in lieu of, or in addition to, filing with the SEC or transmitting to security holders a registration statement, prospectus, application, report, account, record, or other document; and (2) determine whether any information so disclosed shall be deemed filed or transmitted under the Act.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
