<bill session="111" type="h" number="294" updated="2009-03-07T10:22:08-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231390800" datetime="2009-01-08"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231390800" datetime="2009-01-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Veteran-Owned Small Business Promotion Act of 2009</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for the reauthorization of the Department of Veterans Affairs small business loan program, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400056"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400279" joined="2009-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400051" joined="2009-01-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400570" joined="2009-01-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="412196" joined="2009-01-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412256" joined="2009-01-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400049" joined="2009-01-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400040" joined="2009-01-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412311" joined="2009-01-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="412301" joined="2009-01-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400433" joined="2009-01-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="412250" joined="2009-01-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400285" joined="2009-02-24"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231390800" datetime="2009-01-08"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E45-46)</text></action>
		<action date="1231390800" datetime="2009-01-08"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text></action>
		<action date="1231390800" datetime="2009-01-08"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Business investment and capital"/>
		<term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
		<term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
		<term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
		<term name="Government lending"/>
		<term name="Interest and interest rates"/>
		<term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
		<term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Terrorism"/>
		<term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
		<term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/8/2009--Introduced.<br/>Veteran-Owned Small Business Promotion Act of 2009 - Reinstates (under current law, terminated as of the end of FY1986) the veteran-owned small business loan program, under which the Secretary of Veterans Affairs may provide loans to veteran-owned small businesses for: (1) financing plant construction, conversion, or expansion; (2) financing the acquisition of equipment, facilities, machinery, supplies, or materials; or (3) supplying working capital. Makes eligible for such loans small business owners who are veterans and have a disability rated at 10% (under current law, 30%) or more, and includes all veterans (under current law, limited to Vietnam era veterans and veterans discharged or released due to a disability incurred or aggravated in the line of duty). Repeals the authority to make direct loans under the program (thereby allowing only loan guaranties). Increases from $200,000 to $500,000 the maximum loan guaranty amount. Authorizes the Secretary to subsidize a loan lender in order to reduce by up to 1/2% the interest rate paid by the veteran-owned small business. Includes under a loan preference members of the National Guard and reserves activated in support of the Global War on Terrorism. Limits performance bond requirements of veteran-owned small businesses with respect to the construction, alteration, or repair of any Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) public building or public work. Treats a small business owned and controlled by veterans as a socially and economically disadvantaged small business for purposes of contracts awarded to the latter businesses under provisions of the Small Business Act.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
