<bill session="111" type="h" number="299" updated="2009-03-07T10:22:41-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231390800" datetime="2009-01-08"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231390800" datetime="2009-01-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Digital Television Consumer Education Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide American consumers information about the broadcast television transition from an analog to a digital format, and to provide additional funds for the converter box coupon program under the Digital Television Transition and Public Safety Act of 2005.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400122"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231390800" datetime="2009-01-08"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital media"/>
		<term name="Consumer affairs"/>
		<term name="Government information and archives"/>
		<term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
		<term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
		<term name="Television and film"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/8/2009--Introduced.<br/>National Digital Television Consumer Education Act - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to require retail distributors of television receiving equipment (TVs) to place adjacent to each unit displayed for sale a consumer alert in English and Spanish that the TV has only an analog broadcast tuner and will require a converter box after February 17, 2009, to receive over-the-air broadcasts with an antenna. Imposes similar requirements on sellers that use direct mail, catalog, or electronic means such as the Internet. Requires broadcaster public service announcements about the deadline for termination of analog TV broadcasting and the equipment options for consumers following such termination. Amends the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act to authorize the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information to establish a temporary grant program to coordinate and lead a nationwide consumer education and outreach campaign regarding America's conversion to digital television. Amends the Digital Television Transition and Public Safety Act of 2005 to increase funding for the program to provide coupons for digital-to-analog converter boxes.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
