<bill session="111" type="h" number="307" updated="2009-03-07T10:23:38-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231390800" datetime="2009-01-08"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231390800" datetime="2009-01-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Christopher and Dana Reeve Paralysis Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance and further research into paralysis and to improve rehabilitation and the quality of life for persons living with paralysis and other physical disabilities, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400013"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400253" joined="2009-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400230" joined="2009-01-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400155" joined="2009-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400039" joined="2009-01-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2009-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400443" joined="2009-01-21"/>
		<cosponsor id="400193" joined="2009-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="412228" joined="2009-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412250" joined="2009-01-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231390800" datetime="2009-01-08"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
		<term name="Health information and medical records"/>
		<term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
		<term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
		<term name="Medical research"/>
		<term name="Research administration and funding"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/8/2009--Introduced.<br/>Christopher and Dana Reeve Paralysis Act – Authorizes the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to: (1) develop mechanisms to coordinate NIH paralysis research and rehabilitation activities; (2) award grants for each Christopher and Dana Reeve Paralysis Research Consortium; and (3) award grants for multicenter networks of clinical sites that will collaborate to design clinical rehabilitation intervention protocols and measures of outcomes on different forms of paralysis.<br/>Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) study the unique health challenges associated with paralysis and other physical disabilities; and (2) carry out projects and interventions to improve the quality of life and long-term health status of persons with paralysis and other physical disabilities.<br/>Authorizes the Secretary to award grants for activities related to paralysis, including to: (1) establish a population-based database for research on paralysis and other disabling conditions; (2) develop comprehensive paralysis and other physical action plans and activities; (3) provide education and training opportunities and programs for health professionals and allied caregivers; and (4) improve access to services for persons living with paralysis and other physical disabilities and their caregivers.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
