<bill session="111" type="h" number="315" updated="2009-03-07T10:24:33-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231390800" datetime="2009-01-08"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231390800" datetime="2009-01-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Customer Service Enhancement Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To require the establishment of customer service standards for Federal agencies.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400657"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231390800" datetime="2009-01-08"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
		<term name="Consumer affairs"/>
		<term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
		<term name="Government information and archives"/>
		<term name="Government investigations"/>
		<term name="Office of Management and Budget (OMB)"/>
		<term name="Performance measurement"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/8/2009--Introduced.<br/>Federal Customer Service Enhancement Act - Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to develop: (1) performance measures to determine whether federal agencies are providing high quality customer service; and (2) standards to be met by federal agencies to provide high quality customer service.<br/>Requires the head of each agency to: (1) collect information from its customers regarding the quality of its of customer services; and (2) include this information in its performance report to the President and Congress. Requires the Director to report annually on the success of federal agencies in meeting the customer service performance measures and standards.<br/>Requires the head of each agency to designate an employee as its customer relations representative to be responsible for implementing customer service standards.<br/>Directs the Comptroller General to submit to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform and the Senate Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs a report analyzing the information reported by agencies on the quality of customer service. Requires such report to include: (1) whether agencies are implementing the customer service standards; (2) whether there is an increase in overall quality in customer service; and (3) any recommendations the Comptroller General may have to improve performance measures and standards for customer service. Authorizes the report to be used by Congress and the Director to update performance measures for customer service.<br/>Authorizes the head of a federal agency to establish an awards program to pay a cash award to employees for demonstrated excellence in customer service.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
