<bill session="111" type="h" number="330" updated="2009-03-07T10:26:26-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231390800" datetime="2009-01-08"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231390800" datetime="2009-01-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">MEGA</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Metro Economies Green Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish grant programs to encourage energy-efficient economic development and green job training and creation, and to establish the Metro Area Green Institute to produce and disseminate best practice information to economic and workforce development initiatives undertaken by metropolitan communities nationally.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400237"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231390800" datetime="2009-01-08"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Labor and employment"/>
		<term name="Air quality"/>
		<term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
		<term name="Child care and development"/>
		<term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
		<term name="Ecology"/>
		<term name="Employment and training programs"/>
		<term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
		<term name="Environmental technology"/>
		<term name="Mental health"/>
		<term name="Motor vehicles"/>
		<term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
		<term name="Public transit"/>
		<term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
		<term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Unemployment"/>
		<term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
		<term name="Vocational education"/>
		<term name="Wages and earnings"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/8/2009--Introduced.<br/>Metro Economies Green Act or MEGA - Authorizes the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to establish a metro area green zone grant program to make grants to local government units to support and establish green job programs that: (1) target low-income, difficult-to-employ, and formerly incarcerated persons; and (2) involve local business, academia, trade associations, nonprofits, and other stakeholders in energy-efficient economic development and green job training and creation. Authorizes the Secretary also to establish competitive programs to make grants to local government units to support and establish: (1) a similar mini-metro green program that engages smaller communities in green economic and workforce development; and (2) an alternative green academies program that provides green job training, employment opportunities, and other life skills to high school dropouts, formerly incarcerated youth, and individuals unable to attend traditional institutions of higher education. Directs the Secretary to select one unit of general local government or nonprofit organization designated by such a unit to establish and operate a Metro Area Green Institute to serve as a national resource center to support municipally based, green economic and workforce development efforts.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
