<bill session="111" type="h" number="373" updated="2009-03-07T10:31:20-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231477200" datetime="2009-01-09"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231477200" datetime="2009-01-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to render inadmissible and deportable certain aliens convicted of drunk driving, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400134"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231477200" datetime="2009-01-09"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Immigration"/>
		<term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
		<term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
		<term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
		<term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
		<term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
		<term name="Visas and passports"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/9/2009--Introduced.<br/>Amends the the Immigration and Nationality Act to make an alien inadmissible or deportable if such alien has been convicted of three offenses for driving under the influence and at least one of the offenses is a felony under federal or state law for which the alien was sentenced to more than one year in prison. Provides that: (1) a court shall not accept a guilty plea for driving under the influence unless the court has administered to the defendant a specified advisal regarding the possible exclusion, deportation, or denial of naturalization to a noncitizen as a result of a conviction for driving under the influence; and (2) if the court fails to so advise and the defendant shows that conviction of the offense to which the defendant pleaded guilty may result in the defendant's deportation, exclusion, or denial of naturalization, the court, upon the defendant's motion, shall vacate the judgment and permit the defendant to withdraw the plea and enter a plea of not guilty. 
	</summary>
</bill>
