<bill session="111" type="h" number="382" updated="2009-03-07T10:32:22-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231477200" datetime="2009-01-09"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231477200" datetime="2009-01-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Save Our Children: Stop the Predators Against Children DNA Act of 2009</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To create a separate DNA database for predators against children, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400199"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231477200" datetime="2009-01-09"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="288" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Crime prevention"/>
		<term name="Crimes against children"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
		<term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
		<term name="Government information and archives"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
		<term name="State and local government operations"/>
		<term name="Violent crime"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/9/2009--Introduced.<br/>Save Our Children: Stop the Predators Against Children DNA Act of 2009 - Directs the Attorney General to establish and maintain a database solely for collecting DNA (deoxyribonucleic acid) information with respect to predators against children. Authorizes federal, state, and local agencies and other entities to submit DNA information for the database and to compare DNA information within the database. Directs the Attorney General to make grants to states to improve programs to decrease recidivism of such predators. Requires the maximum sentence to be imposed for a crime against an individual under age 18 that would, in and of itself, establish the offender as such a predator, without regard to any mitigating circumstance that would otherwise apply.<br/>Defines a &quot;predator against children&quot; as a person who commits a sex crime against an individual under age of 18. Excludes a person who commits a sex crime against an individual who has not attained the age of 18 years if: (1) the individual against whom such crime was committed has attained 16 years of age or older; (2) the person who commits such crime is not more than four years older than such individual; and (3) the conduct resulting in the commission of such crime was consensual.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
