<bill session="111" type="h" number="397" updated="2009-03-07T10:34:23-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231477200" datetime="2009-01-09"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231477200" datetime="2009-01-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To extend the authorization of the Quinebaug and Shetucket Rivers Valley National Heritage Corridor Act of 1994, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412193"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400291" joined="2009-01-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231477200" datetime="2009-01-09"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1233723600" datetime="2009-02-04"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="196" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Appropriations"/>
		<term name="Connecticut"/>
		<term name="Government investigations"/>
		<term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
		<term name="Massachusetts"/>
		<term name="Watersheds"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/9/2009--Introduced.<br/>Amends the Quinebaug and Shetucket Rivers Valley National Heritage Corridor Act of 1994 to extend the authority of the Secretary of the Interior to make grants or provide any assistance under the Act for the Quinebaug and Shetucket Rivers Valley National Heritage Corridor to September 30, 2015. Requires the Secretary to conduct an evaluation of the accomplishments of the Corridor by no later than three years before the date on which the authority for federal funding terminates for the Corridor, and based upon the evaluation, to prepare and submit to specified congressional committees a report that includes recommendations for the future role of the National Park Service (NPS), if any, with respect to the Corridor. Increases the total amount that may be appropriated for the Corridor. 
	</summary>
</bill>
