<bill session="111" type="h" number="411" updated="2009-03-07T10:36:04-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231477200" datetime="2009-01-09"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231477200" datetime="2009-01-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Great Cats and Rare Canids Act of 2009</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To assist in the conservation of rare felids and rare canids by supporting and providing financial resources for the conservation programs of nations within the range of rare felid and rare canid populations and projects of persons with demonstrated expertise in the conservation of rare felid and rare canid populations.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400193"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400041" joined="2009-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400147" joined="2009-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400395" joined="2009-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400340" joined="2009-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400348" joined="2009-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400049" joined="2009-02-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400264" joined="2009-01-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231477200" datetime="2009-01-09"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1233723600" datetime="2009-02-04"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Animals"/>
		<term name="Advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
		<term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
		<term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="International law and treaties"/>
		<term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
		<term name="Mammals"/>
		<term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
		<term name="Trade restrictions"/>
		<term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/9/2009--Introduced.<br/>Great Cats and Rare Canids Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to provide assistance for projects for the conservation of rare felids and rare canids. Authorizes the Secretary to convene an advisory group of individuals representing public and private organizations actively involved in the conservation of felids and canids. Restricts the use of grants for captive breeding or display purposes.<br/>Establishes in the Multinational Species Conservation Fund as a separate account the Great Cats and Rare Canids Conservation Fund.<br/>Defines &quot;rare canid&quot; to: (1) mean any of the canid species dhole, gray wolf, Ethiopian wolf, bush dog, African wild dog, maned wolf, and Darwin's fox, including any subspecies or population of such a species; and (2) exclude any subspecies or population that is native to the area comprised of the United States and Canada or the European Union.<br/>Defines &quot;rare felid&quot; to: (1) mean any of the felid species lion, leopard, jaguar, snow leopard, clouded leopard, cheetah, Iberian lynx, and Borneo bay cat, including any subspecies or population of such a species; and (2) exclude any species, subspecies, or population that is native to the United States and any tiger.<br/>Authorizes the Secretary to convene an advisory group, to assist in carrying out this Act, consisting of individuals representing public and private organizations actively involved in felid and canid conservation.<br/>Requires the Secretary to initiate a study of felid and canid species listed under the IUCN Red List (the Red List of Threatened Species Maintained by the World Conservation Union) that are not rare canids and rare felids to determine: (1) the conservation status of the species in the wild, including identification of those that are critically endangered or endangered; and (2) any such species that should be made eligible for project assistance.<br/>.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
