<bill session="111" type="h" number="413" updated="2009-03-07T10:36:18-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231477200" datetime="2009-01-09"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231477200" datetime="2009-01-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Public Safety Employer-Employee Cooperation Act of 2009</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide collective bargaining rights for public safety officers employed by States or their political subdivisions.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400216"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400116" joined="2009-01-09"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231477200" datetime="2009-01-09"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
		<term name="Emergency medical services"/>
		<term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
		<term name="Federal Labor Relations Authority"/>
		<term name="Fires"/>
		<term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
		<term name="Health personnel"/>
		<term name="Labor standards"/>
		<term name="Labor-management relations"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
		<term name="State and local courts"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/9/2009--Introduced.<br/>Public Safety Employer-Employee Cooperation Act of 2009 - Provides collective bargaining rights for public safety officers employed by states or local governments. Directs the Federal Labor Relations Authority to determine whether state law provides specified rights and responsibilities for public safety officers, including: (1) granting public safety employees the right to form and join a labor organization which excludes management and supervisory employees, and which is, or seeks to be, recognized as the exclusive bargaining agent for such employees; and (2) requiring public safety employers to recognize and agree to bargain with the employees' labor organization. Requires the Authority to issue regulations establishing rights and responsibilities for public safety employers and employees in states that do not substantially provide for such public safety employee rights and responsibilities. Directs the Authority, in such cases, to: (1) determine the appropriateness of units for labor organization representation; (2) supervise or conduct elections to determine whether a labor organization has been selected as an exclusive representative by a voting majority of the employees in an appropriate unit; (3) resolve issues relating to the duty to bargain in good faith; (4) conduct hearings and resolve complaints of unfair labor practices; and (5) resolve exceptions to arbitrator's awards. Grants a public safety employer, employee, or labor organization the right to seek enforcement of Authority regulations and orders, as well as prohibitions against lockouts or strikes, through appropriate state courts. Prohibits public safety employers, employees, and labor organizations from engaging in lockouts or strikes.<br/>Provides that existing collective bargaining units and agreements shall not be invalidated by this Act.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
