<bill session="111" type="h" number="436" updated="2009-03-07T10:38:57-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231477200" datetime="2009-01-09"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231477200" datetime="2009-01-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Certain Estate Tax Relief Act of 2009</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to repeal the new carryover basis rules in order to prevent tax increases and the imposition of compliance burdens on many more estates than would benefit from repeal, to retain the estate tax with a $3,500,000 exemption, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400323"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231477200" datetime="2009-01-09"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
		<term name="Transfer and inheritance taxes"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/9/2009--Introduced.<br/>Certain Estate Tax Relief Act of 2009 - Restores the tax on estates and generation-skipping transfers and the step-up in basis provisions for property acquired from a decedent, previously repealed by the Economic Growth and Tax Relief Reconciliation Act of 2001 (EGTRRA). Declares that the sunset provision (general terminating date of December 10, 2010) of EGTRRA shall not apply to title V of such Act ( Estate, Gift, and Generation-Skipping Transfer Tax Provisions). Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) provide for an increase to $3.5 million of the estate tax exclusion (eliminating the phase-in period); (2) impose a maximum estate tax rate of 45% ; (3) restore the phaseout of graduated estate tax rates and the unified credit against the estate tax; (4) set forth estate valuation rules for certain transfers of nonbusiness assets; and (5) limit estate tax discounts for certain individuals with minority interests in a business acquired from a decedent.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
