<bill session="111" type="h" number="443" updated="2009-03-07T10:39:44-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231477200" datetime="2009-01-09"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231477200" datetime="2009-01-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Government Reform Act of 2009</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To create a national commission, modeled after the successful Defense Base Closure and Realignment Commission, to establish a timely, independent, and fair process for realigning or closing outdated, ineffective, or inefficient executive agencies.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400348"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231477200" datetime="2009-01-09"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text></action>
		<action date="1235451600" datetime="2009-02-24"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Organization, and Procurement.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="Government Management, Organization, and Procurement" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Budget process"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
		<term name="Government information and archives"/>
		<term name="Government investigations"/>
		<term name="Performance measurement"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/9/2009--Introduced.<br/>Government Reform Act of 2009- Establishes a Government Reform Commission to: (1) examine the current configuration of executive agencies and investigate their duties and responsibilities; (2) review agency operational jurisdictions to determine whether areas of overlap exist and whether the mission of any agency has become obsolete; (3) review and report to the President and Congress on existing Government Accountability Office (GAO), Congressional Budget Office (CBO), and Inspector General reports, together with any other existing governmental and nongovernmental recommendations, including those offered by the President's Private Sector Survey on Cost Control, for reducing waste in executive agencies; (4) submit to the President and Congress a proposed reorganization plan which shall provide for the realignment or closure of executive agencies to reduce duplication of services and increase productivity; and (5) transmit a copy of the plan to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB), who shall issue a public report detailing the predicted savings in federal expenditures that would result from implementing such plan. Sets forth separate provisions for presidential and congressional consideration of and actions on the proposed reorganization plan.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
