<bill session="111" type="h" number="445" updated="2009-03-07T10:39:58-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231477200" datetime="2009-01-09"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231477200" datetime="2009-01-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Heavy Duty Hybrid Vehicle Research, Development, and Demonstration Act of 2009</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a research, development, demonstration, and commercial application program to promote research of appropriate technologies for heavy duty plug-in hybrid vehicles, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400365"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400280" joined="2009-01-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="412227" joined="2009-01-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400381" joined="2009-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400027" joined="2009-01-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400660" joined="2009-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="412305" joined="2009-01-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400119" joined="2009-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400437" joined="2009-01-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400108" joined="2009-01-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231477200" datetime="2009-01-09"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Science and Technology.</text></action>
		<action date="1231477200" datetime="2009-01-09"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Science and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Science and Technology" subcommittee="Energy and Environment" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
		<term name="Air quality"/>
		<term name="Climate change"/>
		<term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
		<term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
		<term name="Energy research"/>
		<term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
		<term name="Hybrid, electric, and advanced technology vehicles"/>
		<term name="Manufacturing"/>
		<term name="Product development and innovation"/>
		<term name="Research administration and funding"/>
		<term name="Research and development"/>
		<term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/9/2009--Introduced.<br/>Heavy Duty Hybrid Vehicle Research, Development, and Demonstration Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Energy to establish a competitive research, development, demonstration, and commercial application program to provide between three and seven grants of up to $3 million per year each to applicants to carry out projects to advance research and development and to demonstrate technologies, including plug-in hybrid technology, for advanced heavy duty hybrid vehicles.<br/>Requires that each grant recipient complete two phases: (1) phase one, research and demonstration of advanced hybrid technology by producing or retrofitting one or more advanced heavy duty hybrid vehicles; and (2) phase two, demonstration of advanced manufacturing processes and technologies by producing or retrofitting 50 advanced heavy duty hybrid vehicles.<br/>Directs the Secretary to: (1) conduct research into alternative power train designs for use in advanced heavy duty hybrid vehicles; and (2) establish a pilot program through the National Laboratories and Technology Centers of the Department of Energy to research and test the effects on the domestic electric power grid of the widespread use of plug-in hybrid vehicles, including plug-in hybrid vehicles that are advanced heavy duty hybrid vehicles. Amends the United States Energy Storage Competitiveness Act of 2007 to direct the Secretary to conduct an applied research program on energy storage systems to support vehicles with a gross weight over 16,000 pounds.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
