<bill session="111" type="h" number="471" updated="2009-03-07T10:43:02-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231822800" datetime="2009-01-13"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231822800" datetime="2009-01-13"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Supporting America's Manufacturers Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Trade Act of 1974 to provide for a limitation on presidential discretion with respect to actions to address market disruption.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412231"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400640" joined="2009-01-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="412227" joined="2009-01-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400209" joined="2009-01-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400385" joined="2009-01-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400211" joined="2009-01-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="412228" joined="2009-01-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400047" joined="2009-01-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400285" joined="2009-01-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400216" joined="2009-01-27"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231822800" datetime="2009-01-13"><text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1231822800" datetime="2009-01-13"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1231822800" datetime="2009-01-13"><text>Referred to House Rules</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Asia"/>
		<term name="China"/>
		<term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Government information and archives"/>
		<term name="Presidents and presidential powers"/>
		<term name="Tariffs"/>
		<term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
		<term name="Trade restrictions"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/13/2009--Introduced.<br/>Supporting America's Manufacturers Act - Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to require a recommendation from the International Trade Commission (ITC) before the President can impose increased duties or other import restrictions on an imported Chinese product that causes or threatens market disruption to a like U.S. product. Revises the authority of the President and the U.S. Trade Representative (USTR) to consider an equally divided ITC vote regarding a determination on the question of whether an imported Chinese product causes or threatens market disruption in the United States. Repeals the authority of the President and the USTR to consider the determination of either group of equally divided Commissioners to be the ITC's determination. Requires such a deadlocked vote to be considered an affirmative ITC determination. Provides that if the Commissioners voting are equally divided with respect to its determination, then the determination agreed upon by either group of Commissioners may be considered by the President and the Trade Representative as the determination of the Commission. Requires the USTR to make available promptly to the public reports recommending the President to take action, if any, to remedy market disruption. Revises requirements involving ITC determinations of critical circumstances and requests for provisional relief with respect to a Chinese product that causes or threatens market disruption to a like U.S. Product Requires the President to provide import relief from Chinese products that cause or threaten market disruption to a like U.S. product within a specified time if an agreement is not reached with the People's Republic of China (PRC) or if the President determines that an agreement reached with the PRC is not remedying the market disruption. Authorizes the President to provide import relief (including provisional relief in critical circumstances) that differs from that recommended by the ITC, or to deny such import relief only: (1) in extraordinary cases; and (2) if the President determines that providing such relief would cause serious harm to U.S. economic interests or to U.S. national security. Requires the President's decision on import relief to be reported to specified congressional committees. Requires import relief recommended by the ITC to take effect upon enactment of a congressional joint resolution in the event that the President: (1) takes action that differs from that recommended by the ITC; or (2) declines to provide import relief (including that recommended by the ITC) because it would cause serious harm to U.S. economic interests or to U.S. national security. 
	</summary>
</bill>
