<bill session="111" type="h" number="499" updated="2009-03-07T10:46:16-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231909200" datetime="2009-01-14"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231909200" datetime="2009-01-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Nonmarket Economy Trade Remedy Act of 2009</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title VII of the Tariff Act of 1930 to provide that the provisions relating to countervailing duties apply to nonmarket economy countries, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400092"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400051" joined="2009-01-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231909200" datetime="2009-01-14"><text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1231909200" datetime="2009-01-14"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1231909200" datetime="2009-01-14"><text>Referred to House Rules</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
		<term name="Administrative remedies"/>
		<term name="Asia"/>
		<term name="China"/>
		<term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
		<term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
		<term name="Government investigations"/>
		<term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
		<term name="Tariffs"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/14/2009--Introduced.<br/>Nonmarket Economy Trade Remedy Act of 2009 - Amends the Tariff Act of 1930 to apply countervailing duties to nonmarket economies. Excludes specified factors, including a subsidy's effect, from the administering authority's consideration when determining whether a countervailable subsidy exists with respect to merchandise imported from nonmarket economy countries. Authorizes the use of alternative methodologies in determining whether a subsidy is countervailable with respect to the People's Republic of China (PRC). Deems subsidies provided predominantly or disportionately by the PRC to a state-owned enterprise as specific to that enterprise. Prohibits the administering authority from considering requests for market economy treatment at the individual business enterprise level in an antidumping duty proceeding involving a nonmarket economy country. Requires congressional approval for revocation of nonmarket economy country determinations made by the administering authority.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
