<bill session="111" type="h" number="539" updated="2009-03-07T10:51:00-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231909200" datetime="2009-01-14"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231909200" datetime="2009-01-14"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">We the People Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To limit the jurisdiction of the Federal courts, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400311"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400209" joined="2009-01-14"/>
		<cosponsor id="400652" joined="2009-01-14"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231909200" datetime="2009-01-14"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E88-89)</text></action>
		<action date="1231909200" datetime="2009-01-14"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Law"/>
		<term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
		<term name="Federal appellate courts"/>
		<term name="Federal district courts"/>
		<term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
		<term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
		<term name="Judges"/>
		<term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
		<term name="Marriage and family status"/>
		<term name="Religion"/>
		<term name="Right of privacy"/>
		<term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
		<term name="State and local courts"/>
		<term name="State and local finance"/>
		<term name="State and local government operations"/>
		<term name="State and local taxation"/>
		<term name="Supreme Court"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/14/2009--Introduced.<br/>We the People Act - Prohibits the Supreme Court and each federal court from adjudicating any claim or relying on judicial decisions involving: (1) state or local laws, regulations, or policies concerning the free exercise or establishment of religion; (2) the right of privacy, including issues of sexual practices, orientation, or reproduction; or (3) the right to marry without regard to sex or sexual orientation where based upon equal protection of the laws. Allows the Supreme Court and the federal courts to determine the constitutionality of federal statutes, administrative rules, or procedures in considering cases arising under the Constitution. Prohibits the Supreme Court and the federal courts from issuing any ruling that appropriates or expends money, imposes taxes, or otherwise interferes with the legislative functions or administrative discretion of the states. Authorizes any party or intervener in matters before any federal court, including the Supreme Court, to challenge the jurisdiction of the court under this Act. Provides that the violation of this Act by any justice or judge is an impeachable offense and a material breach of good behavior subject to removal. Negates as binding precedent on the state courts any federal court decision that relates to an issue removed from federal jurisdiction by this Act. 
	</summary>
</bill>
