<bill session="111" type="h" number="551" updated="2009-03-07T10:52:23-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231995600" datetime="2009-01-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231995600" datetime="2009-01-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Sierra Vista Subwatershed Feasibility Study Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Commissioner of Reclamation, to conduct a feasibility study of water augmentation alternatives in the Sierra Vista Subwatershed.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412188"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231995600" datetime="2009-01-15"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1233723600" datetime="2009-02-04"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water and Power" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Water resources development"/>
		<term name="Arizona"/>
		<term name="Government investigations"/>
		<term name="Water resources funding"/>
		<term name="Water use and supply"/>
		<term name="Watersheds"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/15/2009--Introduced.<br/>Sierra Vista Subwatershed Feasibility Study Act - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior, through the Commissioner of Reclamation, to complete a feasibility study of alternatives to augment water supplies in the Sierra Vista Subwatershed, Arizona, that are identified as appropriate for further study in an appraisal report dated June 2007.<br/>Directs the Secretary, in evaluating the feasibility of alternatives, to: (1) include any required environmental reviews, the construction, operations, maintenance, and replacement costs for each alternative, and the economic feasibility of each alternative; (2) take into consideration the ability of government and private sources to fund such costs; (3) establish the basis for any cost-sharing allocations and any anticipated repayment of federal contributions; and (4) perform a cost-benefit analysis.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
