<bill session="111" type="h" number="578" updated="2009-03-07T10:55:29-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231995600" datetime="2009-01-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231995600" datetime="2009-01-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Iraqi Refugee and Internally Displaced Persons Humanitarian Assistance, Resettlement, and Security Act of 2009</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To address the impending humanitarian crisis and potential security breakdown as a result of the mass influx of Iraqi refugees into neighboring countries, and the growing internally displaced population in Iraq, by increasing directed accountable assistance to these populations and their host countries, facilitating the resettlement of Iraqis at risk, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400170"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400661" joined="2009-01-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="2009-01-27"/>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2009-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400031" joined="2009-01-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="412258" joined="2009-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="412193" joined="2009-01-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400110" joined="2009-01-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400087" joined="2009-01-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2009-01-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400259" joined="2009-01-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2009-01-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400102" joined="2009-01-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400422" joined="2009-01-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2009-01-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400378" joined="2009-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400111" joined="2009-03-02"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2009-01-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412239" joined="2009-02-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412215" joined="2009-02-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2009-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="400423" joined="2009-01-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400204" joined="2009-02-13"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2009-01-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400240" joined="2009-01-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400184" joined="2009-01-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231995600" datetime="2009-01-15"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E97)</text></action>
		<action date="1231995600" datetime="2009-01-15"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1231995600" datetime="2009-01-15"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1231995600" datetime="2009-01-15"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
		<term name="Egypt"/>
		<term name="Europe"/>
		<term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
		<term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
		<term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
		<term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
		<term name="Iraq"/>
		<term name="Jordan"/>
		<term name="Lebanon"/>
		<term name="Middle East"/>
		<term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
		<term name="Syria"/>
		<term name="Turkey"/>
		<term name="United Nations"/>
		<term name="Visas and passports"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/15/2009--Introduced.<br/>Iraqi Refugee and Internally Displaced Persons Humanitarian Assistance, Resettlement, and Security Act of 2009 - Expresses the sense of Congress concerning Iraqi refugees and internally displaced persons. Directs the Secretary of State, with respect to vulnerable populations in Iraq and with respect to countries containing a significant population of Iraqi refugees (including Jordan, Syria, Turkey, Lebanon, and Egypt), to provide such countries or appropriate international organizations and nongovernmental organizations with specified humanitarian assistance. Directs the Secretary to make every effort to ensure that the humanitarian needs of vulnerable populations in Iraq and Iraqi refugees in neighboring countries are met. Authorizes appropriations: (1) for such humanitarian assistance; and (2) to Jordan for humanitarian assistance to Iraqi refugees and to provide the necessary infrastructure to support both the needs of Iraqi refugees and the Jordanian people. Requires that related fund monitoring mechanisms be established. Prohibits direct bilateral assistance to Syria. Increases FY2009-FY2011 refugee admission limitations for the purpose of admitting Iraqi citizens or nationals who became refugees on or after March 19, 2003. Authorizes appropriations. Directs the Secretary, by a specified date and subject to the availability of appropriations, to have increased by 100% the number of federal personnel in Iraq and in other appropriate countries who are conducting security reviews of Iraqi refugee applicants. Authorizes appropriations. Directs the Secretary to work with the international community to provide: (1) financial assistance to vulnerable populations in Iraq and to Iraqi refugees in neighboring countries; and (2) technical and financial assistance to international organizations in order to process refugees. Defines &quot;vulnerable populations in Iraq.&quot;<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
