<bill session="111" type="h" number="591" updated="2009-03-07T10:57:04-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231995600" datetime="2009-01-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231995600" datetime="2009-01-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Interrogation and Detention Reform Act of 2008</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To improve United States capabilities for gathering human intelligence through the effective interrogation and detention of terrorist suspects and for bringing terrorists to justice through effective prosecution in accordance with the principles and values set forth in the Constitution and other laws.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400326"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400133" joined="2009-01-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400280" joined="2009-01-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400103" joined="2009-01-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2009-01-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2009-01-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400360" joined="2009-01-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400129" joined="2009-01-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400424" joined="2009-01-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="412200" joined="2009-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="412236" joined="2009-03-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400310" joined="2009-01-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400033" joined="2009-01-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400184" joined="2009-01-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400301" joined="2009-01-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400233" joined="2009-01-15"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231995600" datetime="2009-01-15"><text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, Foreign Affairs, and Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1231995600" datetime="2009-01-15"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
		<action date="1231995600" datetime="2009-01-15"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1231995600" datetime="2009-01-15"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1231995600" datetime="2009-01-15"><text>Referred to House Intelligence (Permanent Select)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
		<term name="Afghanistan"/>
		<term name="Asia"/>
		<term name="Caribbean area"/>
		<term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
		<term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
		<term name="Cuba"/>
		<term name="Detention of persons"/>
		<term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
		<term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
		<term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
		<term name="Government information and archives"/>
		<term name="Human rights"/>
		<term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
		<term name="International law and treaties"/>
		<term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
		<term name="Internet and video services"/>
		<term name="Investigation, prosecution, interrogation methods"/>
		<term name="Iraq"/>
		<term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
		<term name="Latin America"/>
		<term name="Middle East"/>
		<term name="Military law"/>
		<term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
		<term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
		<term name="Sound recording"/>
		<term name="Specialized courts"/>
		<term name="Terrorism"/>
		<term name="War crimes, genocide, crimes against humanity"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/15/2009--Introduced.<br/>Interrogation and Detention Reform Act of 2008 [sic] - Requires a head of an element of the intelligence community who has custody or effective control of an detained individual to immediately notify the International Committee of the Red Cross of such custody or control and allow such Committee physical and repeat access to such individual. Repeals: (1) the Military Commissions Act of 2006; (2) additional punitive provisions relating to conspiracy to commit crimes against the law of war and additional prohibitions against cruel, inhuman, or degrading treatment or punishment; (3) prohibitions against the issuance of writs of habeas corpus for enemy combatants; and (4) the authority to conduct combatant status review tribunals.<br/>Directs the President to: (1) close the Department of Defense detention facility at Guantanamo Bay, Cuba; (2) remove from such facility each individual designated as an enemy combatant or unlawful enemy combatant; and (3) submit a plan to Congress for the prosecution, transfer, release, or other disposition of such combatants.<br/>Expresses the sense of Congress with respect to the investigation and prosecution of international terrorism.<br/>Directs the President to: (1) establish uniform standards for the interrogation of individuals in U.S. custody or under U.S. control; (2) establish the U.S. Center for Excellence in Human Intelligence Collection to train members of the Armed Forces and personnel of the intelligence community to conduct research and examine doctrine and policy related to human intelligence collection; and (3) submit to Congress a strategy for the detention of terrorist suspects and convicts.<br/>Prohibits the use of private contractors for activities relating to the capture, custody, control, or other pertinent interaction with a detainee or prisoner in U.S. custody.<br/>Establishes requirements for recording strategic intelligence interrogations of individuals held in U.S. custody or under detention in a U.S. facility.<br/>Expresses the sense of Congress relating to international cooperation on human intelligence collection.<br/>Directs the Secretary of Defense to develop incentives for the improvement of human intelligence collection capabilities.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
