<bill session="111" type="h" number="605" updated="2009-03-07T10:58:43-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1232082000" datetime="2009-01-16"/></status>

	<introduced date="1232082000" datetime="2009-01-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Pregnant Women Support Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for programs that reduce the need for abortion, help women bear healthy children, and support new parents.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400096"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400230" joined="2009-02-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400219" joined="2009-01-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400385" joined="2009-02-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400299" joined="2009-01-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400286" joined="2009-01-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="412191" joined="2009-01-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1232082000" datetime="2009-01-16"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, Education and Labor, and Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1232082000" datetime="2009-01-16"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1232082000" datetime="2009-01-16"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1232082000" datetime="2009-01-16"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1232082000" datetime="2009-01-16"><text>Referred to House Agriculture</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="270" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Abortion"/>
		<term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
		<term name="Child care and development"/>
		<term name="Child health"/>
		<term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
		<term name="Crime victims"/>
		<term name="Crimes against women"/>
		<term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
		<term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
		<term name="Education programs funding"/>
		<term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
		<term name="Genetics"/>
		<term name="Government information and archives"/>
		<term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
		<term name="Health information and medical records"/>
		<term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
		<term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
		<term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
		<term name="Hereditary and development disorders"/>
		<term name="Higher education"/>
		<term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
		<term name="Income tax credits"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
		<term name="Nursing"/>
		<term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
		<term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
		<term name="Teenage pregnancy"/>
		<term name="Violent crime"/>
		<term name="Women's health"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/16/2009--Introduced.<br/>Pregnant Women Support Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to increase public awareness of resources available to pregnant women to carry their pregnancy to term and new parents. Amends the Public Health Service Act to allow the Secretary to make grants for the purchase of ultrasound equipment for examinations of pregnant women. Prohibits a health insurance issuer offering individual coverage from imposing a preexisting condition exclusion or a waiting period or otherwise discriminating against a woman on the basis that she is pregnant. Provides for continuation coverage for newborns. Amends title XXI (State Children's Health Insurance Program) (SCHIP) of the Social Security Act to allow states to extend health care coverage to an unborn child. Requires health facilities that perform abortions to obtain informed consent from a pregnant woman seeking an abortion. Provides for the collection and dissemination of information on Down syndrome and other prenatally diagnosed conditions. Directs the Secretary to provide for: (1) higher education pregnant and parenting student services offices; and (2) programs to work with pregnant or parenting teens to complete high school. Authorizes grants for services to pregnant women who are victims of domestic violence, dating violence, or stalking. Requires states to require a pregnancy determination for homicide victims. Requires the Secretary to provide for comprehensive and supportive services for pregnant women, mothers, and children. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to increase and make refundable the tax credit for adoption expenses. Authorizes appropriations to carry out the special supplemental nutrition program for women, infants, and children (WIC program). Amends the Food Stamp Act of 1977 to increase the eligibility threshold for food stamps. Authorizes appropriations to carry out the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990. Authorizes grants to provide to eligible mothers education on the health needs of their infants through visits to their homes by registered nurses. Authorizes grants for collecting and reporting abortion surveillance data.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
