<bill session="111" type="h" number="606" updated="2009-03-07T10:58:50-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1232082000" datetime="2009-01-16"/></status>

	<introduced date="1232082000" datetime="2009-01-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">International Women's Freedom Act of 2009</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To express United States foreign policy with respect to, and to strengthen United States advocacy on behalf of, individuals persecuted and denied their rights in foreign countries on account of gender, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400251"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2009-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400129" joined="2009-03-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400130" joined="2009-01-16"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1232082000" datetime="2009-01-16"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E109)</text></action>
		<action date="1232082000" datetime="2009-01-16"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1232082000" datetime="2009-01-16"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1232082000" datetime="2009-01-16"><text>Referred to House Financial Services</text></action>
		<action date="1232082000" datetime="2009-01-16"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="s" number="230" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="Advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Business ethics"/>
		<term name="Department of State"/>
		<term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
		<term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
		<term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
		<term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
		<term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
		<term name="Government information and archives"/>
		<term name="Human rights"/>
		<term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
		<term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
		<term name="Sanctions"/>
		<term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
		<term name="Trade restrictions"/>
		<term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
		<term name="Women's rights"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/16/2009--Introduced.<br/>International Women's Freedom Act of 2009 - Establishes within the Department of State an Office of International Women's Rights to be headed by an Ambassador at Large for International Women's Rights. Directs the Secretary of State to: (1) establish a women's rights Internet site; and (2) maintain prisoner lists and issue briefs on women's rights concerns. Amends the Foreign Service Act of 1980 to include instruction on the internationally recognized rights of women and the various aspects and manifestations of violations of women's rights in Foreign Service officer training. Establishes the United States Commission on International Women's Rights. (Terminates the Commission 12 years after the date of the initial appointment of its members.) Amends the National Security Act of 1947 to express the sense of Congress that there should be within the National Security Council (NSC) staff a Special Adviser to the President on International Women's Rights. Directs the President to take specified actions in response to women's rights violations, including actions in response to particularly severe rights violations. Provides for prohibition of economic, multilateral, military, and export assistance in instances of particularly severe women's rights violations. Provides for the promotion of women's rights. Provides for women's rights-related training with respect to refugee, asylum, and consular matters. Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide for the inadmissibility of foreign government officials who have engaged in particularly severe women's rights violations. Expresses the sense of Congress that transnational corporations operating overseas should adopt codes of conduct upholding the rights of their female employees. 
	</summary>
</bill>
