<bill session="111" type="h" number="641" updated="2009-03-07T11:02:59-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1232600400" datetime="2009-01-22"/></status>

	<introduced date="1232600400" datetime="2009-01-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">No Net Loss of Private Land Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To limit the authority of the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior to acquire land located in a State in which 25 percent or more of all land in the State is already owned by the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400134"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1232600400" datetime="2009-01-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1233723600" datetime="2009-02-04"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/22/2009--Introduced.<br/>No Net Loss of Private Land Act - Allows the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior to acquire an interest in a parcel of land consisting of 100 or more acres in a state in which 25% or more of all land in the state is owned by the United States only if, before the acquisition of such interest, all right, title, and interest of the United States in the surface estate of another parcel of land in the state is conveyed in accordance with this Act. Provides that, to qualify as a conveyance of the surface estate of a parcel of federal land, the Secretary concerned shall certify to Congress that: (1) the conveyance was made to comply with the requirements described above (the requirements); and (2) the value of the surface estate of the conveyed federal land is approximately equal to the value of the interest to be acquired. Prohibits the Secretary concerned from dividing a parcel of land consisting of 100 acres or more into smaller parcels to avoid the requirements. Makes certain land acquisitions non-applicable to this Act. Permits the waiver of the requirements with respect to the acquisition of a particular parcel of land during a period in which there is in effect a declaration of war or a national emergency declared by the President and the Secretary concerned certifies to Congress that such land acquisition is necessary to respond to such war or national emergency. 
	</summary>
</bill>
