<bill session="111" type="h" number="642" updated="2009-03-07T11:03:06-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1232600400" datetime="2009-01-22"/></status>

	<introduced date="1232600400" datetime="2009-01-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Recreational Shooting Protection Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To provide opportunities for continued recreational shooting on certain Federal public land.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400134"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1232600400" datetime="2009-01-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1233723600" datetime="2009-02-04"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Firearms"/>
		<term name="Government liability"/>
		<term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
		<term name="Land use and conservation"/>
		<term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
		<term name="State and local government operations"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/22/2009--Introduced.<br/>Recreational Shooting Protection Act - Declares that, federal public land shall be open to access and use for recreational shooting, except as limited by the Director of the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) for one or more of the following: (1) reasons of national security; (2) reasons of public safety; (3) to comply with applicable federal law; or (4) to comply with a law (including regulations) of the state in which the land is located that is applicable to recreational shooting. Requires management of federal public land in a manner that supports, promotes, and enhances recreational shooting opportunities.<br/>Provides that, federal public land management decisions and actions, shall to the maximum extent practicable, result in no net loss of land area available for recreational shooting on federal public land. Requires that, if any federal public land is permanently closed to recreational shooting, new acres of federal public land of comparable size and a reasonable distance from the closed location be designated for recreational shooting and be opened for the number of user-days equal to those available at the closed area. Requires the Director to submit annual reports describing: (1) any federal public land that was closed to recreational shooting; (2) the reason for the closure; and (3) federal public land that was opened to recreational hunting so as to compensate for the closure of such land. Permits states a right of action for failure of the Director to comply with this Act. 
	</summary>
</bill>
