<bill session="111" type="h" number="653" updated="2009-03-07T11:04:25-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1232600400" datetime="2009-01-22"/></status>

	<introduced date="1232600400" datetime="2009-01-22"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">National Childhood Brain Tumor Prevention Network Act of 2009</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title IV of the Public Health Service Act to create a National Childhood Brain Tumor Prevention Network to provide grants and coordinate research with respect to the causes of and risk factors associated with childhood brain tumors, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400237"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1232600400" datetime="2009-01-22"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="identical" session="111" type="s" number="305" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Cancer"/>
		<term name="Child health"/>
		<term name="Health information and medical records"/>
		<term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
		<term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
		<term name="Medical research"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/22/2009--Introduced.<br/>National Childhood Brain Tumor Prevention Network Act of 2009 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH), acting through the Director of the National Cancer Institute, to establish, administer, and coordinate a National Childhood Brain Tumor Prevention Network to: (1) provide grants for research on the causes of and risk factors associated with childhood brain tumors; (2) assemble a panel of experts to provide ongoing guidance and recommendations on research funded by the Network, including on a common study design and standard protocols; and (3) designate a central laboratory to collect, analyze, and aggregate data with respect to research funded by the Network and to make such data and analysis available to researchers.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
