<bill session="111" type="h" number="66" updated="2009-03-07T09:55:29-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Military Success in Iraq And Diplomatic Surge for National and Political Reconciliation in Iraq Act of 2009</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To recognize the extraordinary performance of the Armed Forces in achieving the military objectives of the United States in Iraq, to terminate the Authorization for Use of Military Force Against Iraq Resolution of 2002 (Public Law 107-243), to require congressional reauthorization to continue deployment of the Armed Forces to Iraq, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400199"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"><text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"><text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text></action>
		<action date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"><text>Referred to House Armed Services</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
		<term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
		<term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
		<term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Defense spending"/>
		<term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
		<term name="Egypt"/>
		<term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
		<term name="Europe"/>
		<term name="European Union"/>
		<term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
		<term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
		<term name="Iran"/>
		<term name="Iraq"/>
		<term name="Middle East"/>
		<term name="Military assistance and sales, agreements, alliances"/>
		<term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
		<term name="Militias and paramilitary groups"/>
		<term name="Oil and gas"/>
		<term name="Persian Gulf States"/>
		<term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
		<term name="Reconstruction and stabilization"/>
		<term name="Religion"/>
		<term name="Saudi Arabia"/>
		<term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
		<term name="Syria"/>
		<term name="Terrorism"/>
		<term name="United Nations"/>
		<term name="War and emergency powers"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/6/2009--Introduced.<br/>Military Success in Iraq and Diplomatic Surge for National and Political Reconciliation in Iraq Act of 2009 - Makes specified declarations of policy, including that: (1) the Authorization for Use of Military Force Against Iraq Resolution of 2002 (the Iraq Resolution) is the sole basis of authority under which the President launched the invasion of Iraq in 2003; (2) Congress authorized the use of such force to defend U.S. national security and to enforce all relevant United Nations (UN) Security Council resolutions regarding Iraq; and (3) Congress has the ultimate authority to determine whether such objectives have been achieved. Repeals the Iraq Resolution. Requires the withdrawal, by the earlier of October 1, 2009, or 90 days after the enactment of this Act, of all units and members of U.S. Armed Forces deployed in Iraq, as well as all security forces under federal contract and working in Iraq. Provides exceptions. States as the policy of the United States to pursue regional and international initiatives to assist Iraq in achieving certain security, political, and economic milestones. Sets forth presidential actions to implement such policy.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
