<bill session="111" type="h" number="669" updated="2009-03-07T11:06:23-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1232946000" datetime="2009-01-26"/></status>

	<introduced date="1232946000" datetime="2009-01-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Nonnative Wildlife Invasion Prevention Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To prevent the introduction and establishment of nonnative wildlife species that negatively impact the economy, environment, or other animal species' or human health, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400041"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400290" joined="2009-01-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400128" joined="2009-02-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400001" joined="2009-01-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400263" joined="2009-01-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400436" joined="2009-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2009-01-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2009-02-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400140" joined="2009-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="2009-01-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400218" joined="2009-01-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400216" joined="2009-01-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="412198" joined="2009-01-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400278" joined="2009-01-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1232946000" datetime="2009-01-26"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E142)</text></action>
		<action date="1232946000" datetime="2009-01-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1233723600" datetime="2009-02-04"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Animals"/>
		<term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
		<term name="Department of the Interior"/>
		<term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
		<term name="Government information and archives"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
		<term name="Trade restrictions"/>
		<term name="User charges and fees"/>
		<term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/26/2009--Introduced.<br/>Nonnative Wildlife Invasion Prevention Act - Requires the Secretary of the Interior to promulgate regulations establishing a process for assessing the risk of all nonnative wildlife species proposed for importation into the United States, other than those included in a list of approved species issued under this Act. Sets forth factors that must be considered, including the identity of the organism to the species level, the native range of the species, whether the species has caused harm to the economy, the environment, or other animal species or human health in similar ecosystems, and the likelihood of establishment or spread of the species in the United States. Provides procedures for issuance and expansion of a list of nonnative wildlife species approved for importation and a list of nonnative wildlife species that are prohibited.<br/>Establishes prohibitions on: (1) importation or transportation between states of nonnative species that are not included in the list of approved species; (2) permit violations; and (3) possession, purchase, sale, barter, release, or breeding of such species.<br/>Exempts from such prohibitions actions by law enforcement personnel to enforce this Act or by federal or state officials to prevent the introduction or establishment of nonnative wildlife species. Declares that nothing in this act restricts the importation or transportation between states of such species by a federal agency for its own use if the species remains in its possession. Authorizes the Secretary to issue permits authorizing otherwise prohibited importation for scientific research, for medical, accredited zoological or aquarium display purposes, or for educational purposes that are specifically reviewed, approved, and verified by the Secretary if the Secretary finds that there has been a proper showing by the permittee of responsibility for the specimen and continued protection of the public interest and health.<br/>Allows the imposition of fees on persons who submit a proposal to include a species in either of the lists to recover the costs of assessing risks of nonnative wildlife species. Establishes a Nonnative Wildlife Invasion Prevention Fund into which such fees and fines for violations will be deposited.<br/>Redesignates the Invasive Species Council established by Executive Order 13112 as the National Invasive Species Council.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
