<bill session="111" type="h" number="673" updated="2009-03-07T11:06:50-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1232946000" datetime="2009-01-26"/></status>

	<introduced date="1232946000" datetime="2009-01-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Law Enforcement Officers Equity Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the definition of a law enforcement officer under subchapter III of chapter 83 and chapter 84 of title 5, United States Code, respectively, to ensure the inclusion of certain positions.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400133"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412258" joined="2009-02-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="412229" joined="2009-02-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400027" joined="2009-02-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400430" joined="2009-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400647" joined="2009-03-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400415" joined="2009-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400093" joined="2009-02-23"/>
		<cosponsor id="400264" joined="2009-01-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400184" joined="2009-02-10"/>
		<cosponsor id="400321" joined="2009-02-10"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1232946000" datetime="2009-01-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text></action>
		<action date="1233118800" datetime="2009-01-28"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E161-162)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Government operations and politics"/>
		<term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
		<term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
		<term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
		<term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/26/2009--Introduced.<br/>Law Enforcement Officers Equity Act - Amends the definition of the term &quot;law enforcement officer&quot; under provisions of the Federal Employees Retirement System (FERS) and the Civil Service Retirement System (CSRS) to include: (1) federal employees not otherwise covered by such term whose duties include the investigation or apprehension of suspected or convicted individuals and who are authorized to carry a firearm; and (2) such employees of the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) whose duties are primarily the collection of delinquent taxes and the securing of delinquent returns. Requires such service that is performed by an incumbent law enforcement officer: (1) after enactment of this Act to be treated as service performed as a law enforcement officer for federal retirement purposes; and (2) before, on, or after enactment as service performed as such an officer for federal retirement purposes only if an appropriate written election is submitted to the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) within five years after enactment or before separation from government service, whichever is earlier. Provides that nothing under current law respecting mandatory separation from government service under CSRS or FERS shall cause the involuntary separation of an officer before the end of the three-year period following enactment.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
