<bill session="111" type="h" number="68" updated="2009-03-07T09:55:42-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">No More Tulias: Drug Law Enforcement Evidentiary Standards Improvement Act of 2009</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To increase the evidentiary standard required to convict a person for a drug offense, to require screening of law enforcement officers or others acting under color of law participating in drug task forces, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400199"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1234155600" datetime="2009-02-09"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
		<term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
		<term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
		<term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
		<term name="Investigation, prosecution, interrogation methods"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
		<term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/6/2009--Introduced.<br/>No More Tulias: Drug Law Enforcement Evidentiary Standards Improvement Act of 2009 - Prohibits a state from receiving for a fiscal year any drug control and system improvement (Byrne) grant funds under the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968, or any amount from any other law enforcement assistance program of the Department of Justice, unless the state does not fund any antidrug task forces for that fiscal year or the state has in effect laws that ensure that: (1) a person is not convicted of a drug offense unless the facts that a drug offense was committed and that the person committed that offense are supported by evidence other than the eyewitness testimony of a law enforcement officer (officer) or individuals acting on an officer's behalf; and (2) an officer does not participate in a antidrug task force unless that officer's honesty and integrity is evaluated and found to be at an appropriately high level. Requires states receiving federal funds under this Act to collect data on the racial distribution of drug charges, the nature of the criminal law specified in the charges, and the jurisdictions in which such charges are made.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
