<bill session="111" type="h" number="689" updated="2009-03-07T11:08:40-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1232946000" datetime="2009-01-26"/></status>

	<introduced date="1232946000" datetime="2009-01-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To interchange the administrative jurisdiction of certain Federal lands between the Forest Service and the Bureau of Land Management, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400176"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1232946000" datetime="2009-01-26"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E138)</text></action>
		<action date="1232946000" datetime="2009-01-26"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1233723600" datetime="2009-02-04"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
		<term name="California"/>
		<term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
		<term name="Department of the Interior"/>
		<term name="Forests"/>
		<term name="Government information and archives"/>
		<term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/26/2009--Introduced.<br/>Transfers the administrative jurisdiction of specified federally owned lands in the Shasta-Trinity National Forest in California from the Secretary of Agriculture to the Secretary of the Interior. Subjects such lands to the laws, rules, and regulations applicable to the public lands administered by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM). Excepts lands within the Shasta Dam Reclamation Zone from such transfer and continues the administration of those lands by the Secretary of the Interior through the Bureau of Reclamation. Transfers the administrative jurisdiction of specified federally owned lands in California administered by the BLM from the Secretary of the Interior to the Secretary of Agriculture. Subjects such lands to the laws, rules, and regulations applicable to the National Forest System. Requires the Forest Service and the BLM, with respect to the transfer of their lands, to identify any known sites concerning hazardous substances and to provide such information to the receiving agency.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
