<bill session="111" type="h" number="72" updated="2009-03-07T09:56:09-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To increase global stability and security for the United States and the international community by reducing the number of individuals who are de jure or de facto stateless and at risk of being trafficked.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400199"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400423" joined="2009-01-07"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="Department of State"/>
		<term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
		<term name="Human rights"/>
		<term name="Human trafficking"/>
		<term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
		<term name="United Nations"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/6/2009--Introduced.<br/>States that: (1) it shall be U.S. policy that the President and the Permanent Representative of the United States to the United Nations work with the international community to increase political and financial support for the Office of the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) to prevent and resolve problems related to de jure and de facto statelessness and to promote the rights of de jure or de facto stateless persons; (2) the President shall make prevention and reduction of de jure or de facto statelessness an important goal of U.S. foreign policy and human rights efforts; and (3) it shall be U.S. policy to comply with the 1954 Convention Relating to the Status of Stateless Persons and the 1961 Convention on the Reduction of Statelessness. Directs the Secretary of State to increase staff and resources in the Bureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration to work toward the prevention and resolution of de jure and de facto statelessness and the protection of de jure or de facto stateless persons.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
