<bill session="111" type="h" number="760" updated="2009-03-07T11:17:18-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1233118800" datetime="2009-01-28"/></status>

	<introduced date="1233118800" datetime="2009-01-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Advanced Broadband Infrastructure Bond Initiative of 2009</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide an income tax credit to holders of bonds financing new advanced broadband infrastructure, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400124"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400253" joined="2009-01-28"/>
		<cosponsor id="400403" joined="2009-01-28"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1233118800" datetime="2009-01-28"><text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1233118800" datetime="2009-01-28"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1233118800" datetime="2009-01-28"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
		<term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital media"/>
		<term name="Business records"/>
		<term name="Department of Commerce"/>
		<term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
		<term name="Financial services and investments"/>
		<term name="Income tax credits"/>
		<term name="Infrastructure development"/>
		<term name="Internet and video services"/>
		<term name="Securities"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Taxation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/28/2009--Introduced.<br/>Advanced Broadband Infrastructure Bond Initiative of 2009 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a tax credit for investment in qualified advanced broadband infrastructure bonds. Limits the issuance authority for such bonds in 2009, 2010 and 2011 to $1 billion for state and local government issuers and $10 billion for all other issuers. Requires the use of bond proceeds to finance broadband infrastructure projects to provide residential or small business consumers with high-speed access to the Internet.<br/>Amends the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act to require the National Telecommunications and Information Administration in the Department of Commerce to: (1) approve requests for qualified advanced broadband infrastructure projects; (2) monitor the implementation of such projects; and (3) make determinations regarding increases in the transmission speed requirements of the advanced broadband infrastructure bond program. 
	</summary>
</bill>
