<bill session="111" type="h" number="763" updated="2009-03-07T11:17:38-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1233118800" datetime="2009-01-28"/></status>

	<introduced date="1233118800" datetime="2009-01-28"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Carson City Vital Community Act of 2009</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To promote conservation and provide for sensible development in Carson City, Nevada, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412218"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1233118800" datetime="2009-01-28"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1233723600" datetime="2009-02-04"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks, Forests and Public Lands" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
		<term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
		<term name="Forests"/>
		<term name="Gambling"/>
		<term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
		<term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
		<term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
		<term name="Land transfers"/>
		<term name="Land use and conservation"/>
		<term name="Nevada"/>
		<term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
		<term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
		<term name="Religion"/>
		<term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/28/2009--Introduced.<br/>Carson City Vital Community Act of 2009 - Provides for the conveyance of specified Forest Service and Bureau of Land Management (BLM) land or interest in such land (the federal land) in Nevada by the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior in exchange for specified non-federal land by Carson City Consolidated Municipality, Nevada. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to reserve a perpetual conservation easement to the Silver Saddle Ranch and Carson River Area. Releases the reversionary interest of BLM in certain of the conveyed federal land. Provides for the conveyance of such land by the City. Makes the non-federal land part of the Humboldt-Toiyabe National Forest. Provides for the conveyance of specified non-federal land administered by the City to the BLM. Transfers administrative jurisdiction over certain Forest Service land from the Secretary of Agriculture to the Secretary of the Interior. Requires the City to be granted a right-of-way for maintenance of flood management facilities on such land. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to conduct sales of specified BLM land to qualified bidders. Amends the Southern Nevada Public Land Management Act of 1998 to make amounts in the special account available to the City for the development of parks, trails, and natural areas and for the reimbursement of costs incurred by BLM local offices in arranging sales or exchanges under the Act. Makes the City eligible to nominate for expenditure amounts to acquire lands or interests for parks and natural areas and for conservation initiatives adjacent to and within the floodplain of Carson River. Provides for specified land to be held in trust for the Washoe Tribe of Nevada and California. Prohibits the use of such land for class II and class III gaming. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to implement a cooperative agreement ensuring access by the Tribe's members and others in its community across National Forest System land from the City to Lake Tahoe for cultural and religious purposes. Requires the City to notify the Tribe of proposed ground disturbing activities to provide the Tribe with time for inventorying and collecting tribal artifacts. 
	</summary>
</bill>
