<bill session="111" type="h" number="800" updated="2009-03-07T11:21:52-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1233637200" datetime="2009-02-03"/></status>

	<introduced date="1233637200" datetime="2009-02-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Farming Flexibility Act of 2009</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008 to authorize producers on a farm to produce fruits and vegetables for processing on the base acres of the farm.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400013"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412205" joined="2009-02-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400110" joined="2009-03-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400385" joined="2009-02-11"/>
		<cosponsor id="400036" joined="2009-02-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412256" joined="2009-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400318" joined="2009-02-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400315" joined="2009-02-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400218" joined="2009-02-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412214" joined="2009-02-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="400288" joined="2009-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400055" joined="2009-02-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="412206" joined="2009-02-03"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1233637200" datetime="2009-02-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/3/2009--Introduced.<br/>Farming Flexibility Act of 2009 - Amends the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008 to limit the pilot project permitting the planting of cucumbers, green peas, lima beans, pumpkins, snap beans, sweet corn, and tomatoes grown for processing on base acres to crop year 2009. (Under current law such pilot program is authorized through crop year 2012.) Provides that: (1) as of crop year 2010 producers on a farm may reduce the base acres for any covered commodity if such acres are used for the production of fruits or vegetables for processing; (2) such acres devoted to fruits or vegetables shall be included in base acres for the covered commodity for the subsequent crop year unless the producers on the farm make the election to produce fruits and vegetables for the subsequent crop year; and (3) if a farm's base acres are recalculated the production of fruits or vegetables shall be considered to be the same as the planting, prevented planting, or production of the covered commodity.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
