<bill session="111" type="h" number="844" updated="2009-03-07T11:27:25-05:00">
	<status><vote date="1236019260" datetime="2009-03-02T14:41:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" how="by voice vote" roll=""/></status>

	<introduced date="1233637200" datetime="2009-02-03"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Marine Mammal Rescue Assistance Amendments of 2009</title>
		<title type="short" as="passed house">Marine Mammal Rescue Assistance Amendments of 2009</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the provisions of law relating to the John H. Prescott Marine Mammal Rescue Assistance Grant Program, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400440"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1233637200" datetime="2009-02-03"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1233896400" datetime="2009-02-06"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife.</text></action>
		<action date="1236019020" datetime="2009-03-02T14:37:00-05:00"><text>Mr. Holt moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text></action>
		<action date="1236019020" datetime="2009-03-02T14:37:00-05:00"><text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text><reference label="consideration" ref="CR H2883-2884"/></action>
		<action date="1236019020" datetime="2009-03-02T14:37:00-05:00"><text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 844.</text></action>
		<vote date="1236019260" how="by voice vote" datetime="2009-03-02T14:41:00-05:00" where="h" type="vote" result="pass" ><text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text><reference label="text" ref="CR H2883-2884"/></vote>
		<action date="1236056400" datetime="2009-03-03"><text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral" />
		<committee name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife" activity="Referral" />
		<committee name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	3/2/2009--Passed House without amendment. (This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.) Marine Mammal Rescue Assistance Amendments of 2009 - Amends the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 to require the collection and updating of existing practices and procedures for rescuing and rehabilitating stranded or entangled (under current law, only stranded) marine mammals. Authorizes entanglement response agreements. Authorizes appropriations (at an increased annual level) through FY2013 to carry out the existing John H. Prescott Marine Mammal Rescue Assistance Grant Program. Authorizes cooperative agreements, contracts, or other agreements or arrangements to address stranding events requiring emergency assistance. Authorizes appropriations through FY2013 to the Marine Mammal Unusual Mortality Event Fund.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
