<bill session="111" type="h" number="860" updated="2009-03-07T11:29:24-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1233723600" datetime="2009-02-04"/></status>

	<introduced date="1233723600" datetime="2009-02-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Coral Reef Conservation Act Reauthorization and Enhancement Amendments of 2009</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To reauthorize the Coral Reef Conservation Act of 2000, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400041"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400222" joined="2009-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400128" joined="2009-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400073" joined="2009-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400001" joined="2009-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2009-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400237" joined="2009-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400178" joined="2009-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400623" joined="2009-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400129" joined="2009-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400170" joined="2009-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="412195" joined="2009-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="412200" joined="2009-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400344" joined="2009-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="412312" joined="2009-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="412306" joined="2009-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2009-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="400062" joined="2009-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="412198" joined="2009-02-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1233723600" datetime="2009-02-04"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E212)</text></action>
		<action date="1233723600" datetime="2009-02-04"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1233896400" datetime="2009-02-06"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife.</text></action>
		<action date="1235538000" datetime="2009-02-25"><text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife" activity="Referral, Hearings" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/4/2009--Introduced.<br/>Coral Reef Conservation Act Reauthorization and Enhancement Amendments of 2009 - Coral Reef Conservation Amendments Act of 2009 - Amends the Coral Reef Conservation Act of 2000 to extend the award of remaining coral reef conservation program grant funds to appropriate projects, including monitoring and assessment, research, pollution reduction, education, and technical support. Authorizes actions to minimize injury to a coral reef or loss of an ecosystem function from vessel impacts, derelict fishing gear, vessel anchors and anchor chains, and unforeseen or disaster-related circumstances as a result of human activities and to stabilize, repair, or restore the reef, including vessel removal and emergency stabilization of the vessel or reef. Deems specified terms (such as &quot;sanctuary resources&quot; and &quot;national marine sanctuary&quot;) to include any coral reef that is subject to the jurisdiction of the United States or (subject to state consent) any state, regardless of whether the reef is in a national marine sanctuary. Modifies the Act's purposes, the goals and objectives of the national coral reef action strategy, and the Act's authorized activities. Directs the Secretary of Commerce to provide for the long-term stewardship of environmental data. Allows the Coral Reef Conservation Fund to be used to address emergency response actions. Authorizes the Administrator to: (1) make community-based planning grants for increased protection of high priority coral reefs; (2) maintain an inventory of all vessel grounding incidents involving coral reefs; and (3) identify all coral reefs with a high incidence of vessel impacts and measures to reduce such impacts. Establishes the International Coral Reef Conservation Program for ecosystems outside U.S. jurisdiction and establishes an international coral reef ecosystem partnership program. Establishes the U.S. Coral Reef Task Force to coordinate federal actions regarding such ecosystems. Amends the Fish and Wildlife Coordination Act to include such ecosystems in the definition of &quot;wildlife&quot; and &quot;wildlife resources.&quot; Requires, regarding authorities under the Fish and Wildlife Act of 1956 and the Fish and Wildlife Improvement Act of 1978, that references to &quot;wildlife&quot; and &quot;fish and wildlife&quot; be construed to include such ecosystems. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior, subject to appropriations, to provide financial assistance to coastal states.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
