<bill session="111" type="h" number="89" updated="2009-03-07T09:58:10-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Goleta Water Distribution System Conveyance Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to convey a water distribution system to the Goleta Water District, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400062"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text></action>
		<action date="1233723600" datetime="2009-02-04"><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water and Power" activity="Referral" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Water resources development"/>
		<term name="California"/>
		<term name="Water use and supply"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/6/2009--Introduced.<br/>Goleta Water Distribution System Conveyance Act - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to convey all U.S. rights to the Goleta Water Distribution System of the Cachuma Project, California, consistent with the terms of the Agreement Between the United States and the Goleta Water District to Transfer Title of the Federally Owned Distribution System to the Goleta Water District. Shields the United States from liability for damages relating to the conveyed property, except those caused by negligent acts by U.S. employees or agents prior to conveyance. Provides that after the conveyance: (1) the System shall not be considered to be part of a federal reclamation project; and (2) the District shall not be eligible to receive any benefits with respect to any facility comprising the Goleta Water Distribution System, except benefits that would be available to a similarly situated entity with respect to property that is not part of a federal reclamation project. Requires: (1) the Secretary to complete all actions required under environmental and historic preservation laws prior to any conveyance; and (2) the District to comply with all applicable federal, state, and local laws in its operation of the transferred facilities. Provides that federal reclamation law shall continue to apply to project water provided to the District. Requires the Secretary to report to Congress if the conveyance has not been completed within 12 months.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
