<bill session="111" type="h" number="913" updated="2009-03-07T11:35:46-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1234155600" datetime="2009-02-09"/></status>

	<introduced date="1234155600" datetime="2009-02-09"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Mentoring America's Children Act of 2009</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to strengthen mentoring programs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400097"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400082" joined="2009-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400048" joined="2009-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400259" joined="2009-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2009-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="412232" joined="2009-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400342" joined="2009-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="412239" joined="2009-03-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400185" joined="2009-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400215" joined="2009-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400030" joined="2009-03-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="400312" joined="2009-02-25"/>
		<cosponsor id="400179" joined="2009-02-25"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1234155600" datetime="2009-02-09"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E222)</text></action>
		<action date="1234155600" datetime="2009-02-09"><text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Education"/>
		<term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
		<term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
		<term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
		<term name="Education programs funding"/>
		<term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
		<term name="Higher education"/>
		<term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
		<term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
		<term name="Minority education"/>
		<term name="Performance measurement"/>
		<term name="Policy sciences"/>
		<term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
		<term name="Violent crime"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/9/2009--Introduced.<br/>Mentoring America's Children Act of 2009 - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to make miscellaneous changes to the Mentoring grant program under title IV that include: (1) improvement of school connectedness and character education among mentoring's purposes; (2) corporations, universities, and other entities among program providers; (3) a requirement that mentors help children become responsible and successful adults; (4) suburban children in high crime areas and children living in high gang involvement, drug use, or dropout areas among those most in need of mentoring; (5) limitation of each mentor to no more than three children; and (6) mandatory information on grant applicants about plans for monitoring mentor/mentee matches and the satisfaction of grant matching requirements that increase from 10% to 50% over the three-year grant term. Allows grantees to be considered for new grants if: (1) their prior performance was satisfactory; (2) they propose to use the new grant exclusively for expanded service to a new area or population; and (3) they are able to provide a 50% match to the new grant funds. Directs the Secretary of Education to: (1) provide training and technical assistance to grantees, and track and evaluate their performance; and (2) arrange for research on school-based mentoring, the results of which are to be provided to the mentoring community. Includes mentoring in ESEA programs for: (1) Indian, Native Hawaiian, and Alaskan Native education; (2) the transitioning of youth offenders into education; and (3) school violence and drug abuse prevention.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
