<bill session="111" type="h" number="938" updated="2009-03-07T11:38:38-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1234242000" datetime="2009-02-10"/></status>

	<introduced date="1234242000" datetime="2009-02-10"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Keeping Families Together Act of 2009</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to restore certain provisions relating to the definition of aggravated felony and other provisions as they were before the enactment of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400133"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400387" joined="2009-03-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400162" joined="2009-03-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1234242000" datetime="2009-02-10"><text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
		<action date="1234414800" datetime="2009-02-12"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E251)</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/10/2009--Introduced.<br/>Keeping Families Together Act of 2009 - Amends the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 (Act) to repeal the provision amending the definition of &quot;aggravated felony,&quot; and restore provisions of law amended by such provision as if it had not been enacted, including residency-or status-related rights of an affected legal alien. Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to revise detention of criminal alien provisions, effective as if included in the Act. Repeals, as if included in the Act: (1) certain provisions respecting termination of continuous presence or physical presence in the United States; and (2) the definition of &quot;conviction.&quot; Authorizes the Secretary of Homeland Security to admit certain lawfully admitted permanent resident aliens returning to the United States who temporarily proceeded abroad voluntarily and not under an order of deportation or removal, effective as of a specified date, as if certain sections of the Antiterrorism and Effective Death Penalty Act of 1996 and the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 had not been enacted. Revises provisions respecting judicial review of removal orders. Requires the Secretary to establish a post-proceeding removal relief process for affected aliens. 
	</summary>
</bill>
