<bill session="111" type="h" number="98" updated="2009-03-07T09:59:13-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Illegal Immigration Enforcement and Social Security Protection Act of 2009</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to enforce restrictions on employment in the United States of unauthorized aliens through the use of improved Social Security cards and an Employment Eligibility Database, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400115"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400144" joined="2009-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400277" joined="2009-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="400337" joined="2009-01-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400057" joined="2009-01-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400570" joined="2009-01-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400196" joined="2009-01-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E20-21)</text></action>
		<action date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"><text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, Homeland Security, and Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"><text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text></action>
		<action date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
		<action date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"><text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text></action>
		<action date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"><text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text></action>
		<action date="1233810000" datetime="2009-02-05"><committee name="House Homeland Security"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border, Maritime, and Global Counterterrorism.</text></action>
		<action date="1234155600" datetime="2009-02-09"><committee name="House Judiciary"/><text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law" activity="Referral" />
		<committee name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Border, Maritime, and Global Counterterrorism" activity="Referral" />
		<committee name="House Education and Labor" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Immigration"/>
		<term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
		<term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
		<term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
		<term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
		<term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
		<term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
		<term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
		<term name="Foreign labor"/>
		<term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
		<term name="Government information and archives"/>
		<term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
		<term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/6/2009--Introduced.<br/>Illegal Immigration Enforcement and Social Security Protection Act of 2009 - Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) of the Social Security Act to require inclusion of encrypted machine-readable electronic identification strips on Social Security cards. Requires the Commissioner of Social Security to: (1) develop the strip in a manner that enables employers to access the Employment Eligibility Database (EED) established by this Act; and (2) transmit to the Secretary of Homeland Security necessary information from an individual's application for a Social Security card or number for inclusion in the EED. Directs the Secretary to establish and maintain the EED. Requires the EED to include data on the citizenship status and work and residency eligibility of noncitizens authorized to work in the United States. Restricts access to EED information. Prohibits individuals from commencing employment with a U.S. employer absent a Social Security card that meets the requirements of this Act and presentation of such card to the employer. Prohibits employers from hiring individuals absent verification of identity and work authorization. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) assess penalties against employers who knowingly hire unauthorized workers or fail to comply with verification procedures; and (2) bring civil actions against those who fail to pay assessments or otherwise violate this Act. Establishes criminal penalties for such violations. Requires integration of Border Patrol and Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) fingerprint databases. Prohibits this Act from being construed to establish a national identification card.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
