<bill session="111" type="h" number="996" updated="2009-03-07T11:45:28-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1234328400" datetime="2009-02-11"/></status>

	<introduced date="1234328400" datetime="2009-02-11"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">To temporarily exempt certain public and private development projects from any requirement for a review, statement, or analysis under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.), and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400297"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412190" joined="2009-02-11"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1234328400" datetime="2009-02-11"><text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1234328400" datetime="2009-02-11"><text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text></action>
		<action date="1234328400" datetime="2009-02-11"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>

	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/11/2009--Introduced.<br/>Exempts a public or private development project that is to be carried out within three years (other than a project for which a permit for the discharge of dredged or fill material into navigable waters at specified disposal sites is required under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act or that is to be carried out on wetland as defined by the Food Security Act of 1985) from any requirement for a review, statement, or analysis under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969.<br/>Amends the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to require the Secretary of the Interior, on a state governor's declaration of an emergency, to temporarily exempt from the prohibition against taking and the prohibition against the adverse modification of critical habitat under such Act any action that is reasonably necessary to avoid or ameliorate the impact of the emergency, including the operation of any water supply or flood control project by a federal agency.<br/>Gives the United States District Court for the District of Columbia exclusive jurisdiction to hear all causes and claims that arise from any covered energy project. Defines a &quot;covered energy project&quot; as any action or decision by a federal official regarding: (1) the leasing of federal land (including submerged land) for the exploration, development, production, processing, or transmission of oil, natural gas, or any other source or form of energy; or (2) any action under such a lease. Sets forth deadlines for filing and resolving such claims.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
