<bill session="111" type="hr" number="30" updated="2009-03-07T13:07:37-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231304400" datetime="2009-01-07"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231304400" datetime="2009-01-07"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that in order to continue aggressive growth in our Nation's telecommunications and technology industries, the United States Government should &quot;Get Out of the Way and Stay Out of the Way&quot;.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="412256"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231304400" datetime="2009-01-07"><text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text></action>
		<action date="1231304400" datetime="2009-01-07"><text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text></action>
		<action date="1231304400" datetime="2009-01-07"><text>Referred to House Judiciary</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
		<committee name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="hr" number="176" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
		<term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
		<term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
		<term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital media"/>
		<term name="Business investment and capital"/>
		<term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
		<term name="Computers and information technology"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Industrial policy and productivity"/>
		<term name="Intellectual property"/>
		<term name="Internet and video services"/>
		<term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
		<term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
		<term name="Right of privacy"/>
		<term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
		<term name="Telecommunication rates and fees"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/7/2009--Introduced.<br/>Declares that it is the sense of the House of Representatives that, in order to continue aggressive growth in our nation's telecommunications and technology industries, the U.S. government should &quot;Get Out of the Way and Stay Out of the Way&quot; by: (1) promoting investment through deregulation and free-market competition; (2) reforming the Universal Service Fund and encouraging broadband deployment in rural unserved and underserved areas through public-private partnerships; (3) making additional spectrum available for commercial use through unencumbered auctions; (4) establishing a national goal of transmitting high-quality, real-time voice, data, graphics, and video at increasingly higher speeds to all people in the United States; (5) reforming our patent and trademark system to protect leading innovators' intellectual property; and (6) ensuring individual privacy without compromising market efficiencies.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
