<bill session="111" type="s" number="118" updated="2009-03-07T13:46:06-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Section 202 Supportive Housing for the Elderly Act of 2009</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend section 202 of the Housing Act of 1959, to improve the program under such section for supportive housing for the elderly, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300061"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="2009-01-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="400050" joined="2009-01-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2009-01-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2009-01-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300078" joined="2009-01-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2009-01-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="2009-01-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300063" joined="2009-01-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2009-01-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S89)</text></action>
		<action date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S89-92"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Housing and community development"/>
		<term name="Government information and archives"/>
		<term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
		<term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
		<term name="Housing for the elderly and disabled"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/6/2009--Introduced.<br/>Section 202 Supportive Housing for the Elderly Act of 2009 - Amends the Housing Act of 1959 regarding project rental assistance for supportive housing for the elderly. Changes from discretionary to mandatory the authority of the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to adjust the annual amount of a contract for project rental assistance to provide for reasonable project costs. States that owner deposits shall be used only to cover operating deficits during the first three years of operations and shall not be used to cover construction shortfalls or inadequate initial project rental assistance amounts. Allows a national private nonprofit organization that owns multiple housing projects assisted under such Act to satisfy the local governing board requirement by having a local advisory board to its national governing board. Requires the Secretary to permit an owner of assisted housing to give a preference in tenant selection to the homeless elderly. Directs the Secretary either to: (1) operate a national competition for the nonmetropolitan funds allocation of assistance for supportive housing for the elderly; or (2) make allocations to HUD regional offices. Amends the American Homeownership and Economic Opportunity Act of 2000 to revise requirements governing: (1) prepayment of debt for project-based rental housing assistance programs; (2) use of unexpended amounts; and (3) use of project residual receipts. Sets forth requirements governing senior preservation rental assistance contracts in order to: (1) prevent displacement of elderly project residents in the case of refinancing or recapitalization; and (2) further project preservation and affordability. Directs the Secretary to carry out a demonstration program to sell to state housing finance agencies portfolios of mortgages associated with loans related to supportive housing for the elderly. Expands the definition of assisted living facility with respect to grants for conversion of elderly housing to such facilities. Amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 with respect to rental assistance on behalf of a family that uses an assisted living facility as a principal place of residence. Provides that a family may be required at the time it initially receives such assistance to pay rent in an amount exceeding 40% of its monthly adjusted income. Prohibits the Secretary from imposing conditions that restrict the use of sale or refinancing proceeds, or require the filing of a financial report, in connection with a sale or refinancing of a multifamily housing project, or the transfer of an assistance contract on such a property, that requires HUD approval unless such condition is: (1) expressly authorized by an existing contract between the Secretary and the project owner; or (2) a general condition for new financing with a mortgage insured by the Secretary. Requires the Secretary to establish and operate a national senior housing clearinghouse.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
