<bill session="111" type="s" number="172" updated="2009-03-07T13:53:41-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231390800" datetime="2009-01-08"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231390800" datetime="2009-01-08"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">NOAA Ocean Exploration and Undersea Research Program Act of 2009</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a coordinated national ocean exploration program within the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300091"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="2009-01-08"/>
		<cosponsor id="300084" joined="2009-01-08"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231390800" datetime="2009-01-08"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S219-220"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="366" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
		<term name="Advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Government information and archives"/>
		<term name="Great Lakes"/>
		<term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
		<term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
		<term name="Research administration and funding"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/8/2009--Introduced.<br/>NOAA Ocean Exploration and Undersea Research Program Act of 2009 - Requires the administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to: (1) establish within NOAA a coordinated national ocean exploration program that promotes collaboration with other federal ocean and undersea research and exploration programs; (2) convene an ocean exploration and undersea research technology and infrastructure task force; and (3) appoint an Ocean Exploration Advisory Board. Requires the administrator to establish and maintain an undersea research program to increase scientific knowledge essential for the informed management, use, and preservation of oceanic, marine, and coastal areas and the Great Lakes. Requires that the program be conducted through a national headquarters, a network of extramural regional undersea research centers that represent all relevant NOAA regions, and the National Institute for Undersea Science and Technology. Requires that funding for projects conducted through the regional centers be awarded through a competitive, merit-reviewed process.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
