<bill session="111" type="s" number="208" updated="2009-03-07T13:58:04-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231736400" datetime="2009-01-12"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231736400" datetime="2009-01-12"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Mynisha's Law</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide Federal coordination and assistance in preventing gang violence.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300011"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231736400" datetime="2009-01-12"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Child care and development"/>
		<term name="Child health"/>
		<term name="Crime prevention"/>
		<term name="Education programs funding"/>
		<term name="Employment and training programs"/>
		<term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
		<term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
		<term name="Preschool education"/>
		<term name="Youth employment and child labor"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/12/2009--Introduced.<br/>Mynisha's Law - Authorizes any local or tribal government to submit an application to the Attorney General for designation as a High Intensity Gang Activity Area. Directs the Attorney General to: (1) establish criteria for reviewing such applications; and (2) establish an Interagency Gang Prevention Task Force in each Area. Directs each Task Force to: (1) coordinate government activities to create a comprehensive gang prevention response, focusing on early childhood intervention, at-risk youth intervention, literacy, employment, community policing, and comprehensive community-based programs such as Operation Cease Fire; (2) coordinate with local and regional gang prevention efforts; (3) prioritize the needs of each Area for funding under specified federal community assistance and grant programs; and (4) report to the Attorney General on the funding needs and programmatic outcomes for each Area.<br/>Requires the Attorney General to report to Congress, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) and the Domestic Policy Council annually on: (1) the specific long-term and short-term goals and objectives of each Area; (2) the measurements used to evaluate each Area's performance; (3) the gangs and gang crimes committed in each Area; and (5) the programmatic outcomes and funding need of each Area.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
