<bill session="111" type="s" number="21" updated="2009-03-07T13:34:18-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Prevention First Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">At-Risk Communities Teen Pregnancy Prevention Act of 2009</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Compassionate Assistance for Rape Emergencies Act of 2009</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Emergency Contraception Education Act of 2009</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Equity in Prescription Insurance and Contraceptive Coverage Act of 2007</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Prevention Through Affordable Access Act</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Responsible Education About Life Act of 2009</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Title X Family Planning Services Act of 2009</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Truth in Contraception Act of 2009</title>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Unintended Pregnancy Reduction Act of 2009</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reduce unintended pregnancy, reduce abortions, and improve access to women's health care.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300082"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300056" joined="2009-01-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300065" joined="2009-01-29"/>
		<cosponsor id="400272" joined="2009-01-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300005" joined="2009-01-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300009" joined="2009-02-03"/>
		<cosponsor id="300022" joined="2009-01-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2009-01-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300001" joined="2009-01-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300093" joined="2009-01-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2009-01-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300060" joined="2009-01-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300066" joined="2009-01-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300087" joined="2009-02-26"/>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2009-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300019" joined="2009-01-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2009-01-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412247" joined="2009-01-06"/>
		<cosponsor id="412244" joined="2009-01-07"/>
		<cosponsor id="300064" joined="2009-01-06"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S47-53"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="463" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Birth control"/>
		<term name="Child care and development"/>
		<term name="Child health"/>
		<term name="Crimes against women"/>
		<term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
		<term name="Emergency medical services"/>
		<term name="HIV-AIDS"/>
		<term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
		<term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
		<term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
		<term name="Health information and medical records"/>
		<term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
		<term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
		<term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
		<term name="Immigrant health and welfare"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Medical research"/>
		<term name="Prescription drugs"/>
		<term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
		<term name="Sexually transmitted diseases"/>
		<term name="Women's health"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/6/2009--Introduced.<br/>Prevention First Act - Title X Family Planning Services Act of 2009 - Authorizes appropriations for family planning services grants and contracts under the Public Health Service Act (PHSA). Equity in Prescription Insurance and Contraceptive Coverage Act of 2007 [sic]- Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) and PHSA to prohibit a group health plan from excluding or restricting benefits for prescription contraceptive drugs, devices, and outpatient services if the plan provides benefits for other outpatient prescription drugs, devices, or outpatient services. Applies such prohibitions to coverage offered in the individual market. Emergency Contraception Education Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to develop and disseminate information on emergency contraception to the public and to health care providers. Compassionate Assistance for Rape Emergencies Act of 2009 - Requires hospitals, as a condition of receiving federal funds, to offer and to provide, upon request, emergency contraception to victims of sexual assault. At-Risk Communities Teen Pregnancy Prevention Act of 2009 - Authorizes the Secretary to award grants for teenage pregnancy prevention programs. Requires the Secretary to award grants for teenage pregnancy prevention research. Truth in Contraception Act of 2009 - Requires that any information concerning the use of a contraceptive provided through specified federally funded education programs be medically accurate and include health benefits and failure rates. Unintended Pregnancy Reduction Act of 2009 - Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to expand Medicaid's coverage of family planning services. Responsible Education About Life Act of 2009 - Requires the Secretary to make grants to states for family life education, including education on abstinence and contraception, to prevent teenage pregnancy and sexually transmitted diseases. Prevention Through Affordable Access Act - Expands Medicaid rebates to manufacturers for the sale of covered outpatient drugs at nominal prices to include sales to student health care facilities and entities offering family planning services.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
