<bill session="111" type="s" number="252" updated="2009-03-07T14:03:12-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231995600" datetime="2009-01-15"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231995600" datetime="2009-01-15"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Health Care Authorization Act of 2009</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to enhance the capacity of the Department of Veterans Affairs to recruit and retain nurses and other critical health-care professionals, to improve the provision of health care veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300001"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400418" joined="2009-02-12"/>
		<cosponsor id="300076" joined="2009-01-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2009-01-15"/>
		<cosponsor id="400054" joined="2009-01-22"/>
		<cosponsor id="412326" joined="2009-01-30"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231995600" datetime="2009-01-15"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S599)</text></action>
		<action date="1231995600" datetime="2009-01-15"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S599-612"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Child care and development"/>
		<term name="Child health"/>
		<term name="Crime victims"/>
		<term name="Dental care"/>
		<term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
		<term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
		<term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
		<term name="Health care quality"/>
		<term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
		<term name="Health information and medical records"/>
		<term name="Health personnel"/>
		<term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
		<term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
		<term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
		<term name="Medical research"/>
		<term name="Mental health"/>
		<term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
		<term name="Minority health"/>
		<term name="Nursing"/>
		<term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
		<term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
		<term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
		<term name="Women's health"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/15/2009--Introduced.<br/>Veterans Health Care Authorization Act of 2009 - Revises or adds provisions concerning Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) personnel matters, including: (1) the retention of medical professionals; (2) limitations on duty and alternative work schedules for nurses; (3) educational assistance programs; and (4) standards for the appointment and practice of VA physicians. Revises or adds provisions concerning VA health care matters, including: (1) care furnished to children of Vietnam veterans; (2) medical records disclosures; (3) health care quality management; (4) pilot programs on training and certification for family caregivers, respite care to members of the Armed Forces and veterans with traumatic brain injury (TBI), the use of community-based organizations and local and state entities to ensure that veterans receive authorized care and benefits, and the provision of dental insurance plans to veterans and their survivors and dependents; (5) specialized residential care and rehabilitation; (6) the use of non-VA facilities for the rehabilitation of veterans with TBI; and (7) the inclusion of certain tribal organizations in programs for state veterans homes. Revises or adds provisions concerning women veterans health care, including: (1) reports on barriers to their receipt of health care, and full-time women veterans program managers at medical centers; (2) pilot programs or studies on the health consequences of women veterans of Operations Iraqi Freedom and Enduring Freedom, counseling for women veterans recently separated from service, and subsidies for child care for women veterans receiving health care; (3) training and certification for mental health care providers caring for veterans suffering from sexual trauma; and (4) care for newborn children of veterans receiving maternity care. Revises or adds provisions concerning veterans' mental health care, including: (1) services provided through the Readjustment Counseling Service; and (2) a study on veteran suicides. Revises or adds provisions concerning homeless veterans, including pilot programs on financial support for entities providing: (1) supportive services for formerly homeless veterans residing on certain military property or other permanent housing; (2) outreach about pension benefits; and (3) transportation, child care, and clothing assistance to homeless veterans entitled to a rehabilitation program. Revises or adds provisions concerning VA nonprofit research and education corporations. Expands the authority of VA police officers, and provides them a uniform allowance.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
