<bill session="111" type="s" number="275" updated="2009-03-07T14:06:34-05:00">
	<status><calendar date="1232082000" datetime="2009-01-16" /></status>

	<introduced date="1232082000" datetime="2009-01-16"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Children's Health Insurance Program Reauthorization Act of 2009</title>
		<title type="short" as="reported to senate">Children's Health Insurance Program Reauthorization Act of 2009</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">An original bill to amend title XXI of the Social Security Act to extend and improve the Children's Health Insurance Program, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300005"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1232082000" datetime="2009-01-16"><text>Committee on Finance. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Baucus. Without written report.</text></action>
		<calendar date="1232082000" datetime="2009-01-16" ><text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 17.</text></calendar>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Origin, Reporting" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2" />
		<bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="2" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Advisory bodies"/>
		<term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
		<term name="Child health"/>
		<term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
		<term name="Congressional oversight"/>
		<term name="Dental care"/>
		<term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
		<term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
		<term name="Government investigations"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
		<term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
		<term name="Health care quality"/>
		<term name="Health information and medical records"/>
		<term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
		<term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Mental health"/>
		<term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
		<term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
		<term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
		<term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
		<term name="Women's health"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/16/2009--Introduced.<br/>Children's Health Insurance Program Reauthorization Act of 2009 - Amends title XXI (State Children's Health Insurance Program) (SCHIP) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to reauthorize the program (referred to in this Act as CHIP) through FY2013 at increased levels. Revises requirements for: (1) CHIP allotments; (2) optional coverage of low-income pregnant women; (3) outreach and enrollment activities; (4) verification of U.S. citizenship or nationality for CHIP and Medicaid (SSA title XIX); (5) state option for providing premium assistance, including coordination with private coverage; (6) child health quality improvement activities; (7) access to dental and mental health benefits; (8) child health assistance furnished through school-based health centers; and (9) program integrity and data collection, including the payment error rate measurement (PERM). Establishes in the Treasury the Child Enrollment Contingency Fund.<br/>Requires phase-out of CHIP coverage for nonpregnant childless adults. Limits the matching rate for states that propose to cover children with effective family income that exceeds 300% of the poverty line. Establishes the Medicaid and CHIP Payment and Access Commission (MACPAC) to review Medicaid and CHIP policies affecting children's access to covered items and services. Denies federal funding for illegal aliens.<br/>Prohibits initiation of new health opportunity account demonstration programs.<br/>Establishes a task force to conduct a nationwide campaign of education and outreach for small business concerns regarding the availability of coverage for children through private insurance options, the Medicaid program, and CHIP. Expresses the sense of the Senate affirming its intent to enact legislation this year that improves access to affordable and meaningful health insurance coverage for employees of small businesses and individuals. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to increase the excise tax on tobacco products but allow a specified credit against tobacco floor stocks taxes.<br/>Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to study and make recommendations to Congress about the magnitude of tobacco smuggling in the United States. Amends the Tax Increase Prevention and Reconciliation Act of 2005 to increase the amount of any required installment of corporate estimated tax which is otherwise due in July, August, or September 2013. 
	</summary>
</bill>
