<bill session="111" type="s" number="315" updated="2009-03-07T14:11:13-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1232946000" datetime="2009-01-26"/></status>

	<introduced date="1232946000" datetime="2009-01-26"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Outreach Improvement Act of 2009</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the outreach activities of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300042"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400357" joined="2009-01-26"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1232946000" datetime="2009-01-26"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S833-834)</text></action>
		<action date="1232946000" datetime="2009-01-26"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
		<term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
		<term name="Military cemeteries and funerals"/>
		<term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
		<term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
		<term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
		<term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/26/2009--Introduced.<br/>Veterans Outreach Improvement Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Veterans to establish a separate account for the funding of outreach activities of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) and a separate subaccount for the funding of outreach activities of the Veterans Health Administration, the Veterans Benefits Administration, and the National Cemetery Administration. Directs the Secretary to establish and maintain procedures for ensuring the effective coordination of VA outreach activities between and among such elements, the Office of the Secretary, and the Office of Public Affairs. Authorizes the Secretary to award grants to: (1) state and local governments and nonprofit community-based organizations to carry out programs that offer a high probability of improving veterans' outreach and assistance; and (2) appropriate state veterans agencies for such purpose.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
