<bill session="111" type="s" number="379" updated="2009-03-07T14:18:38-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1233723600" datetime="2009-02-04"/></status>

	<introduced date="1233723600" datetime="2009-02-04"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Performance Rights Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide fair compensation to artists for use of their sound recordings.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300065"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="300002" joined="2009-02-09"/>
		<cosponsor id="300011" joined="2009-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300052" joined="2009-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="412248" joined="2009-02-04"/>
		<cosponsor id="300043" joined="2009-02-04"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1233723600" datetime="2009-02-04"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1544-1545)</text></action>
		<action date="1233723600" datetime="2009-02-04"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S1545-1546"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>
		<bill relation="unknown" session="111" type="h" number="848" />
	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Commerce"/>
		<term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital media"/>
		<term name="Intellectual property"/>
		<term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
		<term name="Performing arts"/>
		<term name="Sound recording"/>
		<term name="User charges and fees"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/4/2009--Introduced.<br/>Performance Rights Act - Amends federal copyright law to: (1) grant performers of sound recordings equal rights to compensation from terrestrial broadcasters; and (2) modify the circumstances under which the public performance of a sound recording is subject to statutory licensing. Establishes a flat annual fee in lieu of payment of royalties for individual terrestrial broadcast stations with gross revenues of less than $1.25 million and for noncommercial, public broadcast stations. Grants: (1) an exemption from royalty payments for broadcasts of religious services and for incidental uses of musical sound recordings; and (2) terrestrial broadcast stations that make limited feature uses of sound recordings a per program license option. Prohibits anything in this Act from adversely affecting the public performance rights or royalties payable to songwriters or copyright owners of musical works.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
