<bill session="111" type="s" number="384" updated="2009-03-07T14:19:13-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1233810000" datetime="2009-02-05"/></status>

	<introduced date="1233810000" datetime="2009-02-05"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Global Food Security Act of 2009</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize appropriations for fiscal years 2010 through 2014 to provide assistance to foreign countries to promote food security, to stimulate rural economies, and to improve emergency response to food crises, to amend the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="300070"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="412246" joined="2009-02-05"/>
		<cosponsor id="300038" joined="2009-02-05"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1233810000" datetime="2009-02-05"><text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1679-1680)</text></action>
		<action date="1233810000" datetime="2009-02-05"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="International affairs"/>
		<term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
		<term name="Agricultural education"/>
		<term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
		<term name="Agricultural research"/>
		<term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
		<term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
		<term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
		<term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
		<term name="Higher education"/>
		<term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
		<term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
		<term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	2/5/2009--Introduced.<br/>Global Food Security Act of 2009 - States that it is U.S. policy to promote global food security, improve agricultural productivity, and support the development of institutions of higher learning. Directs the President to designate an individual to serve as the Special Coordinator for Food Security to advise the President on international food security issues and oversee implementation of a comprehensive food security strategy. Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to authorize appropriations for programs of agriculture, rural development, and nutrition. Permits certain of such funds to be made available for: (1) the collaborative research support program; and (2) the consultative group on international agricultural research.<br/>Establishes the higher education collaboration for technology, agriculture, research, and extension to provide assistance for policies and programs in eligible countries that advance agricultural productivity and hunger alleviation through partnerships with institutions of higher education.<br/>Authorizes the President to provide assistance under this Act or the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 for unexpected urgent food assistance needs. Establishes a United States Emergency Food Assistance Fund to carry out such purposes.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
