<bill session="111" type="s" number="82" updated="2009-03-07T13:41:54-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Enhancing Health Care Coverage for Children Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XXI of the Social Security Act to reauthorize the State Children's Health Insurance Program, to limit income eligibility expansions under that program until the lowest income eligible individuals are enrolled, and for other purposes.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400418"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
		<term name="Child health"/>
		<term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
		<term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
		<term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
		<term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
		<term name="Immigrant health and welfare"/>
		<term name="Medicaid"/>
		<term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/6/2009--Introduced.<br/>Enhancing Health Care Coverage for Children Act - Amends title XXI (State Children's Health Insurance) (SCHIP) of the Social Security Act, as amended by the Medicare, Medicaid, and SCHIP Extension Act of 2007, to revise, reauthorize, and extend the SCHIP program through FY2014. Requires the state SCHIP plan to specify how it will achieve coverage for 85% of eligible targeted low-income children in the state. Prohibits payment for child health assistance for a targeted low-income child in a family whose income exceeds 250% of the poverty line. Sets forth special rules for children with family income between 200% and 250% of the applicable poverty line. Applies Medicaid citizenship documentation requirements to SCHIP. Terminates SCHIP coverage for nonpregnant adults. Requires that individuals who are eligible for SCHIP and employer-sponsored coverage use the employer-sponsored coverage instead of SCHIP.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
