<bill session="111" type="s" number="93" updated="2009-03-07T13:43:11-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Empowerment Act</title>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide quality, affordable health insurance for small employers and individuals.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400050"/>
	<cosponsors>

	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"><text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Health"/>
		<term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
		<term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
		<term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
		<term name="Government information and archives"/>
		<term name="Government trust funds"/>
		<term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
		<term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
		<term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
		<term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
		<term name="Small business"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/6/2009--Introduced.<br/>Small Business Empowerment Act - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a national program to make quality, affordable health insurance available to small employers and self-employed individuals in a manner that will spread risk on a national basis, modeled on the federal employees health benefit program.<br/>Requires the Secretary to enter into a contract with an eligible entity for administration of the program. Authorizes such entity to provide health insurance coverage to employees of participating employers and individuals. Directs such entity to: (1) establish a pilot program to provide for the offering by carriers of a model health benefits plan; and (2) contract with the Institute of Medicine to assess the impact of the program on health care coverage costs and access.<br/>Continues state mandated benefit laws for plans under this Act.<br/>Sets minimum standards for program health benefits plans. Directs the Secretary to prescribe regulations providing for employer participation.<br/>Establishes the National Health Coverage Commission. Includes among Commission duties: (1) developing a model that ensures adequate coverage for medically necessary services, promotes disease and chronic disease management, and provides incentives for health provider compliance with best practices protocols; and (2) developing model cost sharing mechanisms that do not discriminate and that accommodate lower income individuals.<br/>Directs the Secretary and the administrative entity to implement an educational campaign concerning the program.<br/>Requires the Secretary to establish a program to provide reinsurance to qualified carriers offering plans under this Act. Establishes the Small Business Health Coverage Trust Fund. 
	</summary>
</bill>
