<bill session="111" type="sr" number="4" updated="2009-03-07T14:38:56-05:00">
	<status><introduced date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"/></status>

	<introduced date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"/>
	<titles>
		<title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate that the Supreme Court of the United States erroneously decided Kennedy v. Louisiana, No. 07-343 (2008), and that the eighth amendment to the Constitution of the United States allows the imposition of the death penalty for the rape of a child.</title>
	</titles>
	<sponsor id="400418"/>
	<cosponsors>
		<cosponsor id="400105" joined="2009-01-12"/>
	</cosponsors>
	<actions>
		<action date="1231218000" datetime="2009-01-06"><text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text><reference label="text of measure as introduced" ref="CR S148"/></action>
	</actions>
	<committees>
		<committee name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral, In Committee" />
	</committees>
	<relatedbills>

	</relatedbills>
	<subjects>
		<term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
		<term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
		<term name="Crimes against children"/>
		<term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
		<term name="Supreme Court"/>
	</subjects>
	<amendments>

	</amendments>
	<summary>
	1/6/2009--Introduced.<br/>Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) the eighth amendment to the Constitution allows the death penalty for the rape of a child where the crime did not result, and was not intended to result, in death of the victim; (2) the Louisiana statute making child rape punishable by death is constitutional; (3) because Kennedy v. Louisiana was decided under a mistaken view of federal law, the U.S. Supreme Court should grant any petition for rehearing of the case and the portions of the decision regarding the national consensus or evolving standards of decency with respect to the imposition of the death penalty for child rape should not be viewed as binding precedent; and (4) the Supreme Court should reverse its decision on rehearing or in a future case because it was supported by neither commonly held beliefs about cruel and unusual punishment nor by the text, structure, or history of the Constitution.<br/>
	</summary>
</bill>
